<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1588891</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:572</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Follmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ines</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ochrombel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kraemer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Troetschel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ansgar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Poetsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42238</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9722-4435</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hueser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Persicke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177004</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dominic</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seiferling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kay</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Marin</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070724</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: The maintenance of internal pH in bacterial cells is challenged by natural stress conditions, during host infection or in biotechnological production processes. Comprehensive transcriptomic and proteomic analyses has been conducted in several bacterial model systems, yet questions remain as to the mechanisms of pH homeostasis. Results: Here we present the comprehensive analysis of pH homeostasis in C. glutamicum, a bacterium of industrial importance. At pH values between 6 and 9 effective maintenance of the internal pH at 7.5 +/- 0.5 pH units was found. By DNA microarray analyses differential mRNA patterns were identified. The expression profiles were validated and extended by 1D-LC-ESI-MS/MS based quantification of soluble and membrane proteins. Regulators involved were identified and thereby participation of numerous signaling modules in pH response was found. The functional analysis revealed for the first time the occurrence of oxidative stress in C. glutamicum cells at neutral and low pH conditions accompanied by activation of the iron starvation response. Intracellular metabolite pool analysis unraveled inhibition of the TCA and other pathways at low pH. Methionine and cysteine synthesis were found to be activated via the McbR regulator, cysteine accumulation was observed and addition of cysteine was shown to be toxic under acidic conditions. Conclusions: Novel limitations for C. glutamicum at non-optimal pH values were identified by a comprehensive analysis on the level of the transcriptome, proteome, and metabolome indicating a functional link between pH acclimatization, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis, and metabolic alterations. The results offer new insights into bacterial stress physiology and new starting points for bacterial strain design or pathogen defense.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Follmann.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1588891/2311102/Follmann.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Genomics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2164</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">20025733</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000273903700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-15888918</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-10-621</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">621</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Follmann, M., Ochrombel, I., Kraemer, R., Troetschel, C., Poetsch, A., Rückert, C., Hueser, A., Persicke, M., Seiferling, D., Kalinowski, J., Marin, K.: Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. BMC Genomics. 10, 621 (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Follmann, Martin, Ochrombel, Ines, Kraemer, Reinhard, Troetschel, Christian, Poetsch, Ansgar, Rückert, Christian, Hueser, Andrea, et al. 2009. “Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 10 (1): 621.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Follmann M, Ochrombel I, Kraemer R, et al. Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;10(1):621.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Follmann, I.  Ochrombel, R.  Kraemer, C.  Troetschel, A.  Poetsch, C.  Rückert, A.  Hueser, M.  Persicke, D.  Seiferling, J.  Kalinowski, et al., “Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 621.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Follmann M, Ochrombel I, Kraemer R, Troetschel C, Poetsch A, Rückert C, Hueser A, Persicke M, Seiferling D, Kalinowski J, Marin K (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 10(1): 621.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Follmann, M., Ochrombel, I., Kraemer, R., Troetschel, C., Poetsch, A., Rückert, C., Hueser, A., Persicke, M., Seiferling, D., Kalinowski, J. &amp;amp; Marin, K. (2009). Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 621. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-10-621.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Follmann, M., Ochrombel, I., Kraemer, R., Troetschel, C., Poetsch, A., Rückert, C., Hueser, A., et al. (2009). Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 621. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-10-621" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-10-621&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Follmann, M., et al., 2009. Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, 10(1), p 621.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Follmann, et al., “Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2009,  pp. 621.</ieee>
<default>Follmann M, Ochrombel I, Kraemer R, Troetschel C, Poetsch A, Rückert C, Hueser A, Persicke M, Seiferling D, Kalinowski J, Marin K (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 10(1): 621.</default>
<frontiers>Follmann, M., Ochrombel, I., Kraemer, R., Troetschel, C., Poetsch, A., Rückert, C., Hueser, A., Persicke, M., Seiferling, D., Kalinowski, J., et al. (2009). Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 10, 621.</frontiers>
<mla>Follmann, Martin, Ochrombel, Ines, Kraemer, Reinhard, Troetschel, Christian, Poetsch, Ansgar, Rückert, Christian, Hueser, Andrea, Persicke, Marcus, Seiferling, Dominic, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Marin, Kay. “Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 10.1 (2009): 621.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Follmann, M., Ochrombel, I., Kraemer, R., Troetschel, C., Poetsch, A., Rückert, C., Hueser, A., et al. (2009). Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 621. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-10-621" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-10-621&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Follmann, M.; Ochrombel, I.; Kraemer, R.; Troetschel, C.; Poetsch, A.; Rückert, C.; Hueser, A.; Persicke, M.; Seiferling, D.; Kalinowski, J.; Marin, K. (2009): Functional genomics of pH homeostasis in Corynebacterium glutamicum revealed novel links between pH response, oxidative stress, iron homeostasis and methionine synthesis &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,10:(1): 621.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1588891</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-26T09:44:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>