<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1606464</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holger</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bekel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bax</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gunther</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heidemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Carl Edward</namePart><namePart type="family">Rasmussen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Heinrich H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bülthoff</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Martin A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Giese</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bernhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Schölkopf</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>26th DAGM Symposium</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The "life" of most neural vision systems splits into a one-time training phase and an application phase during which knowledge is no longer acquired. This is both technically inflexible and cognitively unsatisfying. Here we propose an appearance based vision system for object recognition which can be adapted online, both to acquire visual knowledge about new objects and to correct erroneous classification. The system works in an office scenario, acquisition of object knowledge is triggered by hand gestures. The neural classifier offers two ways of training: Firstly, the new samples can be added immediately to the classifier to obtain a running system at once, though at the cost of reduced classification performance. Secondly, a parallel processing branch adapts the classification system thoroughly to the enlarged image domain and loads the new classifier to the running system when ready.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bekel_bax_heidemann_ritter_DAGM04.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1606464/2719839/bekel_bax_heidemann_ritter_DAGM04.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Tübingen, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Pattern Recognition. Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-22945-0</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000223798300055</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-16064643</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3175</number></detail><extent unit="pages">447-454</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Bekel, H., et al., 2004. Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In C. E.  Rasmussen, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. no.3175  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 447-454.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Bekel, et al., “Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition”, &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, C.E. Rasmussen, et al., eds., Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 3175,  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 2004,  pp.447-454.</ieee>
<apa>Bekel, H., Bax, I., Heidemann, G., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In C. E.  Rasmussen, H. H.  Bülthoff, M. A.  Giese, &amp;amp; B.  Schölkopf (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 3175&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 447-454). Berlin: Springer-Verlag.</apa>
<wels>Bekel, H.; Bax, I.; Heidemann, G.; Ritter, H. (2004): Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In: Carl Edward Rasmussen; Heinrich H. Bülthoff; Martin A. Giese; Bernhard Schölkopf (Hrsg.):  Pattern Recognition. Proceedings. Berlin: Springer-Verlag. (Lecture notes in computer science, 3175).  S. 447-454.</wels>
<mla>Bekel, Holger, Bax, Ingo, Heidemann, Gunther, and Ritter, Helge. “Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition”. &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Carl Edward Rasmussen, Heinrich H. Bülthoff, Martin A. Giese, and Bernhard Schölkopf. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 2004.Vol. 3175. Lecture notes in computer science. 447-454.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bekel, H., Bax, I., Heidemann, G., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In C. E.  Rasmussen, H. H.  Bülthoff, M. A.  Giese, &amp;amp; B.  Schölkopf (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 3175&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 447-454). Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bekel, H., Bax, I., Heidemann, G., and Ritter, H. (2004). “Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition” in &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Rasmussen, C. E., Bülthoff, H. H., Giese, M. A., and Schölkopf, B. eds. Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 3175, (Berlin: Springer-Verlag), 447-454.</frontiers>
<default>Bekel H, Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Pattern Recognition. Proceedings. Rasmussen CE, Bülthoff HH, Giese MA, Schölkopf B (Eds);  Lecture notes in computer science, 3175.  Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  447-454.</default>
<ama>Bekel H, Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H. Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In: Rasmussen CE, Bülthoff HH, Giese MA, Schölkopf B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. Vol 3175. Berlin: Springer-Verlag;  2004: 447-454.</ama>
<lncs> Bekel, H., Bax, I., Heidemann, G., Ritter, H.: Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. In: Rasmussen, C.E., Bülthoff, H.H., Giese, M.A., and Schölkopf, B. (eds.) Pattern Recognition. Proceedings. Lecture notes in computer science. 3175, p. 447-454. Springer-Verlag, Berlin (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bekel, Holger, Bax, Ingo, Heidemann, Gunther, and Ritter, Helge. 2004. “Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition”. In &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Carl Edward Rasmussen, Heinrich H. Bülthoff, Martin A. Giese, and Bernhard Schölkopf, 3175:447-454. Lecture notes in computer science. Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bekel, H., Bax, I., Heidemann, G. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition (Lecture notes in computer science). In C.E. Rasmussen, H.H. Bülthoff, M.A. Giese &amp;amp; B. Schölkopf (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 447-454). Gehalten auf der 26th DAGM Symposium, Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Bekel, I.  Bax, G.  Heidemann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C.E. Rasmussen, H.H. Bülthoff, M.A. Giese, B. Schölkopf), Springer-Verlag, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 447-454.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bekel H, Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptive Computer Vision: Online Learning for Object Recognition. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Pattern Recognition. Proceedings. Rasmussen CE, Bülthoff HH, Giese MA, Schölkopf B (Eds); Lecture notes in computer science, 3175. Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  447-454.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1606464</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:57:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>