<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1606782</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:580</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kluge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4773911</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bolte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S. S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sharma</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanitzsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Satiat-Jeunemaitre</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ross</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177825</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dortje</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Golldack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22121</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karl-Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dietz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21935</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070563</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Vacuolar H+-ATPases are large protein complexes of more than 700 kDa that acidify endomembrane compartments and are part of the secretory system of eukaryotic cells. They are built from 14 different ( VHA)-subunits. The paper addresses the question of sub-cellular localisation and subunit composition of plant V-ATPase in vivo and in vitro mainly by using colocalization and fluorescence resonance energy transfer techniques ( FRET). Focus is placed on the examination and function of the 95 kDa membrane spanning subunit VHA-a. Showing similarities to the already described Vph1 and Stv1 vacuolar ATPase subunits from yeast, VHA-a revealed a bipartite structure with (i) a less conserved cytoplasmically orientated N-terminus and (ii) a membrane-spanning C-terminus with a higher extent of conservation including all amino acids shown to be essential for proton translocation in the yeast. On the basis of sequence data VHA-a appears to be an essential structural and functional element of V-ATPase, although previously a sole function in assembly has been proposed. Results: To elucidate the presence and function of VHA-a in the plant complex, three approaches were undertaken: ( i) co-immunoprecipitation with antibodies directed to epitopes in the N- and C-terminal part of VHA-a, respectively, ( ii) immunocytochemistry approach including co-localisation studies with known plant endomembrane markers, and (iii) in vivo-FRET between subunits fused to variants of green fluorescence protein (CFP, YFP) in transfected cells. Conclusions: All three sets of results show that V-ATPase contains VHA-a protein that interacts in a specific manner with other subunits. The genomes of plants encode three genes of the 95 kDa subunit ( VHA-a) of the vacuolar type H+-ATPase. Immuno-localisation of VHA-a shows that the recognized subunit is exclusively located on the endoplasmic reticulum. This result is in agreement with the hypothesis that the different isoforms of VHA-a may localize on distinct endomembrane compartments, as it was shown for its yeast counterpart Vph1.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1471_2121_5_29.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1606782/2311127/1471_2121_5_29.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>BIOMED CENTRAL LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Cell Biology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2121</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">15310389</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000223687700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-16067826</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2121-5-29</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Kluge, C, Seidel, Thorsten, Bolte, S, Sharma, S. S., Hanitzsch, M, Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B, Ross, J, Sauer, Markus, Golldack, Dortje, and Dietz, Karl-Josef. “Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt; 5.1 (2004): 29.</mla>
<default>Kluge C, Seidel T, Bolte S, Sharma SS, Hanitzsch M, Satiat-Jeunemaitre B, Ross J, Sauer M, Golldack D, Dietz K-J (2004) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt; 5(1): 29.</default>
<lncs> Kluge, C., Seidel, T., Bolte, S., Sharma, S.S., Hanitzsch, M., Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B., Ross, J., Sauer, M., Golldack, D., Dietz, K.-J.: Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. BMC Cell Biology. 5, 29 (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluge, C, Seidel, Thorsten, Bolte, S, Sharma, S. S., Hanitzsch, M, Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B, Ross, J, Sauer, Markus, Golldack, Dortje, and Dietz, Karl-Josef. 2004. “Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt; 5 (1): 29.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluge, C., Seidel, T., Bolte, S., Sharma, S. S., Hanitzsch, M., Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B., Ross, J., et al. (2004). Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(1), 29. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2121-5-29" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2121-5-29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Kluge C, Seidel T, Bolte S, Sharma SS, Hanitzsch M, Satiat-Jeunemaitre B, Ross J, Sauer M, Golldack D, Dietz K-J (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Cell Biology 5(1): 29.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kluge, C., et al., 2004. Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 5(1), p 29.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kluge, T.  Seidel, S.  Bolte, S. S.  Sharma, M.  Hanitzsch, B.  Satiat-Jeunemaitre, J.  Ross, M.  Sauer, D.  Golldack, and K. - J.  Dietz, “Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 29.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Kluge, C.; Seidel, T.; Bolte, S.; Sharma, S. S.; Hanitzsch, M.; Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B.; Ross, J.; Sauer, M.; Golldack, D.; Dietz, K. - J. (2004): Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;,5:(1): 29.</wels>
<apa>Kluge, C., Seidel, T., Bolte, S., Sharma, S. S., Hanitzsch, M., Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B., Ross, J., et al. (2004). Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(1), 29. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2121-5-29" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2121-5-29&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> C. Kluge, et al., “Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 5, 2004,  pp. 29.</ieee>
<ama>Kluge C, Seidel T, Bolte S, et al. Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;. 2004;5(1):29.</ama>
<frontiers>Kluge, C., Seidel, T., Bolte, S., Sharma, S. S., Hanitzsch, M., Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B., Ross, J., Sauer, M., Golldack, D., and Dietz, K. - J. (2004). Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt; 5, 29.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluge, C., Seidel, T., Bolte, S., Sharma, S.S., Hanitzsch, M., Satiat-Jeunemaitre, B., Ross, J., Sauer, M., Golldack, D. &amp;amp; Dietz, K.-J. (2004). Subcellular distribution of the V-ATPase complex in plant cells, and in vivo localisation of the 100 kDa subunit VHA-a within the complex. &lt;em&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(1), 29. BIOMED CENTRAL LTD. doi:10.1186/1471-2121-5-29.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1606782</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:57:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>