<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1607115</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Elisabeth</namePart><namePart type="family">André</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Laila</namePart><namePart type="family">Dybkjær</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart><namePart type="family">Minker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Heisterkamp</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ADS 2004</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We describe an implemented system for the simulation and visualisation of the emotional state of a multimodal conversational agent called Max. The focus of the presented work lies on modeling a coherent. course of emotions over time. The basic idea of the underlying emotion system is the linkage of two interrelated psychological concepts: an emotion axis representing short-time system states - and an orthogonal mood axis that stands for an undirected, longer lasting system state. A third axis was added to realize a dimension of boredom. To enhance the believability and lifelikeness of Max, the emotion system has been integrated in the agent's architecture. In result, Max's facial expression, gesture, speech, and secondary behaviors As well as his cognitive functions are modulated by the emotional system that, in turn, is affected by information arising at various levels within the agent's architecture.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MAX_ADS04_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1607115/2634978/MAX_ADS04_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Kloster Irsee, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-22143-2</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-24842-2</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000222862900015</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-16071156</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3068</number></detail><extent unit="pages">154-165</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Becker, C., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In E.  André, L.  Dybkjær, W.  Minker, &amp;amp; P.  Heisterkamp (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI): Vol. 3068&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 154-165). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> C. Becker, S. Kopp, and I. Wachsmuth, “Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent”, &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;, E. André, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), vol. 3068,  Berlin: Springer, 2004,  pp.154-165.</ieee>
<ama>Becker C, Kopp S, Wachsmuth I. Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In: André E, Dybkjær L, Minker W, Heisterkamp P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). Vol 3068. Berlin: Springer;  2004: 154-165.</ama>
<frontiers>Becker, C., Kopp, S., and Wachsmuth, I. (2004). “Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent” in &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;, André, E., Dybkjær, L., Minker, W., and Heisterkamp, P. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), vol. 3068, (Berlin: Springer), 154-165.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent (Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). In E. André, L. Dybkjær, W. Minker &amp;amp; P. Heisterkamp (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt; (S. 154-165). Gehalten auf der ADS 2004, Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In E.  André, L.  Dybkjær, W.  Minker, &amp;amp; P.  Heisterkamp (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI): Vol. 3068&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 154-165). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24842-2_15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Becker C, Kopp S, Wachsmuth I (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004. André E, Dybkjær L, Minker W, Heisterkamp P (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 3068. Berlin: Springer:  154-165.</bio1>
<harvard1>Becker, C., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2004. Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In E.  André, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). no.3068  Berlin: Springer, pp. 154-165.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Becker, S.  Kopp, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. André, L. Dybkjær, W. Minker, P. Heisterkamp), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 154-165.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Becker, C.; Kopp, S.; Wachsmuth, I. (2004): Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In: Elisabeth André; Laila Dybkjær; Wolfgang Minker; Paul Heisterkamp (Hrsg.):  Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004. Berlin: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 3068).  S. 154-165.</wels>
<mla>Becker, Christian, Kopp, Stefan, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent”. &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Elisabeth André, Laila Dybkjær, Wolfgang Minker, and Paul Heisterkamp. Berlin: Springer, 2004.Vol. 3068. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). 154-165.</mla>
<default>Becker C, Kopp S, Wachsmuth I (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004. André E, Dybkjær L, Minker W, Heisterkamp P (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 3068.  Berlin: Springer:  154-165.</default>
<lncs> Becker, C., Kopp, S., Wachsmuth, I.: Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent. In: André, E., Dybkjær, L., Minker, W., and Heisterkamp, P. (eds.) Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). 3068, p. 154-165. Springer, Berlin (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, Christian, Kopp, Stefan, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2004. “Simulating the emotion dynamics of a multimodal conversational agent”. In &lt;em&gt;Affective Dialogue Systems - Proceedings of the Tutorial and Research Workshop, ADS 2004&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Elisabeth André, Laila Dybkjær, Wolfgang Minker, and Paul Heisterkamp, 3068:154-165. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1607115</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:57:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>