<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1625508</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lenzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gerhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Weiss</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes a multi-agent learning approach to adaptation to users' preferences realized by an interface agency. Using a contract-net-based negotiation technique, agents as contractors as well as managers negotiate with each other to pursue the overall goal of dynamic user adaptation. By learning from indirect user feedback, the adjustment of internal credit vectors and the assignment of contractors that gained maximal credit with respect to the user's current preferences, the preceding session, and current situational circumstances can be realized. In this way,user adaptation is achieved without accumulating explicit user models but by the use of implicit, distributed user models.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="springer97paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1625508/2630546/springer97paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-62934-3</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000074016000014</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-16255088</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1221</number></detail><extent unit="pages">202-222</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1997. Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In G.  Weiss, ed. &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI. no.1221  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 202-222.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Lenzmann and I. Wachsmuth, “Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency”, &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;, G. Weiss, ed., LNAI, vol. 1221,  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1997,  pp.202-222.</ieee>
<apa>Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1997). Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In G.  Weiss (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI: Vol. 1221&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 202-222). Berlin: Springer-Verlag.</apa>
<wels>Lenzmann, B.; Wachsmuth, I. (1997): Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In: Gerhard Weiss (Hrsg.):  Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments. Berlin: Springer-Verlag. (LNAI, 1221).  S. 202-222.</wels>
<mla>Lenzmann, Britta, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency”. &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Gerhard Weiss. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1997.Vol. 1221. LNAI. 202-222.</mla>
<frontiers>Lenzmann, B., and Wachsmuth, I. (1997). “Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency” in &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;, Weiss, G. ed. LNAI, vol. 1221, (Berlin: Springer-Verlag), 202-222.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1997). Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In G.  Weiss (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI: Vol. 1221&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 202-222). Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I (1997)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments. Weiss G (Ed);  LNAI, 1221.  Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  202-222.</default>
<ama>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I. Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In: Weiss G, ed. &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI. Vol 1221. Berlin: Springer-Verlag;  1997: 202-222.</ama>
<lncs> Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I.: Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. In: Weiss, G. (ed.) Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments. LNAI. 1221, p. 202-222. Springer-Verlag, Berlin (1997).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, Britta, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1997. “Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency”. In &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Gerhard Weiss, 1221:202-222. LNAI. Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1997). Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency (LNAI). In G. Weiss (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt; (S. 202-222). Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Lenzmann, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: G. Weiss), Springer-Verlag, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 202-222.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Contract-net-based learning in a user-adaptive interface agency. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Distributed Artificial Intelligence Meets Machine Learning - Learning in Multi-Agent Environments. Weiss G (Ed); LNAI, 1221. Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  202-222.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1625508</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:20:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>