<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1773116</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wibke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellmich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kai</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Leffhalm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andy</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sischka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177063</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thanh Tu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Duong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nickels</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jensen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21877</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niehaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21913</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tönsing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">47837</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ros</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anselmetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40180</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8720-4369</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Klavs F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Jensen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685540</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33079524</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29125395</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">40200282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>9th International Conference on Miniaturized Systems for Chemical and Life Sciences</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="hellmich_utas2005.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1773116/2311197/hellmich_utas2005.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Boston, MA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Single cell analysis</topic><topic>Microfluidics</topic><topic>Protein separation</topic><topic>Label-free detection</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-9743611-1-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-139</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">406-408</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hellmich, W.; Leffhalm, K.; Sischka, A.; Duong, T. T.; Jensen, N.; Niehaus, K.; Tönsing, K.; Ros, A.; Anselmetti, D. (2005): Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In: Klavs F. Jensen (Hrsg.):  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS). (Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1).  S. 406-408.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Hellmich, K.  Leffhalm, A.  Sischka, T. T.  Duong, N.  Jensen, K.  Niehaus, K.  Tönsing, A.  Ros, and D.  Anselmetti, in &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: K.F. Jensen), The Chemical And Biological Microsystems Society (Cbms), Boston, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 406-408.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Hellmich, W., et al., 2005. Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In K. F.  Jensen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). no.1  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), pp. 406-408.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmich, W., Leffhalm, K., Sischka, A., Duong, T. T., Jensen, N., Niehaus, K., Tönsing, K., et al. (2005). Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In K. F.  Jensen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS): Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 406-408). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hellmich W, Leffhalm K, Sischka A, Duong TT, Jensen N, Niehaus K, Tönsing K, Ros A, Anselmetti D (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Jensen KF (Ed); Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS):  406-408.</bio1>
<frontiers>Hellmich, W., Leffhalm, K., Sischka, A., Duong, T. T., Jensen, N., Niehaus, K., Tönsing, K., Ros, A., and Anselmetti, D. (2005). “Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection” in &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, Jensen, K. F. ed. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), vol. 1, (Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 406-408.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmich, W., Leffhalm, K., Sischka, A., Duong, T.T., Jensen, N., Niehaus, K., Tönsing, K., Ros, A. &amp;amp; Anselmetti, D. (2005). Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection (Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). In K.F. Jensen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (S. 406-408). Gehalten auf der 9th International Conference on Miniaturized Systems for Chemical and Life Sciences, Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hellmich W, Leffhalm K, Sischka A, et al. Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In: Jensen KF, ed. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). Vol 1. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS);  2005: 406-408.</ama>
<ieee> W. Hellmich, et al., “Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection”, &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, K.F. Jensen, ed., Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), vol. 1,  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 2005,  pp.406-408.</ieee>
<apa>Hellmich, W., Leffhalm, K., Sischka, A., Duong, T. T., Jensen, N., Niehaus, K., Tönsing, K., et al. (2005). Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In K. F.  Jensen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS): Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 406-408). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmich, Wibke, Leffhalm, Kai, Sischka, Andy, Duong, Thanh Tu, Jensen, Nickels, Niehaus, Karsten, Tönsing, Katja, Ros, Alexandra, and Anselmetti, Dario. 2005. “Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection”. In &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Klavs F. Jensen, 1:406-408. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hellmich, W., Leffhalm, K., Sischka, A., Duong, T.T., Jensen, N., Niehaus, K., Tönsing, K., Ros, A., Anselmetti, D.: Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection. In: Jensen, K.F. (ed.) Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). 1, p. 406-408. The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), Boston (2005).</lncs>
<default>Hellmich W, Leffhalm K, Sischka A, Duong TT, Jensen N, Niehaus K, Tönsing K, Ros A, Anselmetti D (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Jensen KF (Ed);  Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1.  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS):  406-408.</default>
<mla>Hellmich, Wibke, Leffhalm, Kai, Sischka, Andy, Duong, Thanh Tu, Jensen, Nickels, Niehaus, Karsten, Tönsing, Katja, Ros, Alexandra, and Anselmetti, Dario. “Towards single cell fingerprinting in microfluidic device format : single cell manipulation, protein separation and detection”. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Klavs F. Jensen. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 2005.Vol. 1. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). 406-408.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1773116</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-22T10:34:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>