<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1773068</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Martini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tönsing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">47837</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dickob</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anselmetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40180</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8720-4369</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29125395</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33079524</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Conference on Biomedical Optics (ECBO)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Native hyaline cartilage from a human knee joint was directly investigated with laser scanning microscopy via 2-photon autofluorescence excitation with no additional staining or labelling protocols in a nondestructive and sterile manner. Using a femtosecond, near-infrared (NIR) Ti:Sa laser for 2-photon excitation and a dedicated NIR long distance objective, autofluorescence imaging and measurements of the extracellular matrix (ECM) tissue with incorporated chondrocytes were possible with a penetration depth of up to 460 µm inside the sample. Via spectral autofluorescence separation these experiments allowed the discrimination of chondrocytes from the ECM and therefore an estimate of chondrocytic cell density within the cartilage tissue to approximately 0.2-2·10 7/cm³. Furthermore, a comparison of the relative autofluorescence signals between nonarthritic and arthritic cartilage tissue exhibited distinct differences in tissue morphology. As these morphological findings are in keeping with the macroscopic diagnosis, our measurement has the potential of being used in future diagnostic applications.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="spie_martini_bw_2005.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1773068/2311188/spie_martini_bw_2005.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>The International Society for Optical Engineering</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Munich, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Biomedical imaging</topic><topic>Multiphoton processes</topic><topic>Human cartilage</topic><topic>Three-dimensional microscopy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-21</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1117/12.632940</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5860</number></detail><extent unit="pages">16-21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Martini J, Tönsing K, Dickob M, Anselmetti D. 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 5860. The International Society for Optical Engineering;  2005: 16-21.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, J., Tönsing, K., Dickob, M. &amp;amp; Anselmetti, D. (2005). 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt; (S. 16-21). Gehalten auf der European Conference on Biomedical Optics (ECBO), The International Society for Optical Engineering. doi:10.1117/12.632940.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Martini, J., Tönsing, K., Dickob, M., and Anselmetti, D. (2005). “2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 5860, (The International Society for Optical Engineering), 16-21.</frontiers>
<apa>Martini, J., Tönsing, K., Dickob, M., &amp;amp; Anselmetti, D. (2005). 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5860&lt;/em&gt;, 16-21. The International Society for Optical Engineering. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1117/12.632940" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1117/12.632940&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> J. Martini, et al., “2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 5860, The International Society for Optical Engineering, 2005,  pp.16-21.</ieee>
<wels>Martini, J.; Tönsing, K.; Dickob, M.; Anselmetti, D. (2005): 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. In: Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering. The International Society for Optical Engineering. (5860).  S. 16-21.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, J., Tönsing, K., Dickob, M., &amp;amp; Anselmetti, D. (2005). 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5860&lt;/em&gt;, 16-21. The International Society for Optical Engineering. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1117/12.632940" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1117/12.632940&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Martini J, Tönsing K, Dickob M, Anselmetti D (2005) &lt;br /&gt;2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering. 5860. The International Society for Optical Engineering:  16-21.</bio1>
<harvard1>Martini, J., et al., 2005. 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;. no.5860  The International Society for Optical Engineering, pp. 16-21.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Martini, K.  Tönsing, M.  Dickob, and D.  Anselmetti, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, The International Society For Optical Engineering, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 16-21.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Martini, J., Tönsing, K., Dickob, M., Anselmetti, D.: 2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage. Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering. 5860, p. 16-21. The International Society for Optical Engineering (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, Jörg, Tönsing, Katja, Dickob, Michael, and Anselmetti, Dario. 2005. “2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, 5860:16-21. The International Society for Optical Engineering.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Martini, Jörg, Tönsing, Katja, Dickob, Michael, and Anselmetti, Dario. “2-Photon Laser Scanning Microscopy on Native Human Cartilage”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering&lt;/em&gt;. The International Society for Optical Engineering, 2005.Vol. 5860. 16-21.</mla>
<default>Martini J, Tönsing K, Dickob M, Anselmetti D (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering., 5860.  The International Society for Optical Engineering:  16-21.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1773068</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-20T15:28:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>