<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1773184</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank Wilco</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bartels</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Birgit</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baumgarth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anselmetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40180</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8720-4369</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ros</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29125395</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Specific protein-DNA interaction is fundamental for all aspects of gene transcription. We focus on a regulatory DNA-binding protein in the Gram-negative soil bacterium Sinorhizobium meliloti 2011, which is capable of fixing molecular nitrogen in a symbiotic interaction with alfalfa plants. The ExpG protein plays a central role in regulation of the biosynthesis of the exopolysaccharide galactoglucan, which promotes the establishment of symbiosis. ExpG is a transcriptional activator of exp gene expression. We investigated the molecular mechanism of binding of ExpG to three associated target sequences in the exp gene cluster with standard biochemical methods and single molecule force spectroscopy based on the atomic force microscope (AFM). Binding of ExpG to expA1, expG-expD1, and expE1 promoter fragments in a sequence specific manner was demonstrated, and a 28 bp conserved region was found. AFM force spectroscopy experiments confirmed the specific binding of ExpG to the promoter regions, with unbinding forces ranging from 50 to 165pN in a logarithmic dependence from the loading rates of 70-79000 pN/s. Two different regimes of loading rate-dependent behaviour were identified. Thermal off-rates in the range of k off = (1.2 ± 1.0) × 10 -3 s -1 were derived from the lower loading rate regime for all promoter regions. In the upper loading rate regime, however, these fragments exhibited distinct differences which are attributed to the molecular binding mechanism.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="jsb_2003.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1773184/2311206/jsb_2003.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sinorhizobium meliloti</topic><topic>Protein-DNA interaction</topic><topic>Atomic force microscopy</topic><topic>Single molecule force spectroscopy</topic><topic>Galactoglucan</topic><topic>Regulatory protein</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of structural biology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1047-8477</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">12972351</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000185521500006</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17731844</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>143</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">145-152</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>F. W.  Bartels, B.  Baumgarth, D.  Anselmetti, R.  Ros, and A.  Becker, “Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143&lt;/em&gt;, 145-152.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bartels FW, Baumgarth B, Anselmetti D, Ros R, Becker A (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of structural biology 143(2): 145-152.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bartels, F.W., Baumgarth, B., Anselmetti, D., Ros, R. &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2003). Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143&lt;/em&gt;(2), 145-152. Elsevier BV. doi:10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Bartels, F.W., Baumgarth, B., Anselmetti, D., Ros, R., Becker, A.: Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. Journal of structural biology. 143, 145-152 (2003).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bartels, Frank Wilco, Baumgarth, Birgit, Anselmetti, Dario, Ros, Robert, and Becker, Anke. 2003. “Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt; 143 (2): 145-152.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Bartels FW, Baumgarth B, Anselmetti D, Ros R, Becker A. Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;. 2003;143(2):145-152.</ama>
<default>Bartels FW, Baumgarth B, Anselmetti D, Ros R, Becker A (2003) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt; 143(2): 145-152.</default>
<wels>Bartels, F. W.; Baumgarth, B.; Anselmetti, D.; Ros, R.; Becker, A. (2003): Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;,143:(2): 145-152.</wels>
<mla>Bartels, Frank Wilco, Baumgarth, Birgit, Anselmetti, Dario, Ros, Robert, and Becker, Anke. “Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt; 143.2 (2003): 145-152.</mla>
<frontiers>Bartels, F. W., Baumgarth, B., Anselmetti, D., Ros, R., and Becker, A. (2003). Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt; 143, 145-152.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bartels, F. W., Baumgarth, B., Anselmetti, D., Ros, R., &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2003). Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143&lt;/em&gt;(2), 145-152. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Bartels, F. W., Baumgarth, B., Anselmetti, D., Ros, R., &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2003). Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143&lt;/em&gt;(2), 145-152. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S1047-8477(03)00127-8&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Bartels, F.W., et al., 2003. Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;, 143(2), p 145-152.</harvard1>
<ieee> F.W. Bartels, et al., “Specific binding of the regulatory protein ExpG to promoter regions of the galactoglucan biosynthesis gene cluster of Sinorhizobium meliloti: a combined molecular biology and force spectroscopy investigation”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of structural biology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 143, 2003,  pp. 145-152.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1773184</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-23T11:09:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>