<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1773714</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ronellenfitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Catherine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kyobutungi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Razum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">134970</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21333</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Migration is a phenomenon of particular Public Health importance. Since 1990, almost 2 million ethnic Germans (Aussiedler) have migrated from the former Soviet Union (FSU) to Germany. This study compares their overall and cardiovascular disease (CVD) mortality to that of Germany's general population. Because of high overall and CVD mortality in the FSU and low socio-economic status of Aussiedler in Germany, we hypothesize that their mortality is higher. Methods: We conducted a retrospective cohort study for 1990–2002 with data of 34,393 Aussiedler. We assessed vital status at population registries and causes of death at the state statistical office. We calculated standardized mortality ratios (SMRs) for the whole cohort and substrata of covariables such as age, sex and family size. To assess multivariate effects, we used Poisson regression. Results: 1657 cohort members died before December 31, 2002, and 680 deaths (41.03%) were due to CVD. The SMR for the whole cohort was 0.85 (95%-CI 0.81–0.89) for all causes of death and 0.79 (95%-CI 0.73–0.85) for CVD. SMRs were higher than one for younger Aussiedler and lower for older ones. There was no clear effect of duration of stay on SMRs. For 1990–93, SMRs were significantly lower than in subsequent years. In families comprising at least five members upon arrival in Germany, SMRs were significantly lower than in smaller families. Conclusion: In contrast to our hypothesis on migrants' health, overall and CVD mortality among Aussiedler is lower than in Germany's general population. Possible explanations are a substantially better health status of Aussiedler in the FSU as compared to the local average, a higher perceived socio-economic status of Aussiedler in Germany, or selection effects. SMR differences between substrata need further exploration, and risk factor data are needed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1471_2458_6_16.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1773714/2311310/1471_2458_6_16.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">16438727</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000236123900001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17737144</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-6-16</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Ronellenfitsch, C.  Kyobutungi, H.  Becher, and O.  Razum, “All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, : 16.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ronellenfitsch U, Kyobutungi C, Becher H, Razum O (2006) &lt;br /&gt;All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Public Health 6(1): 16.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ronellenfitsch, U., Kyobutungi, C., Becher, H. &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2006). All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1): 16. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-6-16.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Ronellenfitsch, U., Kyobutungi, C., Becher, H., Razum, O.: All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. BMC Public Health. 6, : 16 (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ronellenfitsch, Ulrich, Kyobutungi, Catherine, Becher, Heiko, and Razum, Oliver. 2006. “All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 6 (1): 16.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Ronellenfitsch U, Kyobutungi C, Becher H, Razum O. All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2006;6(1): 16.</ama>
<default>Ronellenfitsch U, Kyobutungi C, Becher H, Razum O (2006) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 6(1): 16.</default>
<wels>Ronellenfitsch, U.; Kyobutungi, C.; Becher, H.; Razum, O. (2006): All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,6:(1):16</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ronellenfitsch, U., Kyobutungi, C., Becher, H., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2006). All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-6-16" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-6-16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Ronellenfitsch, Ulrich, Kyobutungi, Catherine, Becher, Heiko, and Razum, Oliver. “All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 6.1 (2006): 16.</mla>
<frontiers>Ronellenfitsch, U., Kyobutungi, C., Becher, H., and Razum, O. (2006). All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 6:16.</frontiers>
<apa>Ronellenfitsch, U., Kyobutungi, C., Becher, H., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2006). All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-6-16" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-6-16&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Ronellenfitsch, U., et al., 2006. All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 6(1): 16.</harvard1>
<ieee> U. Ronellenfitsch, et al., “All-cause and cardiovascular mortality among ethnic German immigrants from the Former Soviet Union: a cohort study”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 2006, : 16.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1773714</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>