<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1773386</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Egelhaaf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">156194</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9336-4270</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Borst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reichardt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The computations performed by individual movement detectors are analyzed by intracellularly recording from an identified direction-selective motion-sensitive interneuron in the fly's brain and by comparing these results with model predictions based on movement detectors of the correlation type. Three main conclusions were drawn with respect to the movement-detection system of the fly: (1) The essential nonlinear interaction between the two movement-detector input channels can be characterized formally by a mathematically almost perfect multiplication process. (2) Even at high contrasts no significant nonlinearities seem to distort the time course of the movement-detector input signals. (3) The movement detectors of the fly are not perfectly antisymmetrical; i.e., they respond with different time courses and amplitudes to motion in their preferred and null directions. As a consequence of this property, the motion detectors can respond to some degree to stationary patterns whose brightness is modulated in time. Moreover, the direction selectivity, i.e., the relative difference of the responses to motion in the preferred and null directions, depends on the contrast and on the spatial-frequency content of the stimulus pattern.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Egelhaaf_et_al_JOSA_1989.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1773386/2311241/Egelhaaf_et_al_JOSA_1989.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1989</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-862</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1070-1087</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Egelhaaf, M.; Borst, A.; Reichardt, W. (1989): Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;,6:(7): 1070-1087.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A., &amp;amp; Reichardt, W. (1989). Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1070-1087.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Egelhaaf, Martin, Borst, Alexander, and Reichardt, Werner. “Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt; 6.7 (1989): 1070-1087.</mla>
<frontiers>Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A., and Reichardt, W. (1989). Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt; 6, 1070-1087.</frontiers>
<default>Egelhaaf M, Borst A, Reichardt W (1989) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt; 6(7): 1070-1087.</default>
<ieee> M. Egelhaaf, A. Borst, and W. Reichardt, “Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 1989,  pp. 1070-1087.</ieee>
<harvard1>Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A., &amp;amp; Reichardt, W., 1989. Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;, 6(7), p 1070-1087.</harvard1>
<apa>Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A., &amp;amp; Reichardt, W. (1989). Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1070-1087.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A. &amp;amp; Reichardt, W. (1989). Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1070-1087.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Egelhaaf M, Borst A, Reichardt W (1989) &lt;br /&gt;Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision 6(7): 1070-1087.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Egelhaaf, A.  Borst, and W.  Reichardt, “Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1989&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, 1070-1087.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Egelhaaf M, Borst A, Reichardt W. Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt;. 1989;6(7):1070-1087.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Egelhaaf, Martin, Borst, Alexander, and Reichardt, Werner. 1989. “Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision&lt;/em&gt; 6 (7): 1070-1087.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Egelhaaf, M., Borst, A., Reichardt, W.: Computational structure of a biological motion-detection system as revealed by local detector analysis in the fly's nervous system. Journal of the Optical Society of America, A: Optics, Image Science, and Vision. 6, 1070-1087 (1989).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1773386</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>