<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1774898</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Borst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Egelhaaf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">156194</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9336-4270</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Adrianus M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Aertsen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Egelhaaf_39.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1774898/2311667/Egelhaaf_39.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Synaptic signals</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-444-89839-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-6187</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">47-66</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Borst and M. Egelhaaf, “Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects”, &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;, A.M. Aertsen, ed.,  Amsterdam: Elsevier, 1993,  pp.47-66.</ieee>
<harvard1>Borst, A., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M., 1993. Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In A. M.  Aertsen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;.  Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 47-66.</harvard1>
<apa>Borst, A., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (1993). Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In A. M.  Aertsen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 47-66). Amsterdam: Elsevier.</apa>
<wels>Borst, A.; Egelhaaf, M. (1993): Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In: Adrianus M. Aertsen (Hrsg.):  Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992. Amsterdam: Elsevier.  S. 47-66.</wels>
<mla>Borst, Alexander, and Egelhaaf, Martin. “Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects”. &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Adrianus M. Aertsen. Amsterdam: Elsevier, 1993. 47-66.</mla>
<frontiers>Borst, A., and Egelhaaf, M. (1993). “Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects” in &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;, Aertsen, A. M. ed. (Amsterdam: Elsevier), 47-66.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borst, A., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (1993). Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In A. M.  Aertsen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 47-66). Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Borst A, Egelhaaf M (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992. Aertsen AM (Ed);  Amsterdam: Elsevier:  47-66.</default>
<ama>Borst A, Egelhaaf M. Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In: Aertsen AM, ed. &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;. Amsterdam: Elsevier;  1993: 47-66.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borst, Alexander, and Egelhaaf, Martin. 1993. “Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects”. In &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Adrianus M. Aertsen, 47-66. Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Borst, A., Egelhaaf, M.: Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In: Aertsen, A.M. (ed.) Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992. p. 47-66. Elsevier, Amsterdam (1993).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borst, A. &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (1993). Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. In A.M. Aertsen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt; (S. 47-66). Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Borst A, Egelhaaf M (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Processing of synaptic signals in fly interneurons selectively responsive to small moving objects. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992. Aertsen AM (Ed); Amsterdam: Elsevier:  47-66.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Borst, and M.  Egelhaaf, in &lt;em&gt;Brain Theory: Spatio-temporal Aspects of Brain Function; Fourth International Meeting on Brain Theory held in Trento (Italy) on April 11-13, 1992&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: A.M. Aertsen), Elsevier, Amsterdam, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 47-66.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1774898</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:33Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>