<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1774813</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>PENTAMETHYLDISILANYL-SUBSTITUTED CYCLOPENTADIENES - SYNTHESIS, STRUCTURE AND DYNAMIC BEHAVIOR</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jutzi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20144</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kleimeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krallmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Georg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stammler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20167</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Beate</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20154</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The pentamethyldisilanyl-substituted cyclopentadienes Me(n)C(5)H(6-n-m)(Si(2)Me(5))(m) (for n = 0: 1 (m = 1), 2 (m = 2), 3 (m = 3), 4 (m = 4); for n = 1: 5 (m = 1), 7 (m = 2), 9 (m = 3); for n = 3: 13 (m = 1), 14 (m = 2); for n = 4: 15 (m = I)) are accessible in good yields by treatment of the corresponding cyclopentadienyllithium compounds with Me(5)Si(2)Cl. The mono-Me(5)Si(2)-substituted species 1 and 5 are present only to a small extend in form of vinylic isomers and to a greater extend as isomers with the Me(5)Si(2)-group in allylic position; the latter possess a dynamic structure due to sigmatropic rearrangements. In the twice-Me(5)Si(2)-substituted cyclopentadienes 2 and 7, the 5,5 and 2,5 isomers are observed, which can be interconverted by silatropic shifts; in addition, the presence of two vinylic isomers can be proved in the case of 2. In the cyclopentadiene species 3 and 9 with three Me(5)Si(2) groups, only the 2,5,5 isomers can be detected by NMR spectroscopy. Compound 3 possesses a fluxional structure and can thus be deprotonated. On the other hand, 9 does not show a fluxional behaviour and thus cannot be deprotonated. The cyclopentadiene 4 with four Me(5)Si(2) substituents possesses a static structure and cannot be deprotonated. The 2,3,5,5 position of the substituents is proved by an X-ray crystal structure analysis. Only two Me(5)Si(2) groups can be incorporated in the carbon skeleton of 1,2,4-trimethylcyclopentadiene, whereby compounds of the type 1,2,4-Me(3)C(5)H(3-n)(Si(2)Me(5))(n) (13: n = 1; 14: n = 2) are formed. Surprisingly, 14 cannot be deprotonated with (n)BuLi and KH, respectively. The reaction of Me(4)C(5)HLi with Me(5)Si(2)Cl leads to the cyclopentadiene Me(4)C(5)HSi(2)Me(5) (15). Though compound 15 can be deprotonated, further reaction of the resulting anion with Me(5)Si(2)Cl does not lead to the expected cyclopentadiene Me(4)C(5)(Si(2)Me(5))(2) (16). On the other hand, 16 can be prepared by metallation of 14 with C8K and further reaction with CH3I. In contrast to 14, compound 4 cannot be deprotonated with C8K; the reaction of 4 with C8K and CH3I leads to 9 via Si-C bond splitting. The pentamethyldisilanyl-substituted pentamethylcyclopentadiene Me(5)C(5)Si(2)Me(5) (17) is obtained by reaction of Me(5)C(5)K with Me(5)Si(2)Cl; compound 17 shows dynamic behaviour; the migration of the Me(5)Si(2) group is slower than that of the Me(3)Si group in Me(5)C(5)SiMe(3). Three ElMe(3) groups can be introduced stepwise into the 1,2,4-Me(3)C(5)H(3) molecule, as demonstrated by the exemplary synthesis of the cyclopentadienes 1,2,4-Me(3)C(5)H(3-n)(SiMe(3))(n) (10: n = 1; 11: n = 2) and 1,2,4-Me(3)C(5)(SiMe(3))(2)SnMe(3) (12).</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Die Si2Me5-substituierten Cyclopentadiene MenC5H6-n-m(Si2Me5)m (für n = 0: 1 (m = 1), 2 (m = 2), 3 (m = 3), 4 (m = 4); für n = 1: 5 (m = 1), 7 (m = 2), 9 (m = 3); für n = 3: 13 (m = 1), 14 (m = 2); für n = 4: 15 (m = 1)) sind durch Umsetzung der entsprechenden Cyclopentadienyl-Lithium-Verbindung mit Me5Si2Cl in guten Ausbeuten zugänglich. In den einfach Si2Me5-substituierten Systemen 1 und 5 findet man zu einem geringen Anteil Isomere mit vinylständiger Si2Me5-Gruppe und zu einem überwiegenden Anteil das Isomer mit allylständiger Si2Me5-Gruppe, welches aufgrund von sigmatropen Umlagerungen eine dynamische Struktur besitzt. In den zweifach Si2Me5- substituierten Cyclopentadienen 2 und 7 beobachtet man die jeweiligen 5,5- und 2,5-Isomere, welche durch Silatropie miteinander im Gleichgewicht stehen; zusätzlich lassen sich in 2 noch zwei Isomere mit ausschließlich vinylständigen Substituenten nachweisen. In den dreifach Si2Me5-substituierten Systemen 3 und 9 ist nur das 2,5,5-Isomere nachweisbar. 3 besitzt eine dynamische Struktur und ist deshalb deprotonierbar. 9 hingegen ist nicht dynamisch und aufgrund des Fehlens einer Allyl-H-Funktion nicht deprotonierbar. Auch das vierfach Si2Me5-substituierte Cyclopentadien 4 zeigt keine Moleküldynamik und kann nicht deprotoniert werden; die 2,3,5,5-Anordnung der Substituenten in 4 wird anhand einer Röntgenstrukturanalyse belegt. Im 1,2,4-Trimethylcyclopentadien gelingt jedoch nur die Einführung von zwei Si2Me5-Gruppen, wobei die Verbindungen des Typs 1,2,4-Me3C5H3-n(Si2Me5)n (13: n = 1; 14: n = 2) entstehen. Überraschenderweise ist 14 mit nBuLi oder KH nicht deprotonierbar. Die Umsetzung von Me4C5HLi mit Me5Si2Cl führtzum Cyclopentadien Me4C5HSi2Me5 (15). Obwohl 15 deprotonierbar ist, gelingt durch Umsetzung des Anions mit Me5Si2Cl die Synthese von Me4C5(Si2Me5)2 (16) nicht. Verbindung 16 läßt sich allerdings durch Metallierung von 14 mit C8K und anschließende Umsetzung mit CH3I darstellen. Im Gegensatz dazu kann 4 mit C8K nicht deprotoniert werden; die Umsetzung mit C8K und CH3I läuft über Si-C-Bindungsspaltung zu 9. Das Cyclopentadienyldisilan Me5C5Si2Me5 (17) erhält man durch Umsetzung von Me5C5K mit Me5Si2Cl; 17 zeigt dynamisches Verhalten, die Wanderungsgeschwindigkeit der Si2Me5-Gruppe ist geringer als die der SiMe3-Gruppe im Cyclopentadienylsilan Me5C5SiMe3. Im Cyclopentadien 1,2,4-Me3C5H3 lassen sich sukzessiv drei ElMe3-Gruppen (El = Si, Sn) einführen, wie durch die beispielhafte Synthese von 1,2,4-Me3C5H3-n(SiMe3)n (10: n = 1, 11: n = 2) und 1,2,4-Me3 C5(SiMe3)2SnMe3 (12) gezeigt wird.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="stammler_017.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1774813/2311632/stammler_017.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Organometallic Chemistry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0022-328X</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1993MM53500009</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17748137</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>462</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1-2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">57-67</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Jutzi, Peter, Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Neumann, Beate. “Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt; 462.1-2 (1993): 57-67.</mla>
<frontiers>Jutzi, P., Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, H. - G., and Neumann, B. (1993). Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt; 462, 57-67.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jutzi, P., Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Neumann, B. (1993). Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;462&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 57-67. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Jutzi, P.; Kleimeier, J.; Krallmann, R.; Stammler, H. - G.; Neumann, B. (1993): Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;,462:(1-2): 57-67.</wels>
<default>Jutzi P, Kleimeier J, Krallmann R, Stammler H-G, Neumann B (1993) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt; 462(1-2): 57-67.</default>
<harvard1>Jutzi, P., et al., 1993. Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;, 462(1-2), p 57-67.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Jutzi, et al., “Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 462, 1993,  pp. 57-67.</ieee>
<apa>Jutzi, P., Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Neumann, B. (1993). Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;462&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 57-67. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jutzi, P., Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, H.-G. &amp;amp; Neumann, B. (1993). Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;462&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 57-67. Elsevier BV. doi:10.1016/0022-328X(93)83341-R.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Jutzi, J.  Kleimeier, R.  Krallmann, H. - G.  Stammler, and B.  Neumann, “Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;462&lt;/em&gt;, 57-67.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Jutzi P, Kleimeier J, Krallmann R, Stammler H-G, Neumann B (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry 462(1-2): 57-67.</bio1>
<ama>Jutzi P, Kleimeier J, Krallmann R, Stammler H-G, Neumann B. Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;. 1993;462(1-2):57-67.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jutzi, Peter, Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Neumann, Beate. 1993. “Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organometallic Chemistry&lt;/em&gt; 462 (1-2): 57-67.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jutzi, P., Kleimeier, J., Krallmann, R., Stammler, H.-G., Neumann, B.: Pentamethyldisilanyl-substituierte Cyclopentadiene: Synthese, Struktur und dynamisches Verhalten. Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. 462, 57-67 (1993).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1774813</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>