<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1775068</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Xaver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaufmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13183</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dieter</namePart><namePart type="family">Grunow</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Hegener</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kaufmann_B_045.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1775068/2311768/Kaufmann_B_045.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1980</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Implementation</topic><topic>Evaluation</topic><topic>Sozialpolitik</topic><topic>soziale Dienste</topic><topic>Handlungssystem</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-89946-060-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-7265</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>20</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29-43</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kaufmann F-X. Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In: Grunow D, Hegener F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;. Publication of the Science Center Berlin. Vol 20. Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain;  1980: 29-43.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. 1980. “Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation”. In &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dieter Grunow and F. Hegener, 20:29-43. Publication of the Science Center Berlin. Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kaufmann, F.-X.: Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In: Grunow, D. and Hegener, F. (eds.) Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs. Publication of the Science Center Berlin. 20, p. 29-43. Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain, Cambridge, Mass. (1980).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F.-X. (1980). Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation (Publication of the Science Center Berlin). In D. Grunow &amp;amp; F. Hegener (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt; (S. 29-43). Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kaufmann F-X (1980) &lt;br /&gt;Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs. Grunow D, Hegener F (Eds); Publication of the Science Center Berlin, 20. Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain:  29-43.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - X.  Kaufmann, in &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Grunow, F. Hegener), Oelschlager, Gunn And Hain, Cambridge, Mass., &lt;strong&gt;1980&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 29-43.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> F.-X. Kaufmann, “Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;, D. Grunow and F. Hegener, eds., Publication of the Science Center Berlin, vol. 20,  Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain, 1980,  pp.29-43.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kaufmann, F.-X., 1980. Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In D.  Grunow &amp;amp; F.  Hegener, eds. &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;. Publication of the Science Center Berlin. no.20  Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain, pp. 29-43.</harvard1>
<apa>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1980). Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In D.  Grunow &amp;amp; F.  Hegener (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Publication of the Science Center Berlin: Vol. 20&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 29-43). Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain.</apa>
<wels>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1980): Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In: Dieter Grunow; F. Hegener (Hrsg.):  Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs. Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain. (Publication of the Science Center Berlin, 20).  S. 29-43.</wels>
<mla>Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. “Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dieter Grunow and F. Hegener. Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain, 1980.Vol. 20. Publication of the Science Center Berlin. 29-43.</mla>
<frontiers>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1980). “Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation” in &lt;em&gt;Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt;, Grunow, D., and Hegener, F. eds. Publication of the Science Center Berlin, vol. 20, (Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain), 29-43.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F. - X. (1980). Social policy and social services: some problems of policy formation, program implementation, and impact evaluation. In D.  Grunow &amp;amp; F.  Hegener (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Publication of the Science Center Berlin: Vol. 20&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 29-43). Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Kaufmann F-X (1980)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Welfare or bureaucracy? Problems of matching social services to clients' needs. Grunow D, Hegener F (Eds);  Publication of the Science Center Berlin, 20.  Cambridge, Mass.: Oelschlager, Gunn and Hain:  29-43.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1775068</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-05T09:03:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>