<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1775082</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Xaver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaufmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13183</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Franz-Xaver</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaufmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">G.</namePart><namePart type="family">Majone</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">V.</namePart><namePart type="family">Ostrom</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kaufmann_B_086.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1775082/2311780/Kaufmann_B_086.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>de Gruyter</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1986</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-11-009707-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-7381</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">3-24</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1986). Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In F. - X.  Kaufmann, G.  Majone, &amp;amp; V.  Ostrom (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-24). Berlin: de Gruyter.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. 1986. “Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem”. In &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Franz-Xaver Kaufmann, G. Majone, and V. Ostrom, 3-24. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4. Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kaufmann, F.-X.: Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In: Kaufmann, F.-X., Majone, G., and Ostrom, V. (eds.) Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4. p. 3-24. de Gruyter, Berlin (1986).</lncs>
<ieee> F.-X. Kaufmann, “Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem”, &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;, F.-X. Kaufmann, G. Majone, and V. Ostrom, eds., De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4,  Berlin: de Gruyter, 1986,  pp.3-24.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kaufmann, F.-X., 1986. Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In F. - X.  Kaufmann, G.  Majone, &amp;amp; V.  Ostrom, eds. &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4.  Berlin: de Gruyter, pp. 3-24.</harvard1>
<ama>Kaufmann F-X. Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In: Kaufmann F-X, Majone G, Ostrom V, eds. &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4. Berlin: de Gruyter;  1986: 3-24.</ama>
<default>Kaufmann F-X (1986)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project. Kaufmann F-X, Majone G, Ostrom V (Eds);  De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4.  Berlin: de Gruyter:  3-24.</default>
<bio1>Kaufmann F-X (1986) &lt;br /&gt;Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project. Kaufmann F-X, Majone G, Ostrom V (Eds); De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4,  Berlin: de Gruyter:  3-24.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - X.  Kaufmann, in &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: F.-X. Kaufmann, G. Majone, V. Ostrom), De Gruyter, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1986&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 3-24.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1986): Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In: Franz-Xaver Kaufmann; G. Majone; V. Ostrom (Hrsg.):  Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project. Berlin: de Gruyter. (De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4, ).  S. 3-24.</wels>
<frontiers>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1986). “Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem” in &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;, Kaufmann, F. - X., Majone, G., and Ostrom, V. eds. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4 (Berlin: de Gruyter), 3-24.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F. - X. (1986). Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem. In F. - X.  Kaufmann, G.  Majone, &amp;amp; V.  Ostrom (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-24). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. “Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem”. &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Franz-Xaver Kaufmann, G. Majone, and V. Ostrom. Berlin: de Gruyter, 1986. De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4. 3-24.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F.-X. (1986). Introduction: History of the project and background to the problem (De Gruyter studies in organization ; 4). In F.-X. Kaufmann, G. Majone &amp;amp; V. Ostrom (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Guidance, control, and evaluation in the public sector: the Bielefeld interdisciplinary project&lt;/em&gt; (S. 3-24). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1775082</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>