<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1775009</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Xaver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaufmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13183</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart><namePart type="family">Hurrelmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Franz-Xaver</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaufmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Lösel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kaufmann_B_116.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1775009/2311718/Kaufmann_B_116.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>de Gruyter</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1987</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Social intervention: potential and constraints</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-89925-327-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-6716</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">3-20</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> F.-X. Kaufmann, “Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance”, &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;, K. Hurrelmann, F.-X. Kaufmann, and F. Lösel, eds., Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence, vol. 1,  Berlin: de Gruyter, 1987,  pp.3-20.</ieee>
<apa>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1987). Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In K.  Hurrelmann, F. - X.  Kaufmann, &amp;amp; F.  Lösel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-20). Berlin: de Gruyter.</apa>
<frontiers>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1987). “Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance” in &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;, Hurrelmann, K., Kaufmann, F. - X., and Lösel, F. eds. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence, vol. 1, (Berlin: de Gruyter), 3-20.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F.-X. (1987). Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance (Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence). In K. Hurrelmann, F.-X. Kaufmann &amp;amp; F. Lösel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt; (S. 3-20). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kaufmann F-X. Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In: Hurrelmann K, Kaufmann F-X, Lösel F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence. Vol 1. Berlin: de Gruyter;  1987: 3-20.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - X.  Kaufmann, in &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: K. Hurrelmann, F.-X. Kaufmann, F. Lösel), De Gruyter, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1987&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 3-20.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kaufmann F-X (1987) &lt;br /&gt;Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Social intervention: potential and constraints. Hurrelmann K, Kaufmann F-X, Lösel F (Eds); Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence, 1. Berlin: de Gruyter:  3-20.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kaufmann, F.-X., 1987. Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In K.  Hurrelmann, F. - X.  Kaufmann, &amp;amp; F.  Lösel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence. no.1  Berlin: de Gruyter, pp. 3-20.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, F. - X. (1987). Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In K.  Hurrelmann, F. - X.  Kaufmann, &amp;amp; F.  Lösel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-20). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kaufmann, F. - X. (1987): Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In: Klaus Hurrelmann; Franz-Xaver Kaufmann; F. Lösel (Hrsg.):  Social intervention: potential and constraints. Berlin: de Gruyter. (Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence, 1).  S. 3-20.</wels>
<default>Kaufmann F-X (1987)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Social intervention: potential and constraints. Hurrelmann K, Kaufmann F-X, Lösel F (Eds);  Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence, 1.  Berlin: de Gruyter:  3-20.</default>
<mla>Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. “Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance”. &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Klaus Hurrelmann, Franz-Xaver Kaufmann, and F. Lösel. Berlin: de Gruyter, 1987.Vol. 1. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence. 3-20.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaufmann, Franz-Xaver. 1987. “Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance”. In &lt;em&gt;Social intervention: potential and constraints&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Klaus Hurrelmann, Franz-Xaver Kaufmann, and F. Lösel, 1:3-20. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence. Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kaufmann, F.-X.: Prevention and intervention in the analytical perspective of guidance. In: Hurrelmann, K., Kaufmann, F.-X., and Lösel, F. (eds.) Social intervention: potential and constraints. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence. 1, p. 3-20. de Gruyter, Berlin (1987).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1775009</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-20T11:03:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>