<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776815</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20254</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fastabend</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">P.</namePart><namePart type="family">Longevialle</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17975</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kuck_27.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776815/2312251/Kuck_27.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1989</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-86344-011-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13185</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">904-905</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> D. Kuck and U. Fastabend, “Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;, P. Longevialle, ed., Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A,  Amsterdam: Elsevier, 1989,  pp.904-905.</ieee>
<apa>Kuck, D., &amp;amp; Fastabend, U. (1989). Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In P.  Longevialle (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 904-905). Amsterdam: Elsevier.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, D. &amp;amp; Fastabend, U. (1989). Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane (Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A). In P. Longevialle (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt; (S. 904-905). Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kuck, D., and Fastabend, U. (1989). “Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;, Longevialle, P. ed. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A (Amsterdam: Elsevier), 904-905.</frontiers>
<ama>Kuck D, Fastabend U. Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In: Longevialle P, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A. Amsterdam: Elsevier;  1989: 904-905.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Kuck, and U.  Fastabend, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: P. Longevialle), Elsevier, Amsterdam, &lt;strong&gt;1989&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 904-905.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kuck D, Fastabend U (1989) &lt;br /&gt;Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988. Longevialle P (Ed); Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A,  Amsterdam: Elsevier:  904-905.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kuck, D., &amp;amp; Fastabend, U., 1989. Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In P.  Longevialle, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A.  Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 904-905.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, D., &amp;amp; Fastabend, U. (1989). Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In P.  Longevialle (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 904-905). Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kuck, D.; Fastabend, U. (1989): Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In: P. Longevialle (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988. Amsterdam: Elsevier. (Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A, ).  S. 904-905.</wels>
<default>Kuck D, Fastabend U (1989)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988. Longevialle P (Ed);  Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A.  Amsterdam: Elsevier:  904-905.</default>
<mla>Kuck, Dietmar, and Fastabend, U. “Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. P. Longevialle. Amsterdam: Elsevier, 1989. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A. 904-905.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, Dietmar, and Fastabend, U. 1989. “Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988&lt;/em&gt;, ed. P. Longevialle, 904-905. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A. Amsterdam: Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kuck, D., Fastabend, U.: Fast proton exchange and unimolecular formation of ion-molecule complexes: the fragmentation of protonated tri- and tetrabenzylmethane. In: Longevialle, P. (ed.) Proceedings of the 11th International Mass Spectrometry Conference: held at Bordeaux, 29 August - 2 September 1988. Advances in mass spectrometry ; 11,A. p. 904-905. Elsevier, Amsterdam (1989).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776815</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>