<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776236</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10583</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rüdiger</namePart><namePart type="family">Göbel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Let A be a hereditary artin algebra with s = s(A) simple modules. The indecomposable A-modules without self-extensions are of great importance, they may be called complete exceptional sequences. Certain sequences (X1,..., X3) consisting of exceptional modules will be called complete exceptional sequences. Crawley-Boevey has pointed out that the braid group on s-1 generators acts naturally on the set of complete exceptional sequences. In case A is finite-dimensional over an algebraically closed field, he has shown that this action is transitive, using a recnet result by Schofield. We are going to present a direct proof which is valid for arbitrary hereditary artin algebras. It follows that the endomorphism rings of exceptional modules are just those rings which occur as endomorphism rings of the simple modules. Also, we will exhibit the relationship between complete exceptional sequences and tilting modules.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ringel_098.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776236/2312117/Ringel_098.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>American Mathematical Soc.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8218-5178-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-11613</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>171</number></detail><extent unit="pages">339-352</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Ringel CM (1994)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany. Göbel R (Ed);  Contemporary mathematics, 171.  Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.:  339-352.</default>
<mla>Ringel, Claus Michael. “The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra”. &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Rüdiger Göbel. Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc., 1994.Vol. 171. Contemporary mathematics. 339-352.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, Claus Michael. 1994. “The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra”. In &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Rüdiger Göbel, 171:339-352. Contemporary mathematics. Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ringel, C.M.: The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In: Göbel, R. (ed.) Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany. Contemporary mathematics. 171, p. 339-352. American Mathematical Soc., Providence, RI (1994).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>C. M.  Ringel, in &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Göbel), American Mathematical Soc., Providence, RI, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 339-352.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ringel CM (1994) &lt;br /&gt;The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany. Göbel R (Ed); Contemporary mathematics, 171. Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.:  339-352.</bio1>
<harvard1>Ringel, C.M., 1994. The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In R.  Göbel, ed. &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Contemporary mathematics. no.171  Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc., pp. 339-352.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, C. M. (1994). The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In R.  Göbel (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Contemporary mathematics: Vol. 171&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 339-352). Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Ringel, C. M. (1994): The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In: Rüdiger Göbel (Hrsg.):  Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany. Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc. (Contemporary mathematics, 171).  S. 339-352.</wels>
<ieee> C.M. Ringel, “The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra”, &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, R. Göbel, ed., Contemporary mathematics, vol. 171,  Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc., 1994,  pp.339-352.</ieee>
<apa>Ringel, C. M. (1994). The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In R.  Göbel (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Contemporary mathematics: Vol. 171&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 339-352). Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.</apa>
<frontiers>Ringel, C. M. (1994). “The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra” in &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Göbel, R. ed. Contemporary mathematics, vol. 171, (Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.), 339-352.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, C.M. (1994). The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra (Contemporary mathematics). In R. Göbel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (S. 339-352). Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ringel CM. The braid group action on the set of exceptional sequences of a hereditary artin algebra. In: Göbel R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Abelian group theory and related topics: Conference on Abelian Groups, August 1 - 7, 1993, Oberwolfach, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Contemporary mathematics. Vol 171. Providence, RI: American Mathematical Soc.;  1994: 339-352.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776236</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-22T13:20:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>