<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776361</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Geometry in everyday life</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Graumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10520</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Erkki</namePart><namePart type="family">Pehkonen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">At the beginning there will be told some words about the sense of mathematics education and different conceptions of teaching mathematics as well as different approaches to mathematics. In connection with this the conception of the "practice-orientated-mathematics-education (PROM" which the author formulated will be commented. This conception - which must be seen as one point of departure side by side with others - has the aim to qualify the pupils to master life and bases on the method of working on the problems true to life. In the second part it will be discussed how this conception fits with geometry teaching and it will be listed several problems and objects of everyday life in which geometry is of importance. After that experiences with some units of teaching geometry in everyday life in school will be explained.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Graumann_31.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776361/2312162/Graumann_31.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1987</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">951-45-4314-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-12143</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>55</number></detail><extent unit="pages">11-23</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Graumann, G.: Geometry in everyday life. In: Pehkonen, E. (ed.) Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education. 55, p. 11-23. University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education, Helsinki (1987).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, Günter. 1987. “Geometry in everyday life”. In &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Erkki Pehkonen, 55:11-23. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education. Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Graumann, Günter. “Geometry in everyday life”. &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Erkki Pehkonen. Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education, 1987.Vol. 55. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education. 11-23.</mla>
<default>Graumann G (1987)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen. Pehkonen E (Ed);  Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education, 55.  Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education:  11-23.</default>
<ama>Graumann G. Geometry in everyday life. In: Pehkonen E, ed. &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education. Vol 55. Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education;  1987: 11-23.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, G. (1987). Geometry in everyday life (Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education). In E. Pehkonen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt; (S. 11-23). Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Graumann, G. (1987). “Geometry in everyday life” in &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;, Pehkonen, E. ed. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education, vol. 55, (Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education), 11-23.</frontiers>
<apa>Graumann, G. (1987). Geometry in everyday life. In E.  Pehkonen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education: Vol. 55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-23). Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education.</apa>
<ieee> G. Graumann, “Geometry in everyday life”, &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;, E. Pehkonen, ed., Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education, vol. 55,  Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education, 1987,  pp.11-23.</ieee>
<wels>Graumann, G. (1987): Geometry in everyday life. In: Erkki Pehkonen (Hrsg.):  Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen. Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education. (Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education, 55).  S. 11-23.</wels>
<bio1>Graumann G (1987) &lt;br /&gt;Geometry in everyday life. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen. Pehkonen E (Ed); Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education, 55. Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education:  11-23.</bio1>
<harvard1>Graumann, G., 1987. Geometry in everyday life. In E.  Pehkonen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt;. Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education. no.55  Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education, pp. 11-23.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, G. (1987). Geometry in everyday life. In E.  Pehkonen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Research report / University of Helsinki, Department of Teacher Education: Vol. 55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-23). Helsinki: University of Helsinki, Dept. of Teacher Education.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Graumann, in &lt;em&gt;Articles on mathematics education: Erkki Pehkonen&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: E. Pehkonen), University Of Helsinki, Dept. Of Teacher Education, Helsinki, &lt;strong&gt;1987&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 11-23.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776361</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>