<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776986</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alois</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33671</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rainer</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5381445</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5805-4536</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jan</namePart><namePart type="family">Strelau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Riemann_015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776986/2312290/Riemann_015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Plenum Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-306-43782-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13583</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">191-204</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Angleitner and R. Riemann, “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”, &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;, J. Strelau, ed., Perspectives on individual differences,  New York, NY: Plenum Press, 1991,  pp.191-204.</ieee>
<harvard1>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R., 1991. What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau, ed. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;. Perspectives on individual differences.  New York, NY: Plenum Press, pp. 191-204.</harvard1>
<apa>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on individual differences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 191-204). New York, NY: Plenum Press.</apa>
<wels>Angleitner, A.; Riemann, R. (1991): What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: Jan Strelau (Hrsg.):  Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement. New York, NY: Plenum Press. (Perspectives on individual differences, ).  S. 191-204.</wels>
<mla>Angleitner, Alois, and Riemann, Rainer. “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jan Strelau. New York, NY: Plenum Press, 1991. Perspectives on individual differences. 191-204.</mla>
<frontiers>Angleitner, A., and Riemann, R. (1991). “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?” in &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;, Strelau, J. ed. Perspectives on individual differences (New York, NY: Plenum Press), 191-204.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on individual differences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 191-204). New York, NY: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Angleitner A, Riemann R (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement. Strelau J (Ed);  Perspectives on individual differences.  New York, NY: Plenum Press:  191-204.</default>
<ama>Angleitner A, Riemann R. What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: Strelau J, ed. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;. Perspectives on individual differences. New York, NY: Plenum Press;  1991: 191-204.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, Alois, and Riemann, Rainer. 1991. “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”. In &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jan Strelau, 191-204. Perspectives on individual differences. New York, NY: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Angleitner, A., Riemann, R.: What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: Strelau, J. (ed.) Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement. Perspectives on individual differences. p. 191-204. Plenum Press, New York, NY (1991).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A. &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? (Perspectives on individual differences). In J. Strelau (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt; (S. 191-204). New York, NY: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Angleitner A, Riemann R (1991) &lt;br /&gt;What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? &lt;br /&gt;In:  Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement. Strelau J (Ed); Perspectives on individual differences,  New York, NY: Plenum Press:  191-204.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Angleitner, and R.  Riemann, in &lt;em&gt;Explorations in temperament: international perspectives on theory and measurement&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: J. Strelau), Plenum Press, New York, NY, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 191-204.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776986</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>