<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776363</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Geometry in everyday life</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Graumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10520</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Werner</namePart><namePart type="family">Blum</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">My conception of "practice-oriented-mathematical-education", which must be seen as one point of view side-by-side with others, has the aim to qualify pupils to master life and is based on a method of working on problems which are true to life. Therefore I plead for geometry teaching, where the formation of sound geometric concepts and the relevance of applications of geometry in everyday life is important. After discussing this conception a schedule of activities of everyday life where geometry could help, and the description of four units of geometry in everyday life, are given.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Graumann_35.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776363/2312164/Graumann_35.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ellis Horwood</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1989</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-7458-0355-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-12164</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">153-158</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Graumann, G., 1989. Geometry in everyday life. In W.  Blum, ed. &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Mathematics and its applications.  Chichester: Ellis Horwood, pp. 153-158.</harvard1>
<ieee> G. Graumann, “Geometry in everyday life”, &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, W. Blum, ed., Mathematics and its applications,  Chichester: Ellis Horwood, 1989,  pp.153-158.</ieee>
<apa>Graumann, G. (1989). Geometry in everyday life. In W.  Blum (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Mathematics and its applications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153-158). Chichester: Ellis Horwood.</apa>
<mla>Graumann, Günter. “Geometry in everyday life”. &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Werner Blum. Chichester: Ellis Horwood, 1989. Mathematics and its applications. 153-158.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, G. (1989). Geometry in everyday life. In W.  Blum (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Mathematics and its applications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153-158). Chichester: Ellis Horwood.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Graumann, G. (1989). “Geometry in everyday life” in &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, Blum, W. ed. Mathematics and its applications (Chichester: Ellis Horwood), 153-158.</frontiers>
<wels>Graumann, G. (1989): Geometry in everyday life. In: Werner Blum (Hrsg.):  Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics. Chichester: Ellis Horwood. (Mathematics and its applications, ).  S. 153-158.</wels>
<default>Graumann G (1989)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics. Blum W (Ed);  Mathematics and its applications.  Chichester: Ellis Horwood:  153-158.</default>
<ama>Graumann G. Geometry in everyday life. In: Blum W, ed. &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Mathematics and its applications. Chichester: Ellis Horwood;  1989: 153-158.</ama>
<lncs> Graumann, G.: Geometry in everyday life. In: Blum, W. (ed.) Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics. Mathematics and its applications. p. 153-158. Ellis Horwood, Chichester (1989).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, Günter. 1989. “Geometry in everyday life”. In &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Werner Blum, 153-158. Mathematics and its applications. Chichester: Ellis Horwood.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Graumann, G. (1989). Geometry in everyday life (Mathematics and its applications). In W. Blum (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 153-158). Chichester: Ellis Horwood.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Graumann, in &lt;em&gt;Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: W. Blum), Ellis Horwood, Chichester, &lt;strong&gt;1989&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 153-158.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Graumann G (1989) &lt;br /&gt;Geometry in everyday life. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Applications and modelling in learning and teaching mathematics. Blum W (Ed); Mathematics and its applications,  Chichester: Ellis Horwood:  153-158.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776363</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>