<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1776947</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heinzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40276</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hans</namePart><namePart type="family">Kleinpoppen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29133467</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Heinzmann_052.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1776947/2312265/Heinzmann_052.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Plenum Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1985</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-306-42114-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13328</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">269-293</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Heinzmann, U. (1985): Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In: Hans Kleinpoppen (Hrsg.):  Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy. New York: Plenum Press. (NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134, ).  S. 269-293.</wels>
<bio1>Heinzmann U (1985) &lt;br /&gt;Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy. Kleinpoppen H (Ed); NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134,  New York: Plenum Press:  269-293.</bio1>
<harvard1>Heinzmann, U., 1985. Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In H.  Kleinpoppen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134.  New York: Plenum Press, pp. 269-293.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heinzmann, U. (1985). Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In H.  Kleinpoppen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 269-293). New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Heinzmann, in &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: H. Kleinpoppen), Plenum Press, New York, &lt;strong&gt;1985&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 269-293.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Heinzmann U. Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In: Kleinpoppen H, ed. &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134. New York: Plenum Press;  1985: 269-293.</ama>
<frontiers>Heinzmann, U. (1985). “Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy” in &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;, Kleinpoppen, H. ed. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134 (New York: Plenum Press), 269-293.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heinzmann, U. (1985). Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy (NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134). In H. Kleinpoppen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt; (S. 269-293). New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Heinzmann, U. (1985). Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In H.  Kleinpoppen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 269-293). New York: Plenum Press.</apa>
<ieee> U. Heinzmann, “Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy”, &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;, H. Kleinpoppen, ed., NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134,  New York: Plenum Press, 1985,  pp.269-293.</ieee>
<lncs> Heinzmann, U.: Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. In: Kleinpoppen, H. (ed.) Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134. p. 269-293. Plenum Press, New York (1985).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heinzmann, Ulrich. 1985. “Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy”. In &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Hans Kleinpoppen, 269-293. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134. New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Heinzmann, Ulrich. “Angle- and spin-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy”. &lt;em&gt;Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Hans Kleinpoppen. New York: Plenum Press, 1985. NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134. 269-293.</mla>
<default>Heinzmann U (1985)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fundamental processes in atomic collision physics: proceedings of a NATO Advanced Study Inst. on Fundamental Processes in Atomic Collision Physics, held Sept. 10 - 21, 1984, in Santa Flavia, Italy. Kleinpoppen H (Ed);  NATO ASI series : Ser. B ; 134.  New York: Plenum Press:  269-293.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1776947</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-21T11:23:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>