<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1777013</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:572</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eberhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20317</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Felix</namePart><namePart type="family">Gutmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Electric field effects in macromolecular organizations such as proteins, nucleic acids, and membranes frequently involve both chemical-conformational changes and physical-orientational displacements of molecular subgroups. Electro-optic techniques in conjunction with relaxation kinetics in high electric fields provide a tool for the investigation of the complex processes encountered in bioelectric phenomena on the level of macromolecules, membrane fragments, and other cellular units. Whereas part 1 covers the thermodynamics of electric field effects, this part deals with practical and theoretical aspects of kinetics and mechanisms in aqueous solutions of macromolecules and membranes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Neumann_B_32.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1777013/2312304/Neumann_B_32.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Plenum Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1986</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Modern bioelectrochemistry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-306-41981-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13777</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">133-175</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Neumann, E. (1986): Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In: Felix Gutmann (Hrsg.):  Modern bioelectrochemistry. New York: Plenum Press.  S. 133-175.</wels>
<frontiers>Neumann, E. (1986). “Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations” in &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;, Gutmann, F. ed. (New York: Plenum Press), 133-175.</frontiers>
<mla>Neumann, Eberhard. “Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations”. &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Felix Gutmann. New York: Plenum Press, 1986. 133-175.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, E. (1986). Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In F.  Gutmann (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 133-175). New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, E. (1986). Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In F. Gutmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt; (S. 133-175). New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Neumann E (1986)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern bioelectrochemistry. Gutmann F (Ed);  New York: Plenum Press:  133-175.</default>
<bio1>Neumann E (1986) &lt;br /&gt;Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern bioelectrochemistry. Gutmann F (Ed); New York: Plenum Press:  133-175.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Neumann, in &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: F. Gutmann), Plenum Press, New York, &lt;strong&gt;1986&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 133-175.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> E. Neumann, “Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations”, &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;, F. Gutmann, ed.,  New York: Plenum Press, 1986,  pp.133-175.</ieee>
<harvard1>Neumann, E., 1986. Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In F.  Gutmann, ed. &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: Plenum Press, pp. 133-175.</harvard1>
<ama>Neumann E. Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In: Gutmann F, ed. &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Plenum Press;  1986: 133-175.</ama>
<apa>Neumann, E. (1986). Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In F.  Gutmann (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 133-175). New York: Plenum Press.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, Eberhard. 1986. “Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations”. In &lt;em&gt;Modern bioelectrochemistry&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Felix Gutmann, 133-175. New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Neumann, E.: Elementary analysis of chemical electric field effects in biological macromolecules. 2: Kinetic aspects of electro-optic and conductometric relaxations. In: Gutmann, F. (ed.) Modern bioelectrochemistry. p. 133-175. Plenum Press, New York (1986).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1777013</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>