<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1777000</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:572</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hai Won</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ernest</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bock</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eberhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20317</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Pierre</namePart><namePart type="family">Changeux</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Neumann_B_27.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1777000/2312296/Neumann_B_27.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>de Gruyter</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1985</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-11-010345-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13694</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">351-367</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Chang, H. W.; Bock, E.; Neumann, E. (1985): Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In: Jean-Pierre Changeux (Hrsg.):  Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984. Berlin: de Gruyter.  S. 351-367.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chang, H. W., Bock, E., &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (1985). Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In J. - P.  Changeux (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 351-367). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Chang, H. W., Bock, E., and Neumann, E. (1985). “Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states” in &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;, Changeux, J. - P. ed. (Berlin: de Gruyter), 351-367.</frontiers>
<mla>Chang, Hai Won, Bock, Ernest, and Neumann, Eberhard. “Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states”. &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jean-Pierre Changeux. Berlin: de Gruyter, 1985. 351-367.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chang, H.W., Bock, E. &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (1985). Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In J.-P. Changeux (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt; (S. 351-367). Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Chang HW, Bock E, Neumann E (1985)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984. Changeux J-P (Ed);  Berlin: de Gruyter:  351-367.</default>
<bio1>Chang HW, Bock E, Neumann E (1985) &lt;br /&gt;Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984. Changeux J-P (Ed); Berlin: de Gruyter:  351-367.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H. W.  Chang, E.  Bock, and E.  Neumann, in &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: J.-P. Changeux), De Gruyter, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1985&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 351-367.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> H.W. Chang, E. Bock, and E. Neumann, “Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states”, &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;, J.-P. Changeux, ed.,  Berlin: de Gruyter, 1985,  pp.351-367.</ieee>
<harvard1>Chang, H.W., Bock, E., &amp;amp; Neumann, E., 1985. Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In J. - P.  Changeux, ed. &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin: de Gruyter, pp. 351-367.</harvard1>
<ama>Chang HW, Bock E, Neumann E. Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In: Changeux J-P, ed. &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin: de Gruyter;  1985: 351-367.</ama>
<apa>Chang, H. W., Bock, E., &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (1985). Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In J. - P.  Changeux (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 351-367). Berlin: de Gruyter.</apa>
<lncs> Chang, H.W., Bock, E., Neumann, E.: Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states. In: Changeux, J.-P. (ed.) Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984. p. 351-367. de Gruyter, Berlin (1985).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chang, Hai Won, Bock, Ernest, and Neumann, Eberhard. 1985. “Binding of [3H] acetylcholine to acetylcholine receptor from torpedo californica under equilibrium condition: stoichiometry and evidence for long-lived metastable states”. In &lt;em&gt;Molecular basis of nerve activity: proceedings of the Internat. Symposium in Memory of David Nachmansohn (1899 - 1983), Berlin (West), Germany, October 11 - 13, 1984&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jean-Pierre Changeux, 351-367. Berlin: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1777000</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>