<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1777009</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trockel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62508</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9827-6424</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT1373.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1777009/2312300/OCT1373.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Hain</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1980</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-445-12084-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-13733</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">175-187</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Trockel, W. (1980). “A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis” in &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;, Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research ed. Methods of operations research ; 38 (Königstein/Ts.: Hain), 175-187.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, W. (1980). A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis (Methods of operations research ; 38). In Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt; (S. 175-187). Königstein/Ts.: Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Trockel W. A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In: Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research, ed. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;. Methods of operations research ; 38. Königstein/Ts.: Hain;  1980: 175-187.</ama>
<ieee> W. Trockel, “A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;, Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research, ed., Methods of operations research ; 38,  Königstein/Ts.: Hain, 1980,  pp.175-187.</ieee>
<apa>Trockel, W. (1980). A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Methods of operations research ; 38&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 175-187). Königstein/Ts.: Hain.</apa>
<wels>Trockel, W. (1980): A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In: Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Hrsg.):  Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research. Königstein/Ts.: Hain. (Methods of operations research ; 38, ).  S. 175-187.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Trockel, in &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research), Hain, Königstein/Ts., &lt;strong&gt;1980&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 175-187.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Trockel W (1980) &lt;br /&gt;A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research. Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Ed); Methods of operations research ; 38,  Königstein/Ts.: Hain:  175-187.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, W. (1980). A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Methods of operations research ; 38&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 175-187). Königstein/Ts.: Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Trockel, W., 1980. A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research, ed. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;. Methods of operations research ; 38.  Königstein/Ts.: Hain, pp. 175-187.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, Walter. 1980. “A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research, 175-187. Methods of operations research ; 38. Königstein/Ts.: Hain.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Trockel, W.: A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis. In: Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (ed.) Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research. Methods of operations research ; 38. p. 175-187. Hain, Königstein/Ts. (1980).</lncs>
<default>Trockel W (1980)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research. Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research (Ed);  Methods of operations research ; 38.  Königstein/Ts.: Hain:  175-187.</default>
<mla>Trockel, Walter. “A measure theoretical problem in mean demand analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Operations Research: proceedings organized by Ges. für Mathematik, Ökonomie und Operations-Research&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Gesellschaft fuer Mathematik, Oekonomie und Operations Research. Königstein/Ts.: Hain, 1980. Methods of operations research ; 38. 175-187.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1777009</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>