<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1778558</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Brigitte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dreiseikelmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22023</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wilfried</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wackernagel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685250</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Some aspects of the involvment of the terminal reduntant regions of T7 DNA on phage production have been studied by transfection experiments with T7 DNA after treatment of the molecules with [lambda] exonuclease or [lambda] exonuclease plus exonuclease I. It was found that terminal 5prime gaps between 0.08 and 6.4% of the total length did not decrease the infectivity of the molecules although such gaps cannot be filled directly by DNA polymerases. Rather, compared to fully native DNA the infectivity of gapped DNA increased up to 20 fold in rec + spheroplasts and up to 4 fold in recB spheroplasts. This indicates a protective function of the single-stranded termini against the recBC enzyme in rec + and possibly another unidentified exonuclease present also in recB. The possibility that spontaneous circularization of the gapped molecules in vivo provides protection against exonucleolytic degradation was tested by transfection with T7 DNA circularization in vitro by thermal annealing. Such molecules were separated from linear molecules by neutral sucrose gradient centrifugation. They displayed a 3 to 6 fold higher infectivity in rec + and recB compared to linear gapped molecules, which shows that T7 phage production may effectively start from circular DNA. When the 3prime single-stranded ends from gapped molecules were degraded by treatment with exonuclease I the infectivity of the molecules was largely abolished in rec + and recB as soon as 40 to 80 base pairs had been removed per end. It is concluded that the terminal regions of T7 DNA molecules are essential for phage production and that the redundancy comprises probably considerably less than 260 base pairs. The results are discussed with respect to the mode of T7 DNA replication.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dreiseikelmann_02.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1778558/2312468/Dreiseikelmann_02.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1978</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Molecular and General Genetics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0026-8925</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1617-4623</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">345101</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1978EQ98300011</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17785581</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF00268269</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>159</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">321-328</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dreiseikelmann, Brigitte, and Wackernagel, Wilfried. 1978. “The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases”. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt; 159 (3): 321-328.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dreiseikelmann, B., Wackernagel, W.: The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. Molecular and General Genetics. 159, 321-328 (1978).</lncs>
<default>Dreiseikelmann B, Wackernagel W (1978) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt; 159(3): 321-328.</default>
<mla>Dreiseikelmann, Brigitte, and Wackernagel, Wilfried. “The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases”. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt; 159.3 (1978): 321-328.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dreiseikelmann, B. &amp;amp; Wackernagel, W. (1978). The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;159&lt;/em&gt;(3), 321-328. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1007/BF00268269.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Dreiseikelmann, B., and Wackernagel, W. (1978). The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt; 159, 321-328.</frontiers>
<ama>Dreiseikelmann B, Wackernagel W. The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;. 1978;159(3):321-328.</ama>
<ieee> B. Dreiseikelmann and W. Wackernagel, “The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases”, &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 159, 1978,  pp. 321-328.</ieee>
<apa>Dreiseikelmann, B., &amp;amp; Wackernagel, W. (1978). The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;159&lt;/em&gt;(3), 321-328. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00268269" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00268269&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Dreiseikelmann, B.; Wackernagel, W. (1978): The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;,159:(3): 321-328.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Dreiseikelmann, and W.  Wackernagel, “The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases”, &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1978&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;159&lt;/em&gt;, 321-328.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dreiseikelmann B, Wackernagel W (1978) &lt;br /&gt;The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases.&lt;br /&gt;Molecular and General Genetics 159(3): 321-328.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dreiseikelmann, B., &amp;amp; Wackernagel, W., 1978. The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, 159(3), p 321-328.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dreiseikelmann, B., &amp;amp; Wackernagel, W. (1978). The terminal redundant regions of bacteriophage T7 DNA: their necessity for phage production studied by the infectivity of T7 DNA after modification by various exonucleases. &lt;em&gt;Molecular and General Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;159&lt;/em&gt;(3), 321-328. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00268269" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00268269&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1778558</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>