<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1779393</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alois</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33671</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hans</namePart><namePart type="family">Thomae</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Angleitner_16.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779393/2312689/Angleitner_16.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Karger</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1976</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18642</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">68-80</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Angleitner A. Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In: Thomae H, ed. &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;. Contributions to human development ; 3. Basel: Karger;  1976: 68-80.</ama>
<frontiers>Angleitner, A. (1976). “Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life” in &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;, Thomae, H. ed. Contributions to human development ; 3 (Basel: Karger), 68-80.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A. (1976). Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life (Contributions to human development ; 3). In H. Thomae (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt; (S. 68-80). Basel: Karger.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Angleitner, A. (1976). Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In H.  Thomae (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Contributions to human development ; 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 68-80). Basel: Karger.</apa>
<ieee> A. Angleitner, “Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life”, &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;, H. Thomae, ed., Contributions to human development ; 3,  Basel: Karger, 1976,  pp.68-80.</ieee>
<wels>Angleitner, A. (1976): Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In: Hans Thomae (Hrsg.):  Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging. Basel: Karger. (Contributions to human development ; 3, ).  S. 68-80.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A. (1976). Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In H.  Thomae (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Contributions to human development ; 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 68-80). Basel: Karger.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Angleitner, A., 1976. Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In H.  Thomae, ed. &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;. Contributions to human development ; 3.  Basel: Karger, pp. 68-80.</harvard1>
<bio1>Angleitner A (1976) &lt;br /&gt;Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging. Thomae H (Ed); Contributions to human development ; 3,  Basel: Karger:  68-80.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Angleitner, in &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: H. Thomae), Karger, Basel, &lt;strong&gt;1976&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 68-80.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Angleitner, A.: Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life. In: Thomae, H. (ed.) Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging. Contributions to human development ; 3. p. 68-80. Karger, Basel (1976).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, Alois. 1976. “Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life”. In &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Hans Thomae, 68-80. Contributions to human development ; 3. Basel: Karger.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Angleitner, Alois. “Changes in personality observed in questionnaire data from the Riegel questionnaire on rigidity, dogmatism, and attitude toward life”. &lt;em&gt;Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Hans Thomae. Basel: Karger, 1976. Contributions to human development ; 3. 68-80.</mla>
<default>Angleitner A (1976)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Patterns of aging: findings from the Bonn longitudinal study of aging. Thomae H (Ed);  Contributions to human development ; 3.  Basel: Karger:  68-80.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779393</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>