<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1779190</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schwarz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bless</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bohner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">44335</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0564-3625</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mark P. </namePart><namePart type="family">Zanna</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33698</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This chapter outlines different mediating processes that are consistent with the current theory on the interplay of emotion and cognition, and evaluates these assumptions in the light of the available evidence. According to the “Cognitive response” approach, recipients of a persuasive communication may arrive at an attitude judgment by one of the two ways, and may consider the content of the message, paying close attention to the implications of the presented arguments. The recipients may not engage in a thorough consideration of message content, but may rely on simple cues, such as the communicator's prestige or likableness. For the content-oriented, processing strategy is “systematic processing” or the “central route to persuasion”. Current theorizing on the interplay of affect and cognition suggests at least five ways in which the recipients' mood may influence persuasion processes within this general framework. Each of these possibilities has different implications for recipients' attitude change, their cognitive responses to the message, and their evaluation of the presented arguments.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bohner_031.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779190/2312574/Bohner_031.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advances in Experimental Social Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0065-2601</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-12-015224-7</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1991GN46100003</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-17472</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>24</number></detail><extent unit="pages">161-199</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Schwarz, N., Bless, H., &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (1991). Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In M. P.   Zanna (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology: Vol. 24&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 161-199). Elsevier. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> N. Schwarz, H. Bless, and G. Bohner, “Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications”, &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, M.P.  Zanna, ed., Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, vol. 24, Elsevier, 1991,  pp.161-199.</ieee>
<ama>Schwarz N, Bless H, Bohner G. Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In: Zanna MP, ed. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Vol 24. Elsevier;  1991: 161-199.</ama>
<frontiers>Schwarz, N., Bless, H., and Bohner, G. (1991). “Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications” in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, Zanna, M. P. ed. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, vol. 24, (Elsevier), 161-199.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schwarz, N., Bless, H. &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (1991). Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications (Advances in Experimental Social Psychology). In M.P.  Zanna (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (S. 161-199). Elsevier. doi:10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Schwarz N, Bless H, Bohner G (1991) &lt;br /&gt;Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Zanna MP (Ed); Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, 24. Elsevier:  161-199.</bio1>
<harvard1>Schwarz, N., Bless, H., &amp;amp; Bohner, G., 1991. Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In M. P.   Zanna, ed. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. no.24  Elsevier, pp. 161-199.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schwarz, N., Bless, H., &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (1991). Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In M. P.   Zanna (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology: Vol. 24&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 161-199). Elsevier. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60329-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Schwarz, H.  Bless, and G.  Bohner, in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M.P.  Zanna), Elsevier, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 161-199.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Schwarz, N.; Bless, H.; Bohner, G. (1991): Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In: Mark P.  Zanna (Hrsg.):  Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Elsevier. (Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, 24).  S. 161-199.</wels>
<mla>Schwarz, Norbert, Bless, Herbert, and Bohner, Gerd. “Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications”. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Mark P.  Zanna. Elsevier, 1991.Vol. 24. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. 161-199.</mla>
<default>Schwarz N, Bless H, Bohner G (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Zanna MP (Ed);  Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, 24.  Elsevier:  161-199.</default>
<lncs> Schwarz, N., Bless, H., Bohner, G.: Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications. In: Zanna, M.P. (ed.) Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. 24, p. 161-199. Elsevier (1991).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schwarz, Norbert, Bless, Herbert, and Bohner, Gerd. 1991. “Mood and persuasion: affective states influence the processing of persuasive communications”. In &lt;em&gt;Advances in Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Mark P.  Zanna, 24:161-199. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology. Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779190</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-28T10:21:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>