<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1779318</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merlyn J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Behr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Post</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rina</namePart><namePart type="family">Hershkowitz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_65.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779318/2312657/Wachsmuth_65.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1983</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">965-281-000-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18325</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">164-169</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M.J., Post, T.R.: Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In: Hershkowitz, R. and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (eds.) Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. p. 164-169. Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science, Rehovot (1983).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke, Behr, Merlyn J., and Post, Thomas R. 1983. “Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Rina Hershkowitz and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 164-169. Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Wachsmuth I, Behr MJ, Post TR. Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In: Hershkowitz R, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science;  1983: 164-169.</ama>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I, Behr MJ, Post TR (1983) &lt;br /&gt;Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Hershkowitz R, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds); Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science:  164-169.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, M. J.  Behr, and T. R.  Post, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Hershkowitz, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education), Dept. Of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. Of Science, Rehovot, &lt;strong&gt;1983&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 164-169.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M.J. &amp;amp; Post, T.R. (1983). Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In R. Hershkowitz &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 164-169). Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M. J., &amp;amp; Post, T. R. (1983). Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In R.  Hershkowitz &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 164-169). Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science.</apa>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, M.J. Behr, and T.R. Post, “Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, R. Hershkowitz and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds.,  Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science, 1983,  pp.164-169.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M.J., &amp;amp; Post, T.R., 1983. Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In R.  Hershkowitz &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;.  Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science, pp. 164-169.</harvard1>
<default>Wachsmuth I, Behr MJ, Post TR (1983)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Hershkowitz R, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds);  Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science:  164-169.</default>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke, Behr, Merlyn J., and Post, Thomas R. “Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Rina Hershkowitz and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science, 1983. 164-169.</mla>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M. J., and Post, T. R. (1983). “Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, Hershkowitz, R., and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education eds. (Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science), 164-169.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I., Behr, M. J., &amp;amp; Post, T. R. (1983). Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In R.  Hershkowitz &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 164-169). Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I.; Behr, M. J.; Post, T. R. (1983): Children's perception of ratios and fractions in Grade 5. In: Rina Hershkowitz; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Rehovot: Dept. of Science Teaching, Weizmann Inst. of Science.  S. 164-169.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779318</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>