<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1779324</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merlyn J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Behr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart><namePart type="family">Vermandel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_68.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779324/2312659/Wachsmuth_68.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Univ. Instelling</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1982</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">2-87092-000-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18348</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">181-186</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Behr, M.J., Wachsmuth, I.: Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In: Vermandel, A. and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (eds.) Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education. p. 181-186. Univ. Instelling, Antwerpen (1982).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, Merlyn J., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1982. “Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Alfred Vermandel and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 181-186. Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Behr, M. J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In A.  Vermandel &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 181-186). Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling.</apa>
<ama>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I. Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In: Vermandel A, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;. Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling;  1982: 181-186.</ama>
<harvard1>Behr, M.J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1982. Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In A.  Vermandel &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;.  Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling, pp. 181-186.</harvard1>
<ieee> M.J. Behr and I. Wachsmuth, “Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;, A. Vermandel and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, eds.,  Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling, 1982,  pp.181-186.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>M. J.  Behr, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Vermandel, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education), Univ. Instelling, Antwerpen, &lt;strong&gt;1982&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 181-186.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I (1982) &lt;br /&gt;Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education. Vermandel A, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds); Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling:  181-186.</bio1>
<default>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I (1982)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education. Vermandel A, International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds);  Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling:  181-186.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, M.J. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In A. Vermandel &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 181-186). Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, M. J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In A.  Vermandel &amp;amp; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 181-186). Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Behr, Merlyn J., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Alfred Vermandel and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling, 1982. 181-186.</mla>
<frontiers>Behr, M. J., and Wachsmuth, I. (1982). “Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education&lt;/em&gt;, Vermandel, A., and International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education eds. (Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling), 181-186.</frontiers>
<wels>Behr, M. J.; Wachsmuth, I. (1982): Turning the plates: size perception of rational numbers among 9- and 10-year old children. In: Alfred Vermandel; International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematical Education. Antwerpen: Univ. Instelling.  S. 181-186.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779324</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>