<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780048</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alois</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33671</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Strelau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dieter</namePart><namePart type="family">Bartussek</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This study explores some hypotheses developed by Cattell (1972) about the relationships between his objective test factors (U.I.16, U.I.17, U.I.21, U.I.22, U.I.23) and Pavlovian concepts (especially strength of the nervous system as expressed in strength of excitation). A total of 58 subjects were tested individually. Objective test factors were measured with seven tests from the German Objective-Analytic Test Battery (Haecker, Schmidt, Schwenkmezger, &amp; Utz, 1975) and two temperament inventories: (1) the Pavlovian Temperament Survey (PTS; Strelau, Angleitner, Bantelmann, &amp; Ruch, 1990a) and (2) the Formal Characteristics of Behavior-Temperament Survey (FCB-TI; Strelau &amp; Zawadzki, in press).The results supported some of Cattell's hypotheses, and indicated the correctness of his intuitions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Angleitner_51.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780048/2312731/Angleitner_51.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Hogrefe</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-8017-0758-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-19086</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">219-228</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Strelau, J., 1994. Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In D.  Bartussek, ed. &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;.  Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe, pp. 219-228.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Angleitner and J. Strelau, “Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses”, &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;, D. Bartussek, ed.,  Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe, 1994,  pp.219-228.</ieee>
<ama>Angleitner A, Strelau J. Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In: Bartussek D, ed. &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;. Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe;  1994: 219-228.</ama>
<apa>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Strelau, J. (1994). Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In D.  Bartussek (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 219-228). Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe.</apa>
<lncs> Angleitner, A., Strelau, J.: Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In: Bartussek, D. (ed.) Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik. p. 219-228. Hogrefe, Göttingen [u.a.] (1994).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, Alois, and Strelau, Jan. 1994. “Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses”. In &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dieter Bartussek, 219-228. Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Angleitner, A.; Strelau, J. (1994): Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In: Dieter Bartussek (Hrsg.):  Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik. Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe.  S. 219-228.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A. &amp;amp; Strelau, J. (1994). Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In D. Bartussek (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt; (S. 219-228). Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Strelau, J. (1994). Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. In D.  Bartussek (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 219-228). Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Angleitner, A., and Strelau, J. (1994). “Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses” in &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;, Bartussek, D. ed. (Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe), 219-228.</frontiers>
<mla>Angleitner, Alois, and Strelau, Jan. “Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses”. &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dieter Bartussek. Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe, 1994. 219-228.</mla>
<default>Angleitner A, Strelau J (1994)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik. Bartussek D (Ed);  Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe:  219-228.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Angleitner, and J.  Strelau, in &lt;em&gt;Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: D. Bartussek), Hogrefe, Göttingen [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 219-228.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Angleitner A, Strelau J (1994) &lt;br /&gt;Psychometric measures of Pavlovian Temperament traits and objective personality tests: a comeback for Cattell's hypotheses. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fortschritte der differentiellen Psychologie und psychologischen Diagnostik: Festschrift zum 60. Geburtstag von Professor Dr. Kurt Pawlik. Bartussek D (Ed); Göttingen [u.a.]: Hogrefe:  219-228.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780048</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>