<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780506</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahlswede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10479</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ning</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cai</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zhen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zhang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rainer</namePart><namePart type="family">Bodendiek</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart><namePart type="family">Henn</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ahlswede_68.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780506/2312934/Ahlswede_68.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Physica-Verl.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1990</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-7908-0439-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-21211</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">37-39</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Ahlswede, Rudolf, Cai, Ning, and Zhang, Zhen. “A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph”. &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Rainer Bodendiek and Rudolf Henn. Heidelberg: Physica-Verl., 1990. 37-39.</mla>
<default>Ahlswede R, Cai N, Zhang Z (1990)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel. Bodendiek R, Henn R (Eds);  Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.:  37-39.</default>
<lncs> Ahlswede, R., Cai, N., Zhang, Z.: A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In: Bodendiek, R. and Henn, R. (eds.) Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel. p. 37-39. Physica-Verl., Heidelberg (1990).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, Rudolf, Cai, Ning, and Zhang, Zhen. 1990. “A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph”. In &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Rainer Bodendiek and Rudolf Henn, 37-39. Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Ahlswede, R., Cai, N., &amp;amp; Zhang, Z. (1990). A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In R.  Bodendiek &amp;amp; R.  Henn (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 37-39). Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.</apa>
<ieee> R. Ahlswede, N. Cai, and Z. Zhang, “A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph”, &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;, R. Bodendiek and R. Henn, eds.,  Heidelberg: Physica-Verl., 1990,  pp.37-39.</ieee>
<ama>Ahlswede R, Cai N, Zhang Z. A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In: Bodendiek R, Henn R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;. Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.;  1990: 37-39.</ama>
<frontiers>Ahlswede, R., Cai, N., and Zhang, Z. (1990). “A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph” in &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;, Bodendiek, R., and Henn, R. eds. (Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.), 37-39.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, R., Cai, N. &amp;amp; Zhang, Z. (1990). A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In R. Bodendiek &amp;amp; R. Henn (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt; (S. 37-39). Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Ahlswede, R., Cai, N., &amp;amp; Zhang, Z., 1990. A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In R.  Bodendiek &amp;amp; R.  Henn, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt;.  Heidelberg: Physica-Verl., pp. 37-39.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, R., Cai, N., &amp;amp; Zhang, Z. (1990). A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In R.  Bodendiek &amp;amp; R.  Henn (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 37-39). Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Ahlswede R, Cai N, Zhang Z (1990) &lt;br /&gt;A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel. Bodendiek R, Henn R (Eds); Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.:  37-39.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Ahlswede, N.  Cai, and Z.  Zhang, in &lt;em&gt;Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Bodendiek, R. Henn), Physica-Verl., Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;1990&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 37-39.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Ahlswede, R.; Cai, N.; Zhang, Z. (1990): A recursive bound for the number of complete K-subgraphs of a graph. In: Rainer Bodendiek; Rudolf Henn (Hrsg.):  Topics in combinatorics and graph theory: essays in honour of Gerhard Ringel. Heidelberg: Physica-Verl.  S. 37-39.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780506</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>