<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780606</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Drees</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kummert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10372</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Enno</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Littmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Posch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sagerer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10375</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Edzard S.</namePart><namePart type="family">Gelsema</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Laveen S.</namePart><namePart type="family">Kanal</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kummert_016.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780606/2312970/Kummert_016.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>North Holland Publ. Co.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-444-81892-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-21588</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">551-562</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drees, A., Kummert, F., Littmann, E., Posch, S., Ritter, H. &amp;amp; Sagerer, G. (1994). A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images (Pattern recognition in practice). In E.S. Gelsema &amp;amp; L.S. Kanal (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt; (S. 551-562). Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Drees A, Kummert F, Littmann E, Posch S, Ritter H, Sagerer G (1994) &lt;br /&gt;A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994. Gelsema ES, Kanal LS (Eds); Pattern recognition in practice, 4. Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.:  551-562.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Drees, F.  Kummert, E.  Littmann, S.  Posch, H.  Ritter, and G.  Sagerer, in &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E.S. Gelsema, L.S. Kanal), North Holland Publ. Co., Amsterdam, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 551-562.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Drees A, Kummert F, Littmann E, Posch S, Ritter H, Sagerer G. A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In: Gelsema ES, Kanal LS, eds. &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;. Pattern recognition in practice. Vol 4. Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.;  1994: 551-562.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drees, A., Kummert, Franz, Littmann, Enno, Posch, Stefan, Ritter, Helge, and Sagerer, Gerhard. 1994. “A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images”. In &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Edzard S. Gelsema and Laveen S. Kanal, 4:551-562. Pattern recognition in practice. Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Drees, A., Kummert, F., Littmann, E., Posch, S., Ritter, H., Sagerer, G.: A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In: Gelsema, E.S. and Kanal, L.S. (eds.) Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994. Pattern recognition in practice. 4, p. 551-562. North Holland Publ. Co., Amsterdam (1994).</lncs>
<frontiers>Drees, A., Kummert, F., Littmann, E., Posch, S., Ritter, H., and Sagerer, G. (1994). “A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images” in &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;, Gelsema, E. S., and Kanal, L. S. eds. Pattern recognition in practice, vol. 4, (Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.), 551-562.</frontiers>
<mla>Drees, A., Kummert, Franz, Littmann, Enno, Posch, Stefan, Ritter, Helge, and Sagerer, Gerhard. “A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images”. &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Edzard S. Gelsema and Laveen S. Kanal. Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co., 1994.Vol. 4. Pattern recognition in practice. 551-562.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drees, A., Kummert, F., Littmann, E., Posch, S., Ritter, H., &amp;amp; Sagerer, G. (1994). A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In E. S.  Gelsema &amp;amp; L. S.  Kanal (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Pattern recognition in practice: Vol. 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 551-562). Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Drees, A.; Kummert, F.; Littmann, E.; Posch, S.; Ritter, H.; Sagerer, G. (1994): A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In: Edzard S. Gelsema; Laveen S. Kanal (Hrsg.):  Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994. Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co. (Pattern recognition in practice, 4).  S. 551-562.</wels>
<default>Drees A, Kummert F, Littmann E, Posch S, Ritter H, Sagerer G (1994)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994. Gelsema ES, Kanal LS (Eds);  Pattern recognition in practice, 4.  Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.:  551-562.</default>
<ieee> A. Drees, et al., “A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images”, &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;, E.S. Gelsema and L.S. Kanal, eds., Pattern recognition in practice, vol. 4,  Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co., 1994,  pp.551-562.</ieee>
<harvard1>Drees, A., et al., 1994. A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In E. S.  Gelsema &amp;amp; L. S.  Kanal, eds. &lt;em&gt;Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt;. Pattern recognition in practice. no.4  Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co., pp. 551-562.</harvard1>
<apa>Drees, A., Kummert, F., Littmann, E., Posch, S., Ritter, H., &amp;amp; Sagerer, G. (1994). A hybrid system to detect hand orientation orientation in stereo images. In E. S.  Gelsema &amp;amp; L. S.  Kanal (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Pattern recognition in practice: Vol. 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Multiple paradigms, comparative studies and hybrid systems: proceedings of an international workshop held on Vlieland, The Netherlands, 1 - 3 June 1994&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 551-562). Amsterdam: North Holland Publ. Co.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780606</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>