<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780988</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mönckemeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spitta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41186</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Reinhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Budde</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes how prototyping is made possible by using powerful tools ina software engineering environment based on a phase model. Prototyping is considered to be a useful technique within a detailed concept of software production rather than such a concept itself.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Spitta_013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780988/2313127/Spitta_013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1984</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Software Engineering</topic><topic>Prototyping</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-13490-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-23198</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">122-135</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Mönckemeyer, M., &amp;amp; Spitta, T. (1984). Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In R.  Budde (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 122-135). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.</apa>
<harvard1>Mönckemeyer, M., &amp;amp; Spitta, T., 1984. Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In R.  Budde, ed. &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, pp. 122-135.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Mönckemeyer and T. Spitta, “Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL”, &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;, R. Budde, ed.,  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, 1984,  pp.122-135.</ieee>
<default>Mönckemeyer M, Spitta T (1984)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983. Budde R (Ed);  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer:  122-135.</default>
<mla>Mönckemeyer, Manfred, and Spitta, Thorsten. “Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL”. &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Reinhard Budde. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, 1984. 122-135.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mönckemeyer, M., &amp;amp; Spitta, T. (1984). Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In R.  Budde (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 122-135). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Mönckemeyer, M., and Spitta, T. (1984). “Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL” in &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;, Budde, R. ed. (Berlin [u.a.]: Springer), 122-135.</frontiers>
<wels>Mönckemeyer, M.; Spitta, T. (1984): Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In: Reinhard Budde (Hrsg.):  Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.  S. 122-135.</wels>
<lncs> Mönckemeyer, M., Spitta, T.: Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In: Budde, R. (ed.) Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983. p. 122-135. Springer, Berlin [u.a.] (1984).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mönckemeyer, Manfred, and Spitta, Thorsten. 1984. “Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL”. In &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Reinhard Budde, 122-135. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Mönckemeyer M, Spitta T. Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In: Budde R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer;  1984: 122-135.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Mönckemeyer, and T.  Spitta, in &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Budde), Springer, Berlin [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;1984&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 122-135.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Mönckemeyer M, Spitta T (1984) &lt;br /&gt;Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983. Budde R (Ed); Berlin [u.a.]: Springer:  122-135.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mönckemeyer, M. &amp;amp; Spitta, T. (1984). Concept and Experiences of Prototyping in a Software-Engineering Environment with NATURAL. In R. Budde (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Approaches to Prototyping: Proceedings of the Working Conference on Prototyping, Namur, Oct. 1983&lt;/em&gt; (S. 122-135). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780988</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>