<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780372</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahlswede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10479</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jaroslav</namePart><namePart type="family">Kozesník</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ahlswede_13.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780372/2312889/Ahlswede_13.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.]</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1973</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-20759</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">23-37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Ahlswede, Rudolf. “On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz”. &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jaroslav Kozesník. München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.], 1973. 23-37.</mla>
<default>Ahlswede R (1973)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971. Kozesník J (Ed);  München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.]:  23-37.</default>
<lncs> Ahlswede, R.: On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In: Kozesník, J. (ed.) Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971. p. 23-37. Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.], München (1973).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, Rudolf. 1973. “On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz”. In &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jaroslav Kozesník, 23-37. München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.].&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Ahlswede, R. (1973). On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In J.  Kozesník (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 23-37). München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.].</apa>
<ieee> R. Ahlswede, “On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz”, &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;, J. Kozesník, ed.,  München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.], 1973,  pp.23-37.</ieee>
<ama>Ahlswede R. On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In: Kozesník J, ed. &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;. München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.];  1973: 23-37.</ama>
<frontiers>Ahlswede, R. (1973). “On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz” in &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;, Kozesník, J. ed. (München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.]), 23-37.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, R. (1973). On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In J. Kozesník (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt; (S. 23-37). München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.].&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Ahlswede, R., 1973. On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In J.  Kozesník, ed. &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt;.  München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.], pp. 23-37.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ahlswede R (1973) &lt;br /&gt;On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971. Kozesník J (Ed); München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.]:  23-37.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahlswede, R. (1973). On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In J.  Kozesník (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 23-37). München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.].&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Ahlswede, in &lt;em&gt;Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: J. Kozesník), Verl. Dokumentation [U.a.], München, &lt;strong&gt;1973&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 23-37.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Ahlswede, R. (1973): On two-way communication channels and a problem by Zarankiewicz. In: Jaroslav Kozesník (Hrsg.):  Transactions of the Sixth Prague Conference on Information Theory, Statistical Decision Functions, Random Processes: held at Prague, from September 19 to 25, 1971. München: Verl. Dokumentation [u.a.].  S. 23-37.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780372</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>