<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780318</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Evaluation Strategies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albrecht</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13192</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Günter</namePart><namePart type="family">Albrecht</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Albrecht_036.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780318/2312872/Albrecht_036.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>de Gruyter</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Prävention</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-11-012387-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-20584</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">237-242</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albrecht, G. (1991). Evaluation Strategies (Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11). In G. Albrecht (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt; (S. 237-242). Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Albrecht, in &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: G. Albrecht), De Gruyter, Berlin [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 237-242.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Albrecht G (1991) &lt;br /&gt;Evaluation Strategies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies. Albrecht G (Ed); Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11,  Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter:  237-242.</bio1>
<ama>Albrecht G. Evaluation Strategies. In: Albrecht G, ed. &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11. Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter;  1991: 237-242.</ama>
<lncs> Albrecht, G.: Evaluation Strategies. In: Albrecht, G. (ed.) Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11. p. 237-242. de Gruyter, Berlin [u.a.] (1991).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albrecht, Günter. 1991. “Evaluation Strategies”. In &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Günter Albrecht, 237-242. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11. Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Albrecht, Günter. “Evaluation Strategies”. &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Günter Albrecht. Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter, 1991. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11. 237-242.</mla>
<frontiers>Albrecht, G. (1991). “Evaluation Strategies” in &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;, Albrecht, G. ed. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11 (Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter), 237-242.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albrecht, G. (1991). Evaluation Strategies. In G.  Albrecht (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 237-242). Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Albrecht, G. (1991): Evaluation Strategies. In: Günter Albrecht (Hrsg.):  Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies. Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter. (Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11, ).  S. 237-242.</wels>
<default>Albrecht G (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies. Albrecht G (Ed);  Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11.  Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter:  237-242.</default>
<harvard1>Albrecht, G., 1991. Evaluation Strategies. In G.  Albrecht, ed. &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;. Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11.  Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter, pp. 237-242.</harvard1>
<ieee> G. Albrecht, “Evaluation Strategies”, &lt;em&gt;Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt;, G. Albrecht, ed., Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11,  Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter, 1991,  pp.237-242.</ieee>
<apa>Albrecht, G. (1991). Evaluation Strategies. In G.  Albrecht (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Prevention and intervention in childhood and adolescence ; 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Social prevention and the social sciences: theoretical controversies, research problems, and evaluation strategies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 237-242). Berlin [u.a.]: de Gruyter.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780318</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>