<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1780961</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:590</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Flavio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Roces</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">York</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Otto</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">von Helversen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">W.</namePart><namePart type="family">Barthlott</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Nectar concentration preference of flower visiting bats Glossophaga soricina antillarum was studied in the laboratory. In a series of dual choice tests using sugar concentrations from 10 to 80 %, the bats preferred the higher nectar concentration up to a maximum of 50 %. When presented simultaneously with nectar and additional water, the bats took more water, depending on the nectar concentration offered. The regular distribution of nectar and water intake during the activity period resulted in a roughly constant mean ingested concentration. Its maximal value agreed with that of the preferred nectar concentration, indicating that water needs played a role in determining the upper limit of an acceptable concentration. In preliminary experiments with ad libitum-feeders, sugar intake rate was maximal at 60 % despite the high viscosity at this concentration. Results are discussed in relation to the evolution of nectar concentration in bat-pollinated flowers.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Winter_02.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780961/2313109/Winter_02.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>nectar concentration</topic><topic>Glossophaga soricina antillarum</topic><topic>bat</topic><topic>food selection</topic><topic>water balance</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Animal plant interactions in tropical environments</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-925382-36-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17809610</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1992</number></detail><extent unit="pages">159-165</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Roces F, Winter Y, von Helversen O. Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In: Barthlott W, Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig, eds. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology. Vol 1992. Bonn;  1993: 159-165.</ama>
<frontiers>Roces, F., Winter, Y., and von Helversen, O. (1993). “Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum” in &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, Barthlott, W., and Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig eds. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology, vol. 1992, (Bonn), 159-165.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roces, F., Winter, Y. &amp;amp; von Helversen, O. (1993). Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum (Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology). In W. Barthlott &amp;amp; Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (S. 159-165). Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Roces, F., Winter, Y., &amp;amp; von Helversen, O. (1993). Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In W.  Barthlott &amp;amp; Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology: Vol. 1992&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-165). Bonn.</apa>
<ieee> F. Roces, Y. Winter, and O. von Helversen, “Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum”, &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, W. Barthlott and Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig, eds., Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology, vol. 1992,  Bonn: 1993,  pp.159-165.</ieee>
<wels>Roces, F.; Winter, Y.; von Helversen, O. (1993): Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In: W. Barthlott; Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Hrsg.):  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Bonn. (Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology, 1992).  S. 159-165.</wels>
<harvard1>Roces, F., Winter, Y., &amp;amp; von Helversen, O., 1993. Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In W.  Barthlott &amp;amp; Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig, eds. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology. no.1992  Bonn, pp. 159-165.</harvard1>
<bio1>Roces F, Winter Y, von Helversen O (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Barthlott W, Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Eds); Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology, 1992. Bonn:  159-165.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roces, F., Winter, Y., &amp;amp; von Helversen, O. (1993). Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In W.  Barthlott &amp;amp; Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology: Vol. 1992&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-165). Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Roces, Y.  Winter, and O.  von Helversen, in &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: W. Barthlott, Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig), Bonn, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 159-165.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Roces, F., Winter, Y., von Helversen, O.: Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum. In: Barthlott, W. and Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (eds.) Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology. 1992, p. 159-165. Bonn (1993).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roces, Flavio, Winter, York, and von Helversen, Otto. 1993. “Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum”. In &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. W. Barthlott and Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig, 1992:159-165. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology. Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Roces, Flavio, Winter, York, and von Helversen, Otto. “Nectar concentration preference and water balance in a flower visiting bat, Glossophaga Soricina Antillarum”. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. W. Barthlott and Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig. Bonn, 1993.Vol. 1992. Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology. 159-165.</mla>
<default>Roces F, Winter Y, von Helversen O (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Barthlott W, Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut und Museum Alexander Koenig (Eds);  Results of the annual meeting of the German Society for Tropical Ecology, 1992.  Bonn:  159-165.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780961</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-09T06:59:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>