<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781578</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böhm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">80680</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Franco</namePart><namePart type="family">Gori</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT2581.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781578/2313352/OCT2581.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-56704-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-25814</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>399</number></detail><extent unit="pages">69-94</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V. (1993). Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models (Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems). In F. Gori (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt; (S. 69-94). Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Böhm V (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991. Gori F (Ed); Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems, 399. Berlin: Springer:  69-94.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Böhm, in &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: F. Gori), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 69-94.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Böhm V. Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In: Gori F, ed. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems. Vol 399. Berlin: Springer;  1993: 69-94.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, Volker. 1993. “Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models”. In &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Franco Gori, 399:69-94. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Böhm, V.: Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In: Gori, F. (ed.) Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems. 399, p. 69-94. Springer, Berlin (1993).</lncs>
<wels>Böhm, V. (1993): Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In: Franco Gori (Hrsg.):  Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991. Berlin: Springer. (Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems, 399).  S. 69-94.</wels>
<frontiers>Böhm, V. (1993). “Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models” in &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;, Gori, F. ed. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems, vol. 399, (Berlin: Springer), 69-94.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V. (1993). Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In F.  Gori (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems: Vol. 399&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 69-94). Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Böhm, Volker. “Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models”. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Franco Gori. Berlin: Springer, 1993.Vol. 399. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems. 69-94.</mla>
<default>Böhm V (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991. Gori F (Ed);  Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems, 399.  Berlin: Springer:  69-94.</default>
<ieee> V. Böhm, “Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models”, &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;, F. Gori, ed., Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems, vol. 399,  Berlin: Springer, 1993,  pp.69-94.</ieee>
<harvard1>Böhm, V., 1993. Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In F.  Gori, ed. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems. no.399  Berlin: Springer, pp. 69-94.</harvard1>
<apa>Böhm, V. (1993). Recurrence in Keynesian macroeconomic models. In F.  Gori (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in economics and mathematical systems: Vol. 399&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Nonlinear dynamics in economics and social sciences: proceedings of the 2. Informal Workshop held at the Certosa di Pontignano, Siena, Italy, May 27 - 30, 1991&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 69-94). Berlin: Springer.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781578</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>