<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781501</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merlyn J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Behr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Post</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jacques C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bergeron</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nicolas</namePart><namePart type="family">Herscovic</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT2542.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781501/2313319/OCT2542.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1983</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-25422</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>vol. 2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">272-279</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Behr, Merlyn J., Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Post, Thomas R. “On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jacques C. Bergeron and Nicolas Herscovic. Montréal, 1983.Vol. vol. 2. 272-279.</mla>
<default>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I, Post TR (1983)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Bergeron JC, Herscovic N (Eds); , vol. 2.  Montréal:  272-279.</default>
<lncs> Behr, M.J., Wachsmuth, I., Post, T.R.: On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In: Bergeron, J.C. and Herscovic, N. (eds.) Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. vol. 2, p. 272-279. Montréal (1983).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, Merlyn J., Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Post, Thomas R. 1983. “On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jacques C. Bergeron and Nicolas Herscovic, vol. 2:272-279. Montréal.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Behr, M. J., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Post, T. R. (1983). On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In J. C.  Bergeron &amp;amp; N.  Herscovic (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. vol. 2, pp. 272-279). Montréal.</apa>
<ieee> M.J. Behr, I. Wachsmuth, and T.R. Post, “On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, J.C. Bergeron and N. Herscovic, eds., vol. vol. 2,  Montréal: 1983,  pp.272-279.</ieee>
<ama>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I, Post TR. On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In: Bergeron JC, Herscovic N, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Vol vol. 2. Montréal;  1983: 272-279.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, M.J., Wachsmuth, I. &amp;amp; Post, T.R. (1983). On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In J.C. Bergeron &amp;amp; N. Herscovic (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 272-279). Montréal.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Behr, M. J., Wachsmuth, I., and Post, T. R. (1983). “On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, Bergeron, J. C., and Herscovic, N. eds., vol. vol. 2, (Montréal), 272-279.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Behr, M.J., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Post, T.R., 1983. On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In J. C.  Bergeron &amp;amp; N.  Herscovic, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. no.vol. 2  Montréal, pp. 272-279.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Behr, M. J., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Post, T. R. (1983). On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In J. C.  Bergeron &amp;amp; N.  Herscovic (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. vol. 2, pp. 272-279). Montréal.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Behr MJ, Wachsmuth I, Post TR (1983) &lt;br /&gt;On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Bergeron JC, Herscovic N (Eds);vol. 2. Montréal:  272-279.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M. J.  Behr, I.  Wachsmuth, and T. R.  Post, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.C. Bergeron, N. Herscovic), Montréal, &lt;strong&gt;1983&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 272-279.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Behr, M. J.; Wachsmuth, I.; Post, T. R. (1983): On children's quantitative concept of rational number: construct and estimate the sum. In: Jacques C. Bergeron; Nicolas Herscovic (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the fifth annual meeting: Montréal Sept. 29 - Oct. 1, 1983 = actes de la cinquième rencontre annuelle / PME-NA, North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Montréal. (vol. 2).  S. 272-279.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781501</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-04-03T12:25:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>