<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781281</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Storrer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21923</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cruse_12.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781281/2313255/Cruse_12.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1977</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biological cybernetics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0340-1200</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-0770</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1977CV33700002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17812816</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF00365210</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>25</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">131-142</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Storrer, J.; Cruse, H. (1977): Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;,25:(3): 131-142.</wels>
<bio1>Storrer J, Cruse H (1977) &lt;br /&gt;Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles.&lt;br /&gt;Biological cybernetics 25(3): 131-142.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Storrer, J., &amp;amp; Cruse, H. (1977). Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 131-142. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00365210" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00365210&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Storrer, J., &amp;amp; Cruse, H., 1977. Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, 25(3), p 131-142.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Storrer, and H.  Cruse, “Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles”, &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1977&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;, 131-142.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Storrer J, Cruse H. Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;. 1977;25(3):131-142.</ama>
<lncs> Storrer, J., Cruse, H.: Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. Biological cybernetics. 25, 131-142 (1977).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Storrer, J., and Cruse, Holk. 1977. “Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles”. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt; 25 (3): 131-142.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Storrer, J., and Cruse, H. (1977). Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt; 25, 131-142.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Storrer, J. &amp;amp; Cruse, H. (1977). Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 131-142. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1007/BF00365210.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Storrer, J., and Cruse, Holk. “Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles”. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt; 25.3 (1977): 131-142.</mla>
<apa>Storrer, J., &amp;amp; Cruse, H. (1977). Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles. &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 131-142. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00365210" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00365210&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> J. Storrer and H. Cruse, “Systemanalytische Untersuchung eines aufgeschnittenen Regelkreises, der die Beinstellung der Stabheuschrecke Carausius morosus kontrolliert: Kraftmessungen an den Antagonisten Flexor und Extensor tibiae: Open Loop Analysis of a Feedback Mechanism Controllingthe Leg Position in the Stick Insect Carausius morosus: Measurements of the Forces Produced by the Flexor and Extensor Tibiae Muscles”, &lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 25, 1977,  pp. 131-142.</ieee>
<default>Storrer J, Cruse H (1977) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biological cybernetics&lt;/em&gt; 25(3): 131-142.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781281</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>