<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781908</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vlastimil</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dlab</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10583</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Vlastimil</namePart><namePart type="family">Dlab</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Gabriel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ringel_044.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781908/2313573/Ringel_044.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1980</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-10264-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17819087</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BFb0088465</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>832</number></detail><extent unit="pages">216-231</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Dlab, V., and Ringel, C. M. (1980). “The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph” in &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, Dlab, V., and Gabriel, P. eds. Lecture Notes in Mathematics, vol. 832, (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 216-231.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dlab, V., &amp;amp; Ringel, C. M. (1980). The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Mathematics: Vol. 832&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 216-231). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088465" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088465&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Dlab, Vlastimil, and Ringel, Claus Michael. “The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph”. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Vlastimil Dlab and Peter Gabriel. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 1980.Vol. 832. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. 216-231.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dlab, V. &amp;amp; Ringel, C.M. (1980). The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph (Lecture Notes in Mathematics). In V. Dlab &amp;amp; P. Gabriel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (S. 216-231). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/BFb0088465.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Dlab, V.; Ringel, C. M. (1980): The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In: Vlastimil Dlab; Peter Gabriel (Hrsg.):  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832).  S. 216-231.</wels>
<bio1>Dlab V, Ringel CM (1980) &lt;br /&gt;The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Dlab V, Gabriel P (Eds); Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  216-231.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Dlab, and C. M.  Ringel, in &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: V. Dlab, P. Gabriel), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;1980&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 216-231.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Dlab V, Ringel CM (1980)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Dlab V, Gabriel P (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  216-231.</default>
<ama>Dlab V, Ringel CM. The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In: Dlab V, Gabriel P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. Vol 832. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  1980: 216-231.</ama>
<ieee> V. Dlab and C.M. Ringel, “The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph”, &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, V. Dlab and P. Gabriel, eds., Lecture Notes in Mathematics, vol. 832,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 1980,  pp.216-231.</ieee>
<harvard1>Dlab, V., &amp;amp; Ringel, C.M., 1980. The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. no.832  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 216-231.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dlab, Vlastimil, and Ringel, Claus Michael. 1980. “The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph”. In &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Vlastimil Dlab and Peter Gabriel, 832:216-231. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dlab, V., Ringel, C.M.: The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In: Dlab, V. and Gabriel, P. (eds.) Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. 832, p. 216-231. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (1980).</lncs>
<apa>Dlab, V., &amp;amp; Ringel, C. M. (1980). The preprojective algebra of a modulated graph. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Mathematics: Vol. 832&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 216-231). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088465" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088465&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781908</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-26T09:18:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>