<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781904</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dowbor</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10583</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Simson</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Vlastimil</namePart><namePart type="family">Dlab</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Gabriel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ringel_045.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781904/2313572/Ringel_045.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1980</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-10264-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17819044</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BFb0088466</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>832</number></detail><extent unit="pages">232-241</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Dowbor P, Ringel CM, Simson D (1980)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Dlab V, Gabriel P (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832.  Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer:  232-241.</default>
<bio1>Dowbor P, Ringel CM, Simson D (1980) &lt;br /&gt;Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Dlab V, Gabriel P (Eds); Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer:  232-241.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Dowbor, C. M.  Ringel, and D.  Simson, in &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: V. Dlab, P. Gabriel), Springer, Heidelberg, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1980&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 232-241.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Dowbor, P.; Ringel, C. M.; Simson, D. (1980): Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In: Vlastimil Dlab; Peter Gabriel (Hrsg.):  Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Mathematics, 832).  S. 232-241.</wels>
<frontiers>Dowbor, P., Ringel, C. M., and Simson, D. (1980). “Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type” in &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, Dlab, V., and Gabriel, P. eds. Lecture Notes in Mathematics, vol. 832, (Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer), 232-241.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dowbor, P., Ringel, C. M., &amp;amp; Simson, D. (1980). Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Mathematics: Vol. 832&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 232-241). Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088466" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088466&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Dowbor, P., Ringel, Claus Michael, and Simson, Daniel. “Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type”. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Vlastimil Dlab and Peter Gabriel. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer, 1980.Vol. 832. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. 232-241.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dowbor, P., Ringel, C.M. &amp;amp; Simson, D. (1980). Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type (Lecture Notes in Mathematics). In V. Dlab &amp;amp; P. Gabriel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (S. 232-241). Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/BFb0088466.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Dowbor, P., Ringel, C. M., &amp;amp; Simson, D. (1980). Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Mathematics: Vol. 832&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 232-241). Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088466" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BFb0088466&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dowbor, P., Ringel, Claus Michael, and Simson, Daniel. 1980. “Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type”. In &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Vlastimil Dlab and Peter Gabriel, 832:232-241. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dowbor, P., Ringel, C.M., Simson, D.: Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In: Dlab, V. and Gabriel, P. (eds.) Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. 832, p. 232-241. Springer, Heidelberg, Berlin (1980).</lncs>
<ieee> P. Dowbor, C.M. Ringel, and D. Simson, “Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type”, &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;, V. Dlab and P. Gabriel, eds., Lecture Notes in Mathematics, vol. 832,  Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer, 1980,  pp.232-241.</ieee>
<harvard1>Dowbor, P., Ringel, C.M., &amp;amp; Simson, D., 1980. Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In V.  Dlab &amp;amp; P.  Gabriel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. no.832  Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer, pp. 232-241.</harvard1>
<ama>Dowbor P, Ringel CM, Simson D. Hereditary artinian rings of finite representation type. In: Dlab V, Gabriel P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation Theory II. Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Representations of Algebras, Ottawa, Carleton University, August 13-25, 1979: No. 2&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Mathematics. Vol 832. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer;  1980: 232-241.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781904</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-26T09:30:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>