<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781196</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Radosvet</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Todorov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winterhager</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76938</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0331-2539</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Weingart</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Roswitha</namePart><namePart type="family">Sehringer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart><namePart type="family">Winterhager</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656064</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">16315353</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Winterhager_007.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781196/2313217/Winterhager_007.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1992</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">90-6695-060-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-24109</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">277-293</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Todorov, Radosvet, and Winterhager, Matthias. 1992. “Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Peter Weingart, Roswitha Sehringer, and Matthias Winterhager, 277-293. Science studies. Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Todorov, R., Winterhager, M.: Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In: Weingart, P., Sehringer, R., and Winterhager, M. (eds.) Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990. Science studies. p. 277-293. DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ., Leiden (1992).</lncs>
<default>Todorov R, Winterhager M (1992)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990. Weingart P, Sehringer R, Winterhager M (Eds);  Science studies.  Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.:  277-293.</default>
<mla>Todorov, Radosvet, and Winterhager, Matthias. “Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Peter Weingart, Roswitha Sehringer, and Matthias Winterhager. Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ., 1992. Science studies. 277-293.</mla>
<frontiers>Todorov, R., and Winterhager, M. (1992). “Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis” in &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;, Weingart, P., Sehringer, R., and Winterhager, M. eds. Science studies (Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.), 277-293.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Todorov, R. &amp;amp; Winterhager, M. (1992). Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis (Science studies). In P. Weingart, R. Sehringer &amp;amp; M. Winterhager (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt; (S. 277-293). Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Todorov R, Winterhager M. Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In: Weingart P, Sehringer R, Winterhager M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;. Science studies. Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.;  1992: 277-293.</ama>
<ieee> R. Todorov and M. Winterhager, “Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;, P. Weingart, R. Sehringer, and M. Winterhager, eds., Science studies,  Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ., 1992,  pp.277-293.</ieee>
<apa>Todorov, R., &amp;amp; Winterhager, M. (1992). Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In P.  Weingart, R.  Sehringer, &amp;amp; M.  Winterhager (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Science studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-293). Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.</apa>
<wels>Todorov, R.; Winterhager, M. (1992): Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In: Peter Weingart; Roswitha Sehringer; Matthias Winterhager (Hrsg.):  Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990. Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ. (Science studies, ).  S. 277-293.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Todorov, and M.  Winterhager, in &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Weingart, R. Sehringer, M. Winterhager), Dswo Pr., Leiden Univ., Leiden, &lt;strong&gt;1992&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 277-293.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Todorov, R., &amp;amp; Winterhager, M., 1992. Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In P.  Weingart, R.  Sehringer, &amp;amp; M.  Winterhager, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt;. Science studies.  Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ., pp. 277-293.</harvard1>
<bio1>Todorov R, Winterhager M (1992) &lt;br /&gt;Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990. Weingart P, Sehringer R, Winterhager M (Eds); Science studies,  Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.:  277-293.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Todorov, R., &amp;amp; Winterhager, M. (1992). Describing photoelectric conversion by co-word analysis. In P.  Weingart, R.  Sehringer, &amp;amp; M.  Winterhager (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Science studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representations of science and technology: proceedings of the International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators, Bielefeld, Federal Republic of Germany, 10 - 12 Juni 1990&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-293). Leiden: DSWO Pr., Leiden Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781196</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>