<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781730</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13197</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart><namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10056</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT2717.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781730/2313466/OCT2717.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1986</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-923340-10-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-27171</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">31-58</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Birg, in &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: H. Birg), Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. Für Bevölkerungsforschung U. Sozialpolitik, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1986&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 31-58.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Birg H (1986) &lt;br /&gt;Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse. Birg H (Ed); IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21,  Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik:  31-58.</bio1>
<default>Birg H (1986)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse. Birg H (Ed);  IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21.  Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik:  31-58.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1986). Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany (IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21). In H. Birg (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt; (S. 31-58). Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Birg, Herwig. “Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Herwig Birg. Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik, 1986. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21. 31-58.</mla>
<frontiers>Birg, H. (1986). “Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany” in &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;, Birg, H. ed. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21 (Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik), 31-58.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1986). Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In H.  Birg (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-58). Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Birg, H. (1986): Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Herwig Birg (Hrsg.):  Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse. Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik. (IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21, ).  S. 31-58.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, Herwig. 1986. “Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”. In &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Herwig Birg, 31-58. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21. Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Birg, H.: Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Birg, H. (ed.) Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21. p. 31-58. Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik, Bielefeld (1986).</lncs>
<apa>Birg, H. (1986). Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In H.  Birg (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-58). Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik.</apa>
<ama>Birg H. Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Birg H, ed. &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21. Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik;  1986: 31-58.</ama>
<harvard1>Birg, H., 1986. Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In H.  Birg, ed. &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;. IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21.  Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik, pp. 31-58.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Birg, “Empirical analysis and the theoretical implications of spatial concentration and dispersion trends in the population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Regionale Demographie und regionalwissenschaftliche Analyse&lt;/em&gt;, H. Birg, ed., IBS-Materialien / Institut für Bevölkerungsforschung und Sozialpolitik (Bielefeld) ; 21,  Bielefeld: Univ. Bielefeld, Inst. für Bevölkerungsforschung u. Sozialpolitik, 1986,  pp.31-58.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781730</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>