<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1781643</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dieter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Timmermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">156157</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Henry M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Levin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hans G.</namePart><namePart type="family">Schuetze</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">7978238</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT2620.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1781643/2313387/OCT2620.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Sage</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1983</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8039-2068-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-26200</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">99-129</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Timmermann, Dieter. “Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education”. &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Henry M. Levin and Hans G. Schuetze. London: Sage, 1983. 99-129.</mla>
<default>Timmermann D (1983)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity. Levin HM, Schuetze HG (Eds);  London: Sage:  99-129.</default>
<lncs> Timmermann, D.: Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In: Levin, H.M. and Schuetze, H.G. (eds.) Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity. p. 99-129. Sage, London (1983).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Timmermann, Dieter. 1983. “Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education”. In &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Henry M. Levin and Hans G. Schuetze, 99-129. London: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Timmermann, D. (1983). Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In H. M.  Levin &amp;amp; H. G.  Schuetze (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 99-129). London: Sage.</apa>
<ieee> D. Timmermann, “Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education”, &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;, H.M. Levin and H.G. Schuetze, eds.,  London: Sage, 1983,  pp.99-129.</ieee>
<ama>Timmermann D. Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In: Levin HM, Schuetze HG, eds. &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;. London: Sage;  1983: 99-129.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Timmermann, D. (1983). Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In H.M. Levin &amp;amp; H.G. Schuetze (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt; (S. 99-129). London: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Timmermann, D. (1983). “Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education” in &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;, Levin, H. M., and Schuetze, H. G. eds. (London: Sage), 99-129.</frontiers>
<bio1>Timmermann D (1983) &lt;br /&gt;Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity. Levin HM, Schuetze HG (Eds); London: Sage:  99-129.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Timmermann, D. (1983). Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In H. M.  Levin &amp;amp; H. G.  Schuetze (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 99-129). London: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Timmermann, D., 1983. Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In H. M.  Levin &amp;amp; H. G.  Schuetze, eds. &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt;.  London: Sage, pp. 99-129.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Timmermann, in &lt;em&gt;Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H.M. Levin, H.G. Schuetze), Sage, London, &lt;strong&gt;1983&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 99-129.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Timmermann, D. (1983): Financing mechanisms: their impact on postcompulsory education. In: Henry M. Levin; Hans G. Schuetze (Hrsg.):  Financing recurrent education: strategies for increasing employment, job opportunities, and productivity. London: Sage.  S. 99-129.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1781643</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>