<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782807</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3633-4785</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Leslie J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Francis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mandy</namePart><namePart type="family">Robbins</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jeff</namePart><namePart type="family">Astley</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Research_on_Lifestyle.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782807/2314004/Research_on_Lifestyle.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Streib_2005_Research_lifestyle_spirituality_religious_orientation_adolescents_germany-in-Religion_education_and_adolescence.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782807/2212851/Streib_2005_Research_lifestyle_spirituality_religious_orientation_adolescents_germany-in-Religion_education_and_adolescence.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Wales Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>spirituality</topic><topic>Life style</topic><topic>religion</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-7083-1957-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-33363</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">131-163</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Streib H. Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In: Francis LJ, Robbins M, Astley J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Religion, education and culture. Cardiff: University of Wales Press;  2005: 131-163.</ama>
<ieee> H. Streib, “Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, L.J. Francis, M. Robbins, and J. Astley, eds., Religion, education and culture,  Cardiff: University of Wales Press, 2005,  pp.131-163.</ieee>
<harvard1>Streib, H., 2005. Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In L. J.  Francis, M.  Robbins, &amp;amp; J.  Astley, eds. &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Religion, education and culture.  Cardiff: University of Wales Press, pp. 131-163.</harvard1>
<lncs> Streib, H.: Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In: Francis, L.J., Robbins, M., and Astley, J. (eds.) Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives. Religion, education and culture. p. 131-163. University of Wales Press, Cardiff (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, Heinz. 2005. “Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany”. In &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Leslie J. Francis, Mandy Robbins, and Jeff Astley, 131-163. Religion, education and culture. Cardiff: University of Wales Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Streib, H. (2005). Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In L. J.  Francis, M.  Robbins, &amp;amp; J.  Astley (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and culture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 131-163). Cardiff: University of Wales Press.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2005). Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In L. J.  Francis, M.  Robbins, &amp;amp; J.  Astley (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and culture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 131-163). Cardiff: University of Wales Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Streib, H. (2005). “Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany” in &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Francis, L. J., Robbins, M., and Astley, J. eds. Religion, education and culture (Cardiff: University of Wales Press), 131-163.</frontiers>
<mla>Streib, Heinz. “Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Leslie J. Francis, Mandy Robbins, and Jeff Astley. Cardiff: University of Wales Press, 2005. Religion, education and culture. 131-163.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2005). Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany (Religion, education and culture). In L.J. Francis, M. Robbins &amp;amp; J. Astley (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (S. 131-163). Cardiff: University of Wales Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Streib, H. (2005): Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. In: Leslie J. Francis; Mandy Robbins; Jeff Astley (Hrsg.):  Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives. Cardiff: University of Wales Press. (Religion, education and culture, ).  S. 131-163.</wels>
<bio1>Streib H (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Research on life style, spirituality and religious orientation of adolescents in Germany. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives. Francis LJ, Robbins M, Astley J (Eds); Religion, education and culture,  Cardiff: University of Wales Press:  131-163.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Streib, in &lt;em&gt;Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: L.J. Francis, M. Robbins, J. Astley), University Of Wales Press, Cardiff, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 131-163.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Streib H (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Religion, education and adolescence: international empirical perspectives. Francis LJ, Robbins M, Astley J (Eds);  Religion, education and culture.  Cardiff: University of Wales Press:  131-163.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782807</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-12T12:10:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>