<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782126</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10583</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gerhard O.</namePart><namePart type="family">Michler</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Claus Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ringel_085.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782126/2313673/Ringel_085.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Birkhäuser</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-7643-2604-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-29749</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>95</number></detail><extent unit="pages">141-192</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Ringel, C. M. (1991). Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In G. O.  Michler &amp;amp; C. M.  Ringel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Progress in mathematics: Vol. 95&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 141-192). Basel: Birkhäuser. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, Claus Michael. 1991. “Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras”. In &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Gerhard O. Michler and Claus Michael Ringel, 95:141-192. Progress in mathematics. Basel: Birkhäuser.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ringel, C.M.: Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In: Michler, G.O. and Ringel, C.M. (eds.) Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory. Progress in mathematics. 95, p. 141-192. Birkhäuser, Basel (1991).</lncs>
<ieee> C.M. Ringel, “Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras”, &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;, G.O. Michler and C.M. Ringel, eds., Progress in mathematics, vol. 95,  Basel: Birkhäuser, 1991,  pp.141-192.</ieee>
<harvard1>Ringel, C.M., 1991. Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In G. O.  Michler &amp;amp; C. M.  Ringel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;. Progress in mathematics. no.95  Basel: Birkhäuser, pp. 141-192.</harvard1>
<ama>Ringel CM. Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In: Michler GO, Ringel CM, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;. Progress in mathematics. Vol 95. Basel: Birkhäuser;  1991: 141-192.</ama>
<default>Ringel CM (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory. Michler GO, Ringel CM (Eds);  Progress in mathematics, 95.  Basel: Birkhäuser:  141-192.</default>
<bio1>Ringel CM (1991) &lt;br /&gt;Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory. Michler GO, Ringel CM (Eds); Progress in mathematics, 95. Basel: Birkhäuser:  141-192.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C. M.  Ringel, in &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G.O. Michler, C.M. Ringel), Birkhäuser, Basel, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 141-192.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Ringel, C. M. (1991): Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In: Gerhard O. Michler; Claus Michael Ringel (Hrsg.):  Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory. Basel: Birkhäuser. (Progress in mathematics, 95).  S. 141-192.</wels>
<frontiers>Ringel, C. M. (1991). “Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras” in &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;, Michler, G. O., and Ringel, C. M. eds. Progress in mathematics, vol. 95, (Basel: Birkhäuser), 141-192.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, C. M. (1991). Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras. In G. O.  Michler &amp;amp; C. M.  Ringel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Progress in mathematics: Vol. 95&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 141-192). Basel: Birkhäuser. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Ringel, Claus Michael. “Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras”. &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Gerhard O. Michler and Claus Michael Ringel. Basel: Birkhäuser, 1991.Vol. 95. Progress in mathematics. 141-192.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ringel, C.M. (1991). Recent advances in the representation theory of finite dimensional algebras (Progress in mathematics). In G.O. Michler &amp;amp; C.M. Ringel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Representation theory of finite groups and finite-dimensional algebras: proceedings of the conference at the University of Bielefeld from May 15-17, 1991, and 7 survey articles on topics of representation theory&lt;/em&gt; (S. 141-192). Basel: Birkhäuser. doi:10.1007/978-3-0348-8658-1_6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782126</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-06-17T12:55:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>