<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782820</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3633-4785</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart><namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Astrid</namePart><namePart type="family">Dinter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kerstin</namePart><namePart type="family">Söderblom</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Streib2008_More_Spiritual.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782820/2314010/Streib2008_More_Spiritual.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Brill</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-90-04-16377-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-33455</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">53-67</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2008). More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In H. Streib, A. Dinter &amp;amp; K. Söderblom (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt; (S. 53-67). Leiden [u.a.]: Brill. doi:10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Streib, H. (2008). “More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches” in &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;, Streib, H., Dinter, A., and Söderblom, K. eds. (Leiden [u.a.]: Brill), 53-67.</frontiers>
<mla>Streib, Heinz. “More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches”. &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Heinz Streib, Astrid Dinter, and Kerstin Söderblom. Leiden [u.a.]: Brill, 2008. 53-67.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2008). More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In H.  Streib, A.  Dinter, &amp;amp; K.  Söderblom (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 53-67). Leiden [u.a.]: Brill. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Streib, H. (2008): More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In: Heinz Streib; Astrid Dinter; Kerstin Söderblom (Hrsg.):  Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock. Leiden [u.a.]: Brill.  S. 53-67.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Streib, in &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Streib, A. Dinter, K. Söderblom), Brill, Leiden [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 53-67.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Streib H (2008) &lt;br /&gt;More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock. Streib H, Dinter A, Söderblom K (Eds); Leiden [u.a.]: Brill:  53-67.</bio1>
<default>Streib H (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock. Streib H, Dinter A, Söderblom K (Eds);  Leiden [u.a.]: Brill:  53-67.</default>
<ama>Streib H. More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In: Streib H, Dinter A, Söderblom K, eds. &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;. Leiden [u.a.]: Brill;  2008: 53-67.</ama>
<harvard1>Streib, H., 2008. More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In H.  Streib, A.  Dinter, &amp;amp; K.  Söderblom, eds. &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;.  Leiden [u.a.]: Brill, pp. 53-67.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Streib, “More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches”, &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;, H. Streib, A. Dinter, and K. Söderblom, eds.,  Leiden [u.a.]: Brill, 2008,  pp.53-67.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, Heinz. 2008. “More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches”. In &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Heinz Streib, Astrid Dinter, and Kerstin Söderblom, 53-67. Leiden [u.a.]: Brill.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Streib, H.: More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In: Streib, H., Dinter, A., and Söderblom, K. (eds.) Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock. p. 53-67. Brill, Leiden [u.a.] (2008).</lncs>
<apa>Streib, H. (2008). More spiritual than religious: changes in the religious field require new approaches. In H.  Streib, A.  Dinter, &amp;amp; K.  Söderblom (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lived religion: conceptual, empirical and practical-theological approaches ; essays in honor of Hans-Günter Heimbrock&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 53-67). Leiden [u.a.]: Brill. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/ej.9789004163775.i-404.30&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782820</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-05T11:44:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>