<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782348</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heino</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Büntemeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10725</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bertold G. D.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bödeker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lehmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Raymond</namePart><namePart type="family">Spier</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3116.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782348/2313808/OCT3116.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Butterworth</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1987</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-408-02732-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-31160</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><extent unit="pages">411-419</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Büntemeyer H, Bödeker BGD, Lehmann J (1987)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference. Spier R, ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Eds);  The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology, 8.  London: Butterworth:  411-419.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B. G. D., &amp;amp; Lehmann, J. (1987). Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In R.  Spier &amp;amp; ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology: Vol. 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 411-419). London: Butterworth.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Büntemeyer, Heino, Bödeker, Bertold G. D., and Lehmann, Jürgen. “Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion”. &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Raymond Spier and ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona). London: Butterworth, 1987.Vol. 8. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology. 411-419.</mla>
<frontiers>Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B. G. D., and Lehmann, J. (1987). “Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion” in &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;, Spier, R., and ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) eds. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology, vol. 8, (London: Butterworth), 411-419.</frontiers>
<wels>Büntemeyer, H.; Bödeker, B. G. D.; Lehmann, J. (1987): Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In: Raymond Spier; ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Hrsg.):  Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference. London: Butterworth. (The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology, 8).  S. 411-419.</wels>
<apa>Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B. G. D., &amp;amp; Lehmann, J. (1987). Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In R.  Spier &amp;amp; ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology: Vol. 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 411-419). London: Butterworth.</apa>
<ieee> H. Büntemeyer, B.G.D. Bödeker, and J. Lehmann, “Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion”, &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;, R. Spier and ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona), eds., The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology, vol. 8,  London: Butterworth, 1987,  pp.411-419.</ieee>
<harvard1>Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B.G.D., &amp;amp; Lehmann, J., 1987. Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In R.  Spier &amp;amp; ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona), eds. &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology. no.8  London: Butterworth, pp. 411-419.</harvard1>
<bio1>Büntemeyer H, Bödeker BGD, Lehmann J (1987) &lt;br /&gt;Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference. Spier R, ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Eds); The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology, 8. London: Butterworth:  411-419.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Büntemeyer, B. G. D.  Bödeker, and J.  Lehmann, in &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Spier, ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona), Butterworth, London, &lt;strong&gt;1987&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 411-419.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B.G.D. &amp;amp; Lehmann, J. (1987). Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion (The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology). In R. Spier &amp;amp; ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt; (S. 411-419). London: Butterworth.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Büntemeyer, Heino, Bödeker, Bertold G. D., and Lehmann, Jürgen. 1987. “Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion”. In &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Raymond Spier and ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona), 8:411-419. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology. London: Butterworth.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Büntemeyer, H., Bödeker, B.G.D., Lehmann, J.: Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In: Spier, R. and ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona) (eds.) Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology. 8, p. 411-419. Butterworth, London (1987).</lncs>
<ama>Büntemeyer H, Bödeker BGD, Lehmann J. Membranes-stirrer-reactor for bubble free aeration and perfusion. In: Spier R, ham- Māḵôn le-Meḥqār Biyyôlôgî be-Yiśrā'ēl (Nes Ziyyona), eds. &lt;em&gt;Modern approaches to animal cell technology: European Society for Animal Cell Technology, the 8. Meeting ; OHOLO Biological Conference, Israel Institute for Biological Research, the 32. Conference&lt;/em&gt;. The .. meeting / European Society of Animal Cell Technology. Vol 8. London: Butterworth;  1987: 411-419.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782348</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>