<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782996</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13197</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Friedrich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10056</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3425.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782996/2314085/OCT3425.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Nomos Verl.Ges.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1987</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International perspectives of regional decentralisation</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-7890-1357-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-34258</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">61-85</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Birg, H.: Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Friedrich, P. (ed.) International perspectives of regional decentralisation. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87. p. 61-85. Nomos Verl.Ges., Baden-Baden (1987).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, Herwig. 1987. “Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”. In &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Peter Friedrich, 61-85. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Birg H. Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Friedrich P, ed. &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.;  1987: 61-85.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Birg, in &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: P. Friedrich), Nomos Verl.ges., Baden-Baden, &lt;strong&gt;1987&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 61-85.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Birg H (1987) &lt;br /&gt;Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International perspectives of regional decentralisation. Friedrich P (Ed); Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87,  Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.:  61-85.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1987). Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany (Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87). In P. Friedrich (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt; (S. 61-85). Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Birg, H. (1987). Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In P.  Friedrich (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 61-85). Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.</apa>
<harvard1>Birg, H., 1987. Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In P.  Friedrich, ed. &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87.  Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges., pp. 61-85.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Birg, “Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”, &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;, P. Friedrich, ed., Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87,  Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges., 1987,  pp.61-85.</ieee>
<default>Birg H (1987)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International perspectives of regional decentralisation. Friedrich P (Ed);  Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87.  Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.:  61-85.</default>
<mla>Birg, Herwig. “Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany”. &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Peter Friedrich. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges., 1987. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87. 61-85.</mla>
<frontiers>Birg, H. (1987). “Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany” in &lt;em&gt;International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt;, Friedrich, P. ed. Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87 (Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.), 61-85.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1987). Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In P.  Friedrich (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. International perspectives of regional decentralisation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 61-85). Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Birg, H. (1987): Spatial concentration and dispersion trends in population distribution in the Federal Republic of Germany. In: Peter Friedrich (Hrsg.):  International perspectives of regional decentralisation. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verl.Ges. (Schriften zur öffentlichen Verwaltung und öffentlichen Wirtschaft ; 87, ).  S. 61-85.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782996</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>