<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782942</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Walter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bertil</namePart><namePart type="family">Svensson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3407.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782942/2314069/OCT3407.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">91-630-1847-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-34076</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">121-122</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Walter, J., Ritter, H.: Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In: Svensson, B. (ed.) Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action. p. 121-122. Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ., Halmstad (1993).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, Jörg, and Ritter, Helge. 1993. “Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks”. In &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Bertil Svensson, 121-122. Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Walter J, Ritter H. Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In: Svensson B, ed. &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;. Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.;  1993: 121-122.</ama>
<bio1>Walter J, Ritter H (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action. Svensson B (Ed); Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.:  121-122.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Walter, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: B. Svensson), Centre For Computer Architecture, Univ., Halmstad, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 121-122.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, J. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1993). Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In B. Svensson (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (S. 121-122). Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Walter, J., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1993). Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In B.  Svensson (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 121-122). Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.</apa>
<ieee> J. Walter and H. Ritter, “Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks”, &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, B. Svensson, ed.,  Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ., 1993,  pp.121-122.</ieee>
<harvard1>Walter, J., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 1993. Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In B.  Svensson, ed. &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;.  Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ., pp. 121-122.</harvard1>
<default>Walter J, Ritter H (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action. Svensson B (Ed);  Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.:  121-122.</default>
<wels>Walter, J.; Ritter, H. (1993): Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In: Bertil Svensson (Hrsg.):  Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action. Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.  S. 121-122.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, J., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1993). Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks. In B.  Svensson (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 121-122). Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Walter, Jörg, and Ritter, Helge. “Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks”. &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Bertil Svensson. Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ., 1993. 121-122.</mla>
<frontiers>Walter, J., and Ritter, H. (1993). “Experimental platform for visuo-motor control of a robot hand using neural networks” in &lt;em&gt;Preprints of the International Workshop on Mechatronical Computer Systems for Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, Svensson, B. ed. (Halmstad: Centre for Computer Architecture, Univ.), 121-122.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782942</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>