<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782938</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert U.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ayres</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Walter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The buildup of so-called "greenhouse gases" in the atmosphere — CO 2 in particular-appears to be having an adverse impact on the global climate. This paper briefly reviews current expectations with regard to physical and biological effects, their potential costs to society, and likely costs of abatement. For a "worst case" scenario it is impossible to assess, in economic terms, the full range of possible non-linear synergistic effects. In the "most favorable" (although not necessarily "likely") case (of slow-paced climate change), however, it seems likely that the impacts are within the "affordable" range, at least in the industrialized countries of the world. In the "third world" the notion of affordability is of doubtful relevance, making the problem of quantitative evaluation almost impossible. We tentatively assess the lower limit of quantifiable climate-induced damages at $30 to $35 per ton of "CO 2 equivalent", worldwide, with the major damages being concentrated in regions most adversely affected by sea-level rise. The non-quantifiable environmental damages are also significant and should by no means be disregarded. The costs and benefits of (1) reducing CFC use and (2) reducing fossil fuel consumption, as a means of abatement, are considered in some detail. This strategy has remarkably high indirect benefits in terms of reduced air pollution damage and even direct cost savings to consumers. The indirect benefits of reduced air pollution and its associated health and environmental effects from fossil-fuel combustion in the industrialized countries range from $20 to $60 per ton of CO 2 eliminated. In addition, there is good evidence that modest (e.g. 25%) reductions in CO 2 emissions may be achievable by the U.S. (and, by implication, for other countries) by a combination of increased energy efficiency and restructuring that would permit simultaneous direct economic benefits (savings) to energy consumers of the order of $50 per ton of CO 2 saved. A higher level of overall emissions reduction — possibly approaching 50% — could probably be achieved, at little or not net cost, by taking advantage of these savings. We suggest the use of taxes on fossil fuel extraction (or a carbon tax) as a reasonable way of inducing the structural changes that would be required to achieve significant reduction in energy use and CO2 emissions. To minimize the economic burden (and create a political constituency in support of the approach) we suggest the substitution of resource-based taxes in general for other types of taxes (on labor, income, real estate, or trade) that are now the main sources of government revenue. While it is conceded that it would be difficult to calculate the "optimal" tax on extractive resources, we do not think this is a necessary prerequisite to policy-making. In fact, we note that the existing tax system has never been optimized according to theoretical principles, and is far from optimal by any reasonable criteria.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="walter_02.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782938/2314068/walter_02.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>conservation</topic><topic>climate</topic><topic>carbon</topic><topic>Atmosphere</topic><topic>benefits</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Environmental and Resource Economics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0924-6460</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1573-1502</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17829386</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF00367920</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">237-270</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ayres, Robert U., and Walter, Jörg A. 1991. “The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement”. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt; 1 (3): 237-270.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ayres, R.U., Walter, J.A.: The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. Environmental and Resource Economics. 1, 237-270 (1991).</lncs>
<default>Ayres RU, Walter JA (1991) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt; 1(3): 237-270.</default>
<mla>Ayres, Robert U., and Walter, Jörg A. “The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement”. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt; 1.3 (1991): 237-270.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ayres, R.U. &amp;amp; Walter, J.A. (1991). The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(3), 237-270. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1007/BF00367920.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Ayres, R. U., and Walter, J. A. (1991). The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt; 1, 237-270.</frontiers>
<ama>Ayres RU, Walter JA. The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;. 1991;1(3):237-270.</ama>
<ieee> R.U. Ayres and J.A. Walter, “The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement”, &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 1, 1991,  pp. 237-270.</ieee>
<apa>Ayres, R. U., &amp;amp; Walter, J. A. (1991). The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(3), 237-270. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00367920" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00367920&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Ayres, R. U.; Walter, J. A. (1991): The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;,1:(3): 237-270.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>R. U.  Ayres, and J. A.  Walter, “The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement”, &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, 237-270.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Ayres, R.U., &amp;amp; Walter, J.A., 1991. The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 1(3), p 237-270.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ayres RU, Walter JA (1991) &lt;br /&gt;The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement.&lt;br /&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics 1(3): 237-270.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ayres, R. U., &amp;amp; Walter, J. A. (1991). The greenhouse effect: damages, costs and abatement. &lt;em&gt;Environmental and Resource Economics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(3), 237-270. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00367920" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00367920&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782938</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>