<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782175</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friedhelm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Waldhausen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10607</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">James Cecil</namePart><namePart type="family">Cantrell</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">C. Henry</namePart><namePart type="family">Edwards</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Waldhausen_017.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782175/2313705/Waldhausen_017.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Markham Publ. Co.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1971</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8410-1018-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-30085</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">205-211</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Waldhausen, Friedhelm. “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. James Cecil Cantrell and C. Henry Edwards. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., 1971. Markham mathematics series. 205-211.</mla>
<default>Waldhausen F (1971)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Cantrell JC, Edwards CH (Eds);  Markham mathematics series 2. print.  Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.:  205-211.</default>
<lncs> Waldhausen, F.: On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: Cantrell, J.C. and Edwards, C.H. (eds.) Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Markham mathematics series. 2. print. p. 205-211. Markham Publ. Co., Chicago (1971).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, Friedhelm. 1971. “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”. In &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, ed. James Cecil Cantrell and C. Henry Edwards, 2. print., 205-211. Markham mathematics series. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Waldhausen F (1971) &lt;br /&gt;On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Cantrell JC, Edwards CH (Eds); Markham mathematics series,  2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.:  205-211.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.  Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Markham mathematics series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., pp. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Waldhausen, F., 1971. On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.  Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Markham mathematics series. 2. print.  Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., pp. 205-211.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Waldhausen, in &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.C. Cantrell, C.H. Edwards), Markham Publ. Co., Chicago, &lt;strong&gt;1971&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 205-211.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Waldhausen, F. (1971): On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: James Cecil Cantrell; C. Henry Edwards (Hrsg.):  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co. (Markham mathematics series, ).  S. 205-211.</wels>
<apa>Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.  Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Markham mathematics series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., pp. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.</apa>
<ieee> F. Waldhausen, “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”, &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, J.C. Cantrell and C.H. Edwards, eds., Markham mathematics series, 2. print.,  Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., 1971,  pp.205-211.</ieee>
<ama>Waldhausen F. On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: Cantrell JC, Edwards CH, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Markham mathematics series. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.;  1971: 205-211.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings (Markham mathematics series). In J.C. Cantrell &amp;amp; C.H. Edwards (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., S. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Waldhausen, F. (1971). “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings” in &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, Cantrell, J. C., and Edwards, C. H. eds. Markham mathematics series 2. print. (Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.), 205-211.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782175</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>