<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1782584</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3633-4785</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Streib1999Enquete_Final_Report.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782584/2313901/Streib1999Enquete_Final_Report.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-32209</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">402-414</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Streib, Heinz. “Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'”. &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bonn, 1999. 402-414.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (1999). Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, 402-414. Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Streib, H. (1999). “Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'” in &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt; (Bonn), 402-414.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (1999). Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt; (S. 402-414). Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Streib, H. (1999): Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. In: Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany. Bonn.  S. 402-414.</wels>
<bio1>Streib H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany.  Bonn:  402-414.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Streib, in &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Bonn, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 402-414.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Streib H (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany. Bonn:  402-414.</default>
<ama>Streib H. Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. In:  &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bonn;  1999: 402-414.</ama>
<ieee> H. Streib, “Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'”, &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;,  Bonn: 1999,  pp.402-414.</ieee>
<harvard1>Streib, H., 1999. Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. In &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;.  Bonn, pp. 402-414.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, Heinz. 1999. “Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'”. In &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, 402-414. Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Streib, H.: Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany. p. 402-414. Bonn (1999).</lncs>
<apa>Streib, H. (1999). Sub-Projekt on 'Biographies in Christian Fundamentalist Milieus and Organizations'. &lt;em&gt;Final Report of Enquete Commission on So- called Sects and Psychogroups. New Religious and Ideological Communities and Psychogroups in the Federal Republik of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, 402-414. Bonn.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782584</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-11T18:30:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>