<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1783856</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kurt</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heyns</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">K. R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sperling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Friedrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grützmacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41603</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Some partially methylated methyl glucosides were investigated by the gas chromatography-mass spectrometry method. The main properties of their mass spectra can be derived from the fragmentation scheme of permethylated pyranoses by a consideration of the effects of the different substituents. Apart from a shift of the ion masses, due to replacement of methoxyl by hydroxyl groups, the main effect of the substituent is a variation of the inductive stabilisation of the positive charge of the fragments. Furthermore, the derivatives having methoxyl groups at the 1,2,3-, 1,2,3,6-, 1,3,4-, or 1,3,4,6-positions produce a very characteristic peak at m/e 161. The stereochemistry of the partially methylated methyl glucosides has no significant effect on their mass spectra, but the effect of the position of the substituent is important. The type of substitution can thence be deduced from the mass spectra.  The gas chromatography-mass spectrometry method is much more appropriate for the identification of a mixture of monosaccharides obtained from a permethylated polysaccharide by solvolysis than the gas-chromatographic method alone.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="gr_134.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1783856/2314279/gr_134.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1969</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Carbohydrate Research</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0008-6215</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1969C482400010</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17838561</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">79-97</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Heyns K, Sperling KR, Grützmacher H-F (1969) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt; 9(1): 79-97.</default>
<mla>Heyns, Kurt, Sperling, K. R., and Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich. “Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden”. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt; 9.1 (1969): 79-97.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heyns, Kurt, Sperling, K. R., and Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich. 1969. “Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden”. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt; 9 (1): 79-97.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Heyns, K., Sperling, K.R., Grützmacher, H.-F.: Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. Carbohydrate Research. 9, 79-97 (1969).</lncs>
<ieee> K. Heyns, K.R. Sperling, and H.-F. Grützmacher, “Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden”, &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 1969,  pp. 79-97.</ieee>
<apa>Heyns, K., Sperling, K. R., &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1969). Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-97. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<frontiers>Heyns, K., Sperling, K. R., and Grützmacher, H. - F. (1969). Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt; 9, 79-97.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heyns, K., Sperling, K.R. &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H.-F. (1969). Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-97. Elsevier BV. doi:10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Heyns K, Sperling KR, Grützmacher H-F. Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;. 1969;9(1):79-97.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Heyns, K. R.  Sperling, and H. - F.  Grützmacher, “Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden”, &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1969&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 79-97.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heyns, K., Sperling, K. R., &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1969). Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-97. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0008-6215(00)82891-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Heyns, K., Sperling, K.R., &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H.-F., 1969. Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden. &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;, 9(1), p 79-97.</harvard1>
<bio1>Heyns K, Sperling KR, Grützmacher H-F (1969) &lt;br /&gt;Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden.&lt;br /&gt;Carbohydrate Research 9(1): 79-97.</bio1>
<wels>Heyns, K.; Sperling, K. R.; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1969): Massenspektrometrische Untersuchungen. XIX. Mitteilung. Kombination von Gaschromatographie und Massenspektrometrie zur Analyse partiell methylierter Zuckerderivate Die massenspektren von partiell methylierten methylglucosiden: die Massenspektren von partiell methylierten Methylglucosiden &lt;em&gt;Carbohydrate Research&lt;/em&gt;,9:(1): 79-97.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1783856</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>