<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1783004</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13197</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10056</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>VDI-GET Conference</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3431.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1783004/2314091/OCT3431.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Multi-Science Publ.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Düsseldorf, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-906522-09-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-34311</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-16</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1993). The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-16). Gehalten auf der VDI-GET Conference, Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Birg H (1993) &lt;br /&gt;The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference.  Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.:  1-16.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Birg, in &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;, Multi-Science Publ., Brentwood, Essex, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-16.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Birg H. The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. In:  &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.;  1993: 1-16.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, Herwig. 1993. “The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action”. In &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;, 1-16. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Birg, H.: The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference. p. 1-16. Multi-Science Publ., Brentwood, Essex (1993).</lncs>
<frontiers>Birg, H. (1993). “The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action” in &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt; (Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.), 1-16.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (1993). The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;, 1-16. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Birg, Herwig. “The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action”. &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ., 1993. 1-16.</mla>
<wels>Birg, H. (1993): The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. In: Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.  S. 1-16.</wels>
<default>Birg H (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.:  1-16.</default>
<ieee> H. Birg, “The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action”, &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;,  Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ., 1993,  pp.1-16.</ieee>
<harvard1>Birg, H., 1993. The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. In &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;.  Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ., pp. 1-16.</harvard1>
<apa>Birg, H. (1993). The dynamics of world population growth: causes, consequences, necessary action. &lt;em&gt;Influence of man on climate III: proceedings of the VDI-GET Conference&lt;/em&gt;, 1-16. Brentwood, Essex: Multi-Science Publ.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1783004</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>