<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1783000</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13197</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">E.-Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Flöthmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21343</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Iris</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reiter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Henk A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10056</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175763</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3429.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1783000/2314089/OCT3429.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ISOR</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">90-5187-049-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-34298</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">145-182</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, Herwig, Flöthmann, E.-Jürgen, and Reiter, Iris. 1991. “Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts”. In &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Henk A. Becker and Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar), 145-182. Utrecht: ISOR.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Birg, H., Flöthmann, E.-J., Reiter, I.: Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In: Becker, H.A. and Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (eds.) Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar. p. 145-182. ISOR, Utrecht (1991).</lncs>
<default>Birg H, Flöthmann E-J, Reiter I (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar. Becker HA, Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Eds);  Utrecht: ISOR:  145-182.</default>
<mla>Birg, Herwig, Flöthmann, E.-Jürgen, and Reiter, Iris. “Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts”. &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Henk A. Becker and Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar). Utrecht: ISOR, 1991. 145-182.</mla>
<frontiers>Birg, H., Flöthmann, E. - J., and Reiter, I. (1991). “Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts” in &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;, Becker, H. A., and Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) eds. (Utrecht: ISOR), 145-182.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H., Flöthmann, E.-J. &amp;amp; Reiter, I. (1991). Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In H.A. Becker &amp;amp; Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt; (S. 145-182). Utrecht: ISOR.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Birg H, Flöthmann E-J, Reiter I. Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In: Becker HA, Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar), eds. &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht: ISOR;  1991: 145-182.</ama>
<ieee> H. Birg, E.-J. Flöthmann, and I. Reiter, “Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts”, &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;, H.A. Becker and Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar), eds.,  Utrecht: ISOR, 1991,  pp.145-182.</ieee>
<apa>Birg, H., Flöthmann, E. - J., &amp;amp; Reiter, I. (1991). Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In H. A.  Becker &amp;amp; Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 145-182). Utrecht: ISOR.</apa>
<wels>Birg, H.; Flöthmann, E. - J.; Reiter, I. (1991): Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In: Henk A. Becker; Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Hrsg.):  Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar. Utrecht: ISOR.  S. 145-182.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Birg, E. - J.  Flöthmann, and I.  Reiter, in &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H.A. Becker, Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar), Isor, Utrecht, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 145-182.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Birg, H., Flöthmann, E.-J., &amp;amp; Reiter, I., 1991. Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In H. A.  Becker &amp;amp; Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar), eds. &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt;.  Utrecht: ISOR, pp. 145-182.</harvard1>
<bio1>Birg H, Flöthmann E-J, Reiter I (1991) &lt;br /&gt;Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar. Becker HA, Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Eds); Utrecht: ISOR:  145-182.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H., Flöthmann, E. - J., &amp;amp; Reiter, I. (1991). Biographic analysis of the demographic characteristics of the life histories of men and women in regional labour market cohorts as clusters of birth cohorts. In H. A.  Becker &amp;amp; Nederlands Instituut voor Voortgezet Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek op het Gebied van de Mens- en Maatschappijwetenschappen (Wassenaar) (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Life histories and generations: proceedings of a symposium held on 22 and 23 June 1989 at the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences, at Wassenaar&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 145-182). Utrecht: ISOR.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1783000</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>