<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1784535</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:940</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Neithard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bulst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17732</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Neithard</namePart><namePart type="family">Bulst</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.-Ph.</namePart><namePart type="family">Genet</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">78418</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791087</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3914.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1784535/2314471/OCT3914.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Western Michigan Univ.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1986</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-918720-69-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17845356</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-16</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Bulst N. Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In: Bulst N, Genet J-P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;. Medieval Institute publications. Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.;  1986: 1-16.</ama>
<frontiers>Bulst, N. (1986). “Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie” in &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;, Bulst, N., and Genet, J. - P. eds. Medieval Institute publications (Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.), 1-16.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bulst, N. (1986). Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie (Medieval Institute publications). In N. Bulst &amp;amp; J.-P. Genet (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-16). Gehalten auf der First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography, Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Bulst, N. (1986). Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In N.  Bulst &amp;amp; J. - P.  Genet (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-16). Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.</apa>
<ieee> N. Bulst, “Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie”, &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;, N. Bulst and J.-P. Genet, eds., Medieval Institute publications,  Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ., 1986,  pp.1-16.</ieee>
<wels>Bulst, N. (1986): Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In: Neithard Bulst; J.-Ph. Genet (Hrsg.):  Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications. Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ. (Medieval Institute publications, ).  S. 1-16.</wels>
<bio1>Bulst N (1986) &lt;br /&gt;Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications. Bulst N, Genet J-P (Eds); Medieval Institute publications,  Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.:  1-16.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bulst, N. (1986). Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In N.  Bulst &amp;amp; J. - P.  Genet (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-16). Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bulst, N., 1986. Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In N.  Bulst &amp;amp; J. - P.  Genet, eds. &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;. Medieval Institute publications.  Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ., pp. 1-16.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Bulst, in &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Bulst, J.-P. Genet), Western Michigan Univ., Kalamazoo, Mich., &lt;strong&gt;1986&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-16.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Bulst, N.: Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie. In: Bulst, N. and Genet, J.-P. (eds.) Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications. Medieval Institute publications. p. 1-16. Western Michigan Univ., Kalamazoo, Mich. (1986).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bulst, Neithard. 1986. “Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie”. In &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Neithard Bulst and J.-Ph. Genet, 1-16. Medieval Institute publications. Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Bulst, Neithard. “Zum Gegenstand und zur Methode von Prosopographie”. &lt;em&gt;Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Neithard Bulst and J.-Ph. Genet. Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ., 1986. Medieval Institute publications. 1-16.</mla>
<default>Bulst N (1986)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Medieval lives and the historian: studies in medieval prosopography ; proceedings of the First International Interdisciplinary Conference on Medieval Prosopography. Medieval Institute publications. Bulst N, Genet J-P (Eds);  Medieval Institute publications.  Kalamazoo, Mich.: Western Michigan Univ.:  1-16.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1784535</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>