<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1784063</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Biggar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hartmut</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hampl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Friedman</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fuchs</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helmut</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Goedert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Since prevalent cohorts may be biased by the duration of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection (onset bias), it is useful to assess the potential predictive value of markers in incident cohorts of HIV-positive subjects for whom the date of seroconversion is known or can reliably be estimated. Of 131 homosexual men with HIV-1 seroconversion from New York City and Washington, DC, who were evaluated annually beginning in 1982, 60 developed acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) by the end of 1989. The prognostic significance of immunologic markers (proportion of CD4+ T-lymphocytes, neopterin, ß2-microglobulin, serum interferon, and anti-p24 antibody) and of a virologic marker (HIV p24 antigen) was determined using measurements made at defined time intervals after the known or estimated date of HIV seroconversion. When measurements made 3 years after seroconversion were used, all markers except anti-p24 antibody were found to be significant estimators of AIDS risk in univariate analyses. In multivariate Cox regression modeling, the maximum information was obtained by including neopterin, interferon, and the CD4+ T-lymphocyte proportion. The predictive value of markers after HIV seroconversion could change considerably from one interval to another. Elevated levels of ß2-microglobulin and neopterin significantly predicted the development of Kaposi‘s sarcoma. These two markers were highly correlated (r=0. 74). The authors conclude that immunologic markers can be important for an HIV staging system for estimating prognosis and facilitating early therapeutic intervention in HIV-positive patients.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kr_79.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1784063/2314327/kr_79.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>AMER J EPIDEMIOLOGY</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1992</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>beta 2-microglobulin</topic><topic>HIV antigens</topic><topic>HIV-1</topic><topic>interferons</topic><topic>HIV antibodies</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>American Journal of Epidemiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0002-9262</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-37471</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>136</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">71-80</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, A., Biggar, R.J., Hampl, H., Friedman, R.M., Fuchs, D., Wachter, H. &amp;amp; Goedert, J.J. (1992). Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt;(1), 71-80. AMER J EPIDEMIOLOGY.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, A., Biggar, R. J., Hampl, H., Friedman, R. M., Fuchs, D., Wachter, H., &amp;amp; Goedert, J. J. (1992). Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt;(1), 71-80.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Krämer, A., Biggar, R. J., Hampl, H., Friedman, R. M., Fuchs, D., Wachter, H., and Goedert, J. J. (1992). Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 136, 71-80.</frontiers>
<mla>Krämer, Alexander, Biggar, Robert J., Hampl, Hartmut, Friedman, Robert M., Fuchs, Dietmar, Wachter, Helmut, and Goedert, James J. “Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific”. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 136.1 (1992): 71-80.</mla>
<wels>Krämer, A.; Biggar, R. J.; Hampl, H.; Friedman, R. M.; Fuchs, D.; Wachter, H.; Goedert, J. J. (1992): Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;,136:(1): 71-80.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Krämer, R. J.  Biggar, H.  Hampl, R. M.  Friedman, D.  Fuchs, H.  Wachter, and J. J.  Goedert, “Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific”, &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1992&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt;, 71-80.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Krämer A, Biggar RJ, Hampl H, Friedman RM, Fuchs D, Wachter H, Goedert JJ (1992) &lt;br /&gt;Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific.&lt;br /&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology 136(1): 71-80.</bio1>
<default>Krämer A, Biggar RJ, Hampl H, Friedman RM, Fuchs D, Wachter H, Goedert JJ (1992) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 136(1): 71-80.</default>
<ama>Krämer A, Biggar RJ, Hampl H, et al. Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;. 1992;136(1):71-80.</ama>
<harvard1>Krämer, A., et al., 1992. Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, 136(1), p 71-80.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Krämer, et al., “Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific”, &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 136, 1992,  pp. 71-80.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, Alexander, Biggar, Robert J., Hampl, Hartmut, Friedman, Robert M., Fuchs, Dietmar, Wachter, Helmut, and Goedert, James J. 1992. “Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific”. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 136 (1): 71-80.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Krämer, A., Biggar, R.J., Hampl, H., Friedman, R.M., Fuchs, D., Wachter, H., Goedert, J.J.: Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. American Journal of Epidemiology. 136, 71-80 (1992).</lncs>
<apa>Krämer, A., Biggar, R. J., Hampl, H., Friedman, R. M., Fuchs, D., Wachter, H., &amp;amp; Goedert, J. J. (1992). Immunologic markers of progression to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome are time-dependent and illness-specific. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt;(1), 71-80.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1784063</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>