<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1784280</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolf-Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beyn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">12477</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Julius</namePart><namePart type="family">Albrecht</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">L.</namePart><namePart type="family">Collatz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">K.</namePart><namePart type="family">Kirchgässner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT3803.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1784280/2314379/OCT3803.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Birkhäuser</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1978</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>stability</topic><topic>finite difference method</topic><topic>consistency</topic><topic>local convergence theorem</topic><topic>ordinary boundary value problem</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-7643-1098-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-38030</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>48</number></detail><extent unit="pages">9-19</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Beyn, W. - J. (1978). “On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems” in &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;, Albrecht, J., Collatz, L., and Kirchgässner, K. eds. International series of numerical mathematics, vol. 48, (Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser), 9-19.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyn, W.-J. (1978). On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems (International series of numerical mathematics). In J. Albrecht, L. Collatz &amp;amp; K. Kirchgässner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt; (S. 9-19). Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Beyn W-J. On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In: Albrecht J, Collatz L, Kirchgässner K, eds. &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;. International series of numerical mathematics. Vol 48. Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser;  1978: 9-19.</ama>
<ieee> W.-J. Beyn, “On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems”, &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;, J. Albrecht, L. Collatz, and K. Kirchgässner, eds., International series of numerical mathematics, vol. 48,  Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser, 1978,  pp.9-19.</ieee>
<apa>Beyn, W. - J. (1978). On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In J.  Albrecht, L.  Collatz, &amp;amp; K.  Kirchgässner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International series of numerical mathematics: Vol. 48&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 9-19). Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser.</apa>
<wels>Beyn, W. - J. (1978): On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In: Julius Albrecht; L. Collatz; K. Kirchgässner (Hrsg.):  Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978. Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser. (International series of numerical mathematics, 48).  S. 9-19.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>W. - J.  Beyn, in &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Albrecht, L. Collatz, K. Kirchgässner), Birkhäuser, Basel [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;1978&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 9-19.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Beyn, W.-J., 1978. On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In J.  Albrecht, L.  Collatz, &amp;amp; K.  Kirchgässner, eds. &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;. International series of numerical mathematics. no.48  Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser, pp. 9-19.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyn, W. - J. (1978). On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In J.  Albrecht, L.  Collatz, &amp;amp; K.  Kirchgässner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International series of numerical mathematics: Vol. 48&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 9-19). Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Beyn W-J (1978) &lt;br /&gt;On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978. Albrecht J, Collatz L, Kirchgässner K (Eds); International series of numerical mathematics, 48. Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser:  9-19.</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyn, Wolf-Jürgen. 1978. “On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems”. In &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Julius Albrecht, L. Collatz, and K. Kirchgässner, 48:9-19. International series of numerical mathematics. Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Beyn, W.-J.: On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems. In: Albrecht, J., Collatz, L., and Kirchgässner, K. (eds.) Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978. International series of numerical mathematics. 48, p. 9-19. Birkhäuser, Basel [u.a.] (1978).</lncs>
<default>Beyn W-J (1978)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978. Albrecht J, Collatz L, Kirchgässner K (Eds);  International series of numerical mathematics, 48.  Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser:  9-19.</default>
<mla>Beyn, Wolf-Jürgen. “On the convergence of the finite difference method for nonlinear ordinary boundary value problems”. &lt;em&gt;Constructive methods for nonlinear boundary value problems and nonlinear oscillations: conference at the Oberwolfach Mathematical Research Institute, Black Forest, November 19 - 25, 1978&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Julius Albrecht, L. Collatz, and K. Kirchgässner. Basel [u.a.]: Birkhäuser, 1978.Vol. 48. International series of numerical mathematics. 9-19.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1784280</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-18T15:01:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>