<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1785339</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friedhelm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Waldhausen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10607</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Duro R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Kurepa</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT4434.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1785339/2314838/OCT4434.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1969</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-44349</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">331-332</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Waldhausen, F. (1969): On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In: Duro R. Kurepa (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia. Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma.  S. 331-332.</wels>
<mla>Waldhausen, Friedhelm. “On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Duro R. Kurepa. Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma, 1969. 331-332.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1969). On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In D. R.  Kurepa (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 331-332). Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Waldhausen, F. (1969). “On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;, Kurepa, D. R. ed. (Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma), 331-332.</frontiers>
<default>Waldhausen F (1969)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia. Kurepa DR (Ed);  Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma:  331-332.</default>
<ieee> F. Waldhausen, “On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;, D.R. Kurepa, ed.,  Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma, 1969,  pp.331-332.</ieee>
<harvard1>Waldhausen, F., 1969. On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In D. R.  Kurepa, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;.  Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma, pp. 331-332.</harvard1>
<apa>Waldhausen, F. (1969). On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In D. R.  Kurepa (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 331-332). Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1969). On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In D.R. Kurepa (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt; (S. 331-332). Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Waldhausen F (1969) &lt;br /&gt;On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia. Kurepa DR (Ed); Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma:  331-332.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Waldhausen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: D.R. Kurepa), Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara I Astronoma, Beograd, &lt;strong&gt;1969&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 331-332.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Waldhausen F. On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In: Kurepa DR, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;. Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma;  1969: 331-332.</ama>
<lncs> Waldhausen, F.: On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone. In: Kurepa, D.R. (ed.) Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia. p. 331-332. Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma, Beograd (1969).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Waldhausen, Friedhelm. 1969. “On the determination of some 3-manifolds by their fundamental group alone”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Symposium on Topology and its Applications: Herceg-Novi, 25.- 31. 8. 1968, Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Duro R. Kurepa, 331-332. Beograd: Savez Drustava Matematicara, Fizicara i Astronoma.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1785339</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>