<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1785080</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:590</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keary</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25149567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ruploh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23350975</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Voss</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thalau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roswitha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiltschko</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiltschko</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bischof</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22137</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Zebra finches can be trained to use the geomagnetic field as a directional cue for short distance orientation. The physical mechanisms underlying the primary processes of magnetoreception are, however, largely unknown. Two hypotheses of how birds perceive magnetic information are mainly discussed, one dealing with modulation of radical pair processes in retinal structures, the other assuming that iron deposits in the upper beak of the birds are involved. Oscillating magnetic fields in the MHz range disturb radical pair mechanisms but do not affect magnetic particles. Thus, application of such oscillating fields in behavioral experiments can be used as a diagnostic tool to decide between the two alternatives.  Methods: In a setup that eliminates all directional cues except the geomagnetic field zebra finches were trained to search for food in the magnetic north/south axis. The birds were then tested for orientation performance in two magnetic conditions. In condition 1 the horizontal component of the geomagnetic field was shifted by 90 degrees using a helmholtz coil. In condition 2 a high frequently oscillating field (1.156 MHz) was applied in addition to the shifted field. Another group of birds was trained to solve the orientation task, but with visual landmarks as directional cue. The birds were then tested for their orientation performance in the same magnetic conditions as applied for the first experiment.  Results: The zebra finches could be trained successfully to orient in the geomagnetic field for food search in the north/south axis. They were also well oriented in test condition 1, with the magnetic field shifted horizontally by 90 degrees. In contrast, when the oscillating field was added, the directional choices during food search were randomly distributed. Birds that were trained to visually guided orientation showed no difference of orientation performance in the two magnetic conditions.  Conclusion: The results indicate that zebra finches use a receptor that bases on radical pair processes for sensing the direction of the earth magnetic field in this short distance orientation behavior.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Keary.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1785080/2314690/Keary.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Zoology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1742-9994</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">19852792</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000272217600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17850807</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1742-9994-6-25</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">25</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2541308</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Keary, N., et al., 2009. Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, 6(1), p 25.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Keary, et al., “Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 2009,  pp. 25.</ieee>
<apa>Keary, N., Ruploh, T., Voss, J., Thalau, P., Wiltschko, R., Wiltschko, W., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2009). Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 25. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-9994-6-25" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-9994-6-25&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<mla>Keary, Nina, Ruploh, Tim, Voss, Joe, Thalau, Peter, Wiltschko, Roswitha, Wiltschko, Wolfgang, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. “Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt; 6.1 (2009): 25.</mla>
<frontiers>Keary, N., Ruploh, T., Voss, J., Thalau, P., Wiltschko, R., Wiltschko, W., and Bischof, H. - J. (2009). Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt; 6, 25.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Keary, N., Ruploh, T., Voss, J., Thalau, P., Wiltschko, R., Wiltschko, W., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2009). Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 25. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-9994-6-25" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-9994-6-25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Keary, N.; Ruploh, T.; Voss, J.; Thalau, P.; Wiltschko, R.; Wiltschko, W.; Bischof, H. - J. (2009): Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;,6:(1): 25.</wels>
<default>Keary N, Ruploh T, Voss J, Thalau P, Wiltschko R, Wiltschko W, Bischof H-J (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt; 6(1): 25.</default>
<ama>Keary N, Ruploh T, Voss J, et al. Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;6(1):25.</ama>
<lncs> Keary, N., Ruploh, T., Voss, J., Thalau, P., Wiltschko, R., Wiltschko, W., Bischof, H.-J.: Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. Frontiers in Zoology. 6, 25 (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Keary, Nina, Ruploh, Tim, Voss, Joe, Thalau, Peter, Wiltschko, Roswitha, Wiltschko, Wolfgang, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. 2009. “Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt; 6 (1): 25.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Keary, N., Ruploh, T., Voss, J., Thalau, P., Wiltschko, R., Wiltschko, W. &amp;amp; Bischof, H.-J. (2009). Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 25. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1742-9994-6-25.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Keary, T.  Ruploh, J.  Voss, P.  Thalau, R.  Wiltschko, W.  Wiltschko, and H. - J.  Bischof, “Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, 25.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Keary N, Ruploh T, Voss J, Thalau P, Wiltschko R, Wiltschko W, Bischof H-J (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Oscillating magnetic field disrupts magnetic orientation in Zebra finches, Taeniopygia guttata.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Zoology 6(1): 25.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1785080</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>