<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1785088</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:340</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gusy</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21583</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191294</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10029</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Project report (D6) prepared fort he JURISTRAS project funded by the European Commission, DG Research, Priority 7, Citizens and Governance in a Knowledge Based Society (contract no: FP6-028398)</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Das Projekt JURISTRAS hat die bürgerlichen und politischen Rechte der Europäischen Menschenrechtskonvention (EMRK) und die dazu ergangene Rechtsprechung des Europäischen Gerichtshofs für Menschenrechte zum Gegenstand. Auf der Grundlage der zu Art. 8, Art. 9, Art. 10, Art. 11 und Art. 14 EMRK ergangenen Rechtsprechung soll in 9 Konventionsstaaten (Bulgarien, Deutschland, Frankreich. Griechenland, Großbritannien, Italien, Österreich, Rumänien und Türkei) untersucht werden, welche Beziehung es zwischen der Rechtsprechung und der Umsetzung der gefällten Urteile gibt. Der Schwerpunkt liegt auf der Analyse des Einflusses von Straßburger Gerichtsentscheidungen auf nationale Gesetzgebungsprozesse, auf politische Entscheidungen und auf institutionelle Strukturen. Die Universität Bielefeld ist Projektpartner und verantwortlich für die Untersuchung in Deutschland. Der im Rahmen des Projekts verfasste englischsprachige Bericht "Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg jurisprudence: a case study of Germany" basiert auf einer umfassenden empirischen Untersuchung der Umsetzungsprozesse in Deutschland. Der Bericht beschreibt in einem ersten Schritt die unterschiedlichen Motivationslagen der Beschwerdeführer und stellt kurz die in Deutschland existierenden Rahmenbedingungen (finanzielle Hilfe und Rechtsberatung) für eine Beschwerde vor dem EGMR dar. Daran schließt sich eine Darstellung der Akteure und Mechanismen an, die für die Umsetzung der Urteile gegen Deutschland relevant sind. Thematisch sortiert nach Entscheidungsgebieten folgt eine Analyse der Umsetzungsmaßnahmen, die durchgeführt wurden, um die Vorgaben aus den Urteilen gegen Deutschland zu erfüllen. Der Bericht greift schließlich im letzten Kapitel eine nicht an den konkreten Umsetzungsmechanismen orientierte Fragestellung auf. Dabei stehen politische und gesellschaftliche Faktoren, die eine Umsetzung der Urteile fördern oder eher behindern, im Mittelpunkt. Es wird thematisiert, welchen Einfluss das gesellschaftliche Bewusstsein für den EGMR bei der Umsetzung der Urteile hat, welche Rolle der EGMR und seine Rechtsprechung in der nationalen politischen Auseinandersetzung einnimmt und ob bzw. wie Menschenrechtsorganisationen in Deutschland die Rechtsprechung des EGMR aufgreifen. Der Bericht endet nach diesen allgemeinen Ausführungen wieder mit einzelnen Themengebieten und geht der Frage nach, ob und wie Urteile des EGMR rechtliche Entwicklungen in Deutschland anstoßen bzw. gesetzgeberische Prozesse beeinflussen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">JURISTRAS comparatively explores processes of human rights litigation in the European Court of Human Rights (ECtHR) and the effects of its judgments on national laws, judicial attitudes and policy making. The project specifically focuses on the Court's jurisprudence concerning the right to privacy and family life (Art. 8 ECHR), religious freedom and conscience (Art. 9 ECHR), freedom of expression (Art. 10 ECHR), freedom of assembly and association (Art. 11 ECHR) and the prohibition of discrimination (Article 14). Cases brought to the Strasbourg Court by aliens and minorities, as well as cases that in one way or another relate to individuals belonging to vulnerable social groups are similarly studied. The report on Germany "Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg jurisprudence: a case study of Germany" is based on a comprehensive empirical analysis. The report a) inquires into litigation and legal mobilisation before the ECtHR, analysing the resources and structures of legal support for the individuals resorting to the Court; b) describes the mechanisms and processes of implementation of ECtHR rulings; and c) assesses the individual and general measures adopted in order to comply with the Court's judgments. Focus then shifts to the factors leading or constraining effective implementation, examining whether the attitude of government elites, legal culture, judicial politics and social and interest-group mobilisation by non-state actors influence implementation. Next, the impact of ECtHR case law on domestic human rights discourse is considered, verifying whether the Court's jurisprudence is used and appealed to by political parties, parliamentary representatives, NGOs and other public and private actors with the aim to exert pressure for legal and policy reform.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Juristras_Germany_casestudy.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1785088/2314691/Juristras_Germany_casestudy.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>European Court of Human Rights</topic><topic>Jurisprudence</topic><topic>Human rights</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-41977</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Gusy, and S.  Müller, &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gusy, C., &amp;amp; Müller, S. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Gusy C, Müller S (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<harvard1>Gusy, C., &amp;amp; Müller, S., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<wels>Gusy, C.; Müller, S. (2008): Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<ieee> C. Gusy and S. Müller, &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Gusy, C., &amp;amp; Müller, S. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gusy, C. &amp;amp; Müller, S. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Gusy, C., and Müller, S. (2008). Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<ama>Gusy C, Müller S. &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2008.</ama>
<default>Gusy C, Müller S (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Gusy, Christoph, and Müller, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gusy, Christoph, and Müller, Sebastian. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gusy, C., Müller, S.: Supranational rights litigation, implementation and the domestic impact of Strasbourg Court jurisprudence : a case study of Germany. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1785088</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-05T12:42:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>