<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1785187</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Armin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7346775</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8778-1273</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015583</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Linguistic Evidence 2010</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="le.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1785187/2314769/le.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Eberhard-Karls-Universität</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Tübingen</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>We devise a simple</topic><topic>both for context-free production rules and for Combinatory Categorial Grammar categories. It is stronger for task-oriented dialogs</topic><topic>and stronger in lexical categories than in syntactic categories.</topic><topic>distribution-based measure of priming between linguistic categories. Priming is found in tree banks of dialog corpora</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-43525</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Buch, A., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (2010). Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt; Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.</apa>
<ieee> A. Buch and C. Pietsch, “Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;,  Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität, 2010.</ieee>
<ama>Buch A, Pietsch C. Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität;  2010.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buch, A. &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (2010). Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Linguistic Evidence 2010, Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Buch, A., and Pietsch, C. (2010). “Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buch, A., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (2010). Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt; Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Buch A, Pietsch C (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives.  Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.</bio1>
<harvard1>Buch, A., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C., 2010. Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;.  Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Buch, and C.  Pietsch, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Eberhard-Karls-Universität, Tübingen, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Buch, A.; Pietsch, C. (2010): Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. In: Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives. Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.</wels>
<mla>Buch, Armin, and Pietsch, Christian. “Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität, 2010.</mla>
<default>Buch A, Pietsch C (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives. Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.</default>
<lncs> Buch, A., Pietsch, C.: Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora. Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives.  Eberhard-Karls-Universität, Tübingen (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buch, Armin, and Pietsch, Christian. 2010. “Measuring Syntactic Priming in Dialog Corpora”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Linguistic Evidence. Empirical, theoretical and computational perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Tübingen: Eberhard-Karls-Universität.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1785187</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-26T13:46:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>