<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1785406</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Birg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13197</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10056</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OCT4484.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1785406/2314887/OCT4484.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>United Nations</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>World population to 2300</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">92-1-151401-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-44840</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">99-111</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Birg, H.: An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In: Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (ed.) World population to 2300. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs. p. 99-111. United Nations, New York (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, Herwig. 2004. “An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections”. In &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division, 99-111. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs. New York: United Nations.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Birg, Herwig. “An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections”. &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division. New York: United Nations, 2004. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs. 99-111.</mla>
<default>Birg H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  World population to 2300. Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Ed);  Economic &amp;amp; social affairs.  New York: United Nations:  99-111.</default>
<wels>Birg, H. (2004): An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In: Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Hrsg.):  World population to 2300. New York: United Nations. (Economic &amp;amp; social affairs, ).  S. 99-111.</wels>
<harvard1>Birg, H., 2004. An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division, ed. &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs.  New York: United Nations, pp. 99-111.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (2004). An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Economic &amp;amp; social affairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 99-111). New York: United Nations.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Birg H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. &lt;br /&gt;In:  World population to 2300. Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Ed); Economic &amp;amp; social affairs,  New York: United Nations:  99-111.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Birg, in &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division), United Nations, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 99-111.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Birg H. An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In: Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division, ed. &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs. New York: United Nations;  2004: 99-111.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Birg, H. (2004). An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections (Economic &amp;amp; social affairs). In Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt; (S. 99-111). New York: United Nations.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Birg, H. (2004). “An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections” in &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;, Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division ed. Economic &amp;amp; social affairs (New York: United Nations), 99-111.</frontiers>
<apa>Birg, H. (2004). An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections. In Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Economic &amp;amp; social affairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 99-111). New York: United Nations.</apa>
<ieee> H. Birg, “An intergenerational rationale for fertility assumptions in long term world population projections”, &lt;em&gt;World population to 2300&lt;/em&gt;, Vereinte Nationen. Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division, ed., Economic &amp;amp; social affairs,  New York: United Nations, 2004,  pp.99-111.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1785406</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>