<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1857794</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sowa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Antonio</namePart><namePart type="family">Camurri</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gualtiero</namePart><namePart type="family">Volpe</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015432</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>5th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2003</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We describe an anthropomorphic agent that is engaged in an imitation game with the human user. In imitating natural gestures demonstrated by the user, the agent brings together gesture recognition and synthesis on two levels of representation. On the mimicking level, the essential form features of the meaning-bearing gesture phase (stroke) are extracted and reproduced by the agent. Meaning-based imitation requires extracting the semantic content of such gestures and re-expressing it with possibly alternative gestural forms. Based on a compositional semantics for shape-related iconic gestures, we present first steps towards this higher-level gesture imitation in a restricted domain.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="gesture_imitation_GW03.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1857794/2633112/gesture_imitation_GW03.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Genova, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-21072-5</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000189451300040</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18577945</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2915</number></detail><extent unit="pages">436-447</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, Stefan, Sowa, Timo, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2004. “Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Antonio Camurri and Gualtiero Volpe, 2915:436-447. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kopp, S., Sowa, T., Wachsmuth, I.: Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In: Camurri, A. and Volpe, G. (eds.) Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 2915, p. 436-447. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2004).</lncs>
<default>Kopp S, Sowa T, Wachsmuth I (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers. Camurri A, Volpe G (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 2915.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  436-447.</default>
<mla>Kopp, Stefan, Sowa, Timo, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Antonio Camurri and Gualtiero Volpe. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2004.Vol. 2915. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 436-447.</mla>
<wels>Kopp, S.; Sowa, T.; Wachsmuth, I. (2004): Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In: Antonio Camurri; Gualtiero Volpe (Hrsg.):  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 2915).  S. 436-447.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kopp, T.  Sowa, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Camurri, G. Volpe), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 436-447.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kopp S, Sowa T, Wachsmuth I (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers. Camurri A, Volpe G (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 2915. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  436-447.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Sowa, T., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 2915&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 436-447). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kopp, S., Sowa, T., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2004. Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. no.2915  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 436-447.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Sowa, T. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In A. Camurri &amp;amp; G. Volpe (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 436-447). Gehalten auf der 5th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2003, Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kopp, S., Sowa, T., and Wachsmuth, I. (2004). “Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;, Camurri, A., and Volpe, G. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 2915, (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 436-447.</frontiers>
<ama>Kopp S, Sowa T, Wachsmuth I. Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In: Camurri A, Volpe G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Vol 2915. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2004: 436-447.</ama>
<ieee> S. Kopp, T. Sowa, and I. Wachsmuth, “Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt;, A. Camurri and G. Volpe, eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 2915,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2004,  pp.436-447.</ieee>
<apa>Kopp, S., Sowa, T., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Imitation games with an artificial agents: From mimicking to understanding shape-related iconic gestures. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 2915&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction : selected revised papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 436-447). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-24598-8_40&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1857794</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-16T08:08:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>