<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1857078</id><setSpec>preprint</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:preprint</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>preprintFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>preprint</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gudrun</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hessler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">124535</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kai</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unzicker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">170715</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">19134156</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper examines interaction processes and knowledge exchange between social scientists and practitioners. We conducted semi-structured interviews with practitioners working in specified fields of practice who have been involved in sociological research projects - as subjects of investigation or as experts. These research projects focused on social integration and disintegration in different sectors of German society. The interviewed practitioners were working in sectors under scrutiny by the researchers, such as public administration, social work, and labor relations. Therefore, we assume that social scientists and practitioners are concerned with similar aspects of society - the social scientists from a more theoretical point of view and the practitioners from a more practical point of view.
In this paper we focus specifically on the process of knowledge exchange between social scientists and practitioners described above. In four case studies we present findings that elucidate the practitioners' understanding of the social scientists' research and reveal whether they regard the research as valuable for their work. We describe dimensions that have an influence on interaction and knowledge exchange: interest and approach to the topic under investigation; the motivation of social scientists and practitioners to cooperate with each other; the conditions under which contact is established; and the position of both groups in their own fields. Finally, we look at what expectations practitioners have of scientific knowledge and identify some obstacles to interaction and knowledge exchange.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="The_informed_Practitioner.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1857078/2319723/The_informed_Practitioner.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University Bielefeld, Institute for Interdisciplinary Research on Conflict and Violence</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Knowledge exchange</topic><topic>Social sciences</topic><topic>Practitioner</topic><topic>Interaction</topic><topic>Case study</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-15888</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hessler, G., Unzicker, K.: The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners. (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hessler, Gudrun, and Unzicker, Kai. 2006. “The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners”.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hessler, Gudrun, and Unzicker, Kai. “The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners”. (2006).</mla>
<default>Hessler G, Unzicker K (2006) .</default>
<wels>Hessler, G.; Unzicker, K. (2006): The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners</wels>
<harvard1>Hessler, G., &amp;amp; Unzicker, K., 2006. The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hessler G, Unzicker K (2006) &lt;br /&gt;The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hessler, G., &amp;amp; Unzicker, K. (2006). The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Hessler, and K.  Unzicker, “The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners”, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hessler G, Unzicker K. The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners.  2006.</ama>
<frontiers>Hessler, G., and Unzicker, K. (2006). The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hessler, G. &amp;amp; Unzicker, K. (2006). The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners. University Bielefeld, Institute for Interdisciplinary Research on Conflict and Violence.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Hessler, G., &amp;amp; Unzicker, K. (2006). The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners</apa>
<ieee> G. Hessler and K. Unzicker, “The informed Practitioner: Communication between social scientists and practitioners”, 2006.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1857078</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-05-15T11:59:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>