<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1857761</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Allwood</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karl</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabeth</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahlsen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stocksmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart><namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Günther</namePart><namePart type="family">Knoblich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In natural communication, both speakers and listeners are active most of the time. While a speaker contributes new information, a listener gives feedback by producing unobtrusive (usually short) vocal or non-vocal bodily expressions to indicate whether he/she is able and willing to communicate, perceive, and understand the information, and what emotions and attitudes are triggered by this information. The simulation of feedback behavior for artificial conversational agents poses big challenges such as the concurrent and integrated perception and production of multi-modal and multi-functional expressions. We present an approach on modeling feedback for and with virtual humans, based on an approach to study ``embodied feedback'' as a special case of a more general theoretical account of embodied communication. A realization of this approach with the virtual human Max is described and results are presented.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kopp-et-al-2008.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1857761/2914047/Kopp-et-al-2008.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-79037-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18577617</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4930</number></detail><extent unit="pages">18-37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Kopp, S., Allwood, J., Grammer, K., Ahlsen, E., &amp;amp; Stocksmeier, T. (2008). Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; G.  Knoblich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 4930&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 18-37). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> S. Kopp, et al., “Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans”, &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, I. Wachsmuth and G. Knoblich, eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 4930,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008,  pp.18-37.</ieee>
<ama>Kopp S, Allwood J, Grammer K, Ahlsen E, Stocksmeier T. Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In: Wachsmuth I, Knoblich G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 4930. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2008: 18-37.</ama>
<frontiers>Kopp, S., Allwood, J., Grammer, K., Ahlsen, E., and Stocksmeier, T. (2008). “Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans” in &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Wachsmuth, I., and Knoblich, G. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 4930, (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 18-37.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Allwood, J., Grammer, K., Ahlsen, E. &amp;amp; Stocksmeier, T. (2008). Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In I. Wachsmuth &amp;amp; G. Knoblich (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 18-37). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kopp S, Allwood J, Grammer K, Ahlsen E, Stocksmeier T (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers. Wachsmuth I, Knoblich G (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 4930. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  18-37.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kopp, S., et al., 2008. Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; G.  Knoblich, eds. &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.4930  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 18-37.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Allwood, J., Grammer, K., Ahlsen, E., &amp;amp; Stocksmeier, T. (2008). Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; G.  Knoblich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 4930&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 18-37). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-79037-2_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kopp, J.  Allwood, K.  Grammer, E.  Ahlsen, and T.  Stocksmeier, in &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Wachsmuth, G. Knoblich), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 18-37.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Kopp, S.; Allwood, J.; Grammer, K.; Ahlsen, E.; Stocksmeier, T. (2008): Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In: Ipke Wachsmuth; Günther Knoblich (Hrsg.):  Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 4930).  S. 18-37.</wels>
<mla>Kopp, Stefan, Allwood, Jens, Grammer, Karl, Ahlsen, Elisabeth, and Stocksmeier, Thorsten. “Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans”. &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Günther Knoblich. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008.Vol. 4930. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 18-37.</mla>
<default>Kopp S, Allwood J, Grammer K, Ahlsen E, Stocksmeier T (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers. Wachsmuth I, Knoblich G (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 4930.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  18-37.</default>
<lncs> Kopp, S., Allwood, J., Grammer, K., Ahlsen, E., Stocksmeier, T.: Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans. In: Wachsmuth, I. and Knoblich, G. (eds.) Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 4930, p. 18-37. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, Stefan, Allwood, Jens, Grammer, Karl, Ahlsen, Elisabeth, and Stocksmeier, Thorsten. 2008. “Modeling Embodied Feedback with Virtual Humans”. In &lt;em&gt;Modeling Communication With Robots And Virtual Humans. Second ZiF Research Group International Workshop on Embodied Communication in Humans and Machines, Bielefeld, Germany, April 5-8, 2006, Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Günther Knoblich, 4930:18-37. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1857761</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-16T08:08:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>