<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1860163</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:830</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Meinolf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schumacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">139725</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7279-4730</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Richard</namePart><namePart type="family">Newhauser</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schumacher_Meinolf_Des_Teufels_Netz_and_the_Alexander_Romance_2005.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1860163/2914120/Schumacher_Meinolf_Des_Teufels_Netz_and_the_Alexander_Romance_2005.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-88844-818-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18601638</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><extent unit="pages">277-290</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Schumacher M. Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In: Newhauser R, ed. &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Papers in mediaeval studies. Vol 18. Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies;  2005: 277-290.</ama>
<ieee> M. Schumacher, “Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach”, &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, R. Newhauser, ed., Papers in mediaeval studies, vol. 18,  Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies, 2005,  pp.277-290.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schumacher, M., 2005. Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In R.  Newhauser, ed. &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Papers in mediaeval studies. no.18  Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies, pp. 277-290.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schumacher, Meinolf. 2005. “Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach”. In &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Richard Newhauser, 18:277-290. Papers in mediaeval studies. Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schumacher, M.: Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In: Newhauser, R. (ed.) In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages. Papers in mediaeval studies. 18, p. 277-290. Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies, Toronto (2005).</lncs>
<apa>Schumacher, M. (2005). Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In R.  Newhauser (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Papers in mediaeval studies: Vol. 18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-290). Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schumacher, M. (2005). Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In R.  Newhauser (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Papers in mediaeval studies: Vol. 18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-290). Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Schumacher, M. (2005). “Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach” in &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, Newhauser, R. ed. Papers in mediaeval studies, vol. 18, (Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies), 277-290.</frontiers>
<mla>Schumacher, Meinolf. “Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach”. &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Richard Newhauser. Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies, 2005.Vol. 18. Papers in mediaeval studies. 277-290.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schumacher, M. (2005). Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach (Papers in mediaeval studies). In R. Newhauser (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (S. 277-290). Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Schumacher, M. (2005): Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. In: Richard Newhauser (Hrsg.):  In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages. Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies. (Papers in mediaeval studies, 18).  S. 277-290.</wels>
<bio1>Schumacher M (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Catalogues of Demons as Catalogues of Vices in Medieval German Literature: 'Des Teufels Netz' and the Alexander Romance by Ulrich von Etzenbach. &lt;br /&gt;In:  In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages. Newhauser R (Ed); Papers in mediaeval studies, 18. Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies:  277-290.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Schumacher, in &lt;em&gt;In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Newhauser), Pontifical Institute Of Mediaeval Studies, Toronto, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 277-290.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Schumacher M (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  In the Garden of Evil: The Vices and Culture in the Middle Ages. Newhauser R (Ed);  Papers in mediaeval studies, 18.  Toronto: Pontifical Institute of Mediaeval Studies:  277-290.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1860163</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-05-12T13:06:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>