<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1861150</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Production and Finance in EURACE</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van der Hoog</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15269682</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2348-3194</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christophe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Deissenberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart><namePart type="family">Schredelseker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Florian</namePart><namePart type="family">Hauser</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">42173282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">EURACE is a major FP6 STREP project aiming at constructing an exhaustive agent-based model of the European economy, populated by a very large number of sophisticated, autonomous agents. The EURACE model, which has an explicit spatial structure, includes all the major markets considered in quantitative macroeconomic modelling (consumer goods, investment goods, labour, credit and
finance). It offers a unique opportunity for studying, from a new perspective, the empirically observed but theoretically poorly understood link between the real and
the financial sphere of a modern economy. After summarily presenting the main features of EURACE, this paper describes in more detail the newly developed financial
management module that intermediates between the real and the financial spheres in EURACE. In a nutshell, this module defines the link between the hiring and investment behavior of the firms as a function of the revenues they obtain by selling their products, of the money they can raise on the credit and financial markets, of their
dividend policy, and other major aspects of financial decision-making.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="van_der_Hoog_Dawid_Deissenberg-2008-Ch12-Production-and-finance-in-Eurace.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1861150/2782323/van_der_Hoog_Dawid_Deissenberg-2008-Ch12-Production-and-finance-in-Eurace.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Agent-based modelling</topic><topic>Eurace@Unibi model</topic><topic>etace_agent_based_modelling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Complexity and Artificial Markets</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0075-8442</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-70553-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18611502</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>614</number></detail><extent unit="pages">147-158</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C., Dawid, H.: Production and Finance in EURACE. In: Schredelseker, K. and Hauser, F. (eds.) Complexity and Artificial Markets. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets. 614, p. 147-158. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, Sander, Deissenberg, Christophe, and Dawid, Herbert. 2008. “Production and Finance in EURACE”. In &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Klaus Schredelseker and Florian Hauser, 614:147-158. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C, Dawid H. Production and Finance in EURACE. In: Schredelseker K, Hauser F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets. Vol 614. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2008: 147-158.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  van der Hoog, C.  Deissenberg, and H.  Dawid, in &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: K. Schredelseker, F. Hauser), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 147-158.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C, Dawid H (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Production and Finance in EURACE. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Complexity and Artificial Markets. Schredelseker K, Hauser F (Eds); Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets, 614. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  147-158.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C. &amp;amp; Dawid, H. (2008). Production and Finance in EURACE (Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets). In K. Schredelseker &amp;amp; F. Hauser (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt; (S. 147-158). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C., &amp;amp; Dawid, H. (2008). Production and Finance in EURACE. In K.  Schredelseker &amp;amp; F.  Hauser (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets: Vol. 614&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 147-158). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C., &amp;amp; Dawid, H., 2008. Production and Finance in EURACE. In K.  Schredelseker &amp;amp; F.  Hauser, eds. &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets. no.614  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 147-158.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. van der Hoog, C. Deissenberg, and H. Dawid, “Production and Finance in EURACE”, &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;, K. Schredelseker and F. Hauser, eds., Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets, vol. 614,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008,  pp.147-158.</ieee>
<default>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C, Dawid H (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Complexity and Artificial Markets. Schredelseker K, Hauser F (Eds);  Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets, 614.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  147-158.</default>
<frontiers>van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C., and Dawid, H. (2008). “Production and Finance in EURACE” in &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;, Schredelseker, K., and Hauser, F. eds. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets, vol. 614, (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 147-158.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C., &amp;amp; Dawid, H. (2008). Production and Finance in EURACE. In K.  Schredelseker &amp;amp; F.  Hauser (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets: Vol. 614&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 147-158). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70556-7_12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>van der Hoog, Sander, Deissenberg, Christophe, and Dawid, Herbert. “Production and Finance in EURACE”. &lt;em&gt;Complexity and Artificial Markets&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Klaus Schredelseker and Florian Hauser. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008.Vol. 614. Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets. 147-158.</mla>
<wels>van der Hoog, S.; Deissenberg, C.; Dawid, H. (2008): Production and Finance in EURACE. In: Klaus Schredelseker; Florian Hauser (Hrsg.):  Complexity and Artificial Markets. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture notes in economic and mathematical systems, Complexity and artificial markets, 614).  S. 147-158.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1861150</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-05T12:34:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>