<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1862956</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rafael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kurtz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">57780478</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">A</namePart><namePart type="family">Mendez-Vilas</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J</namePart><namePart type="family">Diaz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kurtz_mod_res_edu_topics_micr_2007.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1862956/2904508/Kurtz_mod_res_edu_topics_micr_2007.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Formatex</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18629568</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">154-163</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Kurtz, R.: Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In: Mendez-Vilas, A. and Diaz, J. (eds.) Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1. p. 154-163. Formatex (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtz, Rafael. 2007. “Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches.”. In &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;, ed. A Mendez-Vilas and J Diaz, 154-163. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1. Formatex.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kurtz, Rafael. “Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches.”. &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. A Mendez-Vilas and J Diaz. Formatex, 2007. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1. 154-163.</mla>
<default>Kurtz R (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy. Mendez-Vilas A, Diaz J (Eds);  Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1.  Formatex:  154-163.</default>
<wels>Kurtz, R. (2007): Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In: A Mendez-Vilas; J Diaz (Hrsg.):  Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy. Formatex. (Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1, ).  S. 154-163.</wels>
<bio1>Kurtz R (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy. Mendez-Vilas A, Diaz J (Eds); Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1,  Formatex:  154-163.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kurtz, R., 2007. Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In A.  Mendez-Vilas &amp;amp; J.  Diaz, eds. &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1.  Formatex, pp. 154-163.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtz, R. (2007). Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In A.  Mendez-Vilas &amp;amp; J.  Diaz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 154-163). Formatex.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Kurtz, in &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Mendez-Vilas, J. Diaz), Formatex, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 154-163.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kurtz R. Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In: Mendez-Vilas A, Diaz J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1. Formatex;  2007: 154-163.</ama>
<frontiers>Kurtz, R. (2007). “Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches.” in &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;, Mendez-Vilas, A., and Diaz, J. eds. Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1 (Formatex), 154-163.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtz, R. (2007). Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. (Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1). In A. Mendez-Vilas &amp;amp; J. Diaz (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt; (S. 154-163). Formatex.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kurtz, R. (2007). Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches. In A.  Mendez-Vilas &amp;amp; J.  Diaz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 154-163). Formatex.</apa>
<ieee> R. Kurtz, “Bright Solutions to Get Sharp Images: Confocal and Two-Photon Fluorescence Microscopy and the Pros and Cons of New Multifocal Approaches.”, &lt;em&gt;Modern Research and Educational Topics in Microscopy&lt;/em&gt;, A. Mendez-Vilas and J. Diaz, eds., Microscopy Series No. 3 Vol. 1, Formatex, 2007,  pp.154-163.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1862956</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-05T10:00:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>