<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1862040</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schäfer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">3971812</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1140-6175</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Imunde</namePart><namePart type="family">Schäfer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38670945</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schaefer_2004_Priests-prophets-sorcerers_LA.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1862040/2425706/Schaefer_2004_Priests-prophets-sorcerers_LA.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Evang. Akad.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-8172-1203-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18620409</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12/03</number></detail><extent unit="pages">193-219</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Schäfer, H., 2004. Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In I.  Schäfer, ed. &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;. Loccumer Protokoll. no.12/03  Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad., pp. 193-219.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Schäfer, “Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America”, &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;, I. Schäfer, ed., Loccumer Protokoll, vol. 12/03,  Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad., 2004,  pp.193-219.</ieee>
<apa>Schäfer, H. (2004). Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In I.  Schäfer (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Loccumer Protokoll: Vol. 12/03&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-219). Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.</apa>
<mla>Schäfer, Heinrich. “Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America”. &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Imunde Schäfer. Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad., 2004.Vol. 12/03. Loccumer Protokoll. 193-219.</mla>
<frontiers>Schäfer, H. (2004). “Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America” in &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;, Schäfer, I. ed. Loccumer Protokoll, vol. 12/03, (Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.), 193-219.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2004). Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In I.  Schäfer (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Loccumer Protokoll: Vol. 12/03&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-219). Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Schäfer, H. (2004): Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In: Imunde Schäfer (Hrsg.):  The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique. Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad. (Loccumer Protokoll, 12/03).  S. 193-219.</wels>
<default>Schäfer H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique. Schäfer I (Ed);  Loccumer Protokoll, 12/03.  Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.:  193-219.</default>
<ama>Schäfer H. Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In: Schäfer I, ed. &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;. Loccumer Protokoll. Vol 12/03. Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.;  2004: 193-219.</ama>
<lncs> Schäfer, H.: Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. In: Schäfer, I. (ed.) The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique. Loccumer Protokoll. 12/03, p. 193-219. Evang. Akad., Rehburg-Loccum. (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, Heinrich. 2004. “Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America”. In &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Imunde Schäfer, 12/03:193-219. Loccumer Protokoll. Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2004). Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America (Loccumer Protokoll). In I. Schäfer (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt; (S. 193-219). Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Schäfer, in &lt;em&gt;The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: I. Schäfer), Evang. Akad., Rehburg-Loccum., &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 193-219.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schäfer H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Priests, prophets or sorcerers? On intellectual elites and politics in modernizing Latin America. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The role of the educated class in Africa - between African renaissance and globalisation critique. Schäfer I (Ed); Loccumer Protokoll, 12/03. Rehburg-Loccum.: Evang. Akad.:  193-219.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1862040</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-03T11:36:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>