<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1862058</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schäfer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">3971812</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1140-6175</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38670945</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schaefer_2009_Pent--RelHabitus.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1862058/2425632/Schaefer_2009_Pent--RelHabitus.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-89204-989-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18620581</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">533-585</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Schäfer, Heinrich. “The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus”. &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Bertelsmann-Stiftung. Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung, 2009. 533-585.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2009). The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 533-585). Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Schäfer, H. (2009). “The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus” in &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;, Bertelsmann-Stiftung ed. (Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung), 533-585.</frontiers>
<wels>Schäfer, H. (2009): The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In: Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Hrsg.):  What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008. Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung.  S. 533-585.</wels>
<default>Schäfer H (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008. Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Ed);  Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung:  533-585.</default>
<harvard1>Schäfer, H., 2009. The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In Bertelsmann-Stiftung, ed. &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;.  Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung, pp. 533-585.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Schäfer, “The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus”, &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;, Bertelsmann-Stiftung, ed.,  Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung, 2009,  pp.533-585.</ieee>
<apa>Schäfer, H. (2009). The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 533-585). Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2009). The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt; (S. 533-585). Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Schäfer, in &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: Bertelsmann-Stiftung), Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung, Gütersloh, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 533-585.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schäfer H (2009) &lt;br /&gt;The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. &lt;br /&gt;In:  What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008. Bertelsmann-Stiftung (Ed); Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung:  533-585.</bio1>
<ama>Schäfer H. The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In: Bertelsmann-Stiftung, ed. &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;. Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung;  2009: 533-585.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, Heinrich. 2009. “The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus”. In &lt;em&gt;What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Bertelsmann-Stiftung, 533-585. Gütersloh: Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schäfer, H.: The Pentecostal Movement - Social Transformation and Religious Habitus. In: Bertelsmann-Stiftung (ed.) What the World Believes: Analysis and Commentary on the Religion Monitor 2008. p. 533-585. Verlag Bertelsmann Stiftung, Gütersloh (2009).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1862058</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-29T12:56:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>