<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1862056</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schäfer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">3971812</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1140-6175</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Steve</namePart><namePart type="family">Gramley</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart><namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schaefer_2009_Praxeological-Square.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1862056/2425629/Schaefer_2009_Praxeological-Square.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Aisthesis</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-89528-753-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18620562</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">6-20</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Schäfer H (2009) &lt;br /&gt;The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience. Gramley S, Schneider R (Eds); The Bielefeld English and American Studies, 2. Bielefeld: Aisthesis:  6-20.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Schäfer, in &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Gramley, R. Schneider), Aisthesis, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 6-20.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2009). The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements (The Bielefeld English and American Studies). In S. Gramley &amp;amp; R. Schneider (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt; (S. 6-20). Bielefeld: Aisthesis.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, Heinrich. 2009. “The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements”. In &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Steve Gramley and Ralf Schneider, 2:6-20. The Bielefeld English and American Studies. Bielefeld: Aisthesis.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schäfer, H.: The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In: Gramley, S. and Schneider, R. (eds.) Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience. The Bielefeld English and American Studies. 2, p. 6-20. Aisthesis, Bielefeld (2009).</lncs>
<ama>Schäfer H. The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In: Gramley S, Schneider R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;. The Bielefeld English and American Studies. Vol 2. Bielefeld: Aisthesis;  2009: 6-20.</ama>
<default>Schäfer H (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience. Gramley S, Schneider R (Eds);  The Bielefeld English and American Studies, 2.  Bielefeld: Aisthesis:  6-20.</default>
<mla>Schäfer, Heinrich. “The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements”. &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Steve Gramley and Ralf Schneider. Bielefeld: Aisthesis, 2009.Vol. 2. The Bielefeld English and American Studies. 6-20.</mla>
<frontiers>Schäfer, H. (2009). “The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements” in &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;, Gramley, S., and Schneider, R. eds. The Bielefeld English and American Studies, vol. 2, (Bielefeld: Aisthesis), 6-20.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schäfer, H. (2009). The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In S.  Gramley &amp;amp; R.  Schneider (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Bielefeld English and American Studies: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 6-20). Bielefeld: Aisthesis.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Schäfer, H. (2009): The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In: Steve Gramley; Ralf Schneider (Hrsg.):  Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience. Bielefeld: Aisthesis. (The Bielefeld English and American Studies, 2).  S. 6-20.</wels>
<apa>Schäfer, H. (2009). The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In S.  Gramley &amp;amp; R.  Schneider (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Bielefeld English and American Studies: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 6-20). Bielefeld: Aisthesis.</apa>
<ieee> H. Schäfer, “The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements”, &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;, S. Gramley and R. Schneider, eds., The Bielefeld English and American Studies, vol. 2,  Bielefeld: Aisthesis, 2009,  pp.6-20.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schäfer, H., 2009. The praxeological square as a method for the intercultural study of religious movements. In S.  Gramley &amp;amp; R.  Schneider, eds. &lt;em&gt;Cultures in Process: Encounter and Experience&lt;/em&gt;. The Bielefeld English and American Studies. no.2  Bielefeld: Aisthesis, pp. 6-20.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1862056</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-04T14:00:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>