<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1869312</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus-Gerhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reinhold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">133426</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685497</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">To analyse spermatophore function, various aspects of the mating behaviour (e.g. spermatophore mass, duration of sperm transfer, mating frequency) were compared in two subspecies of the bushcricket P. veluchianus. Body mass was significantly different in both subspecies and had a strong effect on spermatophore mass, resulting in a large difference in absolute and relative (percentage of male body mass) spermatophore mass in both subspecies. After copulation the small P. v. minor spermatophores were consumed much faster by the female than the larger ones of P. v. veluchianus. The time necessary for sperm transfer from the spermatophore to the female spermatheca was much shorter in the subspecies with small spermatophores than in that with large spermatophores, and in both subspecies similar to the time required to consume the spermatophores. Mating frequency varied also between the subspecies and was murh higher in P. v. minor than in P. v. veluchianus. Differences in body mass between the two subspecies therefore resulted in changes in several aspects of mating behaviour. However, despite large differences in the mass of the spermatophore, its main function seems to be to ensure sperm transfer. This can be concluded from the similarity between the duration of sperm transfer and the time period necessary for spermatophore consumption in each of the subspecies. The spermatophore is thus considered to be male mating effort.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Reinhold_02.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1869312/2315015/Reinhold_02.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley Blackwell (Blackwell Publishing)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>acoustic communication</topic><topic>mating efforts</topic><topic>sperm transfer</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biological Journal of the Linnean Society</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0024-4066</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18693124</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>53</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">153-163</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heller, K.-G. &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (1994). Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(2), 153-163. Wiley Blackwell (Blackwell Publishing). doi:10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Heller K-G, Reinhold K (1994) &lt;br /&gt;Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies.&lt;br /&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society 53(2): 153-163.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K. - G.  Heller, and K.  Reinhold, “Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies”, &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;, 153-163.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Heller K-G, Reinhold K. Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;. 1994;53(2):153-163.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heller, Klaus-Gerhard, and Reinhold, Klaus. 1994. “Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies”. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt; 53 (2): 153-163.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Heller, K.-G., Reinhold, K.: Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. Biological Journal of the Linnean Society. 53, 153-163 (1994).</lncs>
<mla>Heller, Klaus-Gerhard, and Reinhold, Klaus. “Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies”. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt; 53.2 (1994): 153-163.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heller, K. - G., &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (1994). Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(2), 153-163. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Heller, K. - G., and Reinhold, K. (1994). Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt; 53, 153-163.</frontiers>
<wels>Heller, K. - G.; Reinhold, K. (1994): Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;,53:(2): 153-163.</wels>
<default>Heller K-G, Reinhold K (1994) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt; 53(2): 153-163.</default>
<ieee> K.-G. Heller and K. Reinhold, “Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies”, &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 53, 1994,  pp. 153-163.</ieee>
<harvard1>Heller, K.-G., &amp;amp; Reinhold, K., 1994. Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;, 53(2), p 153-163.</harvard1>
<apa>Heller, K. - G., &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (1994). Mating effort function of the spermatophore in the bushcricket Poecilimon veluchianus (Orthoptera, Phaneropteridae): Support from a comparison of the mating behaviour of two subspecies. &lt;em&gt;Biological Journal of the Linnean Society&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(2), 153-163. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1095-8312.1994.tb01006.x&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1869312</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-11-22T12:51:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>