<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1871529</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:650</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Xuemin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zhao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinhold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Decker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">140238</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2972-6182</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29895914</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper analyzes critically five basic theories on market entry mode decision with respect to existing strengths and weaknesses and the results of corresponding empirical studies. Starting from conflictions both in theories and empirical studies dealing with the entry mode choice problem we motivate a significant need of further research in this important area of international marketing. Furthermore we provide implications for managers in practice and outline emerging trends in market entry mode theory as well as possible starting points for future research.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="m_entry.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1871529/2315315/m_entry.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Implications and future challenges</topic><topic>Conflictions</topic><topic>Market entry mode choice</topic><topic>Existing theories and empirical studies</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-5072</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>512</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Zhao, X., Decker, R.: Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, 512. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zhao, Xuemin, and Decker, Reinhold. 2004. &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 512. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Zhao, X., &amp;amp; Decker, R. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, 512). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ama>Zhao X, Decker R. &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Vol 512. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2004.</ama>
<ieee> X. Zhao and R. Decker, &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, vol. 512,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2004.</ieee>
<harvard1>Zhao, X., &amp;amp; Decker, R., 2004. &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, no.512, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Zhao X, Decker R (2004) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld; 512.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>X.  Zhao, and R.  Decker, &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Zhao X, Decker R (2004)  Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld; 512.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<frontiers>Zhao, X., and Decker, R. (2004). Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies. &lt;em&gt;Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, 512, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zhao, X., &amp;amp; Decker, R. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, 512). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Zhao, Xuemin, and Decker, Reinhold. &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2004. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. 512.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zhao, X. &amp;amp; Decker, R. (2004). &lt;em&gt;Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Zhao, X.; Decker, R. (2004): Choice of Foreign Market Entry Mode - Cognitions from Empirical and Theoretical Studies. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1871529</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-03-23T12:32:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>