<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1874478</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Regtmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">148272</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thanh Tu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Duong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eichhorn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anselmetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40180</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8720-4369</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reimann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">70631</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ros</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Klavs F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Jensen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29105470</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33079524</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29125395</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>9th International Conference on Miniaturized Systems for Chemical and Life Sciences</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Microfluidic and lab-on-a-chip devices have gained widespread attendance in separation sciences since they are characterized by advantageous properties like a gain in throughput, time, cost, performance and analyte amount. Beyond these advantages, microfluidic devices open access to completely new separation or particle sorting phenomena far from thermal equilibrium based on Brownian motion and non linear dynamics induced through microstructuring. Here, we demonstrate the migration phenomena of absolute negative mobility (ANM) for colloidal particles in structured microfluidic devices and discuss its application for separation of particles and biomolecules, such as DNA.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="regtmeier_utas2005.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1874478/2315021/regtmeier_utas2005.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Boston, MA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Structured microchannel</topic><topic>Brownian motion</topic><topic>Non equilibrium</topic><topic>Separation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-9743611-1-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-141</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">340-342</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Regtmeier, J., Duong, T. T., Eichhorn, R., Anselmetti, D., Reimann, P., &amp;amp; Ros, A. (2005). Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In K. F.  Jensen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS): Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 340-342). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).</apa>
<harvard1>Regtmeier, J., et al., 2005. Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In K. F.  Jensen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). no.1  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), pp. 340-342.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Regtmeier, et al., “Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices”, &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, K.F. Jensen, ed., Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), vol. 1,  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 2005,  pp.340-342.</ieee>
<default>Regtmeier J, Duong TT, Eichhorn R, Anselmetti D, Reimann P, Ros A (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Jensen KF (Ed);  Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1.  Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS):  340-342.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Regtmeier, J., Duong, T. T., Eichhorn, R., Anselmetti, D., Reimann, P., &amp;amp; Ros, A. (2005). Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In K. F.  Jensen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS): Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 340-342). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Regtmeier, Jan, Duong, Thanh Tu, Eichhorn, Ralf, Anselmetti, Dario, Reimann, Peter, and Ros, Alexandra. “Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices”. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Klavs F. Jensen. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 2005.Vol. 1. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). 340-342.</mla>
<frontiers>Regtmeier, J., Duong, T. T., Eichhorn, R., Anselmetti, D., Reimann, P., and Ros, A. (2005). “Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices” in &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, Jensen, K. F. ed. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), vol. 1, (Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), 340-342.</frontiers>
<wels>Regtmeier, J.; Duong, T. T.; Eichhorn, R.; Anselmetti, D.; Reimann, P.; Ros, A. (2005): Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In: Klavs F. Jensen (Hrsg.):  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS). (Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1).  S. 340-342.</wels>
<lncs> Regtmeier, J., Duong, T.T., Eichhorn, R., Anselmetti, D., Reimann, P., Ros, A.: Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In: Jensen, K.F. (ed.) Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). 1, p. 340-342. The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS), Boston (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Regtmeier, Jan, Duong, Thanh Tu, Eichhorn, Ralf, Anselmetti, Dario, Reimann, Peter, and Ros, Alexandra. 2005. “Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices”. In &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Klavs F. Jensen, 1:340-342. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Regtmeier J, Duong TT, Eichhorn R, Anselmetti D, Reimann P, Ros A. Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. In: Jensen KF, ed. &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). Vol 1. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS);  2005: 340-342.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Regtmeier, T. T.  Duong, R.  Eichhorn, D.  Anselmetti, P.  Reimann, and A.  Ros, in &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: K.F. Jensen), The Chemical And Biological Microsystems Society (Cbms), Boston, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 340-342.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Regtmeier J, Duong TT, Eichhorn R, Anselmetti D, Reimann P, Ros A (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005. Jensen KF (Ed); Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS), 1. Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS):  340-342.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Regtmeier, J., Duong, T.T., Eichhorn, R., Anselmetti, D., Reimann, P. &amp;amp; Ros, A. (2005). Novel Migration Phenomena in Structured Microfluidic Devices (Conference Proceedings on Miniaturized Systems for Chemistry and Life Sciences (µTAS). In K.F. Jensen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Micro total analysis systems 2005. Proceedings of µTAS 2005&lt;/em&gt; (S. 340-342). Gehalten auf der 9th International Conference on Miniaturized Systems for Chemical and Life Sciences, Boston: The Chemical and Biological Microsystems Society (CBMS).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1874478</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-20T15:31:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>