<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1881757</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:200</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3633-4785</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hans-Günter</namePart><namePart type="family">Heimbrock</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christoph T.</namePart><namePart type="family">Scheilke</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Schreiner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="InterreligiousNegotiations.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1881757/2315025/InterreligiousNegotiations.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Interrel-Negotiations">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1881757/2231596/Interrel-Negotiations</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Lit Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-8258-5015-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-33311</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">129-149</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Streib, H. (2001): Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In: Hans-Günter Heimbrock; Christoph T. Scheilke; Peter Schreiner (Hrsg.):  Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe. Münster: Lit Verlag. (Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut, 3).  S. 129-149.</wels>
<frontiers>Streib, H. (2001). “Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity” in &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;, Heimbrock, H. - G., Scheilke, C. T., and Schreiner, P. eds. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut, vol. 3, (Münster: Lit Verlag), 129-149.</frontiers>
<mla>Streib, Heinz. “Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity”. &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Hans-Günter Heimbrock, Christoph T. Scheilke, and Peter Schreiner. Münster: Lit Verlag, 2001.Vol. 3. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut. 129-149.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2001). Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In H. - G.  Heimbrock, C. T.  Scheilke, &amp;amp; P.  Schreiner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut: Vol. 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-149). Münster: Lit Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H. (2001). Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity (Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut). In H.-G. Heimbrock, C.T. Scheilke &amp;amp; P. Schreiner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt; (S. 129-149). Münster: Lit Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Streib H (2001)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe. Heimbrock H-G, Scheilke CT, Schreiner P (Eds);  Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut, 3.  Münster: Lit Verlag:  129-149.</default>
<bio1>Streib H (2001) &lt;br /&gt;Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe. Heimbrock H-G, Scheilke CT, Schreiner P (Eds); Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut, 3. Münster: Lit Verlag:  129-149.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Streib, in &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H.-G. Heimbrock, C.T. Scheilke, P. Schreiner), Lit Verlag, Münster, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 129-149.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> H. Streib, “Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity”, &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;, H.-G. Heimbrock, C.T. Scheilke, and P. Schreiner, eds., Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut, vol. 3,  Münster: Lit Verlag, 2001,  pp.129-149.</ieee>
<harvard1>Streib, H., 2001. Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In H. - G.  Heimbrock, C. T.  Scheilke, &amp;amp; P.  Schreiner, eds. &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut. no.3  Münster: Lit Verlag, pp. 129-149.</harvard1>
<ama>Streib H. Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In: Heimbrock H-G, Scheilke CT, Schreiner P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut. Vol 3. Münster: Lit Verlag;  2001: 129-149.</ama>
<apa>Streib, H. (2001). Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In H. - G.  Heimbrock, C. T.  Scheilke, &amp;amp; P.  Schreiner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut: Vol. 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-149). Münster: Lit Verlag.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, Heinz. 2001. “Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity”. In &lt;em&gt;Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Hans-Günter Heimbrock, Christoph T. Scheilke, and Peter Schreiner, 3:129-149. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut. Münster: Lit Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Streib, H.: Inter-Religious Negotiations: Case Studies on Students' Perception of and Dealing With Religious Diversity. In: Heimbrock, H.-G., Scheilke, C.T., and Schreiner, P. (eds.) Towards Religious Competence. Diversity as a Challenge for Education in Europe. Schriften aus dem Comenius-Institut. 3, p. 129-149. Lit Verlag, Münster (2001).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1881757</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-24T13:48:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>