<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1881506</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grüne</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Willi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Semmler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41183</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sieveking</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The paper studies a credit market model with endogenous credit cost and debt constraints in which multiple candidates for steady state equilibria arise. We use dynamic programming (DP) with exible grid size to locate thresholds that separate different domains of attraction. More specifically, we employ DP to (1) compute present value borrowing constraints and thus creditworthiness, (2) locate thresholds where the dynamics separate to different domains of attraction, (3) distinguish between optimal and non-optimal steady states and (5) demonstrate how the thresholds change with change of the credit cost function of the debtor and (6) explore the impact of debt ceilings and consumption paths on creditworthiness. The analytics is provided for a general model and some generic results are presented for a one state variable problem.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="482.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1881506/2315323/482.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-870</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Grüne L, Semmler W, Sieveking M (2001)  Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grüne, L., Semmler, W., &amp;amp; Sieveking, M. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Grüne, Lars, Semmler, Willi, and Sieveking, Malte. &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, 2001. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</mla>
<frontiers>Grüne, L., Semmler, W., and Sieveking, M. (2001). Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria. &lt;em&gt;Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<wels>Grüne, L.; Semmler, W.; Sieveking, M. (2001): Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria. Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa>Grüne, L., Semmler, W., &amp;amp; Sieveking, M. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> L. Grüne, W. Semmler, and M. Sieveking, &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld,  Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, 2001.</ieee>
<harvard1>Grüne, L., Semmler, W., &amp;amp; Sieveking, M., 2001. &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Grüne L, Semmler W, Sieveking M (2001) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Grüne, W.  Semmler, and M.  Sieveking, &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Fakultät Für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grüne, L., Semmler, W. &amp;amp; Sieveking, M. (2001). &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grüne, Lars, Semmler, Willi, and Sieveking, Malte. 2001. &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Grüne, L., Semmler, W., Sieveking, M.: Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2001).</lncs>
<ama>Grüne L, Semmler W, Sieveking M. &lt;em&gt;Thresholds in a credit market model with multiple equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld; 2001.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1881506</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-16T12:17:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>