<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1890267</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8408393</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard-Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brüning</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8052516</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schnier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20814347</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holger</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dierker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9380399</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Kipp</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Claude</namePart><namePart type="family">Martin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrizia</namePart><namePart type="family">Paggio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart><namePart type="family">Heylen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">If we want to model the dynamic and contingent nature of human social interaction (e.g. for the design of human robot interaction), analysis and description of natural interaction is required that combines different methodologies and research tools (qualitative/quantitative; manual/automated). In this paper, we pinpoint the requirements and technical challenges for constituting and managing multimodal corpora that arise when linking Conversation Analysis with novel 3D motion capture technologies: i.e. to robustly track multiple participants over an extended period of time. We present and evaluate a solution to by-pass the limits of the current standard Vicon system (using rigid bodies) and ways of mapping the obtained coordinates to a human skeleton model (inverse kinematics) and to export the data into a format that is supported by standard annotation tools (such as ANVIL).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Pitsch_2010_Linking_Conversation_Analysis_and_Moti_header.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1890267/2423575/Pitsch_2010_Linking_Conversation_Analysis_and_Moti_header.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Malta, Malta</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Inverse Kinematics</topic><topic>Multiple Particpants</topic><topic>Conversation Analysis</topic><topic>Motion Capturing</topic><topic>Vicon</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18902678</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">63-69</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Pitsch K, Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Dierker H, Wachsmuth S. Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In: Kipp M, Martin J-C, Paggio P, Heylen D, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;. 2010: 63-69.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitsch, K., Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Dierker, H. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2010). Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In M. Kipp, J.-C. Martin, P. Paggio &amp;amp; D. Heylen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 63-69). Gehalten auf der Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pitsch, K., Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Dierker, H., and Wachsmuth, S. (2010). “Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants?” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;, Kipp, M., Martin, J. - C., Paggio, P., and Heylen, D. eds. 63-69.</frontiers>
<apa>Pitsch, K., Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Dierker, H., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2010). Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In M.  Kipp, J. - C.  Martin, P.  Paggio, &amp;amp; D.  Heylen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-69).</apa>
<ieee> K. Pitsch, et al., “Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants?”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;, M. Kipp, et al., eds., 2010,  pp.63-69.</ieee>
<wels>Pitsch, K.; Brüning, B. - A.; Schnier, C.; Dierker, H.; Wachsmuth, S. (2010): Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In: Michael Kipp; Jean-Claude Martin; Patrizia Paggio; Dirk Heylen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010).  S. 63-69.</wels>
<bio1>Pitsch K, Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Dierker H, Wachsmuth S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010). Kipp M, Martin J-C, Paggio P, Heylen D (Eds); 63-69.</bio1>
<harvard1>Pitsch, K., et al., 2010. Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In M.  Kipp, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 63-69.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitsch, K., Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Dierker, H., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2010). Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In M.  Kipp, J. - C.  Martin, P.  Paggio, &amp;amp; D.  Heylen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-69).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Pitsch, B. - A.  Brüning, C.  Schnier, H.  Dierker, and S.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Kipp, J.-C. Martin, P. Paggio, D. Heylen), &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 63-69.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Pitsch, K., Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Dierker, H., Wachsmuth, S.: Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants? In: Kipp, M., Martin, J.-C., Paggio, P., and Heylen, D. (eds.) Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010). p. 63-69. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitsch, Karola, Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Dierker, Holger, and Wachsmuth, Sven. 2010. “Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants?”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michael Kipp, Jean-Claude Martin, Patrizia Paggio, and Dirk Heylen, 63-69.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Pitsch, Karola, Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Dierker, Holger, and Wachsmuth, Sven. “Linking Conversation Analysis and Motion Capturing: How to robustly track multiple participants?”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michael Kipp, Jean-Claude Martin, Patrizia Paggio, and Dirk Heylen. 2010. 63-69.</mla>
<default>Pitsch K, Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Dierker H, Wachsmuth S (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality (MMC 2010). Kipp M, Martin J-C, Paggio P, Heylen D (Eds);   63-69.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1890267</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-02T08:39:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>