<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1894513</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marco</namePart><namePart type="family">Schumann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Torsten</namePart><namePart type="family">Kuhlen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27003888</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Of all senses, it is visual perception that is predominantly deluded in Virtual Realities. Yet, the eyes of the observer, despite the fact that they are the fastest perceivable moving body part, have gotten relatively little attention as an interaction modality. A solid integration of gaze, however, provides great opportunities for implicit and explicit human-computer interaction. We present our work on integrating a lightweight head-mounted eye tracking system in a CAVE-like Virtual Reality Set-Up and provide promising data from a user study on the achieved accuracy and latency.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2008_-_Pfeiffer_-_Towards_Gaze_Interaction_in_Immersive_Virtual_Reality.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1894513/2644776/2008_-_Pfeiffer_-_Towards_Gaze_Interaction_in_Immersive_Virtual_Reality.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Shaker Verlag GmbH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Gaze-based Interaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-8322-7572-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18945131</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">81-92</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Pfeiffer, T. (2008). Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In M.  Schumann &amp;amp; T.  Kuhlen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Berichte aus der Informatik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 81-92). Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH.</apa>
<ieee> T. Pfeiffer, “Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up”, &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, M. Schumann and T. Kuhlen, eds., Berichte aus der Informatik,  Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH, 2008,  pp.81-92.</ieee>
<harvard1>Pfeiffer, T., 2008. Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In M.  Schumann &amp;amp; T.  Kuhlen, eds. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;. Berichte aus der Informatik.  Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH, pp. 81-92.</harvard1>
<default>Pfeiffer T (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Schumann M, Kuhlen T (Eds);  Berichte aus der Informatik.  Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH:  81-92.</default>
<wels>Pfeiffer, T. (2008): Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In: Marco Schumann; Torsten Kuhlen (Hrsg.):  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH. (Berichte aus der Informatik, ).  S. 81-92.</wels>
<mla>Pfeiffer, Thies. “Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up”. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Marco Schumann and Torsten Kuhlen. Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH, 2008. Berichte aus der Informatik. 81-92.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T. (2008). Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In M.  Schumann &amp;amp; T.  Kuhlen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Berichte aus der Informatik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 81-92). Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Pfeiffer, T. (2008). “Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up” in &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, Schumann, M., and Kuhlen, T. eds. Berichte aus der Informatik (Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH), 81-92.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, Thies. 2008. “Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up”. In &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Marco Schumann and Torsten Kuhlen, 81-92. Berichte aus der Informatik. Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pfeiffer, T.: Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In: Schumann, M. and Kuhlen, T. (eds.) Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Berichte aus der Informatik. p. 81-92. Shaker Verlag GmbH, Aachen (2008).</lncs>
<ama>Pfeiffer T. Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. In: Schumann M, Kuhlen T, eds. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;. Berichte aus der Informatik. Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH;  2008: 81-92.</ama>
<bio1>Pfeiffer T (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Schumann M, Kuhlen T (Eds); Berichte aus der Informatik,  Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH:  81-92.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Pfeiffer, in &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Schumann, T. Kuhlen), Shaker Verlag Gmbh, Aachen, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 81-92.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T. (2008). Towards Gaze Interaction in Immersive Virtual Reality: Evaluation of a Monocular Eye Tracking Set-Up (Berichte aus der Informatik). In M. Schumann &amp;amp; T. Kuhlen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität - Fünfter Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (S. 81-92). Aachen: Shaker Verlag GmbH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1894513</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-03T10:05:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>