<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1894327</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bovermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">143296</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eckard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedenklau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10270455</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andy</namePart><namePart type="family">Hunt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present a novel tangible computing system for interactively controlling real-time and offline data sonifications. Tangible objects serve as physical correlates for data series such as EEG channels, and their arrangement on our Tangible Desk (tDesk) surface is used to interactively explore features of interest in the real-time rendered sonifications. A listener object and its distances to channel objects are used to select how salient the channels’ sonic representation is in the overall sonification. Selector objects serve for the specification of datasets. This interface enables the user (a) to identify groups of correlated rhythmical behavior, (b) to control multiple channels simultaneously, and (c) to explore the data collaboratively in a team. We give a full account on hard-/software of the system and we demonstrate the system at hand of offline- and real-time sonification of EEG and stock market data.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannBovermannRiedenklauRitter2007tci.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1894327/2279480/HermannBovermannRiedenklauRitter2007tci.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Interactive Sonification community</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">York, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>EEG data analysis</topic><topic>Interactive Sonification</topic><topic>Tangible Computing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-18943272</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/HBRR2007-TCF</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, T.  Bovermann, E.  Riedenklau, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Hunt, T. Hermann), Interactive Sonification Community, York, U.K., &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hermann T, Bovermann T, Riedenklau E, Ritter H (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. Hunt A, Hermann T (Eds); York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Riedenklau, E., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2007). Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In A.  Hunt &amp;amp; T.  Hermann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., et al., 2007. Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In A.  Hunt &amp;amp; T.  Hermann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;.  York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.</harvard1>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Bovermann, T.; Riedenklau, E.; Ritter, H. (2007): Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In: Andy Hunt; Thomas Hermann (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.</wels>
<ieee> T. Hermann, et al., “Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, A. Hunt and T. Hermann, eds.,  York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community, 2007.</ieee>
<apa>Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Riedenklau, E., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2007). Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In A.  Hunt &amp;amp; T.  Hermann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Riedenklau, E. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2007). Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In A. Hunt &amp;amp; T. Hermann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification, York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Riedenklau, E., and Ritter, H. (2007). “Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, Hunt, A., and Hermann, T. eds. (York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community).</frontiers>
<ama>Hermann T, Bovermann T, Riedenklau E, Ritter H. Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In: Hunt A, Hermann T, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community;  2007.</ama>
<default>Hermann T, Bovermann T, Riedenklau E, Ritter H (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. Hunt A, Hermann T (Eds);  York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.</default>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Bovermann, Till, Riedenklau, Eckard, and Ritter, Helge. “Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Andy Hunt and Thomas Hermann. York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community, 2007.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Bovermann, Till, Riedenklau, Eckard, and Ritter, Helge. 2007. “Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Andy Hunt and Thomas Hermann. York, U.K.: Interactive Sonification community.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Riedenklau, E., Ritter, H.: Tangible Computing for Interactive Sonification of Multivariate Data. In: Hunt, A. and Hermann, T. (eds.) Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Interactive Sonification.  Interactive Sonification community, York, U.K. (2007).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1894327</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-03T09:23:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>