<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1900253</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herzberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eckert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This article proves a very general version of the Kirman-Sondermann [Journal of Economic Theory, 5(2):267-277, 1972] correspondence by extending the methodology of Lauwers and Van Liedekerke [Journal of Mathematical Economics, 24(3):217-237, 1995]. The paper first proposes a unified framework for the analysis of the relation between various aggregation problems and the social structure they induce, based on first-order predicate logic and model theory. Thereafter, aggregators satisfying Arrow-type rationality axioms are shown to be restricted reduced product constructions with respect to the filter of decisive coalitions; an oligarchic impossibility result follows. Under stronger assumptions, aggregators are restricted ultraproduct constructions, whence a generalized Kirman-Sondermann correspondence as well as a dictatorial impossiblity result follow.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="424.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1900253/2319751/424.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Systematicity</topic><topic>Arrow-type preference aggregation</topic><topic>Judgment aggregation</topic><topic>Ultrafilter</topic><topic>First-order predicate logic</topic><topic>Model theory</topic><topic>Filter</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-47725</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>424</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, Frederik, and Eckert, Daniel. 2009. &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 424. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herzberg, F., Eckert, D.: General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 424. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2009).</lncs>
<default>Herzberg F, Eckert D (2009)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 424.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Herzberg, Frederik, and Eckert, Daniel. &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 424.</mla>
<wels>Herzberg, F.; Eckert, D. (2009): General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Herzberg, and D.  Eckert, &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Herzberg F, Eckert D (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 424.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F., &amp;amp; Eckert, D. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 424). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Herzberg, F., &amp;amp; Eckert, D., 2009. &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.424, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Herzberg, F., and Eckert, D. (2009). General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 424, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. &amp;amp; Eckert, D. (2009). &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Herzberg F, Eckert D. &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 424. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2009.</ama>
<ieee> F. Herzberg and D. Eckert, &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 424,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009.</ieee>
<apa>Herzberg, F., &amp;amp; Eckert, D. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;General aggregation problems and social structure: A model-theoretic generalisation of the Kirman-Sondermann correspondence&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 424). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1900253</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-03T23:26:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>