<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1901698</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wiebe</namePart><namePart type="family">van der Hoek</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gal A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaminka</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Luck</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sandip</namePart><namePart type="family">Sen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>AAMAS 2010 – 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Speakers in dialogue tend to adapt to each other by starting to use similar lexical items, syntactic structures, or gestures. This behaviour, called alignment, may serve important cognitive, communicative and social functions (such as speech facilitation, grounding and rapport). Our aim is to enable and study the effects of these subtle aspects of communication in virtual conversational agents. Building upon a model for autonomous speech and gesture generation, we describe an approach to make the agent's multimodal behaviour adaptive in an interactive manner. This includes (1) an activation-based microplanner that makes linguistic choices based on lexical and syntactic priming, and (2) an empirically grounded gesture generation such that linguistic priming parallels concordant gestural adaptation. First results show that the agent aligns to its interaction partners by picking up their syntactic structures and lexical items in its subsequent utterances. These changes in the agent's verbal behaviour also have a direct influence on gestural expressions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Buschmeier_etal_2010_AAMAS.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1901698/2315033/Buschmeier_etal_2010_AAMAS.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Toronto, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>multimodal interaction</topic><topic>modelling natural language</topic><topic>verbal and non-verbal expressiveness</topic><topic>interactive alignment</topic><topic>user-adaptated interaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-46120</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">91-98</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Buschmeier, H.; Bergmann, K.; Kopp, S. (2010): Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In: Wiebe van der Hoek; Gal A. Kaminka; Michael Luck; Sandip Sen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems. International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems.  S. 91-98.</wels>
<harvard1>Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2010. Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In W.  van der Hoek, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, pp. 91-98.</harvard1>
<bio1>Buschmeier H, Bergmann K, Kopp S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems. van der Hoek W, Kaminka GA, Luck M, Sen S (Eds); International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems:  91-98.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In W.  van der Hoek, G. A.  Kaminka, M.  Luck, &amp;amp; S.  Sen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 91-98). International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Buschmeier, K.  Bergmann, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: W. van der Hoek, G.A. Kaminka, M. Luck, S. Sen), International Foundation For Autonomous Agents And Multiagent Systems, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 91-98.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Buschmeier H, Bergmann K, Kopp S. Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In: van der Hoek W, Kaminka GA, Luck M, Sen S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems;  2010: 91-98.</ama>
<frontiers>Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K., and Kopp, S. (2010). “Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, van der Hoek, W., Kaminka, G. A., Luck, M., and Sen, S. eds. (International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems), 91-98.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In W. van der Hoek, G.A. Kaminka, M. Luck &amp;amp; S. Sen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 91-98). Gehalten auf der AAMAS 2010 – 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In W.  van der Hoek, G. A.  Kaminka, M.  Luck, &amp;amp; S.  Sen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 91-98). International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems.</apa>
<ieee> H. Buschmeier, K. Bergmann, and S. Kopp, “Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, W. van der Hoek, et al., eds., International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, 2010,  pp.91-98.</ieee>
<lncs> Buschmeier, H., Bergmann, K., Kopp, S.: Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner. In: van der Hoek, W., Kaminka, G.A., Luck, M., and Sen, S. (eds.) Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems. p. 91-98. International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Buschmeier, Hendrik, Bergmann, Kirsten, and Kopp, Stefan. 2010. “Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Wiebe van der Hoek, Gal A. Kaminka, Michael Luck, and Sandip Sen, 91-98. International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Buschmeier, Hendrik, Bergmann, Kirsten, and Kopp, Stefan. “Adaptive Expressiveness – Virtual Conversational Agents That Can Align to Their Interaction Partner”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Wiebe van der Hoek, Gal A. Kaminka, Michael Luck, and Sandip Sen. International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, 2010. 91-98.</mla>
<default>Buschmeier H, Bergmann K, Kopp S (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems. van der Hoek W, Kaminka GA, Luck M, Sen S (Eds);  International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems:  91-98.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1901698</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-15T10:19:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>