<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1912695</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:572</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kleindt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182435</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stracke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">101395</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9261-2279</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mehrtens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weisshaar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">86212</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7635-3473</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684836</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070678</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background:

The coordinated activity of different flavonoid biosynthesis genes in Arabidopsis thaliana results in tissue-specific accumulation of flavonols, anthocyanins and proanthocyanidins (PAs). These compounds possess diverse functions in plants including light-attenuation and oxidative stress protection. Flavonoids accumulate in a stimulus- and/or development-dependent manner in specific parts of the plant. PAs accumulate in the seed coat (testa).
Findings:

We describe the biological material and the preparation of total RNA for the AtGenExpress developmental silique and seed series. AtGenExpress ATH1 GeneChip expression data from the different stages were reanalyzed and verified using quantitative real time PCR (qPCR). We observed organ-specific transcript accumulation of specific flavonoid biosynthetic genes consistent with previously published data and our PA compound accumulation data. In addition, we investigated the regulation of PA accumulation in developing A. thaliana seeds by correlating gene expression patterns of specific flavonoid biosynthesis genes with different seed embryonic developmental stages and organs and present two useful marker genes for isolated valve and replum organs, as well as one seed-specific marker.
Conclusions:

Potential caveats of array-based expression data are discussed based on comparisons with qPCR data. Results from ATH1 microarray and qPCR experiments revealed a shift in gene activity from general flavonoid biosynthesis at early stages of seed development to PA synthesis at late (mature) stages of embryogenesis. The examined PA accumulation-associated genes, including biosynthetic and regulatory genes, were found to be exclusively expressed in immature seeds. Accumulation of PAs initiates at the early heart stage of silique and seed development. Our findings provide new insights for further studies targeting the PA pathway in seeds.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1756-0500-3-255.kleindt.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1912695/2465713/1756-0500-3-255.kleindt.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Research Notes</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1756-0500</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">20929528</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19126957</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-3-255</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kleindt, Christiane Katja, Stracke, Ralf, Mehrtens, Frank, and Weisshaar, Bernd. 2010. “Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3 (1): 255.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kleindt, C.K., Stracke, R., Mehrtens, F., Weisshaar, B.: Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. BMC Research Notes. 3, : 255 (2010).</lncs>
<default>Kleindt CK, Stracke R, Mehrtens F, Weisshaar B (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3(1): 255.</default>
<mla>Kleindt, Christiane Katja, Stracke, Ralf, Mehrtens, Frank, and Weisshaar, Bernd. “Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3.1 (2010): 255.</mla>
<wels>Kleindt, C. K.; Stracke, R.; Mehrtens, F.; Weisshaar, B. (2010): Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,3:(1):255</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>C. K.  Kleindt, R.  Stracke, F.  Mehrtens, and B.  Weisshaar, “Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, : 255.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kleindt CK, Stracke R, Mehrtens F, Weisshaar B (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Research Notes 3(1): 255.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kleindt, C. K., Stracke, R., Mehrtens, F., &amp;amp; Weisshaar, B. (2010). Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1), 255. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-255" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-255&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kleindt, C.K., et al., 2010. Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, 3(1): 255.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kleindt, C.K., Stracke, R., Mehrtens, F. &amp;amp; Weisshaar, B. (2010). Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1): 255. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1756-0500-3-255.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kleindt, C. K., Stracke, R., Mehrtens, F., and Weisshaar, B. (2010). Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3:255.</frontiers>
<ama>Kleindt CK, Stracke R, Mehrtens F, Weisshaar B. Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;. 2010;3(1): 255.</ama>
<ieee> C.K. Kleindt, et al., “Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 3, 2010, : 255.</ieee>
<apa>Kleindt, C. K., Stracke, R., Mehrtens, F., &amp;amp; Weisshaar, B. (2010). Expression analysis of flavonoid biosynthesis genes during Arabidopsis thaliana silique and seed development with a primary focus on the proanthocyanidin biosynthetic pathway. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1), 255. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-255" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-255&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1912695</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-10T13:57:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>