<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1916796</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Speech Prosody</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper examines the acoustic and perceptual properties of iambic vs. trochaic meter in a large corpus of read German poetry. Psychoacoustic evidence of metrical grouping is not straightforwardly applicable to speech, due to the complex interaction of the involved acoustic parameters in prominence expression. It is possible that grouping effects in (poetic) speech are merely an artifact of listeners’ expectations based on rhythmic alternations previously heard. Empirical ﬁndings show small but signiﬁcant duration differences between iambic and
trochaic feet. Furthermore, it was found that stressed and unstressed syllables are produced with a stable phase relationship of 3:2, independent of meter. Experience in poetry reading plays a role in production style. On the level of prosodic prominence, only subtle differences can be traced. Our ﬁndings do not provide convincing evidence for meter speciﬁc prosodic shapes and are compatible with an affordance based dynamic view of rhythmic structure.

Index Terms: grouping, rhythm, prominence, meter</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="sp2010_wagner.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1916796/2424458/sp2010_wagner.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Chicago</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19167966</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">P1.47</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., 2010. Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. pp. P1.47.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Wagner, “Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry.”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, 2010,  pp.P1.47.</ieee>
<apa>Wagner, P. (2010). Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P1.47.</apa>
<mla>Wagner, Petra. “Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry.”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. 2010. P1.47.</mla>
<frontiers>Wagner, P. (2010). “Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry.” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt; P1.47.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. (2010). Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P1.47.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Wagner, P. (2010): Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. In: Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  S. P1.47.</wels>
<default>Wagner P (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  P1.47.</default>
<ama>Wagner P. Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. 2010: P1.47.</ama>
<lncs> Wagner, P.: Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010. p. P1.47. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra. 2010. “Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry.”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P1.47.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. (2010). Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt; (S. P1.47). Gehalten auf der Speech Prosody.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. P1.47.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wagner P (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Two Sides of the Same Coin? Investigating Iambic and Trochaic Timing and Prominence in German Poetry. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  P1.47.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1916796</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T10:41:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>