<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917019</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this study, rhythmic alternations in German read speech have been examined on prosodic phrase level. Based on statistical examinations and phonological theory, several hypotheses concerning the status of rhythm rules and word−class related prominence have been formulated, formalized and implemented. The predictions made by these rules were compared with speaker’s judgements on
perceptual prominence patterns in a prosodic database of read speech. The basic outcomes of this study are the following: If the predictions are based upon different levels of prominence depending on lexical class, the correlation between predicted and perceived prominences lies within the range of different speakers’ correlations. Stress clashes hardly ever occur on the basis of this (successful) method.
Speakers of German tend to fill rhythmical gaps, especially in polysyllabic words. An FST modelling
the filling of rhythmical gaps improves the predictions the algorithm.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SP00_wagner.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917019/2352658/SP00_wagner.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19170198</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">237-245</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. (2000). Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt; (S. 237-245).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 237-245.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wagner P (2000) &lt;br /&gt;Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling.  237-245.</bio1>
<ama>Wagner P. Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;. 2000: 237-245.</ama>
<lncs> Wagner, P.: Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling. p. 237-245. (2000).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra. 2000. “Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;, 237-245.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Wagner, P. (2000): Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. In: Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling.  S. 237-245.</wels>
<mla>Wagner, Petra. “Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;. 2000. 237-245.</mla>
<frontiers>Wagner, P. (2000). “Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt; 237-245.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. (2000). Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;, 237-245.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Wagner P (2000)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling.  237-245.</default>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., 2000. Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 237-245.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Wagner, “Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;, 2000,  pp.237-245.</ieee>
<apa>Wagner, P. (2000). Rhythmical Alternations in German read speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Prosody 2000. Special Session on Intonational Modeling&lt;/em&gt;, 237-245.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917019</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T15:58:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>