<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917053</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Denis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arnold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Möbius</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Speech Prosody 2010</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In previous research we showed that the priming paradigm can be used to significantly alter the prominence ratings of subjects. In that study we only looked at the changes in the subjects’ ratings. In the present study, we analyzed the acoustic parameters of the stimuli used in the priming study and investigated the correlation between prominence ratings and acoustic parameters. The results show that priming has a significant effect on these correlations. The contribution of acoustic features on perceived prominence was found to depend on the prominence pattern. If a dominantly prominent syllable is present in a given utterance, f0 and intensity contribute most to the perceived prominence, while duration contributes most when no syllable is dominantly prominent.

Index Terms: syllable, prominence, priming, acoustic correlates</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Prominence_2010_ARNOLD.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917053/2348688/Prominence_2010_ARNOLD.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Chicago</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19170536</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">W1.02</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Arnold D, Wagner P, Möbius B (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop).  W1.02.</default>
<wels>Arnold, D.; Wagner, P.; Möbius, B. (2010): The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. In: Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop).  S. W1.02.</wels>
<mla>Arnold, Denis, Wagner, Petra, and Möbius, Bernd. “The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features”. &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;. 2010. W1.02.</mla>
<frontiers>Arnold, D., Wagner, P., and Möbius, B. (2010). “The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features” in &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt; W1.02.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arnold, D., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Möbius, B. (2010). The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;, W1.02.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Arnold, D., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Möbius, B. (2010). The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;, W1.02.</apa>
<harvard1>Arnold, D., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Möbius, B., 2010. The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. In &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. W1.02.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Arnold, P. Wagner, and B. Möbius, “The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features”, &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;, 2010,  pp.W1.02.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Arnold, P.  Wagner, and B.  Möbius, in &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. W1.02.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Arnold D, Wagner P, Möbius B (2010) &lt;br /&gt;The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop).  W1.02.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arnold, D., Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Möbius, B. (2010). The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt; (S. W1.02). Gehalten auf der Speech Prosody 2010.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Arnold, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B.: The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop). p. W1.02. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arnold, Denis, Wagner, Petra, and Möbius, Bernd. 2010. “The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features”. In &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;, W1.02.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Arnold D, Wagner P, Möbius B. The effect of priming on the correlations between prominence ratings and acoustic features. In:  &lt;em&gt;Prosodic Prominence: Perceptual and Automatic Identification (Speech Prosody 2010 Workshop)&lt;/em&gt;. 2010: W1.02.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917053</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T15:58:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>