<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917220</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kühnlein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Recent rethinking of the Phonetics/Phonology-Interface has come to drop the old notion of a syntactic relationship between both research domains and replaced it by a semantic one. However, it remained relatively unclear how this relationship ought to look like. Progress in diagrammatic reasoning provides a fruitful approach towards a mutually constraining interface description. But to utilise this tool we first have to argue that it is reasonable to suppose a common ontology of a certain variant for both fiels of research. This is so, bacause the heterogenous logics-approach attempted here relies on the sharing of models.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fhcg98_wagner.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917220/2352670/fhcg98_wagner.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19172208</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-10</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Wagner, P.; Kühnlein, P. (1998): A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. In: Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar. Saarbrücken, Germany.  S. 1-10.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Kühnlein, P. (1998). A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Saarbrücken, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Wagner, P., and Kühnlein, P. (1998). “A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt; (Saarbrücken, Germany), 1-10.</frontiers>
<mla>Wagner, Petra, and Kühnlein, Peter. “A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;. Saarbrücken, Germany, 1998. 1-10.</mla>
<default>Wagner P, Kühnlein P (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar. Saarbrücken, Germany:  1-10.</default>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Kühnlein, P., 1998. A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;.  Saarbrücken, Germany, pp. 1-10.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Wagner and P. Kühnlein, “A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;,  Saarbrücken, Germany: 1998,  pp.1-10.</ieee>
<apa>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Kühnlein, P. (1998). A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Saarbrücken, Germany.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Kühnlein, P. (1998). A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-10). Saarbrücken, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, and P.  Kühnlein, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;, Saarbrücken, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-10.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wagner P, Kühnlein P (1998) &lt;br /&gt;A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar.  Saarbrücken, Germany:  1-10.</bio1>
<ama>Wagner P, Kühnlein P. A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;. Saarbrücken, Germany;  1998: 1-10.</ama>
<lncs> Wagner, P., Kühnlein, P.: A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface. Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar. p. 1-10. Saarbrücken, Germany (1998).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra, and Kühnlein, Peter. 1998. “A point-based event phonology for the phonetics-phonology interface”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Formal Grammar, Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar, and Categorial Grammar&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Saarbrücken, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917220</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T17:22:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>