<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917004</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Two dimensions of prominence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Portele</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Prosody fulfills a variety of functions in dialogues. Our study examines the relationship between different levels of perceived prominence of syllables and the linguistic and paralinguistic categories accent and emphasis which are conveyed prosodically.
It is still unclear, how a notational system might look like that is able to capture the fine–grained differences between both. The notion of perceptual prominence—defined as a relational parameter on a scale between 0 and 31—seems to be a useful phonetic measure to capture both the subtle differences and shared characteristics
of the phenomena commonly referred to as linguistic and
paralinguistic. Our data indicate that the overall level of prominence within an utterance reflects the level of emphasis, whereas the relative difference of prominences to each other distinguishes between different linguistic accent types.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="eindhoven99_wagner_portele.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917004/2352668/eindhoven99_wagner_portele.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19170044</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Wagner, P.; Portele, T. (1999): Two dimensions of prominence. In: Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody. Eindhoven, The Netherlands.</wels>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Portele, T., 1999. Two dimensions of prominence. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;.  Eindhoven, The Netherlands.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wagner P, Portele T (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Two dimensions of prominence. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody.  Eindhoven, The Netherlands.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Portele, T. (1999). Two dimensions of prominence. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt; Eindhoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, and T.  Portele, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;, Eindhoven, The Netherlands, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Wagner P, Portele T. Two dimensions of prominence. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;. Eindhoven, The Netherlands;  1999.</ama>
<frontiers>Wagner, P., and Portele, T. (1999). “Two dimensions of prominence” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt; (Eindhoven, The Netherlands).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Portele, T. (1999). Two dimensions of prominence. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;. Eindhoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Portele, T. (1999). Two dimensions of prominence. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt; Eindhoven, The Netherlands.</apa>
<ieee> P. Wagner and T. Portele, “Two dimensions of prominence”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;,  Eindhoven, The Netherlands: 1999.</ieee>
<lncs> Wagner, P., Portele, T.: Two dimensions of prominence. Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody.  Eindhoven, The Netherlands (1999).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra, and Portele, Thomas. 1999. “Two dimensions of prominence”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;. Eindhoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Wagner, Petra, and Portele, Thomas. “Two dimensions of prominence”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody&lt;/em&gt;. Eindhoven, The Netherlands, 1999.</mla>
<default>Wagner P, Portele T (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESCA Workshop on Dialogue and Prosody. Eindhoven, The Netherlands.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917004</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T15:58:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>