<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917021</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eva</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fischenbeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Several production and perception experiments have been carried out in order to investigate, whether stress clash environments in A(BC)-compounds really trigger a stress shift or a destressing of the secondary stress or not. The results indicate that stress shifting is rather rare than common in German. If it occurs, it manifests itself both on a production and perception level. This situation remains stable, no matter if listeners are presented the full acoustic signal or only delexicalised stimuli. The only environment where stress shift tends to take place
more often are words consisting of four syllables. These allow for placement of an additional foot. Stress clashes in trisyllabic compounds are often handled by a destressing of the secondary accent as an alternative to stress shift. However, in the majority of stress clash environments, listeners did perceive the primary
and secondary stress in the immediate neighbourhood. Obvi-
ously, a stress clash creates less of a problem in German than it does in other Germanic languages.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SP2_wagner_fischenbeck.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917021/2352651/SP2_wagner_fischenbeck.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19170214</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Wagner, P., Fischenbeck, E.: Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002.  Aix en Provence, France (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra, and Fischenbeck, Eva. 2002. “Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;. Aix en Provence, France.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Wagner, Petra, and Fischenbeck, Eva. “Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;. Aix en Provence, France, 2002.</mla>
<default>Wagner P, Fischenbeck E (2002)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002. Aix en Provence, France.</default>
<ama>Wagner P, Fischenbeck E. Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;. Aix en Provence, France;  2002.</ama>
<frontiers>Wagner, P., and Fischenbeck, E. (2002). “Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt; (Aix en Provence, France).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Fischenbeck, E. (2002). Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;. Aix en Provence, France.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Fischenbeck, E. (2002). Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt; Aix en Provence, France.</apa>
<ieee> P. Wagner and E. Fischenbeck, “Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;,  Aix en Provence, France: 2002.</ieee>
<wels>Wagner, P.; Fischenbeck, E. (2002): Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. In: Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002. Aix en Provence, France.</wels>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Fischenbeck, E., 2002. Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;.  Aix en Provence, France.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Fischenbeck, E. (2002). Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt; Aix en Provence, France.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Wagner P, Fischenbeck E (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Stress perception and production in German stress clash environments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002.  Aix en Provence, France.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, and E.  Fischenbeck, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2002&lt;/em&gt;, Aix en Provence, France, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917021</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T15:58:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>