<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1917158</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Donata</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Möbius</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Filip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müllers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Igor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jauk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Speech Prosody 2010</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper examines viable paths for integrating a fast speech corpus into a unit selection synthesis system. After selecting a suitable speaker, two inventories were recorded: one at normal and one at fast speech rate articulated as accurately as possible. A perceptual evaluation showed that for ultra fast speech rate, stimuli generated from fast utterances were judged to be as intelligible as stimuli generated from normal rate utterances; moreover, they were clearly preferred with respect to naturalness. Based on the results of an automatic phone segmentation which produced only marginal differences in label timing accuracy, CART based duration prediction models for both corpora were built. Prediction accuracy was very similar. We concluded that automatic phone segmentation and CART based duration prediction are applicable to both normal and fast rate recordings.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SP10_dmoetal.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1917158/2352490/SP10_dmoetal.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Chicago</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19171583</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">P2a-28</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Moers, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B., Müllers, F., &amp;amp; Jauk, I. (2010). Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P2a-28.</apa>
<ieee> D. Moers, et al., “Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, 2010,  pp.P2a-28.</ieee>
<ama>Moers D, Wagner P, Möbius B, Müllers F, Jauk I. Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. 2010: P2a-28.</ama>
<frontiers>Moers, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B., Müllers, F., and Jauk, I. (2010). “Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt; P2a-28.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moers, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B., Müllers, F. &amp;amp; Jauk, I. (2010). Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt; (S. P2a-28). Gehalten auf der Speech Prosody 2010.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Moers D, Wagner P, Möbius B, Müllers F, Jauk I (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  P2a-28.</bio1>
<harvard1>Moers, D., et al., 2010. Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. pp. P2a-28.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moers, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B., Müllers, F., &amp;amp; Jauk, I. (2010). Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P2a-28.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Moers, P.  Wagner, B.  Möbius, F.  Müllers, and I.  Jauk, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. P2a-28.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Moers, D.; Wagner, P.; Möbius, B.; Müllers, F.; Jauk, I. (2010): Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. In: Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  S. P2a-28.</wels>
<mla>Moers, Donata, Wagner, Petra, Möbius, Bernd, Müllers, Filip, and Jauk, Igor. “Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;. 2010. P2a-28.</mla>
<default>Moers D, Wagner P, Möbius B, Müllers F, Jauk I (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010.  P2a-28.</default>
<lncs> Moers, D., Wagner, P., Möbius, B., Müllers, F., Jauk, I.: Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction. Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010. p. P2a-28. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moers, Donata, Wagner, Petra, Möbius, Bernd, Müllers, Filip, and Jauk, Igor. 2010. “Integrating a fast speech corpus in unit selection speech synthesis: Experiments on perception, segmentation and duration prediction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Speech Prosody 2010&lt;/em&gt;, P2a-28.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917158</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-16T17:22:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>