<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1919465</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van der Hoog</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15269682</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2348-3194</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christophe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Deissenberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart><namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Willi</namePart><namePart type="family">Semmler</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">42173282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this chapter we consider the effects of exogenous energy shocks on an agent-based macroeconomic system and study the out-of-equilibrium dynamics. We introduce automatic stabilizers that allow the artificial economy to absorbe the shocks.
Two types of macroeconomic stabilization policies are implemented: a consumer subsidy scheme that compensates households for their loss in purchasing power,
and a tax reduction scheme that affects both households and firms to support consumption and investments. Policy experiments are then carried out to evaluate the
effectiveness of these macroeconomic policies. Finally, we are able to distinguish between short- and long-term effects of the policy measures.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Hoog_Deissenberg_2011_Energy.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1919465/2549616/Hoog_Deissenberg_2011_Energy.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>energy shocks</topic><topic>agent-based modelling</topic><topic>stabilization policies</topic><topic>Agent-based macroeconomics</topic><topic>ETACE_Agent_Based_Modelling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-16942-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19194653</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><extent unit="pages">159-181</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics. Dawid H, Semmler W (Eds);  Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance, 13.  Berlin: Springer:  159-181.</default>
<wels>van der Hoog, S.; Deissenberg, C. (2011): Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In: Herbert Dawid; Willi Semmler (Hrsg.):  Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics. Berlin: Springer. (Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance, 13).  S. 159-181.</wels>
<frontiers>van der Hoog, S., and Deissenberg, C. (2011). “Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model” in &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;, Dawid, H., and Semmler, W. eds. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance, vol. 13, (Berlin: Springer), 159-181.</frontiers>
<mla>van der Hoog, Sander, and Deissenberg, Christophe. “Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model”. &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Herbert Dawid and Willi Semmler. Berlin: Springer, 2011.Vol. 13. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance. 159-181.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, S., &amp;amp; Deissenberg, C. (2011). Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In H.  Dawid &amp;amp; W.  Semmler (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance: Vol. 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-181). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>van der Hoog, S., &amp;amp; Deissenberg, C. (2011). Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In H.  Dawid &amp;amp; W.  Semmler (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance: Vol. 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-181). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>van der Hoog, S., &amp;amp; Deissenberg, C., 2011. Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In H.  Dawid &amp;amp; W.  Semmler, eds. &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance. no.13  Berlin: Springer, pp. 159-181.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. van der Hoog and C. Deissenberg, “Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model”, &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;, H. Dawid and W. Semmler, eds., Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance, vol. 13,  Berlin: Springer, 2011,  pp.159-181.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  van der Hoog, and C.  Deissenberg, in &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Dawid, W. Semmler), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 159-181.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics. Dawid H, Semmler W (Eds); Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance, 13. Berlin: Springer:  159-181.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, S. &amp;amp; Deissenberg, C. (2011). Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model (Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance). In H. Dawid &amp;amp; W. Semmler (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 159-181). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-16943-4_8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> van der Hoog, S., Deissenberg, C.: Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In: Dawid, H. and Semmler, W. (eds.) Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance. 13, p. 159-181. Springer, Berlin (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van der Hoog, Sander, and Deissenberg, Christophe. 2011. “Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model”. In &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Herbert Dawid and Willi Semmler, 13:159-181. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>van der Hoog S, Deissenberg C. Energy Shocks and Macroeconomic Stabilization Policies in an Agent-based Macro Model. In: Dawid H, Semmler W, eds. &lt;em&gt;Computational Methods in Economic Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;. Dynamic Modeling and Econometrics in Economics and Finance. Vol 13. Berlin: Springer;  2011: 159-181.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1919465</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-24T12:06:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-21T14:54:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>