<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1961997</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bockemühl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">129845</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dürr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21971</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9239-4964</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685507</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Substantial evidence suggests that nervous systems simplify motor control of complex body geometries by use of higher level functional units, so called motor primitives or synergies. Although simpler, such high level functional units still require an adequate controller. In a previous study, we found that kinematic inter-joint couplings allow the extraction of simple movement synergies during unconstrained 3D catching movements of the human arm and shoulder girdle. Here, we show that there is a bijective mapping between movement synergy space and 3D Cartesian hand coordinates within the arm's physiological working range. Based on this mapping, we propose a minimal control schema for a 10-DoF arm and shoulder girdle. All key elements of this schema are implemented as artificial neural networks (ANNs). For the central controller, we evaluate two different ANN architectures: a feed-forward network and a recurrent Elman network. We show that this control schema is capable of controlling goal-directed movements of a 10-DoF arm with as few as five hidden units. Both controller variants are sufficient for the task. However, end-point stability is better in the feed-forward controller.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bockemuhl_and_Durr_2010_VD09484.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1961997/2285035/Bockemuhl_and_Durr_2010_VD09484.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Valencia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>movement primitive</topic><topic>principal component analysis</topic><topic>artificial neural network</topic><topic>modelling</topic><topic>Arm movement</topic><topic>inter-joint coupling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19619977</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.5220/0003084102200226</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Bockemühl, Till, and Dürr, Volker. “A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;. 2010.</mla>
<default>Bockemühl T, Dürr V (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain).</default>
<lncs> Bockemühl, T., Dürr, V.: A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain).  (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bockemühl, Till, and Dürr, Volker. 2010. “A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Bockemühl, T., &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2010). A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5220/0003084102200226" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5220/0003084102200226&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> T. Bockemühl and V. Dürr, “A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;, 2010.</ieee>
<ama>Bockemühl T, Dürr V. A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;. 2010.</ama>
<frontiers>Bockemühl, T., and Dürr, V. (2010). “A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bockemühl, T. &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2010). A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain). doi:10.5220/0003084102200226.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bockemühl T, Dürr V (2010) &lt;br /&gt;A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain). .</bio1>
<harvard1>Bockemühl, T., &amp;amp; Dürr, V., 2010. A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bockemühl, T., &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2010). A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5220/0003084102200226" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5220/0003084102200226&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Bockemühl, and V.  Dürr, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Bockemühl, T.; Dürr, V. (2010): A minimal control schema for goal-directed arm movements based on physiological inter-joint coupling. In: Proceedings of the International Conference on Neural Computation (ICNC 2010, Valencia, Spain).</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1961997</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-10T10:25:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>