<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1989997</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gieselmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Prisca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stenneken</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5687774</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">K.</namePart><namePart type="family">Fischer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015402</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GieselmannStenneken_TechnReportBremen2006.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1989997/2487171/GieselmannStenneken_TechnReportBremen2006.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19899975</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>Report No. 010-09/2006</number></detail><extent unit="pages">68-78</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Gieselmann, P.; Stenneken, P. (2006): How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In: K. Fischer (Hrsg.):  How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners. (Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition, Report No. 010-09/2006).  S. 68-78.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Gieselmann, and P.  Stenneken, in &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: K. Fischer), &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 68-78.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Gieselmann, P., &amp;amp; Stenneken, P., 2006. How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In K.  Fischer, ed. &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition. no.Report No. 010-09/2006 pp. 68-78.</harvard1>
<bio1>Gieselmann P, Stenneken P (2006) &lt;br /&gt;How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. &lt;br /&gt;In:  How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners. Fischer K (Ed); Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition, Report No. 010-09/2006. 68-78.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gieselmann, P., &amp;amp; Stenneken, P. (2006). How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In K.  Fischer (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition: Vol. Report No. 010-09/2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 68-78).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Gieselmann, P., and Stenneken, P. (2006). “How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication” in &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;, Fischer, K. ed. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition, vol. Report No. 010-09/2006, 68-78.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gieselmann, P. &amp;amp; Stenneken, P. (2006). How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication (Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition). In K. Fischer (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt; (S. 68-78).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Gieselmann P, Stenneken P. How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In: Fischer K, ed. &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition. Vol Report No. 010-09/2006. 2006: 68-78.</ama>
<ieee> P. Gieselmann and P. Stenneken, “How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication”, &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;, K. Fischer, ed., Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition, vol. Report No. 010-09/2006, 2006,  pp.68-78.</ieee>
<apa>Gieselmann, P., &amp;amp; Stenneken, P. (2006). How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In K.  Fischer (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition: Vol. Report No. 010-09/2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 68-78).</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gieselmann, P., and Stenneken, Prisca. 2006. “How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication”. In &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;, ed. K. Fischer, Report No. 010-09/2006:68-78. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gieselmann, P., Stenneken, P.: How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication. In: Fischer, K. (ed.) How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition. Report No. 010-09/2006, p. 68-78. (2006).</lncs>
<default>Gieselmann P, Stenneken P (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners. Fischer K (Ed);  Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition, Report No. 010-09/2006.   68-78.</default>
<mla>Gieselmann, P., and Stenneken, Prisca. “How to talk to robots: Evidence from user studies on human-robot communication”. &lt;em&gt;How People Talk to Computers, Robots, and Other Artificial Communication Partners&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. K. Fischer. 2006.Vol. Report No. 010-09/2006. Report Series of the Transregional Collaborative Research Center SFB/TR 8 Spatial Cognition. 68-78.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1989997</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-10T11:47:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>