<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1991250</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">178620</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Biermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc Erich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Latoschik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8937325</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bastos</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">M.M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Wanderley</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">S.</namePart><namePart type="family">Gibet</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Dias</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we describe how coverbal iconic gestures can be used to express shape-related references to objects in a Virtual Construction Environment. Shape information is represented using Imagistic Description Trees (IDTs), an extended semantic representation which includes relational information (as well as numerical data) about the objects’ spatial features. The IDTs are generated online according to the trajectory of the user’s hand movements when the system is instructed to select an existing or to create a new object. A tight integration of the semantic information into the objects’ data structures allows to access this information via so-called semantic entities as interfaces during the multimodal analysis and integration process.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="vwerk_gw.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1991250/2644063/vwerk_gw.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>gesture representation</topic><topic>iconic gestures</topic><topic>virtual construction</topic><topic>multimodal human-computer interaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-92864-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19912504</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5085</number></detail><extent unit="pages">187-192</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Fröhlich, C.; Biermann, P.; Latoschik, M. E.; Wachsmuth, I. (2009): Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In: R. Bastos; M.M. Wanderley; S. Gibet; M. Dias (Hrsg.):  Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation. Berlin: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 5085).  S. 187-192.</wels>
<mla>Fröhlich, Christian, Biermann, Peter, Latoschik, Marc Erich, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. R. Bastos, M.M. Wanderley, S. Gibet, and M. Dias. Berlin: Springer, 2009.Vol. 5085. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). 187-192.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, C., Biermann, P., Latoschik, M. E., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2009). Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In R.  Bastos, M. M.  Wanderley, S.  Gibet, &amp;amp; M.  Dias (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI): Vol. 5085&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 187-192). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Fröhlich, C., Biermann, P., Latoschik, M. E., and Wachsmuth, I. (2009). “Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, Bastos, R., Wanderley, M. M., Gibet, S., and Dias, M. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), vol. 5085, (Berlin: Springer), 187-192.</frontiers>
<default>Fröhlich C, Biermann P, Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation. Bastos R, Wanderley MM, Gibet S, Dias M (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 5085.  Berlin: Springer:  187-192.</default>
<harvard1>Fröhlich, C., et al., 2009. Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In R.  Bastos, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). no.5085  Berlin: Springer, pp. 187-192.</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Fröhlich, et al., “Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, R. Bastos, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), vol. 5085,  Berlin: Springer, 2009,  pp.187-192.</ieee>
<apa>Fröhlich, C., Biermann, P., Latoschik, M. E., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2009). Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In R.  Bastos, M. M.  Wanderley, S.  Gibet, &amp;amp; M.  Dias (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI): Vol. 5085&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 187-192). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, C., Biermann, P., Latoschik, M.E. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2009). Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment (Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). In R. Bastos, M.M. Wanderley, S. Gibet &amp;amp; M. Dias (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; (S. 187-192). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-92865-2_20.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Fröhlich, P.  Biermann, M. E.  Latoschik, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Bastos, M.M. Wanderley, S. Gibet, M. Dias), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 187-192.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Fröhlich C, Biermann P, Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation. Bastos R, Wanderley MM, Gibet S, Dias M (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI), 5085. Berlin: Springer:  187-192.</bio1>
<ama>Fröhlich C, Biermann P, Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I. Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In: Bastos R, Wanderley MM, Gibet S, Dias M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). Vol 5085. Berlin: Springer;  2009: 187-192.</ama>
<lncs> Fröhlich, C., Biermann, P., Latoschik, M.E., Wachsmuth, I.: Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment. In: Bastos, R., Wanderley, M.M., Gibet, S., and Dias, M. (eds.) Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). 5085, p. 187-192. Springer, Berlin (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, Christian, Biermann, Peter, Latoschik, Marc Erich, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2009. “Processing iconic gestures in a multimodal virtual construction environment”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Human-Computer Interaction and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, ed. R. Bastos, M.M. Wanderley, S. Gibet, and M. Dias, 5085:187-192. Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNAI). Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1991250</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-14T15:07:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>