<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1992178</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kepa Joseba</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rodríguez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Enric</namePart><namePart type="family">Vallduv'ı</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Form__Intonation">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1992178/2265631/Form__Intonation</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">84-609-2205-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19921785</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">101-108</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Rodríguez, K.J., Schlangen, D.: Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In: Vallduv'ı, E. (ed.) Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04). p. 101-108. Barcelona, Spain (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rodríguez, Kepa Joseba, and Schlangen, David. 2004. “Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Enric Vallduv'ı, 101-108. Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Rodríguez, Kepa Joseba, and Schlangen, David. “Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Enric Vallduv'ı. Barcelona, Spain, 2004. 101-108.</mla>
<default>Rodríguez KJ, Schlangen D (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04). Vallduv'ı E (Ed);  Barcelona, Spain:  101-108.</default>
<wels>Rodríguez, K. J.; Schlangen, D. (2004): Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In: Enric Vallduv'ı (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04). Barcelona, Spain.  S. 101-108.</wels>
<bio1>Rodríguez KJ, Schlangen D (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04). Vallduv'ı E (Ed); Barcelona, Spain:  101-108.</bio1>
<harvard1>Rodríguez, K.J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2004. Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In E.  Vallduv'ı, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;.  Barcelona, Spain, pp. 101-108.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rodríguez, K. J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2004). Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In E.  Vallduv'ı (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 101-108). Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>K. J.  Rodríguez, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: E. Vallduv'ı), Barcelona, Spain, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 101-108.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Rodríguez KJ, Schlangen D. Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In: Vallduv'ı E, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;. Barcelona, Spain;  2004: 101-108.</ama>
<frontiers>Rodríguez, K. J., and Schlangen, D. (2004). “Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;, Vallduv'ı, E. ed. (Barcelona, Spain), 101-108.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rodríguez, K.J. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2004). Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In E. Vallduv'ı (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 101-108). Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Rodríguez, K. J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2004). Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues. In E.  Vallduv'ı (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 101-108). Barcelona, Spain.</apa>
<ieee> K.J. Rodríguez and D. Schlangen, “Form, Intonation and Function of Clarification Requests in German Task-Oriented Spoken Dialogues”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Catalog (the 8th workshop on the semantics and pragmatics of dialogue; SemDial04)&lt;/em&gt;, E. Vallduv'ı, ed.,  Barcelona, Spain: 2004,  pp.101-108.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1992178</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-16T00:15:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>