<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1992161</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alex</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lascarides</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jason</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baldridge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ivana</namePart><namePart type="family">Krujiff-Korbayová</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart><namePart type="family">Kosny</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Tool_for_Semi-Automatic">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1992161/2265621/Tool_for_Semi-Automatic</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19921616</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">205-206</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A. &amp;amp; Baldridge, J. (2003). A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In I. Krujiff-Korbayová &amp;amp; C. Kosny (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 205-206). Saarbrücken.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Schlangen D, Lascarides A, Baldridge J (2003) &lt;br /&gt;A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue). Krujiff-Korbayová I, Kosny C (Eds); Saarbrücken:  205-206.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Schlangen, A.  Lascarides, and J.  Baldridge, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Krujiff-Korbayová, C. Kosny), Saarbrücken, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 205-206.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Schlangen D, Lascarides A, Baldridge J. A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In: Krujiff-Korbayová I, Kosny C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;. Saarbrücken;  2003: 205-206.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, David, Lascarides, Alex, and Baldridge, Jason. 2003. “A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ivana Krujiff-Korbayová and Claudia Kosny, 205-206. Saarbrücken.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A., Baldridge, J.: A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In: Krujiff-Korbayová, I. and Kosny, C. (eds.) Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue). p. 205-206. Saarbrücken (2003).</lncs>
<frontiers>Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A., and Baldridge, J. (2003). “A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;, Krujiff-Korbayová, I., and Kosny, C. eds. (Saarbrücken), 205-206.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A., &amp;amp; Baldridge, J. (2003). A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In I.  Krujiff-Korbayová &amp;amp; C.  Kosny (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 205-206). Saarbrücken.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Schlangen, David, Lascarides, Alex, and Baldridge, Jason. “A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ivana Krujiff-Korbayová and Claudia Kosny. Saarbrücken, 2003. 205-206.</mla>
<wels>Schlangen, D.; Lascarides, A.; Baldridge, J. (2003): A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In: Ivana Krujiff-Korbayová; Claudia Kosny (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue). Saarbrücken.  S. 205-206.</wels>
<default>Schlangen D, Lascarides A, Baldridge J (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue). Krujiff-Korbayová I, Kosny C (Eds);  Saarbrücken:  205-206.</default>
<ieee> D. Schlangen, A. Lascarides, and J. Baldridge, “A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;, I. Krujiff-Korbayová and C. Kosny, eds.,  Saarbrücken: 2003,  pp.205-206.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A., &amp;amp; Baldridge, J., 2003. A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In I.  Krujiff-Korbayová &amp;amp; C.  Kosny, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt;.  Saarbrücken, pp. 205-206.</harvard1>
<apa>Schlangen, D., Lascarides, A., &amp;amp; Baldridge, J. (2003). A Tool for Semi-Automatic and Interactive Annotation of Dialogue Utterances with Information States. In I.  Krujiff-Korbayová &amp;amp; C.  Kosny (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of DiaBruck (the 7th Workshop on Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 205-206). Saarbrücken.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1992161</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-16T00:15:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>