<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1992222</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raquel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fernández</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tatjana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lucht</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kepa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rodríguez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Interaction_in_Task-Oriented">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1992222/2265661/Interaction_in_Task-Oriented</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">1424408725</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19922228</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/slt.2006.326791</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Fernández, R.; Lucht, T.; Rodríguez, K.; Schlangen, D. (2006): Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In: Association for Computational Linguistics; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology. Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fernández, R., Lucht, T., Rodríguez, K., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2006). Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In Association for Computational Linguistics &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt; Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/slt.2006.326791" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/slt.2006.326791&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Fernández, Raquel, Lucht, Tatjana, Rodríguez, Kepa, and Schlangen, David. “Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Association for Computational Linguistics and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE, 2006.</mla>
<frontiers>Fernández, R., Lucht, T., Rodríguez, K., and Schlangen, D. (2006). “Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;, Association for Computational Linguistics, and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers eds. (Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE).</frontiers>
<default>Fernández R, Lucht T, Rodríguez K, Schlangen D (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology. Association for Computational Linguistics, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds);  Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE.</default>
<ieee> R. Fernández, et al., “Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;, Association for Computational Linguistics and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds.,  Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE, 2006.</ieee>
<harvard1>Fernández, R., et al., 2006. Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In Association for Computational Linguistics &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;.  Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE.</harvard1>
<apa>Fernández, R., Lucht, T., Rodríguez, K., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2006). Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In Association for Computational Linguistics &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt; Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/slt.2006.326791" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/slt.2006.326791&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fernández, R., Lucht, T., Rodríguez, K. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2006). Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In Association for Computational Linguistics &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;. Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE. doi:10.1109/slt.2006.326791.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Fernández R, Lucht T, Rodríguez K, Schlangen D (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology. Association for Computational Linguistics, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds); Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Fernández, T.  Lucht, K.  Rodríguez, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: Association for Computational Linguistics, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers), Ieee, Palm Beach, Aruba, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Fernández R, Lucht T, Rodríguez K, Schlangen D. Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In: Association for Computational Linguistics, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;. Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE;  2006.</ama>
<lncs> Fernández, R., Lucht, T., Rodríguez, K., Schlangen, D.: Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies. In: Association for Computational Linguistics and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (eds.) Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology.  IEEE, Palm Beach, Aruba (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fernández, Raquel, Lucht, Tatjana, Rodríguez, Kepa, and Schlangen, David. 2006. “Interaction in Task-Oriented Human–Human Dialogue: The Effects of Different Turn-Taking Policies”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International IEEE/ACL Workshop on Spoken Language Technology&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Association for Computational Linguistics and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Palm Beach, Aruba: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1992222</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-16T00:15:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>