<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1993187</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friederike Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eyssel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">140331</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4978-8922</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Allbeck</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">N.</namePart><namePart type="family">Badler</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">T.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bickmore</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pelachaud</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Safonova</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">How does a virtual agent’s gesturing behavior influence the user’s perception of communication quality and the agent’s personality? This question was investigated in an evaluation study of co-verbal iconic gestures produced with the Bayesian network-based production model GNetIc. A network learned from a corpus of several speakers was compared with networks learned from individual speaker data, as well as two control conditions. Results showed that automatically GNetIc-generated gestures increased the perceived quality of an object description given by a virtual human. Moreover, the virtual agent showing gesturing behavior generated with individual speaker networks was rated more positively in terms of likeability, competence and human-likeness.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bergmann_Kopp_Eyssel2010-PREPRINT.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1993187/2410377/Bergmann_Kopp_Eyssel2010-PREPRINT.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Philadelphia, PA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-15892-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19931874</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6356</number></detail><extent unit="pages">104-117</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, Kopp, Stefan, and Eyssel, Friederike Anne. 2010. “Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans”. In &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. Allbeck, N. Badler, T. Bickmore, C. Pelachaud, and A. Safonova, 6356:104-117. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Kopp, S., Eyssel, F.A.: Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In: Allbeck, J., Badler, N., Bickmore, T., Pelachaud, C., and Safonova, A. (eds.) Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 6356, p. 104-117. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany (2010).</lncs>
<default>Bergmann K, Kopp S, Eyssel FA (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Allbeck J, Badler N, Bickmore T, Pelachaud C, Safonova A (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6356.  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  104-117.</default>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, Kopp, Stefan, and Eyssel, Friederike Anne. “Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans”. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. J. Allbeck, N. Badler, T. Bickmore, C. Pelachaud, and A. Safonova. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2010.Vol. 6356. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 104-117.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Eyssel, F.A. (2010). Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In J. Allbeck, N. Badler, T. Bickmore, C. Pelachaud &amp;amp; A. Safonova (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (S. 104-117). Gehalten auf der 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., Kopp, S., and Eyssel, F. A. (2010). “Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans” in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Allbeck, J., Badler, N., Bickmore, T., Pelachaud, C., and Safonova, A. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 6356, (Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer), 104-117.</frontiers>
<ama>Bergmann K, Kopp S, Eyssel FA. Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In: Allbeck J, Badler N, Bickmore T, Pelachaud C, Safonova A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 6356. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer;  2010: 104-117.</ama>
<ieee> K. Bergmann, S. Kopp, and F.A. Eyssel, “Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans”, &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, J. Allbeck, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 6356,  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2010,  pp.104-117.</ieee>
<apa>Bergmann, K., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F. A. (2010). Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In J.  Allbeck, N.  Badler, T.  Bickmore, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; A.  Safonova (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 6356&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 104-117). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.</apa>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Kopp, S.; Eyssel, F. A. (2010): Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In: J. Allbeck; N. Badler; T. Bickmore; C. Pelachaud; A. Safonova (Hrsg.):  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6356).  S. 104-117.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, S.  Kopp, and F. A.  Eyssel, in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Allbeck, N. Badler, T. Bickmore, C. Pelachaud, A. Safonova), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 104-117.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F. A. (2010). Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In J.  Allbeck, N.  Badler, T.  Bickmore, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; A.  Safonova (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 6356&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 104-117). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Kopp S, Eyssel FA (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Allbeck J, Badler N, Bickmore T, Pelachaud C, Safonova A (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6356. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  104-117.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F.A., 2010. Individualized Gesturing Outperforms Average Gesturing – Evaluating Gesture Production in Virtual Humans. In J.  Allbeck, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.6356  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, pp. 104-117.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1993187</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-16T15:53:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>