<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1996275</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4522994</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Leonardo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Alves jun.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">162486</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Merkle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">108333</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684836</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background:

microRNAs (miRNAs) are endogenous small non-coding RNAs that post-transcriptionally regulate gene expression. In plants, they typically show high complementarity to a single sequence motif within their target mRNAs and act by catalyzing specific mRNA cleavage and degradation. miRNAs are processed from much longer primary transcripts via precursor miRNAs containing fold-back structures. Leaving these secondary structures intact, miRNAs can be re-designed experimentally to target mRNAs of choice.

Results:

We designed primary synthetic miRNAs (pri-smiRNAs) on the basis of the primary transcript of the Arabidopsis MIR159A gene by replacing the original miR159a and the corresponding miR159a* with novel sequences, keeping the overall secondary structure as predicted by the program RNAfold. We used the program RNAhybrid to optimize smiRNA design and to screen the complete Arabidopsis transcriptome for potential off-targets. To improve the molecular cloning of the pri-smiRNA we inserted restriction sites in the original MIR159A primary transcript to easily accommodate the smiRNA/smiRNA* DNA fragment. As a proof-of-concept, we targeted the single gene encoding chalcone synthase (CHS) in Arabidopsis. We demonstrate smiRNA(CHS) expression and CHS mRNA cleavage in different transgenic lines. Phenotypic changes in these lines were observed for seed color and flavonol derivatives, and quantified with respect to anthocyanin content. We also tested the effect of mismatches and excess G:U base pairs on knockdown efficiency.

Conclusions:

RNAhybrid-assisted design of smiRNAs and generation of pri-smiRNAs using a novel vector containing restriction sites greatly improves specificity and speed of the generation of stable knockdown lines for functional analyses in plants.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1756-0500-3-59.niemeier.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1996275/2471125/1756-0500-3-59.niemeier.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Research Notes</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1756-0500</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">20202197</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19962751</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-3-59</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L., &amp;amp; Merkle, T. (2010). Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1), 59. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-59" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-59&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> S. Niemeier, L. Alves jun., and T. Merkle, “Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs)”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 3, 2010, : 59.</ieee>
<ama>Niemeier S, Alves jun. L, Merkle T. Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;. 2010;3(1): 59.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L. &amp;amp; Merkle, T. (2010). Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1): 59. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1756-0500-3-59.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L., and Merkle, T. (2010). Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3:59.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L., &amp;amp; Merkle, T., 2010. Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, 3(1): 59.</harvard1>
<bio1>Niemeier S, Alves jun. L, Merkle T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs).&lt;br /&gt;BMC Research Notes 3(1): 59.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L., &amp;amp; Merkle, T. (2010). Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1), 59. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-59" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-3-59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Niemeier, L.  Alves jun., and T.  Merkle, “Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs)”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, : 59.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Niemeier, S.; Alves jun., L.; Merkle, T. (2010): Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs) &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,3:(1):59</wels>
<mla>Niemeier, Sandra, Alves jun., Leonardo, and Merkle, Thomas. “Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs)”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3.1 (2010): 59.</mla>
<default>Niemeier S, Alves jun. L, Merkle T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3(1): 59.</default>
<lncs> Niemeier, S., Alves jun., L., Merkle, T.: Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs). BMC Research Notes. 3, : 59 (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemeier, Sandra, Alves jun., Leonardo, and Merkle, Thomas. 2010. “Improvement of the design and generation of highly specific plant knockdown lines using primary synthetic microRNAs (pri-smiRNAs)”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 3 (1): 59.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1996275</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-21T17:10:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>