<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1997547</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gaston</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Burek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7346775</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8778-1273</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">De Roeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015583</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics (ACL 2007)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Latent Semantic Analysis has only recently been applied to textual entailment recognition. However, these efforts have suffered from inadequate bag of words vector representations. Our prototype implementation for the Third Recognising Textual Entailment Challenge (RTE-3) improves the approach by applying it to vector representations that contain semi-structured representations of words. It uses variable size n-grams of word stems to model independently verbs, subjects and objects displayed in textual statements. The system performance shows positive results and provides insights about how to improve them further.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="burek-pietsch-deroeck-acl07-wtep-rte3.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1997547/2425136/burek-pietsch-deroeck-acl07-wtep-rte3.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Prague, Czech Republic</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>recognizing textual entailment</topic><topic>shared task</topic><topic>latent semantic analysis</topic><topic>LSA</topic><topic>WTEP</topic><topic>RTE</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19975474</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3115/1654536.1654559</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">113-118</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Burek, C.  Pietsch, and A.  De Roeck, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;, Association For Computational Linguistics, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 113-118.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Burek, G., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; De Roeck, A. (2007). SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;, 113-118. Association for Computational Linguistics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3115/1654536.1654559" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3115/1654536.1654559&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Burek, G., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; De Roeck, A., 2007. SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;.  Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 113-118.</harvard1>
<bio1>Burek G, Pietsch C, De Roeck A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP).  Association for Computational Linguistics:  113-118.</bio1>
<wels>Burek, G.; Pietsch, C.; De Roeck, A. (2007): SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. In: Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP). Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 113-118.</wels>
<ieee> G. Burek, C. Pietsch, and A. De Roeck, “SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;, Association for Computational Linguistics, 2007,  pp.113-118.</ieee>
<default>Burek G, Pietsch C, De Roeck A (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP). Association for Computational Linguistics:  113-118.</default>
<mla>Burek, Gaston, Pietsch, Christian, and De Roeck, Anne. “SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics, 2007. 113-118.</mla>
<apa>Burek, G., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; De Roeck, A. (2007). SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;, 113-118. Association for Computational Linguistics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3115/1654536.1654559" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3115/1654536.1654559&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Burek, Gaston, Pietsch, Christian, and De Roeck, Anne. 2007. “SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;, 113-118. Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Burek, G., Pietsch, C., and De Roeck, A. (2007). “SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt; (Association for Computational Linguistics), 113-118.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Burek, G., Pietsch, C. &amp;amp; De Roeck, A. (2007). SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 113-118). Gehalten auf der 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics (ACL 2007), Association for Computational Linguistics. doi:10.3115/1654536.1654559.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Burek G, Pietsch C, De Roeck A. SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP)&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics;  2007: 113-118.</ama>
<lncs> Burek, G., Pietsch, C., De Roeck, A.: SVO triple based Latent Semantic Analysis for recognising textual entailment. Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing (WTEP). p. 113-118. Association for Computational Linguistics (2007).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1997547</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-24T09:45:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>