<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>1998569</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tscherepanow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">128602</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zöllner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hillebrand</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kummert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10372</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Petra</namePart><namePart type="family">Perner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ovidio</namePart><namePart type="family">Salvetti</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The automatic subcellular localisation of proteins in living cells is a critical step in determining their function. The evaluation of fluorescence images constitutes a common method of localising these proteins. For this, additional knowledge about the position of the considered cells within an image is required. In an automated system, it is advantageous to recognise these cells in bright-field microscope images taken in parallel with the regarded fluorescence micrographs. Unfortunately, currently available cell recognition methods are only of limited use within the context of protein localisation, since they frequently require microscopy techniques that enable images of higher contrast (e.g. phase contrast microscopy or additional dyes) or can only be employed with too low magnifications. Therefore, this article introduces a novel approach to the robust automatic recognition of unstained living cells in bright-field microscope images. Here, the focus is on the automatic segmentation of cells.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="tscherepanow.marko2008automatic-MDA.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1998569/2502919/tscherepanow.marko2008automatic-MDA.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>bright-field microscopy</topic><topic>cell segmentation</topic><topic>protein localisation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-19985692</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">158-172</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> M. Tscherepanow, et al., “Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;, P. Perner and O. Salvetti, eds.,  Berlin: Springer, 2008,  pp.158-172.</ieee>
<harvard1>Tscherepanow, M., et al., 2008. Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In P.  Perner &amp;amp; O.  Salvetti, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin: Springer, pp. 158-172.</harvard1>
<apa>Tscherepanow, M., Zöllner, F., Hillebrand, M., &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2008). Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In P.  Perner &amp;amp; O.  Salvetti (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 158-172). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M., Zöllner, F., Hillebrand, M., &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2008). Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In P.  Perner &amp;amp; O.  Salvetti (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 158-172). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Tscherepanow, M., Zöllner, F., Hillebrand, M., and Kummert, F. (2008). “Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;, Perner, P., and Salvetti, O. eds. (Berlin: Springer), 158-172.</frontiers>
<mla>Tscherepanow, Marko, Zöllner, Frank, Hillebrand, Matthias, and Kummert, Franz. “Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Petra Perner and Ovidio Salvetti. Berlin: Springer, 2008. 158-172.</mla>
<wels>Tscherepanow, M.; Zöllner, F.; Hillebrand, M.; Kummert, F. (2008): Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In: Petra Perner; Ovidio Salvetti (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA). Berlin: Springer.  S. 158-172.</wels>
<default>Tscherepanow M, Zöllner F, Hillebrand M, Kummert F (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA). Perner P, Salvetti O (Eds);  Berlin: Springer:  158-172.</default>
<ama>Tscherepanow M, Zöllner F, Hillebrand M, Kummert F. Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In: Perner P, Salvetti O, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin: Springer;  2008: 158-172.</ama>
<lncs> Tscherepanow, M., Zöllner, F., Hillebrand, M., Kummert, F.: Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In: Perner, P. and Salvetti, O. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA). p. 158-172. Springer, Berlin (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, Marko, Zöllner, Frank, Hillebrand, Matthias, and Kummert, Franz. 2008. “Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Petra Perner and Ovidio Salvetti, 158-172. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M., Zöllner, F., Hillebrand, M. &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2008). Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. In P. Perner &amp;amp; O. Salvetti (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 158-172). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA), Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-70715-8_13.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Tscherepanow M, Zöllner F, Hillebrand M, Kummert F (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Automatic Segmentation of Unstained Living Cells in Bright-Field Microscope Images. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA). Perner P, Salvetti O (Eds); Berlin: Springer:  158-172.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Tscherepanow, F.  Zöllner, M.  Hillebrand, and F.  Kummert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Mass-Data Analysis of Images and Signals (MDA)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Perner, O. Salvetti), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 158-172.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1998569</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-02-25T15:46:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>