<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2001816</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart><namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart><namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Why an iconic gesture takes its particular form is a largely open question, given the variations one finds across both situations and speakers. We present results of an empirical study that analyzes correlations between contextual factors (referent features, discourse) and gesture features, and tests whether they are systematic (shared among speakers) or idiosyncratic (inter-individually different). Based on this, a computational model of gesture formation is presented that combines data-based, probabilistic and model-based decision making.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bergmann_Kopp2010.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2001816/2534576/Bergmann_Kopp2010.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20018168</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">182-194</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, and Kopp, Stefan. “Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Stefan Kopp and Ipke Wachsmuth. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2010. 182-194.</mla>
<default>Bergmann K, Kopp S (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Kopp S, Wachsmuth I (Eds);  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  182-194.</default>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Kopp, S.: Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In: Kopp, S. and Wachsmuth, I. (eds.) Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. p. 182-194. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, and Kopp, Stefan. 2010. “Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Stefan Kopp and Ipke Wachsmuth, 182-194. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In S.  Kopp &amp;amp; I.  Wachsmuth (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 182-194). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.</apa>
<ieee> K. Bergmann and S. Kopp, “Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, S. Kopp and I. Wachsmuth, eds.,  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2010,  pp.182-194.</ieee>
<ama>Bergmann K, Kopp S. Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In: Kopp S, Wachsmuth I, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer;  2010: 182-194.</ama>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., and Kopp, S. (2010). “Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Kopp, S., and Wachsmuth, I. eds. (Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer), 182-194.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In S. Kopp &amp;amp; I. Wachsmuth (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 182-194). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Kopp S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Kopp S, Wachsmuth I (Eds); Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  182-194.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2010. Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In S.  Kopp &amp;amp; I.  Wachsmuth, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, pp. 182-194.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2010). Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In S.  Kopp &amp;amp; I.  Wachsmuth (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 182-194). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Kopp, I. Wachsmuth), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 182-194.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Kopp, S. (2010): Systematicity and Idiosyncrasy in Iconic Gesture Use: Empirical Analysis and Computational Modeling. In: Stefan Kopp; Ipke Wachsmuth (Hrsg.):  Gesture in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.  S. 182-194.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2001816</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-04T10:29:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>