<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2002115</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arlinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">171789</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Petra</namePart><namePart type="family">Schulte</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marco</namePart><namePart type="family">Mostert</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Irene</namePart><namePart type="family">van Renswoude</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791087</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Arlinghaus_Point_of_Reference.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2002115/2904347/Arlinghaus_Point_of_Reference.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/save</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Brepols Publications</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-2503517582</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20021151</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">277-299</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. “Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town”. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Petra Schulte, Marco Mostert, and Irene van Renswoude. Turnout: Brepols Publications, 2008. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13. 277-299.</mla>
<default>Arlinghaus F-J (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”). Schulte P, Mostert M, van Renswoude I (Eds);  Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13.  Turnout: Brepols Publications:  277-299.</default>
<lncs> Arlinghaus, F.-J.: Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In: Schulte, P., Mostert, M., and van Renswoude, I. (eds.) Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”). Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13. p. 277-299. Brepols Publications, Turnout (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. 2008. “Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town”. In &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Petra Schulte, Marco Mostert, and Irene van Renswoude, 277-299. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13. Turnout: Brepols Publications.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2008). Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In P.  Schulte, M.  Mostert, &amp;amp; I.  van Renswoude (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-299). Turnout: Brepols Publications.</apa>
<ieee> F.-J. Arlinghaus, “Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town”, &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;, P. Schulte, M. Mostert, and I. van Renswoude, eds., Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13,  Turnout: Brepols Publications, 2008,  pp.277-299.</ieee>
<ama>Arlinghaus F-J. Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In: Schulte P, Mostert M, van Renswoude I, eds. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13. Turnout: Brepols Publications;  2008: 277-299.</ama>
<frontiers>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2008). “Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town” in &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;, Schulte, P., Mostert, M., and van Renswoude, I. eds. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13 (Turnout: Brepols Publications), 277-299.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F.-J. (2008). Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town (Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13). In P. Schulte, M. Mostert &amp;amp; I. van Renswoude (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 277-299). Turnout: Brepols Publications.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Arlinghaus, F.-J., 2008. Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In P.  Schulte, M.  Mostert, &amp;amp; I.  van Renswoude, eds. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13.  Turnout: Brepols Publications, pp. 277-299.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2008). Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In P.  Schulte, M.  Mostert, &amp;amp; I.  van Renswoude (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-299). Turnout: Brepols Publications.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Arlinghaus F-J (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”). Schulte P, Mostert M, van Renswoude I (Eds); Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13,  Turnout: Brepols Publications:  277-299.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - J.  Arlinghaus, in &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Schulte, M. Mostert, I. van Renswoude), Brepols Publications, Turnout, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 277-299.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2008): Point of Reference. Trust and the Function of Written Agreements in a Late-Medieval Town. In: Petra Schulte; Marco Mostert; Irene van Renswoude (Hrsg.):  Strategies of Writing. Studies on Text and Trust in the Middle Ages (Papers from “Trust in Writing in the Middle Ages”). Turnout: Brepols Publications. (Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 13, ).  S. 277-299.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2002115</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-07T08:25:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>