<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2002229</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arlinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">171789</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Caroline</namePart><namePart type="family">Goodson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anne E.</namePart><namePart type="family">Lester</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Carol</namePart><namePart type="family">Symes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791087</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Arlinghaus_Myth_of_Urban_Unity.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2002229/2537848/Arlinghaus_Myth_of_Urban_Unity.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ashgate</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0754667230</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20022299</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">215-232</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2010). The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In C.  Goodson, A. E.  Lester, &amp;amp; C.  Symes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 215-232). Farnham: Ashgate.</apa>
<ieee> F.-J. Arlinghaus, “The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig”, &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;, C. Goodson, A.E. Lester, and C. Symes, eds.,  Farnham: Ashgate, 2010,  pp.215-232.</ieee>
<harvard1>Arlinghaus, F.-J., 2010. The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In C.  Goodson, A. E.  Lester, &amp;amp; C.  Symes, eds. &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;.  Farnham: Ashgate, pp. 215-232.</harvard1>
<default>Arlinghaus F-J (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space. Goodson C, Lester AE, Symes C (Eds);  Farnham: Ashgate:  215-232.</default>
<wels>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2010): The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In: Caroline Goodson; Anne E. Lester; Carol Symes (Hrsg.):  Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space. Farnham: Ashgate.  S. 215-232.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2010). The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In C.  Goodson, A. E.  Lester, &amp;amp; C.  Symes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 215-232). Farnham: Ashgate.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2010). “The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig” in &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;, Goodson, C., Lester, A. E., and Symes, C. eds. (Farnham: Ashgate), 215-232.</frontiers>
<mla>Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. “The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig”. &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Caroline Goodson, Anne E. Lester, and Carol Symes. Farnham: Ashgate, 2010. 215-232.</mla>
<lncs> Arlinghaus, F.-J.: The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In: Goodson, C., Lester, A.E., and Symes, C. (eds.) Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space. p. 215-232. Ashgate, Farnham (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. 2010. “The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig”. In &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Caroline Goodson, Anne E. Lester, and Carol Symes, 215-232. Farnham: Ashgate.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Arlinghaus F-J. The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In: Goodson C, Lester AE, Symes C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt;. Farnham: Ashgate;  2010: 215-232.</ama>
<bio1>Arlinghaus F-J (2010) &lt;br /&gt;The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space. Goodson C, Lester AE, Symes C (Eds); Farnham: Ashgate:  215-232.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - J.  Arlinghaus, in &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Goodson, A.E. Lester, C. Symes), Ashgate, Farnham, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 215-232.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F.-J. (2010). The Myth of Urban Unity. Religion and Social Performance in Late Medieval Braunschweig. In C. Goodson, A.E. Lester &amp;amp; C. Symes (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Cities, Texts, and Social Networks, 400-1500: Experiences and Perceptions of Medieval Urban Space&lt;/em&gt; (S. 215-232). Farnham: Ashgate.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2002229</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-07T10:32:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>