<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2002110</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arlinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">171789</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ostermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Plessow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gudrun</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tscherpel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Franz-Josef</namePart><namePart type="family">Arlinghaus</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart><namePart type="family">Ostermann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart><namePart type="family">Plessow</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gudrun</namePart><namePart type="family">Tscherpel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791087</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Arlinghaus_et_al_Wirtten_Texts.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2002110/2537531/Arlinghaus_et_al_Wirtten_Texts.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Brepols</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">2-503-51166-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20021103</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1-15</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Arlinghaus, F. - J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., &amp;amp; Tscherpel, G. (2006). Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In F. - J.  Arlinghaus, M.  Ostermann, O.  Plessow, &amp;amp; G.  Tscherpel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy: Vol. 6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-15). Turnhout: Brepols.</apa>
<ieee> F.-J. Arlinghaus, et al., “Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment”, &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, F.-J. Arlinghaus, et al., eds., Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, vol. 6,  Turnhout: Brepols, 2006,  pp.1-15.</ieee>
<ama>Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G. Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In: Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy. Vol 6. Turnhout: Brepols;  2006: 1-15.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F.-J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O. &amp;amp; Tscherpel, G. (2006). Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment (Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy). In F.-J. Arlinghaus, M. Ostermann, O. Plessow &amp;amp; G. Tscherpel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-15). Turnhout: Brepols.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Arlinghaus, F. - J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., and Tscherpel, G. (2006). “Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment” in &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, Arlinghaus, F. - J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., and Tscherpel, G. eds. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, vol. 6, (Turnhout: Brepols), 1-15.</frontiers>
<bio1>Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages. Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G (Eds); Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 6. Turnhout: Brepols:  1-15.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F. - J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., &amp;amp; Tscherpel, G. (2006). Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In F. - J.  Arlinghaus, M.  Ostermann, O.  Plessow, &amp;amp; G.  Tscherpel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy: Vol. 6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-15). Turnhout: Brepols.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Arlinghaus, F.-J., et al., 2006. Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In F. - J.  Arlinghaus, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy. no.6  Turnhout: Brepols, pp. 1-15.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - J.  Arlinghaus, M.  Ostermann, O.  Plessow, and G.  Tscherpel, in &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: F.-J. Arlinghaus, M. Ostermann, O. Plessow, G. Tscherpel), Brepols, Turnhout, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-15.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Arlinghaus, F. - J.; Ostermann, M.; Plessow, O.; Tscherpel, G. (2006): Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In: Franz-Josef Arlinghaus; Marcus Ostermann; Oliver Plessow; Gudrun Tscherpel (Hrsg.):  Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages. Turnhout: Brepols. (Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 6).  S. 1-15.</wels>
<mla>Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef, Ostermann, Marcus, Plessow, Oliver, and Tscherpel, Gudrun. “Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment”. &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Franz-Josef Arlinghaus, Marcus Ostermann, Oliver Plessow, and Gudrun Tscherpel. Turnhout: Brepols, 2006.Vol. 6. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy. 1-15.</mla>
<default>Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages. Arlinghaus F-J, Ostermann M, Plessow O, Tscherpel G (Eds);  Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy, 6.  Turnhout: Brepols:  1-15.</default>
<lncs> Arlinghaus, F.-J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., Tscherpel, G.: Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment. In: Arlinghaus, F.-J., Ostermann, M., Plessow, O., and Tscherpel, G. (eds.) Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy. 6, p. 1-15. Brepols, Turnhout (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef, Ostermann, Marcus, Plessow, Oliver, and Tscherpel, Gudrun. 2006. “Introduction: Written texts on the Move. Medieval Manuscript Culture in a Multimedia Environment”. In &lt;em&gt;Transforming the Medieval World. Uses of Pragmatic Literacy in the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Franz-Josef Arlinghaus, Marcus Ostermann, Oliver Plessow, and Gudrun Tscherpel, 6:1-15. Utrecht Studies in Medieval Literacy. Turnhout: Brepols.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2002110</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-07T08:01:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>