<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017409</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">G. E.</namePart><namePart type="family">Lasker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mahbubur Rahman</namePart><namePart type="family">Syed</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Symposium on Intelligent Multimedia and Distance Education (ISIMADE-99)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Sonification is the use of non-speech audio to convey information. We are developing tools for interactive data exploration, which make use of sonification for data presentation. In this paper, model-based sonification is presented as a concept to design auditory displays. Two designs are described: (1) particle trajectories in a "data potential" is a sonification model to reveal information about the clustering of vectorial data and (2) "data-sonograms" is a sonification for data from a classification problem to reveal information about the mixing of distinct classes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannRitter1999-LTY.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017409/2784307/HermannRitter1999-LTY.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Baden-Baden, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Acoustics</topic><topic>Cluster Analysis</topic><topic>Exploratory Data Analysis</topic><topic>Sonification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-921836-80-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20174096</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">189-194</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2701116</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1999). Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In G.E. Lasker &amp;amp; M.R. Syed (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 189-194). Gehalten auf der International Symposium on Intelligent Multimedia and Distance Education (ISIMADE-99), Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Hermann T, Ritter H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems. Lasker GE, Syed MR (Eds); Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics:  189-194.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G.E. Lasker, M.R. Syed), Int. Inst. For Advanced Studies In System Research And Cybernetics, Windsor, Ontario, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 189-194.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hermann T, Ritter H. Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In: Lasker GE, Syed MR, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;. Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics;  1999: 189-194.</ama>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In: Lasker, G.E. and Syed, M.R. (eds.) Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems. p. 189-194. Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics, Windsor, Ontario (1999).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 1999. “Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. G. E. Lasker and Mahbubur Rahman Syed, 189-194. Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (1999). “Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis” in &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;, Lasker, G. E., and Syed, M. R. eds. (Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics), 189-194.</frontiers>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. G. E. Lasker and Mahbubur Rahman Syed. Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics, 1999. 189-194.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1999). Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In G. E.  Lasker &amp;amp; M. R.  Syed (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 189-194). Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (1999): Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In: G. E. Lasker; Mahbubur Rahman Syed (Hrsg.):  Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems. Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics.  S. 189-194.</wels>
<default>Hermann T, Ritter H (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems. Lasker GE, Syed MR (Eds);  Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics:  189-194.</default>
<ieee> T. Hermann and H. Ritter, “Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;, G.E. Lasker and M.R. Syed, eds.,  Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics, 1999,  pp.189-194.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 1999. Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In G. E.  Lasker &amp;amp; M. R.  Syed, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt;.  Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics, pp. 189-194.</harvard1>
<apa>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (1999). Listen to your Data: Model-Based Sonification for Data Analysis. In G. E.  Lasker &amp;amp; M. R.  Syed (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in intelligent computing and multimedia systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 189-194). Windsor, Ontario: Int. Inst. for Advanced Studies in System research and cybernetics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017409</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>