<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017519</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Martini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anselmetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40180</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8720-4369</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andy</namePart><namePart type="family">Hunt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33079524</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">29125395</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ISon 2004</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents an interactive audio-haptic human-computer interface for controlling an atomic force microscope (AFM) in force spectroscopy experiments on single molecules. The sensor data used are proportional to the force that is applied to a single molecule. These forces are measured in real-time by using the reflection of a laser beam from a cantilever. We present a system that involves (a) a visual display of the data (b) a force-feedback joystick for navigating the sample and providing a tactile feedback of the forces, and (c) an auditory display to monitor the measured data while interactively moving the sample. The sonification we have developed integrates information at various levels of detail, including audifications of the high-frequency cantilever movement, and an auditory stream that communicates the instantaneous deviation of forces between the approach and retract phase of the sample. The sonification design and offline-computed sonifications will be presented and discussed. We further report on our first experiences with this interactive multi-modal control interface for manipulation of individual DNA molecules.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MartiniHermannAnselmettiRitter2004-ISF.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017519/2784293/MartiniHermannAnselmettiRitter2004-ISF.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Interactive Sonification Community</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20175199</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2703101</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Martini J, Hermann T, Anselmetti D, Ritter H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. Hermann T, Hunt A (Eds);  Interactive Sonification Community.</default>
<bio1>Martini J, Hermann T, Anselmetti D, Ritter H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. Hermann T, Hunt A (Eds); Interactive Sonification Community.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Martini, T.  Hermann, D.  Anselmetti, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Hermann, A. Hunt), Interactive Sonification Community, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Martini, J.; Hermann, T.; Anselmetti, D.; Ritter, H. (2004): Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In: Thomas Hermann; Andy Hunt (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification. Interactive Sonification Community.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, J., Hermann, T., Anselmetti, D., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In T.  Hermann &amp;amp; A.  Hunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; Interactive Sonification Community.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Martini, Jörg, Hermann, Thomas, Anselmetti, Dario, and Ritter, Helge. “Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Thomas Hermann and Andy Hunt. Interactive Sonification Community, 2004.</mla>
<frontiers>Martini, J., Hermann, T., Anselmetti, D., and Ritter, H. (2004). “Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, Hermann, T., and Hunt, A. eds. (Interactive Sonification Community).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, J., Hermann, T., Anselmetti, D. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In T. Hermann &amp;amp; A. Hunt (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der ISon 2004, Interactive Sonification Community.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Martini, J., Hermann, T., Anselmetti, D., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In T.  Hermann &amp;amp; A.  Hunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; Interactive Sonification Community.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Martini, Jörg, Hermann, Thomas, Anselmetti, Dario, and Ritter, Helge. 2004. “Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Thomas Hermann and Andy Hunt. Interactive Sonification Community.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Martini, J., Hermann, T., Anselmetti, D., Ritter, H.: Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In: Hermann, T. and Hunt, A. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification.  Interactive Sonification Community (2004).</lncs>
<ieee> J. Martini, et al., “Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, T. Hermann and A. Hunt, eds., Interactive Sonification Community, 2004.</ieee>
<harvard1>Martini, J., et al., 2004. Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In T.  Hermann &amp;amp; A.  Hunt, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;.  Interactive Sonification Community.</harvard1>
<ama>Martini J, Hermann T, Anselmetti D, Ritter H. Interactive Sonification for exploring Single Molecule Properties with AFM-based Force Spectroscopy. In: Hermann T, Hunt A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Interactive Sonification Community;  2004.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017519</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>