<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017556</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Louise Valgerður</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nickerson</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Audio Mostly</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents novel designs for the sonification (auditory representation) of data from grid-based games such as Connect Four, Sudoku and others, motivated by the search for effective auditory representations that are useful for visually-impaired users as well as to support overviews in case that the visual sense is already otherwise allocated. Grid-based games are ideal to develop sonification strategies since they offer the advantage of providing an excellent test environment to evaluate the designs by measuring details of the interaction, learning, performance of the users, etc. We present in detail two new playable sonification-based audio games, and finally discuss how the approaches might generalise to general grid-based interactive exploration, e.g. for spreadsheet data.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="NickersonHermann2008-ISO.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017556/2785032/NickersonHermann2008-ISO.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Piteå, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20175564</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">27-34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2698649</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/NH2008-ISO</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Nickerson LV, Hermann T. Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå;  2008: 27-34.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nickerson, Louise Valgerður, and Hermann, Thomas. 2008. “Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;, 27-34. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Nickerson, L.V., Hermann, T.: Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound. p. 27-34. Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå, Piteå, Sweden (2008).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nickerson, L.V. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2008). Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt; (S. 27-34). Gehalten auf der Audio Mostly, Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>L. V.  Nickerson, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;, Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå, Piteå, Sweden, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 27-34.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Nickerson LV, Hermann T (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound.  Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå:  27-34.</bio1>
<harvard1>Nickerson, L.V., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2008. Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;.  Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå, pp. 27-34.</harvard1>
<ieee> L.V. Nickerson and T. Hermann, “Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;,  Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå, 2008,  pp.27-34.</ieee>
<apa>Nickerson, L. V., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2008). Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;, 27-34. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå.</apa>
<frontiers>Nickerson, L. V., and Hermann, T. (2008). “Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt; (Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå), 27-34.</frontiers>
<mla>Nickerson, Louise Valgerður, and Hermann, Thomas. “Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå, 2008. 27-34.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nickerson, L. V., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2008). Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound&lt;/em&gt;, 27-34. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Nickerson, L. V.; Hermann, T. (2008): Interactive Sonification of Grid-based Games. In: Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå.  S. 27-34.</wels>
<default>Nickerson LV, Hermann T (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Audio Mostly Conference - A Conference on Interaction with Sound. Piteå, Sweden: Interactive Institute - Sonic Studio Piteå:  27-34.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017556</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>