<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017374</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tim Wilhelm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nattkemper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11602</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7986-1158</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schubert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">V.</namePart><namePart type="family">Falavar</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>METMBS 2000</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents a method to inspect multi-channel image data by creating audible em sonifications, which are `sound images', computed from a stack of image data. While visualization of multi-channel image data is limited by the available three color channels, our perception of sound is sensitive to a potentially much larger number of frequency channels or dynamic patterns, that can be perceived simultaneously. Browsing the image stack while listening to the sonifications facilitates the identification of intensity patterns and the discrimination of similar patterns. Some sonification designs which use different organization principles of acoustic elements derived from the data in the image stack are presented and sound examples are given. The evaluation of Multi-Parameter Fluorescence Microscopy Data is presented as a well suited application of this sonification method.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannNattkemperSchubertRitter2000-SOM.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017374/2784304/HermannNattkemperSchubertRitter2000-SOM.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>CSREA Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sonification</topic><topic>Multi-Channel Image Data</topic><topic>Proteomics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20173741</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">745-750</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2763993</url>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2701103</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Nattkemper, T.W., Schubert, W., Ritter, H.: Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In: Falavar, V. (ed.) Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences. p. 745-750. CSREA Press, Las Vegas (2000).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Nattkemper, Tim Wilhelm, Schubert, Walter, and Ritter, Helge. 2000. “Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data”. In &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, ed. V. Falavar, 745-750. Las Vegas: CSREA Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Nattkemper, Tim Wilhelm, Schubert, Walter, and Ritter, Helge. “Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data”. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. V. Falavar. Las Vegas: CSREA Press, 2000. 745-750.</mla>
<default>Hermann T, Nattkemper TW, Schubert W, Ritter H (2000)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences. Falavar V (Ed);  Las Vegas: CSREA Press:  745-750.</default>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Nattkemper, T. W.; Schubert, W.; Ritter, H. (2000): Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In: V. Falavar (Hrsg.):  Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences. Las Vegas: CSREA Press.  S. 745-750.</wels>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., et al., 2000. Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In V.  Falavar, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;.  Las Vegas: CSREA Press, pp. 745-750.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Nattkemper, T. W., Schubert, W., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2000). Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In V.  Falavar (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 745-750). Las Vegas: CSREA Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hermann T, Nattkemper TW, Schubert W, Ritter H (2000) &lt;br /&gt;Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences. Falavar V (Ed); Las Vegas: CSREA Press:  745-750.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, T. W.  Nattkemper, W.  Schubert, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: V. Falavar), Csrea Press, Las Vegas, &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 745-750.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hermann T, Nattkemper TW, Schubert W, Ritter H. Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In: Falavar V, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Las Vegas: CSREA Press;  2000: 745-750.</ama>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Nattkemper, T. W., Schubert, W., and Ritter, H. (2000). “Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data” in &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, Falavar, V. ed. (Las Vegas: CSREA Press), 745-750.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Nattkemper, T.W., Schubert, W. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2000). Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In V. Falavar (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt; (S. 745-750). Gehalten auf der METMBS 2000, Las Vegas: CSREA Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Hermann, T., Nattkemper, T. W., Schubert, W., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2000). Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data. In V.  Falavar (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 745-750). Las Vegas: CSREA Press.</apa>
<ieee> T. Hermann, et al., “Sonification of Multi-Channel Image Data”, &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the Mathematical and Engineering Techniques in Medical and Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, V. Falavar, ed.,  Las Vegas: CSREA Press, 2000,  pp.745-750.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017374</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:33Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>