<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017509</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lange</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">67610</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Antonio</namePart><namePart type="family">Camurri</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gualtiero</namePart><namePart type="family">Volpe</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>GW 2003</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present an approach to track a moving body in a sequence of camera images by model adaptation. The parameters of a stick figure model are varied by using a stochastic search algorithm. The similarity of rendered model images and camera images of the user are used as quality measure. A refinement of the algorithm is introduced by using combined stereo views and relevance maps to infer responsible joint angles from the difference of successive input images. Finally, the successful application of various versions of the algorithm on sequences of synthetic images is demonstrated.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="LangeHermannRitter2003-HBT.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017509/2787152/LangeHermannRitter2003-HBT.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Genova, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-21072-6</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000189451300013</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20175097</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">132-139</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Lange, C., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 132-139). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.</apa>
<ieee> C. Lange, T. Hermann, and H. Ritter, “Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;, A. Camurri and G. Volpe, eds.,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2004,  pp.132-139.</ieee>
<harvard1>Lange, C., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2004. Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 132-139.</harvard1>
<default>Lange C, Hermann T, Ritter H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915. Camurri A, Volpe G (Eds);  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  132-139.</default>
<mla>Lange, Christian, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Antonio Camurri and Gualtiero Volpe. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2004. 132-139.</mla>
<frontiers>Lange, C., Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2004). “Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;, Camurri, A., and Volpe, G. eds. (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 132-139.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lange, C., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In A.  Camurri &amp;amp; G.  Volpe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 132-139). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Lange, C.; Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2004): Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In: Antonio Camurri; Gualtiero Volpe (Hrsg.):  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.  S. 132-139.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lange, Christian, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2004. “Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Antonio Camurri and Gualtiero Volpe, 132-139. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lange, C., Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In: Camurri, A. and Volpe, G. (eds.) Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915. p. 132-139. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2004).</lncs>
<ama>Lange C, Hermann T, Ritter H. Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In: Camurri A, Volpe G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2004: 132-139.</ama>
<bio1>Lange C, Hermann T, Ritter H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915. Camurri A, Volpe G (Eds); Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  132-139.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Lange, T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Camurri, G. Volpe), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 132-139.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lange, C., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Holistic Body Tracking for Gestural Interfaces. In A. Camurri &amp;amp; G. Volpe (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction 5th International Gesture Workshop, Selected Revised Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2915&lt;/em&gt; (S. 132-139). Gehalten auf der GW 2003, Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017509</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-01T13:45:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>