<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017443</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andy</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hunt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pauletto</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ebad</namePart><namePart type="family">Banissi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Katy</namePart><namePart type="family">Börner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper stresses the importance of the human user being tightly embedded within an interactive control loop for exploring data sets using sound. We consider the quality of interaction, and how this can be improved in computer systems by learning from real-world acoustic interactions. We describe how different sonification methods can utilise the human feedback loop to enhance the perception and analysis of the data under investigation. Some considerations are given regarding systems and applications.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HuntHermannPauletto2004-IWS.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017443/2930355/HuntHermannPauletto2004-IWS.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-7695-2177-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20174432</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/IV.2004.1320244</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">879-884</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hunt, A., Hermann, T., Pauletto, S.: Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In: Banissi, E. and Börner, K. (eds.) IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). p. 879-884. IEEE Computer Society, Washington, DC, USA (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunt, Andy, Hermann, Thomas, and Pauletto, Sandra. 2004. “Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop”. In &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ebad Banissi and Katy Börner, 879-884. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hunt, Andy, Hermann, Thomas, and Pauletto, Sandra. “Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop”. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ebad Banissi and Katy Börner. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2004. 879-884.</mla>
<default>Hunt A, Hermann T, Pauletto S (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Banissi E, Börner K (Eds);  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  879-884.</default>
<wels>Hunt, A.; Hermann, T.; Pauletto, S. (2004): Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In: Ebad Banissi; Katy Börner (Hrsg.):  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society.  S. 879-884.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunt, A., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Pauletto, S. (2004). Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 879-884). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320244" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320244&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hunt A, Hermann T, Pauletto S (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Banissi E, Börner K (Eds); Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  879-884.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hunt, A., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Pauletto, S., 2004. Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner, eds. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;.  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, pp. 879-884.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Hunt, T.  Hermann, and S.  Pauletto, in &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Banissi, K. Börner), Ieee Computer Society, Washington, DC, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 879-884.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hunt A, Hermann T, Pauletto S. Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In: Banissi E, Börner K, eds. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society;  2004: 879-884.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunt, A., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Pauletto, S. (2004). Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In E. Banissi &amp;amp; K. Börner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 879-884). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/IV.2004.1320244.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hunt, A., Hermann, T., and Pauletto, S. (2004). “Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop” in &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, Banissi, E., and Börner, K. eds. (Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society), 879-884.</frontiers>
<apa>Hunt, A., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Pauletto, S. (2004). Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 879-884). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320244" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320244&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> A. Hunt, T. Hermann, and S. Pauletto, “Interacting with Sonification Systems. Closing the Loop”, &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, E. Banissi and K. Börner, eds.,  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2004,  pp.879-884.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017443</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-09T11:52:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>