<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017285</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stephani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart><namePart type="family">Susini</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Olivier</namePart><namePart type="family">Warusfel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper introduces kernel regression mapping sonification (KRMS) for optimized mappings between data features and the parameter space of Parameter Mapping Sonification. Kernel regression allows to map data spaces to high-dimensional parameter spaces such that specific locations in data space with pre-determined extent are represented by selected acoustic parameter vectors. Thereby, specifically chosen correlated settings of parameters may be selected to create perceptual fingerprints, such as a particular timbre or vowel. With KRMS, the perceptual fingerprints become clearly audible and separable. Furthermore, kernel regression defines meaningful interpolations for any point in between. We present and discuss the basic approach exemplified by our previously introduced vocal EEG sonification, report new sonifications and generalize the approach towards automatic parameter mapping generators using unsupervised learning approaches.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannBaier2008.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017285/2784283/HermannBaier2008.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IRCAM</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Paris, France</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172857</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2698580</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/HBSR2008-KRM</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Baier, Gerold, Stephani, Ulrich, and Ritter, Helge. 2008. “Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Patrick Susini and Olivier Warusfel. Paris, France: IRCAM.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Baier, G., Stephani, U., Ritter, H.: Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In: Susini, P. and Warusfel, O. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008).  IRCAM, Paris, France (2008).</lncs>
<default>Hermann T, Baier G, Stephani U, Ritter H (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008). Susini P, Warusfel O (Eds);  Paris, France: IRCAM.</default>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Baier, Gerold, Stephani, Ulrich, and Ritter, Helge. “Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Patrick Susini and Olivier Warusfel. Paris, France: IRCAM, 2008.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Baier, G., Stephani, U. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2008). Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In P. Susini &amp;amp; O. Warusfel (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008), Paris, France: IRCAM.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Baier, G., Stephani, U., and Ritter, H. (2008). “Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;, Susini, P., and Warusfel, O. eds. (Paris, France: IRCAM).</frontiers>
<ama>Hermann T, Baier G, Stephani U, Ritter H. Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In: Susini P, Warusfel O, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;. Paris, France: IRCAM;  2008.</ama>
<ieee> T. Hermann, et al., “Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;, P. Susini and O. Warusfel, eds.,  Paris, France: IRCAM, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Hermann, T., Baier, G., Stephani, U., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2008). Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In P.  Susini &amp;amp; O.  Warusfel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt; Paris, France: IRCAM.</apa>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Baier, G.; Stephani, U.; Ritter, H. (2008): Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In: Patrick Susini; Olivier Warusfel (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008). Paris, France: IRCAM.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, G.  Baier, U.  Stephani, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Susini, O. Warusfel), Ircam, Paris, France, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., et al., 2008. Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In P.  Susini &amp;amp; O.  Warusfel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt;.  Paris, France: IRCAM.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hermann T, Baier G, Stephani U, Ritter H (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008). Susini P, Warusfel O (Eds); Paris, France: IRCAM.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Baier, G., Stephani, U., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2008). Kernel Regression Mapping for Vocal EEG Sonification. In P.  Susini &amp;amp; O.  Warusfel (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2008)&lt;/em&gt; Paris, France: IRCAM.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017285</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>