<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017143</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bovermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">143296</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eoin</namePart><namePart type="family">Brazil</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD 2005</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents a new sonification model for the exploration of topographically ordered high-dimensional data (multi-parameter maps, volume data) where each data item consists of a position and feature vector. The sonification model implements a common metaphor from thermodynamics that heat can be interpreted as stochastic motion of 'molecules'. The latter are determined by the data under examination, and 'live' only in the feature space. Heat-induced interactions cause acoustic events that fuse to a granular sound texture which conveys meaningful information about the underlying distribution in feature space. As a second ingredient of the model, data selection is achieved by a separated navigation process in position space using a dynamic aura model, such that heat can be induced locally. Both, a visual and an auditory display are driven by the underlying model. We exemplify the sonification by means of interaction examples for different high-dimensional distributions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BovermannHermannRitter2005-TLH.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017143/2760917/BovermannHermannRitter2005-TLH.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>International Community for Auditory Display</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Limerick, Ireland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">1-874653-81X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20171431</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">85-91</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2700941</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E (Ed);  International Community for Auditory Display:  85-91.</default>
<mla>Bovermann, Till, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eoin Brazil. International Community for Auditory Display, 2005. 85-91.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, Till, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2005. “The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eoin Brazil, 85-91. International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In: Brazil, E. (ed.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 85-91. International Community for Auditory Display (2005).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Bovermann, T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: E. Brazil), International Community For Auditory Display, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 85-91.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H (2005) &lt;br /&gt;The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E (Ed); International Community for Auditory Display:  85-91.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2005. The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In E.  Brazil, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  International Community for Auditory Display, pp. 85-91.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In E.  Brazil (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 85-91). International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Bovermann, T.; Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2005): The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In: Eoin Brazil (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. International Community for Auditory Display.  S. 85-91.</wels>
<ieee> T. Bovermann, T. Hermann, and H. Ritter, “The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, E. Brazil, ed., International Community for Auditory Display, 2005,  pp.85-91.</ieee>
<apa>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In E.  Brazil (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 85-91). International Community for Auditory Display.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, T., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In E. Brazil (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 85-91). Gehalten auf der ICAD 2005, International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2005). “The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Brazil, E. ed. (International Community for Auditory Display), 85-91.</frontiers>
<ama>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H. The Local Heat Exploration Model for Interactive Sonification. In: Brazil E, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. International Community for Auditory Display;  2005: 85-91.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017143</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>