<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017209</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großhauser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10261456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Roberto</namePart><namePart type="family">Bresin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Interactive Sonification Workshop (ISon 2010)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The paper presents a multi-modal approach to tightly close the interaction loop between a human user and any tool in operation. Every activity of a human being generates multi-modal feedback, more or less related to the eyes (visual), the skin (sensory), the nose (olfactory) and the ears (auditive). Here we show the useful augmentation or complete creation of a nonexistent or less available feedback. As an example the performance of drilling tasks, line drawing tasks, or the complex task of bowing a violin can be considered.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GrosshauserH2010-MCL.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017209/2784333/GrosshauserH2010-MCL.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stockholm, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sound</topic><topic>Sensor</topic><topic>interaction</topic><topic>Sonification</topic><topic>closed-loop</topic><topic>Wearable</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172094</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">59-63</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2698347</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/GH2010-MCL</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In R. Bresin (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (S. 59-63). Gehalten auf der Interactive Sonification Workshop (ISon 2010), KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Großhauser, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Bresin), Kth School Of Computer Science And Communication (Csc), KTH, Stockholm, Sweden, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 59-63.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. Bresin R (Ed); KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC):  59-63.</bio1>
<ama>Großhauser T, Hermann T. Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In: Bresin R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC);  2010: 59-63.</ama>
<lncs> Großhauser, T., Hermann, T.: Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In: Bresin, R. (ed.) Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. p. 59-63. KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), KTH, Stockholm, Sweden (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. 2010. “Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Roberto Bresin, 59-63. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Großhauser, T.; Hermann, T. (2010): Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In: Roberto Bresin (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).  S. 59-63.</wels>
<mla>Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. “Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Roberto Bresin. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 2010. 59-63.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In R.  Bresin (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-63). KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Großhauser, T., and Hermann, T. (2010). “Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, Bresin, R. ed. (KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 59-63.</frontiers>
<default>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. Bresin R (Ed);  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC):  59-63.</default>
<harvard1>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2010. Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In R.  Bresin, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;.  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), pp. 59-63.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Großhauser and T. Hermann, “Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, R. Bresin, ed.,  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 2010,  pp.59-63.</ieee>
<apa>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Multimodal Closed-loop Human Machine Interaction. In R.  Bresin (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-63). KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017209</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>