<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017280</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Polyrhythm in the Human Brain</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stephen</namePart><namePart type="family">Barrass</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Three complementary methods are used to analyze the dynamics of multivariate EEG data obtained from a human listening to a piece of music. The analysis yields parameters for a data sonification that conserves temporal and frequency relationships as well as wave intensities of the data. Multiple events taking place on different time scales are combined to a polyrhythmic display in real time.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannBaierMueller2004-PIT.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017280/2760928/HermannBaierMueller2004-PIT.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ICAD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172807</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Baier, G.; Müller, M. (2004): Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In: Stephen Barrass (Hrsg.):  Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House. Sydney, Australia: ICAD.</wels>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Baier, Gerold, and Müller, Markus. “Polyrhythm in the Human Brain”. &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Stephen Barrass. Sydney, Australia: ICAD, 2004.</mla>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Baier, G., and Müller, M. (2004). “Polyrhythm in the Human Brain” in &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;, Barrass, S. ed. (Sydney, Australia: ICAD).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Baier, G., &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2004). Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In S.  Barrass (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt; Sydney, Australia: ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Hermann T, Baier G, Müller M (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House. Barrass S (Ed);  Sydney, Australia: ICAD.</default>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., Baier, G., &amp;amp; Müller, M., 2004. Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In S.  Barrass, ed. &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;.  Sydney, Australia: ICAD.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Hermann, G. Baier, and M. Müller, “Polyrhythm in the Human Brain”, &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;, S. Barrass, ed.,  Sydney, Australia: ICAD, 2004.</ieee>
<apa>Hermann, T., Baier, G., &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2004). Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In S.  Barrass (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt; Sydney, Australia: ICAD.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Baier, G. &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2004). Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In S. Barrass (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der ICAD, Sydney, Australia: ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, G.  Baier, and M.  Müller, in &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: S. Barrass), Icad, Sydney, Australia, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hermann T, Baier G, Müller M (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House. Barrass S (Ed); Sydney, Australia: ICAD.</bio1>
<ama>Hermann T, Baier G, Müller M. Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In: Barrass S, ed. &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;. Sydney, Australia: ICAD;  2004.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Baier, Gerold, and Müller, Markus. 2004. “Polyrhythm in the Human Brain”. In &lt;em&gt;Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Stephen Barrass. Sydney, Australia: ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Baier, G., Müller, M.: Polyrhythm in the Human Brain. In: Barrass, S. (ed.) Listening to the Mind Listening - Concert of Sonifications at the Sydney Opera House.  ICAD, Sydney, Australia (2004).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017280</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>