<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017309</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Drees</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eoin</namePart><namePart type="family">Brazil</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart><namePart type="family">Shinn-Cunningham</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD 2003</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper reports on a pilot project between our research department and and a local radio station, investigating the use of sonification to render and present auditory weather forecasts. The sonifications include auditory markers for certain relevant time points, expected weather events like thunder, snow or fog and several auditory streams to summarize the temporal weather changes during the day. To our knowledge, this is the first utilization of sonification in a regular radio program. We introduce the sonification concept and present our design of the sonification which is oriented at combined perceptional salience and emotional truthfulness. Sound examples are given for typical weather situations in Germany and several prototypical weather conditions which tune to be connected with emotional value. We will report first experiences with this pilot project and feedback of the audience on ICAD since broadcast started in February 2003.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannDrees2003.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017309/2760936/HermannDrees2003.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Boston University Publications Production Department</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20173095</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">208-211</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2703142</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Drees, J.M., Ritter, H.: Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In: Brazil, E. and Shinn-Cunningham, B. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 208-211. Boston University Publications Production Department, Boston, MA, USA (2003).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Drees, Jan M., and Ritter, Helge. 2003. “Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eoin Brazil and Barbara Shinn-Cunningham, 208-211. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Drees, Jan M., and Ritter, Helge. “Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eoin Brazil and Barbara Shinn-Cunningham. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, 2003. 208-211.</mla>
<default>Hermann T, Drees JM, Ritter H (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B (Eds);  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department:  208-211.</default>
<ama>Hermann T, Drees JM, Ritter H. Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In: Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department;  2003: 208-211.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Drees, J.M. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In E. Brazil &amp;amp; B. Shinn-Cunningham (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 208-211). Gehalten auf der ICAD 2003, Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Drees, J. M., and Ritter, H. (2003). “Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Brazil, E., and Shinn-Cunningham, B. eds. (Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department), 208-211.</frontiers>
<apa>Hermann, T., Drees, J. M., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 208-211). Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.</apa>
<ieee> T. Hermann, J.M. Drees, and H. Ritter, “Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, E. Brazil and B. Shinn-Cunningham, eds.,  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, 2003,  pp.208-211.</ieee>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Drees, J. M.; Ritter, H. (2003): Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In: Eoin Brazil; Barbara Shinn-Cunningham (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.  S. 208-211.</wels>
<bio1>Hermann T, Drees JM, Ritter H (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B (Eds); Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department:  208-211.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Drees, J. M., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 208-211). Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., Drees, J.M., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2003. Broadcasting Auditory Weather Reports – A Pilot Project. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, pp. 208-211.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, J. M.  Drees, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Brazil, B. Shinn-Cunningham), Boston University Publications Production Department, Boston, MA, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 208-211.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017309</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>