<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017380</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niehus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eoin</namePart><namePart type="family">Brazil</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart><namePart type="family">Shinn-Cunningham</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD 2003</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper introduces AVDisplay, a versatile auditory and visual display for monitoring, querying and accessing information about modules or processes in complex systems. In the context of a collaborative research effort (SFB360, artificial communicators) at Bielefeld University, a cognitive robotics system for human-machine interaction is being developed. The AVDisplay provides the central interface for monitoring and debugging this system, currently involving about 20 computers hosting more than 30 complex processes. The display is designed to provide a summary over the system's activities combining visualization and sonification techniques. The dynamic visualization allows inference of correlated activity of processes. A habituation simulation process automatically sets a perceptional focus on interesting and relevant process activities. The sonification part is designed to integrate emotional aspects – if the system suffers from poor sensory quality, the sound conveys this by sounding uncomfortable.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannNiehus2003.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017380/2760940/HermannNiehus2003.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Boston University Publications Production Department</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20173808</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">247-250</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2703597</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, Niehus, Christian, and Ritter, Helge. 2003. “Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eoin Brazil and Barbara Shinn-Cunningham, 247-250. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Niehus, C., Ritter, H.: Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In: Brazil, E. and Shinn-Cunningham, B. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 247-250. Boston University Publications Production Department, Boston, MA, USA (2003).</lncs>
<ama>Hermann T, Niehus C, Ritter H. Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In: Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department;  2003: 247-250.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, C.  Niehus, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Brazil, B. Shinn-Cunningham), Boston University Publications Production Department, Boston, MA, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 247-250.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hermann T, Niehus C, Ritter H (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B (Eds); Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department:  247-250.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Niehus, C. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In E. Brazil &amp;amp; B. Shinn-Cunningham (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 247-250). Gehalten auf der ICAD 2003, Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Hermann, T., Niehus, C., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 247-250). Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.</apa>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., Niehus, C., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2003. Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, pp. 247-250.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Hermann, C. Niehus, and H. Ritter, “Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, E. Brazil and B. Shinn-Cunningham, eds.,  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, 2003,  pp.247-250.</ieee>
<default>Hermann T, Niehus C, Ritter H (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Brazil E, Shinn-Cunningham B (Eds);  Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department:  247-250.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., Niehus, C., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2003). Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In E.  Brazil &amp;amp; B.  Shinn-Cunningham (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 247-250). Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, Niehus, Christian, and Ritter, Helge. “Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eoin Brazil and Barbara Shinn-Cunningham. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department, 2003. 247-250.</mla>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., Niehus, C., and Ritter, H. (2003). “Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Brazil, E., and Shinn-Cunningham, B. eds. (Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department), 247-250.</frontiers>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Niehus, C.; Ritter, H. (2003): Interactive Visualization and Sonification for Monitoring Complex Processes. In: Eoin Brazil; Barbara Shinn-Cunningham (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Boston, MA, USA: Boston University Publications Production Department.  S. 247-250.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017380</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>