<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017400</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ebad</namePart><namePart type="family">Banissi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Katy</namePart><namePart type="family">Börner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present an approach using incrementally constructed neural gas networks to 'grow' an intuitive interface for interactive exploratory sonification of high-dimensional data. The sonifications portray information about the intrinsic data dimensionality and its variation within the data space. The interface follows the paradigm of model-based sonification and consists of a graph of nodes that can be acoustically ý with simple mouse actions. The sound generation process is defined in terms of the node parameters and the graph topology, following a physically motivated model of energy flow through the graph structure. The resulting sonification model is tied to the given data set by constructing both graph topology and node parameters by an adaptive, fully data-driven learning process, using a growing neural gas network. We report several examples of applying this method to static data sets and point out a generalization to the task of process analysis</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannRitter2004-NGS.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017400/2930351/HermannRitter2004-NGS.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-7695-2177-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20174003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/IV.2004.1320243</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">871-878</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2921050</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data”. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ebad Banissi and Katy Börner. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2004. 871-878.</mla>
<default>Hermann T, Ritter H (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Banissi E, Börner K (Eds);  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  871-878.</default>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In: Banissi, E. and Börner, K. (eds.) IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). p. 871-878. IEEE Computer Society, Washington, DC, USA (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2004. “Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data”. In &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ebad Banissi and Katy Börner, 871-878. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2004. Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner, eds. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;.  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, pp. 871-878.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hermann T, Ritter H (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Banissi E, Börner K (Eds); Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  871-878.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 871-878). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320243" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Banissi, K. Börner), Ieee Computer Society, Washington, DC, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 871-878.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2004): Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In: Ebad Banissi; Katy Börner (Hrsg.):  IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society.  S. 871-878.</wels>
<apa>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In E.  Banissi &amp;amp; K.  Börner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 871-878). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320243" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2004.1320243&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> T. Hermann and H. Ritter, “Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data”, &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, E. Banissi and K. Börner, eds.,  Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2004,  pp.871-878.</ieee>
<ama>Hermann T, Ritter H. Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In: Banissi E, Börner K, eds. &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;. Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society;  2004: 871-878.</ama>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2004). “Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data” in &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt;, Banissi, E., and Börner, K. eds. (Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society), 871-878.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2004). Neural Gas Sonification - Growing Adaptive Interfaces for Interacting with Data. In E. Banissi &amp;amp; K. Börner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;IV '04: Proceedings of the Information Visualisation, Eighth International Conference on (IV'04)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 871-878). Washington, DC, USA: IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/IV.2004.1320243.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017400</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>