<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017539</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Milczynski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bovermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">143296</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tony</namePart><namePart type="family">Stockman</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD 2006</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This article introduces a novel human computer interaction device, developed in the scope of a Master's Thesis. The device allows continuous localized interaction by providing a malleable interaction surface. Diverse multi-finger as well as multi-handed manipulations can be applied. Furthermore, the device acts as a tangible user interface object, integrated into a tangible computing framework called tDesk. Software to convert the malleable element's shape into an internal surface representation has been developed. Malleable interactions are applied to a new Model-based Sonification approach for exploratory data analysis. High-dimensional data are acoustically explored via their informative interaction sound in result to the user's excitation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MilczynskiHermannBovermannRitter2006-AMD.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017539/2760914/MilczynskiHermannBovermannRitter2006-AMD.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-902-23821-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20175393</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">69-76</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2700564</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Milczynski, M., Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., Ritter, H.: A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In: Stockman, T. (ed.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 69-76. Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, London, UK (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Milczynski, Matthias, Hermann, Thomas, Bovermann, Till, and Ritter, Helge. 2006. “A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Tony Stockman, 69-76. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Milczynski, Matthias, Hermann, Thomas, Bovermann, Till, and Ritter, Helge. “A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Tony Stockman. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, 2006. 69-76.</mla>
<default>Milczynski M, Hermann T, Bovermann T, Ritter H (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Stockman T (Ed);  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London:  69-76.</default>
<wels>Milczynski, M.; Hermann, T.; Bovermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2006): A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In: Tony Stockman (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.  S. 69-76.</wels>
<bio1>Milczynski M, Hermann T, Bovermann T, Ritter H (2006) &lt;br /&gt;A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Stockman T (Ed); London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London:  69-76.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Milczynski, M., Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In T.  Stockman (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 69-76). London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Milczynski, M., et al., 2006. A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In T.  Stockman, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, pp. 69-76.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Milczynski, T.  Hermann, T.  Bovermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: T. Stockman), Department Of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University Of London, London, UK, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 69-76.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Milczynski M, Hermann T, Bovermann T, Ritter H. A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In: Stockman T, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London;  2006: 69-76.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Milczynski, M., Hermann, T., Bovermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In T. Stockman (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 69-76). Gehalten auf der ICAD 2006, London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Milczynski, M., Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2006). “A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Stockman, T. ed. (London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London), 69-76.</frontiers>
<apa>Milczynski, M., Hermann, T., Bovermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration. In T.  Stockman (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 69-76). London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.</apa>
<ieee> M. Milczynski, et al., “A Malleable Device with Applications to Sonification-based Data Exploration”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, T. Stockman, ed.,  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, 2006,  pp.69-76.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017539</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>