<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017213</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großhauser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10261456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Roberto</namePart><namePart type="family">Bresin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andy</namePart><namePart type="family">Hunt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Interactive Sonification Workshop, ISon 2010</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Wearable sensing technologies give the user the possibility of on-site and real-time measurements, analysis and feedback of movements and postures in everyday behaviour, learning and training situations. There are many established motion capturing technologies to support complex movements, but less mobile and wearable systems. One of the key disadvantages of the existing systems is their high complexity, for instance they demand high-speed cameras, multi-channel audio systems or the fixation to a special room or laboratory. As a low-cost and flexible solution, this paper presents an easily relocatable, flexible sensor-based system for motion capturing and multi-modal real-time feedback. Our system is easy to use, it even allows operation without an external computer. Here we introduce our wearable sensor-setup and outline its applications and benefits in typical everyday training situations in combination with multi-modal feedback and embedded systems including closed loop interactive sonification.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GrosshauserHermann_2_ISon2010.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017213/2698064/GrosshauserHermann_2_ISon2010.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stockholm, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>real-time</topic><topic>sensor</topic><topic>wearable</topic><topic>sonification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172130</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">75-79</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/GH2010-WMS</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Großhauser, T.; Hermann, T. (2010): Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In: Roberto Bresin; Thomas Hermann; Andy Hunt (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).  S. 75-79.</wels>
<frontiers>Großhauser, T., and Hermann, T. (2010). “Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, Bresin, R., Hermann, T., and Hunt, A. eds. (KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 75-79.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In R.  Bresin, T.  Hermann, &amp;amp; A.  Hunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 75-79). KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. “Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Roberto Bresin, Thomas Hermann, and Andy Hunt. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 2010. 75-79.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In R. Bresin, T. Hermann &amp;amp; A. Hunt (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (S. 75-79). Gehalten auf der Interactive Sonification Workshop, ISon 2010, KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. Bresin R, Hermann T, Hunt A (Eds);  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC):  75-79.</default>
<bio1>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. Bresin R, Hermann T, Hunt A (Eds); KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC):  75-79.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Großhauser, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Bresin, T. Hermann, A. Hunt), Kth School Of Computer Science And Communication (Csc), KTH, Stockholm, Sweden, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 75-79.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> T. Großhauser and T. Hermann, “Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, R. Bresin, T. Hermann, and A. Hunt, eds.,  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), 2010,  pp.75-79.</ieee>
<harvard1>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2010. Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In R.  Bresin, T.  Hermann, &amp;amp; A.  Hunt, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;.  KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), pp. 75-79.</harvard1>
<ama>Großhauser T, Hermann T. Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In: Bresin R, Hermann T, Hunt A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC);  2010: 75-79.</ama>
<apa>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In R.  Bresin, T.  Hermann, &amp;amp; A.  Hunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 75-79). KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. 2010. “Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Roberto Bresin, Thomas Hermann, and Andy Hunt, 75-79. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden: KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Großhauser, T., Hermann, T.: Wearable Multi-Modal Sensor System for Embedded Audio-Haptic Feedback. In: Bresin, R., Hermann, T., and Hunt, A. (eds.) Proceedings of the 3rd International workshop on Interactive Sonification. p. 75-79. KTH School of Computer Science and Communication (CSC), KTH, Stockholm, Sweden (2010).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017213</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>