<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017200</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großhauser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10261456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großekathöfer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11642967</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kirsty</namePart><namePart type="family">Beilharz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andrew</namePart><namePart type="family">Johnston</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sam</namePart><namePart type="family">Ferguson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Amy Yi-Chun</namePart><namePart type="family">Chen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>New Interfaces for Musical Expression 2010 (NIME 2010)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Pressure, motion, and gesture are important parameters in musical instrument playing. Pressure sensing allows to interpret complex hidden forces, which appear during playing a musical instrument. The combination of our new sensor setup with pattern recognition techniques like the lately developed ordered means models allows fast and precise recognition of highly skilled playing techniques.
This includes left and right hand analysis as well as a combination of both. In this paper we show bow position recognition for string instruments by means of support vector regression machines on the right hand finger pressure, as well as bowing recognition and inaccurate
playing detection with ordered means models. We also introduce a new left hand and chin pressure sensing method for coordination and position change analysis. Our methods in combination with our audio, video, and gesture recording software can be used for teaching and exercising. Especially studies of complex movements and finger force
distribution changes can benefit from such an approach. Practical applications include the recognition of inaccuracy, cramping, or malposition, and, last but not least, the development of augmented instruments and new playing techniques.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="New_Sensors_and_Pattern_Recognition_Techniques_for_String_Instruments.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017200/2698069/New_Sensors_and_Pattern_Recognition_Techniques_for_String_Instruments.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Sydney, Australia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>multimodal</topic><topic>real-time</topic><topic>feedback</topic><topic>pattern recognition</topic><topic>violin</topic><topic>piano</topic><topic>teaching</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-646-53482-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172001</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">271-276</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/GGH2010-NSA</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2010. New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In K.  Beilharz, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 271-276.</harvard1>
<bio1>Großhauser T, Großekathöfer U, Hermann T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia. Beilharz K, Johnston A, Ferguson S, Chen AY-C (Eds); 271-276.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In K.  Beilharz, A.  Johnston, S.  Ferguson, &amp;amp; A. Y. - C.  Chen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 271-276).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Großhauser, U.  Großekathöfer, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: K. Beilharz, A. Johnston, S. Ferguson, A.Y.-C. Chen), &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 271-276.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Großhauser, T.; Großekathöfer, U.; Hermann, T. (2010): New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In: Kirsty Beilharz; Andrew Johnston; Sam Ferguson; Amy Yi-Chun Chen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia.  S. 271-276.</wels>
<apa>Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In K.  Beilharz, A.  Johnston, S.  Ferguson, &amp;amp; A. Y. - C.  Chen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 271-276).</apa>
<ieee> T. Großhauser, U. Großekathöfer, and T. Hermann, “New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;, K. Beilharz, et al., eds., 2010,  pp.271-276.</ieee>
<ama>Großhauser T, Großekathöfer U, Hermann T. New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In: Beilharz K, Johnston A, Ferguson S, Chen AY-C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;. 2010: 271-276.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In K. Beilharz, A. Johnston, S. Ferguson &amp;amp; A.Y.-C. Chen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt; (S. 271-276). Gehalten auf der New Interfaces for Musical Expression 2010 (NIME 2010).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U., and Hermann, T. (2010). “New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;, Beilharz, K., Johnston, A., Ferguson, S., and Chen, A. Y. - C. eds. 271-276.</frontiers>
<mla>Großhauser, Tobias, Großekathöfer, Ulf, and Hermann, Thomas. “New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Kirsty Beilharz, Andrew Johnston, Sam Ferguson, and Amy Yi-Chun Chen. 2010. 271-276.</mla>
<default>Großhauser T, Großekathöfer U, Hermann T (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia. Beilharz K, Johnston A, Ferguson S, Chen AY-C (Eds);   271-276.</default>
<lncs> Großhauser, T., Großekathöfer, U., Hermann, T.: New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments. In: Beilharz, K., Johnston, A., Ferguson, S., and Chen, A.Y.-C. (eds.) Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia. p. 271-276. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, Tobias, Großekathöfer, Ulf, and Hermann, Thomas. 2010. “New Sensors and Pattern Recognition Techniques for String Instruments”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on New Interfaces for Musical Expression++ (NIME 2010), Sydney, Australia&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Kirsty Beilharz, Andrew Johnston, Sam Ferguson, and Amy Yi-Chun Chen, 271-276.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017200</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>