<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017413</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Nakatsu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Kawahara</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper introduces Crystallization Sonification, a sonification model for exploratory analysis of high-dimensional datasets. The  model  is  designed  to  provide  information  about  the  intrinsic data dimensionality (which is a local feature) and the global data dimensionality, as well as the transitions between a local and global view on a dataset. Furthermore the sound allows to display the clustering in high-dimensional datasets.  The model defines a crystal growth process in the high-dimensional data-space which starts at a user selected “condensation nucleus” and incrementally includes neighboring data according to some growth criterion. The sound  summarizes  the temporal evolution  of this crystal growth process.  For introducing the model, a simple growth law is used. Other growth laws which are used in the context of hierarchical clustering  are  also  suited  and  their  application  in  crystallization sonification offers new ways to inspect the results of data clustering as an alternative to dendrogram plots.
In this paper, the sonification model is described and example sonifications  are  presented  for  some  synthetic  high-dimensional datasets.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HermannRitter2002.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017413/2784298/HermannRitter2002.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ICAD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Kyoto, Japan</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20174131</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">76-81</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2704155</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2002. “Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. R. Nakatsu and H. Kawahara, 76-81. ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In: Nakatsu, R. and Kawahara, H. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 76-81. ICAD (2002).</lncs>
<default>Hermann T, Ritter H (2002)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Nakatsu R, Kawahara H (Eds);  ICAD:  76-81.</default>
<mla>Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. R. Nakatsu and H. Kawahara. ICAD, 2002. 76-81.</mla>
<frontiers>Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2002). “Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Nakatsu, R., and Kawahara, H. eds. (ICAD), 76-81.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2002). Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In R. Nakatsu &amp;amp; H. Kawahara (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 76-81). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display, ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hermann T, Ritter H. Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In: Nakatsu R, Kawahara H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. ICAD;  2002: 76-81.</ama>
<ieee> T. Hermann and H. Ritter, “Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, R. Nakatsu and H. Kawahara, eds., ICAD, 2002,  pp.76-81.</ieee>
<apa>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2002). Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In R.  Nakatsu &amp;amp; H.  Kawahara (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 76-81). ICAD.</apa>
<wels>Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2002): Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In: R. Nakatsu; H. Kawahara (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. ICAD.  S. 76-81.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Nakatsu, H. Kawahara), Icad, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 76-81.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hermann T, Ritter H (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Nakatsu R, Kawahara H (Eds); ICAD:  76-81.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2002. Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In R.  Nakatsu &amp;amp; H.  Kawahara, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  ICAD, pp. 76-81.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2002). Crystallization Sonification of High-dimensional Datasets. In R.  Nakatsu &amp;amp; H.  Kawahara (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 76-81). ICAD.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017413</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>