<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017154</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bovermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">143296</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tony</namePart><namePart type="family">Stockman</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICAD 2006</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we develop a sonification model following the Model-based Sonification approach that allows to scan high-dimensional data distributions by means of a physical object in the hand of the user. In the sonification model, the user is immersed in a 3D space of invisible but acoustically active objects which can be excited by him. Tangible computing allows to identify the excitation object (e.g. a geometric surface) with a physical object used as controller, and thus creates a strong metaphor for understanding and relating feedback sounds in response to the user's own activity, position and orientation. We explain the technique and our current implementation in detail and give examples at hand of synthetic and real-world data sets.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BovermannHermann2006.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017154/2760903/BovermannHermann2006.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-902-23821-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20171548</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">77-82</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2699962</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Stockman T (Ed);  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London:  77-82.</default>
<wels>Bovermann, T.; Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2006): Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In: Tony Stockman (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.  S. 77-82.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In T.  Stockman (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-82). London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2006). “Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Stockman, T. ed. (London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London), 77-82.</frontiers>
<mla>Bovermann, Till, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Tony Stockman. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, 2006. 77-82.</mla>
<apa>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In T.  Stockman (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-82). London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.</apa>
<harvard1>Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2006. Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In T.  Stockman, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, pp. 77-82.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Bovermann, T. Hermann, and H. Ritter, “Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, T. Stockman, ed.,  London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, 2006,  pp.77-82.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Bovermann, T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: T. Stockman), Department Of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University Of London, London, UK, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 77-82.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Stockman T (Ed); London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London:  77-82.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, T., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2006). Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In T. Stockman (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 77-82). Gehalten auf der ICAD 2006, London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Bovermann, T., Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In: Stockman, T. (ed.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 77-82. Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London, London, UK (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bovermann, Till, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2006. “Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Tony Stockman, 77-82. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Bovermann T, Hermann T, Ritter H. Tangible Data Scanning Sonification Model. In: Stockman T, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. London, UK: Department of Computer Science, Queen Mary, University of London;  2006: 77-82.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017154</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>