<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017114</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study the rhythmic organization of coupled nonlinear oscillators. If oscillators with non-identical internal frequency are coupled, they generate a great variety of periodic and chaotic rhythmic patterns. Sonification of these patterns suggests their characterization in terms of polyrhythms: each oscillatory unit subdivides "measures" of equal or varying length differently. For the case of two coupled oscillators, the organization of these polyrhythms is exemplified as a function of the internal frequency ratio and the coupling strength. Some sonification strategies are presented which aid to detect complex rhythmic relationships between oscillators. The results may be of importance for the analysis of complex multivariate time series like human EEG.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BaierHermannMueller2005-POO.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017114/2788643/BaierHermannMueller2005-POO.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thermann</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-7695-2397-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20171144</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/IV.2005.99</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">5-10</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2700951</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baier, Gerold, Hermann, Thomas, and Müller, Marcus. 2005. “Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators”. In &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia, 5-10. Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Baier, G., Hermann, T., Müller, M.: Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In: School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (ed.) IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05). p. 5-10. IEEE Computer Society, Los Alamitos, CA, USA (2005).</lncs>
<ama>Baier G, Hermann T, Müller M. Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In: School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia, ed. &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;. Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society;  2005: 5-10.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Baier, T.  Hermann, and M.  Müller, in &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia), Ieee Computer Society, Los Alamitos, CA, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 5-10.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Baier G, Hermann T, Müller M (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05). School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Ed); Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  5-10.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baier, G., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2005). Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 5-10). Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/IV.2005.99.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Baier, G., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2005). Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 5-10). Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2005.99" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2005.99&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Baier, G., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Müller, M., 2005. Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia, ed. &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;.  Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society, pp. 5-10.</harvard1>
<ieee> G. Baier, T. Hermann, and M. Müller, “Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators”, &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;, School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia, ed.,  Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2005,  pp.5-10.</ieee>
<default>Baier G, Hermann T, Müller M (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05). School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Ed);  Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society:  5-10.</default>
<wels>Baier, G.; Hermann, T.; Müller, M. (2005): Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In: School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Hrsg.):  IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05). Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society.  S. 5-10.</wels>
<mla>Baier, Gerold, Hermann, Thomas, and Müller, Marcus. “Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators”. &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia. Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society, 2005. 5-10.</mla>
<frontiers>Baier, G., Hermann, T., and Müller, M. (2005). “Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators” in &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt;, School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia ed. (Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society), 5-10.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baier, G., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Müller, M. (2005). Polyrhythmic Organization of Coupled Nonlinear Oscillators. In School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (Greenwich). Department of Information Systems and Multimedia (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;IV' 05: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Information Visualisation (IV'05)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 5-10). Los Alamitos, CA, USA: IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2005.99" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/IV.2005.99&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017114</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>