<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2017222</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großhauser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10261456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eoin</namePart><namePart type="family">Brazil</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2010)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The wearable sensor and feedback system presented in this paper is a type of audio-haptic display which contains on board sensors, embedded sound synthesis, external sensors, and on the feedback side a loudspeaker and several vibrating motors. The so-called "embedded sonification" in this case here is an onboard IC with implemented sound synthesis. This is adjusted directly by the user and/or controlled in real-time by the sensors, which are on the board or fixed on the human body and connected to the board via cable or radio frequency transmission. Direct audio out and tactile feedback closes the loop between the wearable board and the user. In many situations, this setup can serve as a complement to visual output, e.g. exploring data in 3D-space or learning motion and gestures in dance, sports or outdoor and every-day  activities. A new metaphor for interactive acoustical augmentation is introduced, the so called "audio loupe". In this case it means the sonification of minimal movements or state changes, which can sometimes hardly be perceived visually or corporal. These are for example small jitters or deviations of predefined ideal gestures or movements. Our system is easy to use, it even allows operation without an external computer. We demonstrate and outline the benefits of our wearable interactive setup in highly skilled motion learning scenarios in dance and sports.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GrosshauserHermann2010.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2017222/2698351/GrosshauserHermann2010.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>International Community for Auditory Display</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Washington, DC, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>interaction</topic><topic>real-time</topic><topic>Closed-loop</topic><topic>Gesture</topic><topic>Motion</topic><topic>sonification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-9670904-3-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20172227</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">31-38</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In E. Brazil (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 31-38). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2010), Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Großhauser, T., and Hermann, T. (2010). “Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Brazil, E. ed. (Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display), 31-38.</frontiers>
<ama>Großhauser T, Hermann T. Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In: Brazil E, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display;  2010: 31-38.</ama>
<ieee> T. Großhauser and T. Hermann, “Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, E. Brazil, ed.,  Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display, 2010,  pp.31-38.</ieee>
<apa>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In E.  Brazil (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-38). Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display.</apa>
<wels>Großhauser, T.; Hermann, T. (2010): Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In: Eoin Brazil (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display. Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display.  S. 31-38.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Großhauser, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: E. Brazil), International Community For Auditory Display, Washington, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 31-38.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display. Brazil E (Ed); Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display:  31-38.</bio1>
<harvard1>Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2010. Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In E.  Brazil, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display, pp. 31-38.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2010). Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In E.  Brazil (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-38). Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. 2010. “Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eoin Brazil, 31-38. Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Großhauser, T., Hermann, T.: Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction. In: Brazil, E. (ed.) Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display. p. 31-38. International Community for Auditory Display, Washington, USA (2010).</lncs>
<default>Großhauser T, Hermann T (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display. Brazil E (Ed);  Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display:  31-38.</default>
<mla>Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. “Wearable Setup for Gesture and Motion based Closed Loop Audio-Haptic Interaction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 16th International Community for Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eoin Brazil. Washington, USA: International Community for Auditory Display, 2010. 31-38.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2017222</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-14T10:08:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:39Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>