<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2028215</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kreysa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16869621</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10822979</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Boicho</namePart><namePart type="family">Kokinov</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Annette</namePart><namePart type="family">Karmiloff-Smith</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nancy J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Nersessian</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27003888</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Perspectives on Cognitive Science (EuroCogSci)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="EuroCogSci-paper168.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2028215/2615344/EuroCogSci-paper168.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>New Bulgarian University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Sofia, Bulgaria</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-954-535-660-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20282151</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">141</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P. Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In: Kokinov B, Karmiloff-Smith A, Nersessian NJ, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;. Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press;  2011: 141.</ama>
<frontiers>Kreysa, H., and Knoeferle, P. (2011). “Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, Kokinov, B., Karmiloff-Smith, A., and Nersessian, N. J. eds. (Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press), 141.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, H. &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In B. Kokinov, A. Karmiloff-Smith &amp;amp; N.J. Nersessian (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt; (S. 141). Gehalten auf der European Perspectives on Cognitive Science (EuroCogSci), Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In B.  Kokinov, A.  Karmiloff-Smith, &amp;amp; N. J.  Nersessian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt; (p. 141). Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press.</apa>
<ieee> H. Kreysa and P. Knoeferle, “Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, B. Kokinov, A. Karmiloff-Smith, and N.J. Nersessian, eds.,  Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press, 2011,  pp.141.</ieee>
<wels>Kreysa, H.; Knoeferle, P. (2011): Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In: Boicho Kokinov; Annette Karmiloff-Smith; Nancy J. Nersessian (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science. Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press.  S. 141.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In B.  Kokinov, A.  Karmiloff-Smith, &amp;amp; N. J.  Nersessian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt; (p. 141). Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P., 2011. Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In B.  Kokinov, A.  Karmiloff-Smith, &amp;amp; N. J.  Nersessian, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;.  Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press, pp. 141.</harvard1>
<bio1>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science. Kokinov B, Karmiloff-Smith A, Nersessian NJ (Eds); Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press:  141.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Kreysa, and P.  Knoeferle, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Kokinov, A. Karmiloff-Smith, N.J. Nersessian), New Bulgarian University Press, Sofia, Bulgaria, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 141.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Kreysa, H., Knoeferle, P.: Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German. In: Kokinov, B., Karmiloff-Smith, A., and Nersessian, N.J. (eds.) Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science. p. 141. New Bulgarian University Press, Sofia, Bulgaria (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, Helene, and Knoeferle, Pia. 2011. “Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Boicho Kokinov, Annette Karmiloff-Smith, and Nancy J. Nersessian, 141. Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kreysa, Helene, and Knoeferle, Pia. “Peripheral speaker gaze facilitates spoken language comprehension: syntactic structuring and thematic role asssignment in German”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Boicho Kokinov, Annette Karmiloff-Smith, and Nancy J. Nersessian. Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press, 2011. 141.</mla>
<default>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the European Conference on Cognitive Science. Kokinov B, Karmiloff-Smith A, Nersessian NJ (Eds);  Sofia, Bulgaria: New Bulgarian University Press:  141.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2028215</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-03-28T17:07:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>