<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2034737</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Peltason</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">3694854</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10380</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">While human-robot interaction is typically limited to restrictive command-control style, traditional dialog modeling approaches are not directly applicable to robotics due to the lack of real-world integration. We present an approach that combines insights from dialog modeling with software-engineering demands that arise in robotics system research to provide a generalizable framework that can easily be applied to new scenarios. This goal is achieved by defining interaction patterns that combine abstract task states (such as task accepted or failed) with robot dialog acts (such as assertion or apology). An evaluation of the usability for robotic experts and novices showed that both groups were able to program 3 out of 5 dialog fragments in one hour while showing a steep learning curve. We argue that the proposed approach allows for less restricted and more informative human-robot interactions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="jpeltaso-modeling-hri.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2034737/2448352/jpeltaso-modeling-hri.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>AAAI Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20347377</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Peltason, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, B., 2010. Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. In &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;.  Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Peltason and B. Wrede, “Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns”, &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;,  Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press, 2010.</ieee>
<apa>Peltason, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, B. (2010). Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt; Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.</apa>
<wels>Peltason, J.; Wrede, B. (2010): Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. In: AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.</wels>
<mla>Peltason, Julia, and Wrede, Britta. “Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns”. &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press, 2010.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peltason, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, B. (2010). Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt; Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Peltason, J., and Wrede, B. (2010). “Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns” in &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt; (Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press).</frontiers>
<default>Peltason J, Wrede B (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.</default>
<ama>Peltason J, Wrede B. Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. In:  &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press;  2010.</ama>
<lncs> Peltason, J., Wrede, B.: Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots.  AAAI Press, Arlington, VA, USA (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peltason, Julia, and Wrede, Britta. 2010. “Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns”. In &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peltason, J. &amp;amp; Wrede, B. (2010). Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Peltason, and B.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots&lt;/em&gt;, Aaai Press, Arlington, VA, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Peltason J, Wrede B (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Modeling Human-Robot Interaction Based on Generic Interaction Patterns. &lt;br /&gt;In:  AAAI Fall Symposium: Dialog with Robots.  Arlington, VA, USA: AAAI Press.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2034737</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-04-07T10:37:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>