<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2036216</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Basak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bilecen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6023853</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Despite their expanding significance in a globalizing world today, international students are not thoroughly studied. The international student mobility is not a contemporary phenomenon, yet the examination of such mobility within theoretical concepts is a contemporary one. The concept of transnational social space combines the sending and receiving contexts used in analyzing different forms of migration; however not for international students yet. This article first examines the general definitions in the literature related to international student mobility and shows the complexity regarding to their status. Then it suggests the necessity and convenience of applying transnational social space concept as a tool used currently in migration studies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_63_bilcen.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2036216/2319773/workingpaper_63_bilcen.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48602</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, Basak. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bilecen, B.: Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2009).</lncs>
<default>Bilecen B (2009)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<mla>Bilecen, Basak. &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2009. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63.</mla>
<wels>Bilecen, B. (2009): Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Bilecen, &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Bilecen, B., 2009. &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bilecen B (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, B. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, B. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bilecen, B. (2009). Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<ama>Bilecen B. &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2009.</ama>
<ieee> B. Bilecen, &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2009.</ieee>
<apa>Bilecen, B. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Lost in Status? Temporary, Permanent, Potential, Highly Skilled: The International Student Mobility&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 63). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2036216</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-04-12T08:10:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>