<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2083906</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lösch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15393387</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2845-7072</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart><namePart type="family">Depping</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart><namePart type="family">Suthaus</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>EBSLG Annual General Conference</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">There is no doubt that the increased visibility of publications deposited in freely accessible documents servers is an important motivation for scholars to publish their works Open Access. Bielefeld Academic Search Engine (BASE) is a service provider that indexes scientific content stored in both institutional and subject repositories. After a short introduction to the technical and conceptual background, this article describes the features of BASE and finally projects future developments to be taken out to further improve the system.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="loesch_2011.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2083906/2272791/loesch_2011.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Köln</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Bielefeld Academic Search Engine</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-931596-56-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20839066</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">11-15</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Lösch, M.: A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In: Depping, R. and Suthaus, C. (eds.) EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. 2, p. 11-15. Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, Köln (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lösch, Mathias. 2011. “A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents”. In &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ralf Depping and Christiane Suthaus, 2:11-15. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Lösch, Mathias. “A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents”. &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ralf Depping and Christiane Suthaus. Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, 2011.Vol. 2. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. 11-15.</mla>
<default>Lösch M (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers. Depping R, Suthaus C (Eds);  Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, 2.  Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln:  11-15.</default>
<wels>Lösch, M. (2011): A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In: Ralf Depping; Christiane Suthaus (Hrsg.):  EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers. Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. (Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, 2).  S. 11-15.</wels>
<harvard1>Lösch, M., 2011. A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In R.  Depping &amp;amp; C.  Suthaus, eds. &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. no.2  Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, pp. 11-15.</harvard1>
<bio1>Lösch M (2011) &lt;br /&gt;A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. &lt;br /&gt;In:  EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers. Depping R, Suthaus C (Eds); Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, 2. Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln:  11-15.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lösch, M. (2011). A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In R.  Depping &amp;amp; C.  Suthaus (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-15). Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Lösch, in &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Depping, C. Suthaus), Universitäts- Und Stadtbibliothek Köln, Köln, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 11-15.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Lösch M. A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In: Depping R, Suthaus C, eds. &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln. Vol 2. Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln;  2011: 11-15.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lösch, M. (2011). A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents (Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln). In R. Depping &amp;amp; C. Suthaus (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 11-15). Gehalten auf der EBSLG Annual General Conference, Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Lösch, M. (2011). “A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents” in &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;, Depping, R., and Suthaus, C. eds. Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, vol. 2, (Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln), 11-15.</frontiers>
<apa>Lösch, M. (2011). A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents. In R.  Depping &amp;amp; C.  Suthaus (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-15). Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln.</apa>
<ieee> M. Lösch, “A Multidisciplinary Search Engine for Scientific Open Access Documents”, &lt;em&gt;EBSLG Annual General Conference, 18. - 21.05.2010, Cologne. Selected papers&lt;/em&gt;, R. Depping and C. Suthaus, eds., Elektronische Schriftenreihe der Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, vol. 2,  Köln: Universitäts- und Stadtbibliothek Köln, 2011,  pp.11-15.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2083906</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-02T07:58:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>