<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2094977</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stavros</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Skopeteas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20588480</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Caroline</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Féry</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nino</namePart><namePart type="family">Amiridze</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tamar</namePart><namePart type="family">Reseck</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Manana</namePart><namePart type="family">Topadze Gäumann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The expression of focus in Georgian differs from the expression of focus in other intonational languages like English and German. The crucial prosodic device in Georgian
is the division of the utterance in prosodic phrases, signaled by boundary tones. In contrast to German and English, pitch accents – if present at all in Georgian – do not constitute unambiguous cues for the focus structure, even though pitch register extension is a possible correlate of focus. However, it has been observed for other languages that a particular prosodic realization of noun phrase subconstituents may evoke an exhaustive
interpretation, i.e., a reading in which the relevant alternatives in discourse are excluded.
This phenomenon is well known from languages like English or German, which may signal focus through pitch accents, but is puzzling for a language like Georgian, which
lacks this prosodic strategy. This article presents a small-scale production study on the prosodic reflexes of exhaustivity in Georgian. Our findings show that prosodic phrasing is the main correlate of exhaustivity, but that the element on which exhaustivity is coded
may present phonetic features resembling pitch accent. These features are not associated with a single syllable, but rather affect the entire word.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A47 Skopeteas Fery 2011 Exhaustivity Georgian.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2094977/2900624/A47 Skopeteas Fery 2011 Exhaustivity Georgian.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>text/x-moz-deleted</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Brockmeyer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>exhaustivity</topic><topic>Georgian</topic><topic>Intonation</topic><topic>word order</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20949773</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">79-100</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, Stavros, and Féry, Caroline. 2014. “Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation”. In &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Nino Amiridze, Tamar Reseck, and Manana Topadze Gäumann, 79-100. Bochum: Brockmeyer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Skopeteas, S., Féry, C.: Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In: Amiridze, N., Reseck, T., and Topadze Gäumann, M. (eds.) Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax. p. 79-100. Brockmeyer, Bochum (2014).</lncs>
<ama>Skopeteas S, Féry C. Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In: Amiridze N, Reseck T, Topadze Gäumann M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;. Bochum: Brockmeyer;  2014: 79-100.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Skopeteas, and C.  Féry, in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Amiridze, T. Reseck, M. Topadze Gäumann), Brockmeyer, Bochum, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 79-100.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Skopeteas S, Féry C (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax. Amiridze N, Reseck T, Topadze Gäumann M (Eds); Bochum: Brockmeyer:  79-100.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, S. &amp;amp; Féry, C. (2014). Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In N. Amiridze, T. Reseck &amp;amp; M. Topadze Gäumann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt; (S. 79-100). Bochum: Brockmeyer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Skopeteas, S., &amp;amp; Féry, C. (2014). Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In N.  Amiridze, T.  Reseck, &amp;amp; M.  Topadze Gäumann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 79-100). Bochum: Brockmeyer.</apa>
<harvard1>Skopeteas, S., &amp;amp; Féry, C., 2014. Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In N.  Amiridze, T.  Reseck, &amp;amp; M.  Topadze Gäumann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;.  Bochum: Brockmeyer, pp. 79-100.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Skopeteas and C. Féry, “Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation”, &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;, N. Amiridze, T. Reseck, and M. Topadze Gäumann, eds.,  Bochum: Brockmeyer, 2014,  pp.79-100.</ieee>
<default>Skopeteas S, Féry C (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax. Amiridze N, Reseck T, Topadze Gäumann M (Eds);  Bochum: Brockmeyer:  79-100.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, S., &amp;amp; Féry, C. (2014). Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In N.  Amiridze, T.  Reseck, &amp;amp; M.  Topadze Gäumann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 79-100). Bochum: Brockmeyer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Skopeteas, Stavros, and Féry, Caroline. “Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation”. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Nino Amiridze, Tamar Reseck, and Manana Topadze Gäumann. Bochum: Brockmeyer, 2014. 79-100.</mla>
<frontiers>Skopeteas, S., and Féry, C. (2014). “Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation” in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax&lt;/em&gt;, Amiridze, N., Reseck, T., and Topadze Gäumann, M. eds. (Bochum: Brockmeyer), 79-100.</frontiers>
<wels>Skopeteas, S.; Féry, C. (2014): Prosodic cues for exhaustive interpretations: A production study on Georgian intonation. In: Nino Amiridze; Tamar Reseck; Manana Topadze Gäumann (Hrsg.):  Advances in Kartvelian Morphology and Syntax. Bochum: Brockmeyer.  S. 79-100.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2094977</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-13T11:23:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>