<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2095191</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stavros</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Skopeteas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20588480</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gisbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fanselow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rusudan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Asatiani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Monique</namePart><namePart type="family">Lamers</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">De Swart</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The morphological and syntactic facts from Georgian create a unique puzzle for the study of sentence processing. The word order is characterized by considerable freedom and case marking is not uni-directionally associated with -roles. This article presents a grammatical account of Georgian case marking and a study on incremental sentences processing. The empirical findings show that case is indeed a more reliable cue than word order in processing clauses with thematically ambiguous arguments. Furthermore, the obtained data suggest an asymmetry between dative experiencers and dative actors, such that only the revision of the thematic properties of the latter is associated with high processing cost.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A36_Skopeteas_Fanselow_Asatiani_2010_Case_Inversion.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2095191/2275184/A36_Skopeteas_Fanselow_Asatiani_2010_Case_Inversion.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>syntactic processing</topic><topic>inversion</topic><topic>case</topic><topic>Georgian</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Case, Word Order, and Prominence</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="ISI">000323857400007</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20951918</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">145-171</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> S. Skopeteas, G. Fanselow, and R. Asatiani, “Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing”, &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;, M. Lamers and P. De Swart, eds., Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics,  New York: Springer, 2011,  pp.145-171.</ieee>
<apa>Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G., &amp;amp; Asatiani, R. (2011). Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In M.  Lamers &amp;amp; P.  De Swart (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 145-171). New York: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<frontiers>Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G., and Asatiani, R. (2011). “Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing” in &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;, Lamers, M., and De Swart, P. eds. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics (New York: Springer), 145-171.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G. &amp;amp; Asatiani, R. (2011). Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing (Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics). In M. Lamers &amp;amp; P. De Swart (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt; (S. 145-171). New York: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Skopeteas S, Fanselow G, Asatiani R. Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In: Lamers M, De Swart P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics. New York: Springer;  2011: 145-171.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Skopeteas, G.  Fanselow, and R.  Asatiani, in &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Lamers, P. De Swart), Springer, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 145-171.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G., &amp;amp; Asatiani, R. (2011). Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In M.  Lamers &amp;amp; P.  De Swart (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 145-171). New York: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-1463-2_7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G., &amp;amp; Asatiani, R., 2011. Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In M.  Lamers &amp;amp; P.  De Swart, eds. &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics.  New York: Springer, pp. 145-171.</harvard1>
<bio1>Skopeteas S, Fanselow G, Asatiani R (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Case, Word Order, and Prominence. Lamers M, De Swart P (Eds); Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics,  New York: Springer:  145-171.</bio1>
<wels>Skopeteas, S.; Fanselow, G.; Asatiani, R. (2011): Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In: Monique Lamers; Peter De Swart (Hrsg.):  Case, Word Order, and Prominence. New York: Springer. (Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics, ).  S. 145-171.</wels>
<default>Skopeteas S, Fanselow G, Asatiani R (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Case, Word Order, and Prominence. Lamers M, De Swart P (Eds);  Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics.  New York: Springer:  145-171.</default>
<mla>Skopeteas, Stavros, Fanselow, Gisbert, and Asatiani, Rusudan. “Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing”. &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Monique Lamers and Peter De Swart. New York: Springer, 2011. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics. 145-171.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Skopeteas, Stavros, Fanselow, Gisbert, and Asatiani, Rusudan. 2011. “Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing”. In &lt;em&gt;Case, Word Order, and Prominence&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Monique Lamers and Peter De Swart, 145-171. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics. New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Skopeteas, S., Fanselow, G., Asatiani, R.: Case inversion in Georgian: Syntactic properties and sentence processing. In: Lamers, M. and De Swart, P. (eds.) Case, Word Order, and Prominence. Studies in Theoretical Psycholinguistics. p. 145-171. Springer, New York (2011).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2095191</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-13T16:47:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>