<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2097157</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rieser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11749</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.Y.</namePart><namePart type="family">Chai</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.D.</namePart><namePart type="family">Moore</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Passonneau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">D.R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Traum</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>12th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Although not very well investigated, a crucial aspect of gesture use in dialogues is to regulate the organisation of the interaction. People use gestures decisively, for example to indicate that they want someone to take the turn, to 'brush away' what someone else said, or to acknowledge others' contributions. We present first insights from a corpus-based investigation of how gestures are used to regulate dialogue, and we provide first results from an account to capture these phenomena in agent-based communication simulations. By advancing a model for autonomous gesture generation to also cover gesture interpretation, this account enables a full gesture turn exchange cycle of generation, understanding and acceptance/generation in virtual conversational agents.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BergmannRieserKopp_SigDial2011_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2097157/2410351/BergmannRieserKopp_SigDial2011_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-20971570</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">88-97</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bergmann K, Rieser H, Kopp S (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference. Chai JY, Moore JD, Passonneau RJ, Traum DR (Eds);  Association for Computational Linguistics:  88-97.</default>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, Rieser, Hannes, and Kopp, Stefan. “Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. J.Y. Chai, J.D. Moore, R.J. Passonneau, and D.R. Traum. Association for Computational Linguistics, 2011. 88-97.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, Rieser, Hannes, and Kopp, Stefan. 2011. “Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J.Y. Chai, J.D. Moore, R.J. Passonneau, and D.R. Traum, 88-97. Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Rieser, H., Kopp, S.: Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In: Chai, J.Y., Moore, J.D., Passonneau, R.J., and Traum, D.R. (eds.) Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference. p. 88-97. Association for Computational Linguistics (2011).</lncs>
<ieee> K. Bergmann, H. Rieser, and S. Kopp, “Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;, J.Y. Chai, et al., eds., Association for Computational Linguistics, 2011,  pp.88-97.</ieee>
<apa>Bergmann, K., Rieser, H., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2011). Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In J. Y.  Chai, J. D.  Moore, R. J.  Passonneau, &amp;amp; D. R.  Traum (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 88-97). Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., Rieser, H., and Kopp, S. (2011). “Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;, Chai, J. Y., Moore, J. D., Passonneau, R. J., and Traum, D. R. eds. (Association for Computational Linguistics), 88-97.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Rieser, H. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2011). Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In J.Y. Chai, J.D. Moore, R.J. Passonneau &amp;amp; D.R. Traum (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt; (S. 88-97). Gehalten auf der 12th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue, Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bergmann K, Rieser H, Kopp S. Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In: Chai JY, Moore JD, Passonneau RJ, Traum DR, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics;  2011: 88-97.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, H.  Rieser, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.Y. Chai, J.D. Moore, R.J. Passonneau, D.R. Traum), Association For Computational Linguistics, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 88-97.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Rieser, H., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2011). Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In J. Y.  Chai, J. D.  Moore, R. J.  Passonneau, &amp;amp; D. R.  Traum (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 88-97). Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Rieser H, Kopp S (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference. Chai JY, Moore JD, Passonneau RJ, Traum DR (Eds); Association for Computational Linguistics:  88-97.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., Rieser, H., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2011. Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In J. Y.  Chai, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference&lt;/em&gt;.  Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 88-97.</harvard1>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Rieser, H.; Kopp, S. (2011): Regulating Dialogue With Gestures---Towards an Empirically Grounded Simulation with Conversational Agents. In: J.Y. Chai; J.D. Moore; R.J. Passonneau; D.R. Traum (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the SIGdial 2011 Conference. Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 88-97.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2097157</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-19T16:01:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>