<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2140606</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eckard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedenklau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10270455</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Julie A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Jacko</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>14th International Conference, HCI International 2011</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img
src="https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2696637/2702775"
width="200" style="float:right;"&gt;&lt;/center&gt; In this paper we present a proof of concept for saving and restoring mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces (TUIs). We describe our actuated Tangible Active Objects (TAOs) and explain the design which allows equal user access to a dial-based fully tangible actuated menu metaphor. We present a new application extending an existing TUI for interactive sonification of process data with saving and restoring mechanisms and we outline another application proposal for family therapists.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Riedenklau-HCII2011-camera-ready.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2140606/2684444/Riedenklau-HCII2011-camera-ready.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Orlando, Fl, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-21604-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21406062</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6762</number></detail><extent unit="pages">110-118</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2696637</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/RHR2011-SRM</url>
  
     <url>http://www.tangibleactiveobjects.de/project/SRM2011.html</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Riedenklau E, Hermann T, Ritter H. Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In: Jacko JA, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 6762. Heidelberg: Springer;  2011: 110-118.</ama>
<frontiers>Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T., and Ritter, H. (2011). “Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects” in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;, Jacko, J. A. ed. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 6762, (Heidelberg: Springer), 110-118.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2011). Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In J.A. Jacko (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt; (S. 110-118). Gehalten auf der 14th International Conference, HCI International 2011, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2011). Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In J. A.  Jacko (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 6762&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 110-118). Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> E. Riedenklau, T. Hermann, and H. Ritter, “Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects”, &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;, J.A. Jacko, ed., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 6762,  Heidelberg: Springer, 2011,  pp.110-118.</ieee>
<wels>Riedenklau, E.; Hermann, T.; Ritter, H. (2011): Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In: Julie A. Jacko (Hrsg.):  Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II. Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6762).  S. 110-118.</wels>
<bio1>Riedenklau E, Hermann T, Ritter H (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II. Jacko JA (Ed); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6762. Heidelberg: Springer:  110-118.</bio1>
<harvard1>Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2011. Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In J. A.  Jacko, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.6762  Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 110-118.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2011). Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In J. A.  Jacko (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 6762&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 110-118). Heidelberg: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21605-3_12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Riedenklau, T.  Hermann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: J.A. Jacko), Springer, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 110-118.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Riedenklau, E., Hermann, T., Ritter, H.: Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects. In: Jacko, J.A. (ed.) Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 6762, p. 110-118. Springer, Heidelberg (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Riedenklau, Eckard, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. 2011. “Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects”. In &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Julie A. Jacko, 6762:110-118. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Riedenklau, Eckard, Hermann, Thomas, and Ritter, Helge. “Saving and Restoring Mechanisms for Tangible User Interfaces through Tangible Active Objects”. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Julie A. Jacko. Heidelberg: Springer, 2011.Vol. 6762. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 110-118.</mla>
<default>Riedenklau E, Hermann T, Ritter H (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction. Interaction Techniques and Environments. 14th International Conference, Proceedings, Part II. Jacko JA (Ed);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6762.  Heidelberg: Springer:  110-118.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2140606</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-20T12:55:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>