<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2141786</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Horstmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6591682</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart><namePart type="family">Rosemann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services 2009</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Scenarios of collaboration for supporting Open Access to research results through institutional repository networks have been explored between the IR Grid of the National Science Library of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the European DRIVER-Initiative through its German partners Bielefeld University Library as well as the State and University Library Göttingen. The activities included a joint analysis of the DRIVER infrastructure software D-NET and also resulted in the registration of chinese repositories in the DRIVER network</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="horstmann_driver.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2141786/2319774/horstmann_driver.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Zentralbibliothek für Medizin</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Kunming, China</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Institutional repository</topic><topic>Open Access</topic><topic>Research infrastructure</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-9808397-6-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21417862</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4126/cas2009</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Horstmann, W.: Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In: Rosemann, U. (ed.) Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services.  Zentralbibliothek für Medizin, Cologne, Germany (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Horstmann, Wolfram. 2009. “Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Uwe Rosemann. Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Horstmann W. Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In: Rosemann U, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;. Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin;  2009.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Horstmann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: U. Rosemann), Zentralbibliothek Für Medizin, Cologne, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Horstmann W (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services. Rosemann U (Ed); Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Horstmann, W. (2009). Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In U. Rosemann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services 2009, Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin. doi:10.4126/cas2009.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Horstmann, W. (2009). Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In U.  Rosemann (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt; Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4126/cas2009" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4126/cas2009&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Horstmann, W., 2009. Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In U.  Rosemann, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;.  Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin.</harvard1>
<ieee> W. Horstmann, “Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;, U. Rosemann, ed.,  Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin, 2009.</ieee>
<default>Horstmann W (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services. Rosemann U (Ed);  Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin.</default>
<wels>Horstmann, W. (2009): Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In: Uwe Rosemann (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services. Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin.</wels>
<mla>Horstmann, Wolfram. “Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Uwe Rosemann. Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin, 2009.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Horstmann, W. (2009). Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China. In U.  Rosemann (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt; Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4126/cas2009" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4126/cas2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Horstmann, W. (2009). “Building Repository Networks with DRIVER: Joint Explorations with the IR Grid in China” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Sino-German Symposium on Development of Library and Information Services&lt;/em&gt;, Rosemann, U. ed. (Cologne, Germany: Zentralbibliothek für Medizin).</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2141786</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-26T09:46:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>