<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2142025</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26109209</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8875773</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11608</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gienger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stéphane</namePart><namePart type="family">Doncieux</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Benoît</namePart><namePart type="family">Girard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Agnès</namePart><namePart type="family">Guillot</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">John</namePart><namePart type="family">Hallam</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Arcady</namePart><namePart type="family">Meyer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Baptiste</namePart><namePart type="family">Mouret</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present a neural network approach to learn inverse kinematics
of the humanoid robot ASIMO, where we focus on bi-manual
tool use. The learning copes with both the highly redundant inverse
kinematics of ASIMO and the additional arbitrary constraint imposed
by the tool that couples both hands. We show that this complex kinematics
can be learned from few ground-truth examples using an efficient
recurrent reservoir framework, which has been introduced previously for
kinematics learning and movement generation. We analyze and quantify
the network’s generalization for a given tool by means of reproducing
the constraint in untrained target motions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="NeumannRolfSteilSAB2010.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2142025/2903544/NeumannRolfSteilSAB2010.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Paris, France</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>CoR-Lab Publication</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-15192-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21420253</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6226</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, K., Rolf, M., Steil, J.J. &amp;amp; Gienger, M. (2010). Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements (Lecture notes in computer science). In S. Doncieux, B. Girard, A. Guillot, J. Hallam, J.-A. Meyer &amp;amp; J.-B. Mouret (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010, Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Neumann K, Rolf M, Steil JJ, Gienger M (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings. Doncieux S, Girard B, Guillot A, Hallam J, Meyer J-A, Mouret J-B (Eds); Lecture notes in computer science, 6226. Springer.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Neumann, M.  Rolf, J. J.  Steil, and M.  Gienger, in &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Doncieux, B. Girard, A. Guillot, J. Hallam, J.-A. Meyer, J.-B. Mouret), Springer, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Neumann K, Rolf M, Steil JJ, Gienger M. Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In: Doncieux S, Girard B, Guillot A, Hallam J, Meyer J-A, Mouret J-B, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. Vol 6226. Springer;  2010.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, Klaus, Rolf, Matthias, Steil, Jochen J., and Gienger, Michael. 2010. “Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements”. In &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Stéphane Doncieux, Benoît Girard, Agnès Guillot, John Hallam, Jean-Arcady Meyer, and Jean-Baptiste Mouret. Vol. 6226. Lecture notes in computer science. Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Neumann, K., Rolf, M., Steil, J.J., Gienger, M.: Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In: Doncieux, S., Girard, B., Guillot, A., Hallam, J., Meyer, J.-A., and Mouret, J.-B. (eds.) From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings. Lecture notes in computer science. 6226,  Springer (2010).</lncs>
<wels>Neumann, K.; Rolf, M.; Steil, J. J.; Gienger, M. (2010): Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In: Stéphane Doncieux; Benoît Girard; Agnès Guillot; John Hallam; Jean-Arcady Meyer; Jean-Baptiste Mouret (Hrsg.):  From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings. Springer. (Lecture notes in computer science, 6226).</wels>
<mla>Neumann, Klaus, Rolf, Matthias, Steil, Jochen J., and Gienger, Michael. “Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements”. &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Stéphane Doncieux, Benoît Girard, Agnès Guillot, John Hallam, Jean-Arcady Meyer, and Jean-Baptiste Mouret. Springer, 2010.Vol. 6226. Lecture notes in computer science.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, K., Rolf, M., Steil, J. J., &amp;amp; Gienger, M. (2010). Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In S.  Doncieux, B.  Girard, A.  Guillot, J.  Hallam, J. - A.  Meyer, &amp;amp; J. - B.  Mouret (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 6226&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Neumann, K., Rolf, M., Steil, J. J., and Gienger, M. (2010). “Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements” in &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Doncieux, S., Girard, B., Guillot, A., Hallam, J., Meyer, J. - A., and Mouret, J. - B. eds. Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 6226, (Springer).</frontiers>
<default>Neumann K, Rolf M, Steil JJ, Gienger M (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings. Doncieux S, Girard B, Guillot A, Hallam J, Meyer J-A, Mouret J-B (Eds);  Lecture notes in computer science, 6226.  Springer.</default>
<ieee> K. Neumann, et al., “Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements”, &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, S. Doncieux, et al., eds., Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 6226, Springer, 2010.</ieee>
<harvard1>Neumann, K., et al., 2010. Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In S.  Doncieux, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. no.6226  Springer.</harvard1>
<apa>Neumann, K., Rolf, M., Steil, J. J., &amp;amp; Gienger, M. (2010). Learning Inverse Kinematics for Pose-Constraint Bi-Manual Movements. In S.  Doncieux, B.  Girard, A.  Guillot, J.  Hallam, J. - A.  Meyer, &amp;amp; J. - B.  Mouret (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 6226&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Animals to Animats 11. 11th International Conference on Simulation of Adaptive Behavior, SAB 2010. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15193-4_45&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2142025</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-27T13:36:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>