<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2143414</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Götze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stavros</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Skopeteas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20588480</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Torsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Roloff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ruben</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stoel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Balder</namePart><namePart type="family">Ten Cate</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Henk</namePart><namePart type="family">Zeevat</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A22_Goetze_et_al_2007_Archive.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2143414/2276185/A22_Goetze_et_al_2007_Archive.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-75143-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21434148</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4363</number></detail><extent unit="pages">127-138</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Götze M, Skopeteas S, Roloff T, Stoel R (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005. Ten Cate B, Zeevat H (Eds);  Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 4363.  Berlin: Springer:  127-138.</default>
<frontiers>Götze, M., Skopeteas, S., Roloff, T., and Stoel, R. (2007). “Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;, Ten Cate, B., and Zeevat, H. eds. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 4363, (Berlin: Springer), 127-138.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Götze, M., Skopeteas, S., Roloff, T., &amp;amp; Stoel, R. (2007). Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In B.  Ten Cate &amp;amp; H.  Zeevat (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 4363&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 127-138). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Götze, Michael, Skopeteas, Stavros, Roloff, Torsten, and Stoel, Ruben. “Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Balder Ten Cate and Henk Zeevat. Berlin: Springer, 2007.Vol. 4363. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 127-138.</mla>
<wels>Götze, M.; Skopeteas, S.; Roloff, T.; Stoel, R. (2007): Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In: Balder Ten Cate; Henk Zeevat (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005. Berlin: Springer. (Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 4363).  S. 127-138.</wels>
<apa>Götze, M., Skopeteas, S., Roloff, T., &amp;amp; Stoel, R. (2007). Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In B.  Ten Cate &amp;amp; H.  Zeevat (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 4363&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 127-138). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Götze, M., et al., 2007. Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In B.  Ten Cate &amp;amp; H.  Zeevat, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence. no.4363  Berlin: Springer, pp. 127-138.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Götze, et al., “Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;, B. Ten Cate and H. Zeevat, eds., Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 4363,  Berlin: Springer, 2007,  pp.127-138.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Götze, S.  Skopeteas, T.  Roloff, and R.  Stoel, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Ten Cate, H. Zeevat), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 127-138.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Götze M, Skopeteas S, Roloff T, Stoel R (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005. Ten Cate B, Zeevat H (Eds); Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 4363. Berlin: Springer:  127-138.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Götze, M., Skopeteas, S., Roloff, T. &amp;amp; Stoel, R. (2007). Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration (Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In B. Ten Cate &amp;amp; H. Zeevat (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt; (S. 127-138). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-75144-1_10.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Götze, M., Skopeteas, S., Roloff, T., Stoel, R.: Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In: Ten Cate, B. and Zeevat, H. (eds.) Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 4363, p. 127-138. Springer, Berlin (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Götze, Michael, Skopeteas, Stavros, Roloff, Torsten, and Stoel, Ruben. 2007. “Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Balder Ten Cate and Henk Zeevat, 4363:127-138. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Götze M, Skopeteas S, Roloff T, Stoel R. Towards a cross-linguistic production data archive: structure and exploration. In: Ten Cate B, Zeevat H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic and Computation 2005&lt;/em&gt;. Lectures Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Vol 4363. Berlin: Springer;  2007: 127-138.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2143414</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-31T19:55:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>