<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2144347</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liguda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sara</namePart><namePart type="family">Barbieri</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Katherine</namePart><namePart type="family">Scott</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Luigina</namePart><namePart type="family">Ciolfi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Since 2004 the virtual agent Max is living at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum – a computer science museum. He is welcoming and entertaining visitors ten hours a day, six days a week, for seven years. This article brings together the experiences made by the staff of the museum, the scientists who created and maintained the installation, the visitors and the agent himself. It provides insights about the installation’s hard- and software and presents highlights of the agent’s ontogenesis in terms of the features he has gained. A special focus is on the means Max uses to engage with visitors and the features which make him attractive.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2011_-_Pfeiffer,_Liguda,_Wachsmuth_-_Living with a Virtual Agent.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2144347/2932904/2011_-_Pfeiffer,_Liguda,_Wachsmuth_-_Living with a Virtual Agent.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>thinkk creative &amp; the University of Limerick</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Limerick</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Embodied Conversational Agent</topic><topic>ECA</topic><topic>Chatterbot</topic><topic>Max</topic><topic>Museum</topic><topic>Artificial Intelligence</topic><topic>Virtual Agent</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-905952-31-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21443472</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">121-131</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Pfeiffer T, Liguda C, Wachsmuth I, Stein S. Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In: Barbieri S, Scott K, Ciolfi L, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;. Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick;  2011: 121-131.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T., Liguda, C., Wachsmuth, I. &amp;amp; Stein, S. (2011). Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In S. Barbieri, K. Scott &amp;amp; L. Ciolfi (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt; (S. 121-131). Gehalten auf der Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011, Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pfeiffer, T., Liguda, C., Wachsmuth, I., and Stein, S. (2011). “Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;, Barbieri, S., Scott, K., and Ciolfi, L. eds. (Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick), 121-131.</frontiers>
<apa>Pfeiffer, T., Liguda, C., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Stein, S. (2011). Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In S.  Barbieri, K.  Scott, &amp;amp; L.  Ciolfi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 121-131). Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick.</apa>
<ieee> T. Pfeiffer, et al., “Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;, S. Barbieri, K. Scott, and L. Ciolfi, eds.,  Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick, 2011,  pp.121-131.</ieee>
<wels>Pfeiffer, T.; Liguda, C.; Wachsmuth, I.; Stein, S. (2011): Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In: Sara Barbieri; Katherine Scott; Luigina Ciolfi (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences. Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick.  S. 121-131.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T., Liguda, C., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Stein, S. (2011). Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In S.  Barbieri, K.  Scott, &amp;amp; L.  Ciolfi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 121-131). Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Pfeiffer, T., et al., 2011. Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In S.  Barbieri, K.  Scott, &amp;amp; L.  Ciolfi, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;.  Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick, pp. 121-131.</harvard1>
<bio1>Pfeiffer T, Liguda C, Wachsmuth I, Stein S (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences. Barbieri S, Scott K, Ciolfi L (Eds); Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick:  121-131.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Pfeiffer, C.  Liguda, I.  Wachsmuth, and S.  Stein, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Barbieri, K. Scott, L. Ciolfi), Thinkk Creative &amp;amp; The University Of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 121-131.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Pfeiffer, T., Liguda, C., Wachsmuth, I., Stein, S.: Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum. In: Barbieri, S., Scott, K., and Ciolfi, L. (eds.) Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences. p. 121-131. thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, Thies, Liguda, Christian, Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Stein, Stefan. 2011. “Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sara Barbieri, Katherine Scott, and Luigina Ciolfi, 121-131. Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Pfeiffer, Thies, Liguda, Christian, Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Stein, Stefan. “Living with a Virtual Agent: Seven Years with an Embodied Conversational Agent at the Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sara Barbieri, Katherine Scott, and Luigina Ciolfi. Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick, 2011. 121-131.</mla>
<default>Pfeiffer T, Liguda C, Wachsmuth I, Stein S (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Re-Thinking Technology in Museums 2011 - Emerging Experiences. Barbieri S, Scott K, Ciolfi L (Eds);  Limerick, Ireland: thinkk creative &amp;amp; the University of Limerick:  121-131.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2144347</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-06T15:05:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-06T15:18:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>