<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2144805</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emad</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Monier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Per</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wilhelm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23056178</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents a video tracking system for tracking players in indoor sports using two high quality digital cameras. The tracking algorithm is based on template matching technique taking into consideration closed world assumptions. The output of the system can be visualized interactively for convenient analysis of player movements. The implementation has been efficiently done as a software system that can be used by coaches and sport
scientists.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A_Computer_Vision_Based_Tracking_System_for_Indoor_Team_Sports.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2144805/2407048/A_Computer_Vision_Based_Tracking_System_for_Indoor_Team_Sports.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-21448057</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Monier, E., Wilhelm, P., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2009). A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt; Cairo, Egypt.</apa>
<ieee> E. Monier, P. Wilhelm, and U. Rückert, “A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports”, &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;,  Cairo, Egypt: 2009.</ieee>
<harvard1>Monier, E., Wilhelm, P., &amp;amp; Rückert, U., 2009. A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. In &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  Cairo, Egypt.</harvard1>
<default>Monier E, Wilhelm P, Rückert U (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems. Cairo, Egypt.</default>
<wels>Monier, E.; Wilhelm, P.; Rückert, U. (2009): A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. In: The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems. Cairo, Egypt.</wels>
<frontiers>Monier, E., Wilhelm, P., and Rückert, U. (2009). “A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports” in &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Cairo, Egypt).</frontiers>
<mla>Monier, Emad, Wilhelm, Per, and Rückert, Ulrich. “A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports”. &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Cairo, Egypt, 2009.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Monier, E., Wilhelm, P., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2009). A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt; Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs> Monier, E., Wilhelm, P., Rückert, U.: A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems.  Cairo, Egypt (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Monier, Emad, Wilhelm, Per, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2009. “A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports”. In &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Monier E, Wilhelm P, Rückert U. A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. In:  &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Cairo, Egypt;  2009.</ama>
<bio1>Monier E, Wilhelm P, Rückert U (2009) &lt;br /&gt;A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems.  Cairo, Egypt.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Monier, P.  Wilhelm, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Cairo, Egypt, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Monier, E., Wilhelm, P. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2009). A Computer Vision Based Tracking System for Indoor Team Sports. &lt;em&gt;The fourth International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2144805</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-08T13:26:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>