<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2278579</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thierry</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Declerck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krieger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susan M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thomas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Paul</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buitelaar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sean</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">O'Riain</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wunner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gilles</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maguet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">McCrae</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15477100</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7227-1331</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dennis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spohr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20297557</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Montiel-Ponsoda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">József</namePart><namePart type="family">Roóz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">János</namePart><namePart type="family">Ivanyos</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MONTIFIC-Monnet_20paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2278579/2650493/MONTIFIC-Monnet_20paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>HVG Press Kft.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-963-08-0012-9 </identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22785791</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">67-76</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Declerck, Thierry, Krieger, Hans-Ulrich, Thomas, Susan M., Buitelaar, Paul, O'Riain, Sean, Wunner, Tobias, Maguet, Gilles, McCrae, John, Spohr, Dennis, and Montiel-Ponsoda, Elena. 2010. “Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe”. In &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;, ed. József Roóz and János Ivanyos, 67-76. Budapest: HVG Press Kft.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Declerck, T., Krieger, H.-U., Thomas, S.M., Buitelaar, P., O'Riain, S., Wunner, T., Maguet, G., McCrae, J., Spohr, D., Montiel-Ponsoda, E.: Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In: Roóz, J. and Ivanyos, J. (eds.) Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework. p. 67-76. HVG Press Kft., Budapest (2010).</lncs>
<default>Declerck T, Krieger H-U, Thomas SM, Buitelaar P, O'Riain S, Wunner T, Maguet G, McCrae J, Spohr D, Montiel-Ponsoda E (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework. Roóz J, Ivanyos J (Eds);  Budapest: HVG Press Kft.:  67-76.</default>
<mla>Declerck, Thierry, Krieger, Hans-Ulrich, Thomas, Susan M., Buitelaar, Paul, O'Riain, Sean, Wunner, Tobias, Maguet, Gilles, McCrae, John, Spohr, Dennis, and Montiel-Ponsoda, Elena. “Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe”. &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. József Roóz and János Ivanyos. Budapest: HVG Press Kft., 2010. 67-76.</mla>
<wels>Declerck, T.; Krieger, H. - U.; Thomas, S. M.; Buitelaar, P.; O'Riain, S.; Wunner, T.; Maguet, G.; McCrae, J.; Spohr, D.; Montiel-Ponsoda, E. (2010): Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In: József Roóz; János Ivanyos (Hrsg.):  Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework. Budapest: HVG Press Kft.  S. 67-76.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Declerck, H. - U.  Krieger, S. M.  Thomas, P.  Buitelaar, S.  O'Riain, T.  Wunner, G.  Maguet, J.  McCrae, D.  Spohr, and E.  Montiel-Ponsoda, in &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Roóz, J. Ivanyos), Hvg Press Kft., Budapest, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 67-76.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Declerck T, Krieger H-U, Thomas SM, Buitelaar P, O'Riain S, Wunner T, Maguet G, McCrae J, Spohr D, Montiel-Ponsoda E (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework. Roóz J, Ivanyos J (Eds); Budapest: HVG Press Kft.:  67-76.</bio1>
<harvard1>Declerck, T., et al., 2010. Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In J.  Roóz &amp;amp; J.  Ivanyos, eds. &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;.  Budapest: HVG Press Kft., pp. 67-76.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Declerck, T., Krieger, H. - U., Thomas, S. M., Buitelaar, P., O'Riain, S., Wunner, T., Maguet, G., et al. (2010). Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In J.  Roóz &amp;amp; J.  Ivanyos (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 67-76). Budapest: HVG Press Kft.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Declerck, T., Krieger, H.-U., Thomas, S.M., Buitelaar, P., O'Riain, S., Wunner, T., Maguet, G., McCrae, J., Spohr, D. &amp;amp; Montiel-Ponsoda, E. (2010). Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In J. Roóz &amp;amp; J. Ivanyos (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt; (S. 67-76). Budapest: HVG Press Kft.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Declerck, T., Krieger, H. - U., Thomas, S. M., Buitelaar, P., O'Riain, S., Wunner, T., Maguet, G., McCrae, J., Spohr, D., and Montiel-Ponsoda, E. (2010). “Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe” in &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;, Roóz, J., and Ivanyos, J. eds. (Budapest: HVG Press Kft.), 67-76.</frontiers>
<ama>Declerck T, Krieger H-U, Thomas SM, et al. Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In: Roóz J, Ivanyos J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;. Budapest: HVG Press Kft.;  2010: 67-76.</ama>
<ieee> T. Declerck, et al., “Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe”, &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt;, J. Roóz and J. Ivanyos, eds.,  Budapest: HVG Press Kft., 2010,  pp.67-76.</ieee>
<apa>Declerck, T., Krieger, H. - U., Thomas, S. M., Buitelaar, P., O'Riain, S., Wunner, T., Maguet, G., et al. (2010). Ontology-based Multilingual Access to Financial Reports for Sharing Business Knowledge across Europe. In J.  Roóz &amp;amp; J.  Ivanyos (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Internal Financial Control Assessment Applying Multilingual Ontology Framework&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 67-76). Budapest: HVG Press Kft.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2278579</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-14T09:24:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-14T13:17:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>