<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2279386</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11839576</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tscherepanow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">128602</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yukie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nagai</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Timo</namePart><namePart type="family">Honkela</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wlodzislaw</namePart><namePart type="family">Duch</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mark</namePart><namePart type="family">Girolami</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Samuel</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaski</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2011 : 21st International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks, Proceedings, Part II</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Memory constitutes an essential cognitive capability of humans and animals. It allows them to act in very complex, non-stationary environments. In this paper, we propose a perceptual memory system, which is intended to be applied on a humanoid robot learning affordances. According to the properties of biological memory systems, it has been designed in such a way as to enable life-long learning without catastrophic forgetting. Based on clustering sensory information, a symbolic representation is derived automatically. In contrast to alternative approaches, our memory system does not rely on pre-trained models and works completely unsupervised.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kammer.marc2011aperceptual-ICANN.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2279386/2508172/kammer.marc2011aperceptual-ICANN.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Espoo, Finland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>life-long learning</topic><topic>affordances</topic><topic>cognitive robotics</topic><topic>artificial memory</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-21738-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22793861</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">349-356</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kammer M, Tscherepanow M, Schack T, Nagai Y. A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In: Honkela T, Duch W, Girolami M, Kaski S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792. Berlin: Springer;  2011: 349-356.</ama>
<ieee> M. Kammer, et al., “A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;, T. Honkela, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792,  Berlin: Springer, 2011,  pp.349-356.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kammer, M., et al., 2011. A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In T.  Honkela, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792.  Berlin: Springer, pp. 349-356.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kammer, Marc, Tscherepanow, Marko, Schack, Thomas, and Nagai, Yukie. 2011. “A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Timo Honkela, Wlodzislaw Duch, Mark Girolami, and Samuel Kaski, 349-356. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kammer, M., Tscherepanow, M., Schack, T., Nagai, Y.: A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In: Honkela, T., Duch, W., Girolami, M., and Kaski, S. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN). Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792. p. 349-356. Springer, Berlin (2011).</lncs>
<apa>Kammer, M., Tscherepanow, M., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Nagai, Y. (2011). A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In T.  Honkela, W.  Duch, M.  Girolami, &amp;amp; S.  Kaski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 349-356). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kammer, M., Tscherepanow, M., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Nagai, Y. (2011). A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In T.  Honkela, W.  Duch, M.  Girolami, &amp;amp; S.  Kaski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 349-356). Berlin: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kammer, M., Tscherepanow, M., Schack, T., and Nagai, Y. (2011). “A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;, Honkela, T., Duch, W., Girolami, M., and Kaski, S. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792 (Berlin: Springer), 349-356.</frontiers>
<mla>Kammer, Marc, Tscherepanow, Marko, Schack, Thomas, and Nagai, Yukie. “A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Timo Honkela, Wlodzislaw Duch, Mark Girolami, and Samuel Kaski. Berlin: Springer, 2011. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792. 349-356.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kammer, M., Tscherepanow, M., Schack, T. &amp;amp; Nagai, Y. (2011). A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792). In T. Honkela, W. Duch, M. Girolami &amp;amp; S. Kaski (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 349-356). Gehalten auf der Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2011 : 21st International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks, Proceedings, Part II, Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-21738-8_45.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Kammer, M.; Tscherepanow, M.; Schack, T.; Nagai, Y. (2011): A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. In: Timo Honkela; Wlodzislaw Duch; Mark Girolami; Samuel Kaski (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN). Berlin: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792, ).  S. 349-356.</wels>
<bio1>Kammer M, Tscherepanow M, Schack T, Nagai Y (2011) &lt;br /&gt;A Perceptual Memory System for Affordance Learning in Humanoid Robots. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN). Honkela T, Duch W, Girolami M, Kaski S (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792,  Berlin: Springer:  349-356.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Kammer, M.  Tscherepanow, T.  Schack, and Y.  Nagai, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Honkela, W. Duch, M. Girolami, S. Kaski), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 349-356.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Kammer M, Tscherepanow M, Schack T, Nagai Y (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN). Honkela T, Duch W, Girolami M, Kaski S (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 6792.  Berlin: Springer:  349-356.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2279386</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-14T13:23:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:33Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>