<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2280467</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Erik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weitnauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16558226</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33056</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5842-9991</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>SIMPAR 2010</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Physics engines have been used in robotics research for a long time. Beside their traditional application as a  substitute for real world interactions due to their higher speed, safety and flexibility, they have recently also been used for motion planning and high level action planning. We propose to further explore the idea of using a physics engine as means to give a robot a basic physical understanding of its environment. In this paper, as a preliminary step, we study, how accurately the process
of pushing flat objects across a table with a robot arm can be predicted in a physics engine. We also present an approach to adapt the engines parameters to enhance the simulation accuracy.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="simpar2010_weitnauer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2280467/2280468/simpar2010_weitnauer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Darmstadt, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>physical reasoning</topic><topic>physics engines</topic><topic>physical simulation</topic><topic>robotics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22804671</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">144-155</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Weitnauer E, Haschke R, Ritter H (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots.  Springer Verlag:  144-155.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2010). Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;, 144-155. Springer Verlag. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2010. Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;.  Springer Verlag, pp. 144-155.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Weitnauer, R.  Haschke, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;, Springer Verlag, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 144-155.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Weitnauer, E.; Haschke, R.; Ritter, H. (2010): Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. In: Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots. Springer Verlag.  S. 144-155.</wels>
<apa>Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2010). Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;, 144-155. Springer Verlag. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> E. Weitnauer, R. Haschke, and H. Ritter, “Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;, Springer Verlag, 2010,  pp.144-155.</ieee>
<ama>Weitnauer E, Haschke R, Ritter H. Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;. Springer Verlag;  2010: 144-155.</ama>
<frontiers>Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R., and Ritter, H. (2010). “Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt; (Springer Verlag), 144-155.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2010). Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt; (S. 144-155). Gehalten auf der SIMPAR 2010, Springer Verlag. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-17319-6_16.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Weitnauer, Erik, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. “Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;. Springer Verlag, 2010. 144-155.</mla>
<default>Weitnauer E, Haschke R, Ritter H (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots. Springer Verlag:  144-155.</default>
<lncs> Weitnauer, E., Haschke, R., Ritter, H.: Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning. Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots. p. 144-155. Springer Verlag (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weitnauer, Erik, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. 2010. “Evaluating a physics engine as an ingredient for physical reasoning”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Second international conference on Simulation, modeling, and programming for autonomous robots&lt;/em&gt;, 144-155. Springer Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2280467</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-16T07:35:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>