<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2280918</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">René</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tünnermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Leichsenring</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>First International Workshop on Mobile Social Signal Processing (MSSP 2010)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Touch can convey emotions on a very direct level. We propose feelabuzz, a system implementing a remote touch connection using standard mobile phone hardware. Accelerometer data is mapped to vibration strength on
two smartphones connected via the Internet. This is done using direct mapping techniques, without any abstraction of the acceleration signal. By this, feelabuzz can be used for implicit context communication, i.e. the background monitoring of the natural movements of the users  themselves or their environments, as well as for direct communication, i.e. voluntary and symbolic signalling through this new channel. We describe the system and its implementation, discuss its possible implications and verify the system's ability to recognizably transmit different actions in a preliminary user study.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="TuennermannLeichsenringHermann2010.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2280918/2280965/TuennermannLeichsenringHermann2010.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Lisbon, Portugal</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>mediated communication</topic><topic>tactile feedback</topic><topic>haptic display</topic><topic>mobile devices</topic><topic>wearable computing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-54324-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22809181</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8045</number></detail><extent unit="pages">74-83</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.feelabuzz.org/</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> R. Tünnermann, C. Leichsenring, and T. Hermann, “Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System”, &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8045,  Heidelberg: Springer, 2014,  pp.74-83.</ieee>
<apa>Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, &lt;em&gt;8045&lt;/em&gt;, 74-83. Heidelberg: Springer.</apa>
<frontiers>Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C., and Hermann, T. (2014). “Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System” in &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt; Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8045, (Heidelberg: Springer), 74-83.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 74-83). Gehalten auf der First International Workshop on Mobile Social Signal Processing (MSSP 2010), Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Tünnermann R, Leichsenring C, Hermann T. Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. In:  &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8045. Heidelberg: Springer;  2014: 74-83.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Tünnermann, C.  Leichsenring, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Springer, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 74-83.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2014. Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. In &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8045  Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 74-83.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, &lt;em&gt;8045&lt;/em&gt;, 74-83. Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Tünnermann R, Leichsenring C, Hermann T (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers.  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8045. Heidelberg: Springer:  74-83.</bio1>
<wels>Tünnermann, R.; Leichsenring, C.; Hermann, T. (2014): Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. In: Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers. Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8045).  S. 74-83.</wels>
<default>Tünnermann R, Leichsenring C, Hermann T (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8045.  Heidelberg: Springer:  74-83.</default>
<mla>Tünnermann, René, Leichsenring, Christian, and Hermann, Thomas. “Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System”. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Heidelberg: Springer, 2014.Vol. 8045. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 74-83.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tünnermann, René, Leichsenring, Christian, and Hermann, Thomas. 2014. “Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System”. In &lt;em&gt;Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 8045:74-83. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Tünnermann, R., Leichsenring, C., Hermann, T.: Direct Tactile Coupling of Mobile Phones with the feelabuzz System. Mobile Social Signal Processing. First International Workshop, MSSP 2010, Lisbon, Portugal, September 7, 2010, Invited Papers. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8045, p. 74-83. Springer, Heidelberg (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2280918</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-16T13:06:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>