<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2284314</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schilling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">172354</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0849-483X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="FINAL_PID1834471.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2284314/2908886/FINAL_PID1834471.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22843147</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Schilling, M. (2011). “Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schilling, M. (2011). Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schilling M. Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.</ama>
<ieee> M. Schilling, “Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;, 2011.</ieee>
<apa>Schilling, M. (2011). Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<wels>Schilling, M. (2011): Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. In: Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA).</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Schilling, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schilling, M. (2011). Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Schilling M (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA). .</bio1>
<harvard1>Schilling, M., 2011. Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schilling, Malte. 2011. “Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schilling, M.: Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control. Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA).  (2011).</lncs>
<default>Schilling M (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA).</default>
<mla>Schilling, Malte. “Integrating multi-sensory input in the body model – a RNN approach to connect proprioception, visual features and motor control”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks 2011, San Jose (CA)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2284314</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-24T18:00:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>