<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2284899</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kreysa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16869621</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10822979</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Pia</namePart><namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michele</namePart><namePart type="family">Burigo</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Maria Nella</namePart><namePart type="family">Carminati</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Helene</namePart><namePart type="family">Kreysa</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing (ESLP) 2011</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ESLP2011_hkpk_final.doc">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2284899/2341106/ESLP2011_hkpk_final.doc</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-ole-storage</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>syntax</topic><topic>eye tracking</topic><topic>language comprehension</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22848993</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Kreysa, H., Knoeferle, P.: Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In: Knoeferle, P., Burigo, M., Carminati, M.N., and Kreysa, H. (eds.) Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011. p. 32. ZiF, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, Helene, and Knoeferle, Pia. 2011. “Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Pia Knoeferle, Michele Burigo, Maria Nella Carminati, and Helene Kreysa, 32. ZiF, Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In P.  Knoeferle, M.  Burigo, M. N.  Carminati, &amp;amp; H.  Kreysa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt; (p. 32). ZiF, Bielefeld.</apa>
<ama>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P. Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In: Knoeferle P, Burigo M, Carminati MN, Kreysa H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;. ZiF, Bielefeld;  2011: 32.</ama>
<harvard1>Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P., 2011. Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In P.  Knoeferle, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;.  ZiF, Bielefeld, pp. 32.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Kreysa and P. Knoeferle, “Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;, P. Knoeferle, et al., eds.,  ZiF, Bielefeld: 2011,  pp.32.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Kreysa, and P.  Knoeferle, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Knoeferle, M. Burigo, M.N. Carminati, H. Kreysa), ZiF, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 32.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011. Knoeferle P, Burigo M, Carminati MN, Kreysa H (Eds); ZiF, Bielefeld:  32.</bio1>
<default>Kreysa H, Knoeferle P (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011. Knoeferle P, Burigo M, Carminati MN, Kreysa H (Eds);  ZiF, Bielefeld:  32.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, H. &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In P. Knoeferle, M. Burigo, M.N. Carminati &amp;amp; H. Kreysa (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt; (S. 32). Gehalten auf der Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing (ESLP) 2011, ZiF, Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Kreysa, Helene, and Knoeferle, Pia. “Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Pia Knoeferle, Michele Burigo, Maria Nella Carminati, and Helene Kreysa. ZiF, Bielefeld, 2011. 32.</mla>
<frontiers>Kreysa, H., and Knoeferle, P. (2011). “Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt;, Knoeferle, P., Burigo, M., Carminati, M. N., and Kreysa, H. eds. (ZiF, Bielefeld), 32.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kreysa, H., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2011). Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In P.  Knoeferle, M.  Burigo, M. N.  Carminati, &amp;amp; H.  Kreysa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011&lt;/em&gt; (p. 32). ZiF, Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kreysa, H.; Knoeferle, P. (2011): Differences in comprehension task affect the processing of a speaker’s gaze direction. In: Pia Knoeferle; Michele Burigo; Maria Nella Carminati; Helene Kreysa (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ZiF-Workshop on Embodied and Situated Language Processing 2011. ZiF, Bielefeld.  S. 32.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2284899</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-29T12:07:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>