<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2286532</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Axel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Löffler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klahold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hußmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dario</namePart><namePart type="family">Floreano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Daniel</namePart><namePart type="family">Nicoud</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Francesco</namePart><namePart type="family">Mondada</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The design of behavior generating control structures for real robots acting autonomously in a real and changing environment is a complex task. This is in particular true with respect to the debugging process, the documentation of the encountered behavior, its quantitative analysis and the final evaluation. To successfully implement such a behavior, it is vital to couple the synthesis on a simulator and the experiment on a real robot with a thorough analysis. The available simulator tools in general only allow behavioral snapshots and do not provide the option of online interference. In order to cure these shortcomings, a visualization tool for aposteriori graphical analysis of recorded data sets which gives access to all relevant internal states and parameters of the system is presented. The mini-robot Khepera has been chosen as experimentatory platform.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A_Visualization_Tool_for_the_Mini-Robot_Khepera-_Behavior_Analysis_and_Optimization.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2286532/2407068/A_Visualization_Tool_for_the_Mini-Robot_Khepera-_Behavior_Analysis_and_Optimization.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22865325</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1674</number></detail><extent unit="pages">329-333</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Löffler A, Klahold J, Hußmann M, Rückert U. A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In: Floreano D, Nicoud J-D, Mondada F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 1674. Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag;  1999: 329-333.</ama>
<harvard1>Löffler, A., et al., 1999. A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In D.  Floreano, J. - D.  Nicoud, &amp;amp; F.  Mondada, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;. no.1674  Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag, pp. 329-333.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Löffler, et al., “A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;, D. Floreano, J.-D. Nicoud, and F. Mondada, eds., vol. 1674,  Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag, 1999,  pp.329-333.</ieee>
<lncs> Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Hußmann, M., Rückert, U.: A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In: Floreano, D., Nicoud, J.-D., and Mondada, F. (eds.) Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99). 1674, p. 329-333. Springer-Verlag, Lausanne, Switzerland (1999).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, Hußmann, Manfred, and Rückert, Ulrich. 1999. “A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dario Floreano, Jean-Daniel Nicoud, and Francesco Mondada, 1674:329-333. Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Hußmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1999). A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In D.  Floreano, J. - D.  Nicoud, &amp;amp; F.  Mondada (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 1674, pp. 329-333). Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Hußmann, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1999). A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In D. Floreano, J.-D. Nicoud &amp;amp; F. Mondada (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 329-333). Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Hußmann, M., and Rückert, U. (1999). “A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;, Floreano, D., Nicoud, J. - D., and Mondada, F. eds., vol. 1674, (Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag), 329-333.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Hußmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1999). A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In D.  Floreano, J. - D.  Nicoud, &amp;amp; F.  Mondada (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 1674, pp. 329-333). Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, Hußmann, Manfred, and Rückert, Ulrich. “A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dario Floreano, Jean-Daniel Nicoud, and Francesco Mondada. Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag, 1999.Vol. 1674. 329-333.</mla>
<wels>Löffler, A.; Klahold, J.; Hußmann, M.; Rückert, U. (1999): A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. In: Dario Floreano; Jean-Daniel Nicoud; Francesco Mondada (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99). Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag. (1674).  S. 329-333.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Löffler, J.  Klahold, M.  Hußmann, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Floreano, J.-D. Nicoud, F. Mondada), Springer-Verlag, Lausanne, Switzerland, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 329-333.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Löffler A, Klahold J, Hußmann M, Rückert U (1999) &lt;br /&gt;A Visualization Tool for the Mini-Robot Khepera: Behaviour Analysis and Optimization. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99). Floreano D, Nicoud J-D, Mondada F (Eds);1674. Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag:  329-333.</bio1>
<default>Löffler A, Klahold J, Hußmann M, Rückert U (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International European Conference on Artificial Life (ECAL99). Floreano D, Nicoud J-D, Mondada F (Eds); , 1674.  Lausanne, Switzerland: Springer-Verlag:  329-333.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2286532</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-30T13:20:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>