<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2286486</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Axel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Löffler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klahold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jin-Kao</namePart><namePart type="family">Hao</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Evelyne</namePart><namePart type="family">Lutton</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Edmund</namePart><namePart type="family">Ronald</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marc</namePart><namePart type="family">Schoenauer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dominique</namePart><namePart type="family">Snyers</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we present the implementation, both in a simulator
and in a real-robot version, of an efficient solution to the so-called
dynamical nightwatch’s problem on the micro-robot Khepera. The problem
consists mainly in exploring a previously unknown environment while
detecting, registering and recognizing light sources which may dynamically
be turned on and off. At the end of each round a report is requested
from the robot. Therein we made use of an agent-based approach and
applied a self-organizing feature map in order to refine some of the behaviour
generating control-modules.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="The_Dynamical_Nightwatch_s_Problem_Solved_by_the_Autonomous_Micro-Robot_Khepera.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2286486/2407262/The_Dynamical_Nightwatch_s_Problem_Solved_by_the_Autonomous_Micro-Robot_Khepera.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22864860</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1363</number></detail><extent unit="pages">303-313</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Löffler, J.  Klahold, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.-K. Hao, E. Lutton, E. Ronald, M. Schoenauer, D. Snyers), Springer-Verlag, Nimes, France, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 303-313.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U., 1998. The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In J. - K.  Hao, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;. no.1363  Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag, pp. 303-313.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1998). The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In J. - K.  Hao, E.  Lutton, E.  Ronald, M.  Schoenauer, &amp;amp; D.  Snyers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 1363, pp. 303-313). Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U (1998) &lt;br /&gt;The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97). Hao J-K, Lutton E, Ronald E, Schoenauer M, Snyers D (Eds);1363. Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag:  303-313.</bio1>
<wels>Löffler, A.; Klahold, J.; Rückert, U. (1998): The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In: Jin-Kao Hao; Evelyne Lutton; Edmund Ronald; Marc Schoenauer; Dominique Snyers (Hrsg.):  Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97). Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag. (1363).  S. 303-313.</wels>
<ieee> A. Löffler, J. Klahold, and U. Rückert, “The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera”, &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;, J.-K. Hao, et al., eds., vol. 1363,  Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag, 1998,  pp.303-313.</ieee>
<apa>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1998). The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In J. - K.  Hao, E.  Lutton, E.  Ronald, M.  Schoenauer, &amp;amp; D.  Snyers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 1363, pp. 303-313). Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (1998). The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In J.-K. Hao, E. Lutton, E. Ronald, M. Schoenauer &amp;amp; D. Snyers (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 303-313). Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., and Rückert, U. (1998). “The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera” in &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;, Hao, J. - K., Lutton, E., Ronald, E., Schoenauer, M., and Snyers, D. eds., vol. 1363, (Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag), 303-313.</frontiers>
<ama>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U. The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In: Hao J-K, Lutton E, Ronald E, Schoenauer M, Snyers D, eds. &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 1363. Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag;  1998: 303-313.</ama>
<default>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97). Hao J-K, Lutton E, Ronald E, Schoenauer M, Snyers D (Eds); , 1363.  Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag:  303-313.</default>
<mla>Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, and Rückert, Ulrich. “The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera”. &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jin-Kao Hao, Evelyne Lutton, Edmund Ronald, Marc Schoenauer, and Dominique Snyers. Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag, 1998.Vol. 1363. 303-313.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, and Rückert, Ulrich. 1998. “The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera”. In &lt;em&gt;Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jin-Kao Hao, Evelyne Lutton, Edmund Ronald, Marc Schoenauer, and Dominique Snyers, 1363:303-313. Nimes, France: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Rückert, U.: The Dynamical Nightwatch's Problem Solved by the Autonomous Micro-Robot Khepera. In: Hao, J.-K., Lutton, E., Ronald, E., Schoenauer, M., and Snyers, D. (eds.) Selected Papers of the 3rd European Conference on Artificial Evolution (AE97). 1363, p. 303-313. Springer-Verlag, Nimes, France (1998).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2286486</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-30T13:14:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:57:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>