<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288504</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klahold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rautenberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart><namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Joaquin</namePart><namePart type="family">Sitte</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart><namePart type="family">Witkowski</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ultrasonic_Sensor_for_Mobile_Mini-Robots_Using_Pseudo-Random_Codes.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288504/2407281/Ultrasonic_Sensor_for_Mobile_Mini-Robots_Using_Pseudo-Random_Codes.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22885047</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>97</number></detail><extent unit="pages">225-232</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Klahold J, Rautenberg J, Rückert U (2001)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U (Eds); , 97.  Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn:  225-232.</default>
<wels>Klahold, J.; Rautenberg, J.; Rückert, U. (2001): Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In: Ulrich Rückert; Joaquin Sitte; Ulf Witkowski (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn. (97).  S. 225-232.</wels>
<frontiers>Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J., and Rückert, U. (2001). “Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, Rückert, U., Sitte, J., and Witkowski, U. eds., vol. 97, (Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn), 225-232.</frontiers>
<mla>Klahold, Jürgen, Rautenberg, Jens, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ulrich Rückert, Joaquin Sitte, and Ulf Witkowski. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, 2001.Vol. 97. 225-232.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 97, pp. 225-232). Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 97, pp. 225-232). Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.</apa>
<harvard1>Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U., 2001. Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. no.97  Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, pp. 225-232.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Klahold, J. Rautenberg, and U. Rückert, “Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, U. Rückert, J. Sitte, and U. Witkowski, eds., vol. 97, Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, 2001,  pp.225-232.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Klahold, J.  Rautenberg, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U. Rückert, J. Sitte, U. Witkowski), Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 225-232.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Klahold J, Rautenberg J, Rückert U (2001) &lt;br /&gt;Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U (Eds);97. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn:  225-232.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In U. Rückert, J. Sitte &amp;amp; U. Witkowski (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 225-232). Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klahold, Jürgen, Rautenberg, Jens, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2001. “Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ulrich Rückert, Joaquin Sitte, and Ulf Witkowski, 97:225-232. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Klahold, J., Rautenberg, J., Rückert, U.: Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In: Rückert, U., Sitte, J., and Witkowski, U. (eds.) Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). 97, p. 225-232. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn (2001).</lncs>
<ama>Klahold J, Rautenberg J, Rückert U. Ultrasonic Sensor for Mobile Mini-Robots Using Pseudo-Random Codes. In: Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 97. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn;  2001: 225-232.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288504</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T07:49:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>