<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288681</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ognyan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Manolov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Burkhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Iske</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sv.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Noykov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klahold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Georgiev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Witkowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Gard_-_An_Intelligent_System_for_Distributed_Exploration_of_Landmine_Fields_Simulated_by_a_Team_of_Khepera_Robots.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288681/2407159/Gard_-_An_Intelligent_System_for_Distributed_Exploration_of_Landmine_Fields_Simulated_by_a_Team_of_Khepera_Robots.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22886811</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">199-202</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Manolov, O.; Iske, B.; Noykov, S.; Klahold, J.; Georgiev, G.; Witkowski, U.; Rückert, U. (2003): Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. In: Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03. Sofia, Bulgaria. (1).  S. 199-202.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Manolov, B.  Iske, S.  Noykov, J.  Klahold, G.  Georgiev, U.  Witkowski, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, Sofia, Bulgaria, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 199-202.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Manolov O, Iske B, Noykov S, Klahold J, Georgiev G, Witkowski U, Rückert U (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03. 1. Sofia, Bulgaria:  199-202.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Manolov, O., Iske, B., Noykov, S., Klahold, J., Georgiev, G., Witkowski, U., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, 199-202. Sofia, Bulgaria.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Manolov, O., et al., 2003. Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;. no.1  Sofia, Bulgaria, pp. 199-202.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Manolov, O., Iske, B., Noykov, S., Klahold, J., Georgiev, G., Witkowski, U. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt; (S. 199-202). Sofia, Bulgaria.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Manolov, O., Iske, B., Noykov, S., Klahold, J., Georgiev, G., Witkowski, U., and Rückert, U. (2003). “Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 1, (Sofia, Bulgaria), 199-202.</frontiers>
<ama>Manolov O, Iske B, Noykov S, et al. Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 1. Sofia, Bulgaria;  2003: 199-202.</ama>
<ieee> O. Manolov, et al., “Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 1,  Sofia, Bulgaria: 2003,  pp.199-202.</ieee>
<apa>Manolov, O., Iske, B., Noykov, S., Klahold, J., Georgiev, G., Witkowski, U., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, 199-202. Sofia, Bulgaria.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Manolov, Ognyan, Iske, Burkhard, Noykov, Sv., Klahold, Jürgen, Georgiev, G., Witkowski, Ulf, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2003. “Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;, 1:199-202. Sofia, Bulgaria.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Manolov, O., Iske, B., Noykov, S., Klahold, J., Georgiev, G., Witkowski, U., Rückert, U.: Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots. Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03. 1, p. 199-202. Sofia, Bulgaria (2003).</lncs>
<default>Manolov O, Iske B, Noykov S, Klahold J, Georgiev G, Witkowski U, Rückert U (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03., 1.  Sofia, Bulgaria:  199-202.</default>
<mla>Manolov, Ognyan, Iske, Burkhard, Noykov, Sv., Klahold, Jürgen, Georgiev, G., Witkowski, Ulf, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Gard – An Intelligent System for Distributed Exploration of Landmine Fields Simulated by a Team of Khepera Robots”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference Automatics and Informatics’03&lt;/em&gt;. Sofia, Bulgaria, 2003.Vol. 1. 199-202.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288681</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T08:26:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>