<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288649</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">André</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brinkmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friedhelm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer auf der Heide</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kay</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Salzwedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Scheideler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vodisek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The advances in Internet technology have led to
tremendous improvements in business, education, and science and
have changed the way we think, live, and communicate.
Information exchange has become ubiquitous by the possibilities
offered through modern technologies. We are able to offer
information 24 hours a day through our web sites and can leave
messages every time and from anywhere in the world.
This change in communication has led to new challenges.
Enterprises have to deal with an information amount that doubles
every year. The technological foundation to cope with this
information explosion is given by Storage Area Networks (SANs),
which are able to connect a great number of storage systems over
a fast interconnection network. However, to be able to use the
benefits of a SAN, an easy-to-use and efficient management
support has to be given to the storage administrator. In this
paper, we will suggest new storage management concepts and we
will introduce a new management environment that is able to
significantly reduce management costs and increases the
performance and resource utilization of the given SAN
infrastructure.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Storage_Management_as_Means_to_Cope_with_Exponential_Information_Growth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288649/2407246/Storage_Management_as_Means_to_Cope_with_Exponential_Information_Growth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of SSGRR 2003</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22886495</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Brinkmann A, Meyer auf der Heide F, Salzwedel K, Scheideler C, Vodisek M, Rückert U. Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;. L'Aquila, Italy;  2003.</ama>
<lncs> Brinkmann, A., Meyer auf der Heide, F., Salzwedel, K., Scheideler, C., Vodisek, M., Rückert, U.: Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. Proceedings of SSGRR 2003.  L'Aquila, Italy (2003).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brinkmann, André, Meyer auf der Heide, Friedhelm, Salzwedel, Kay, Scheideler, Christian, Vodisek, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2003. “Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;. L'Aquila, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brinkmann, A., Meyer auf der Heide, F., Salzwedel, K., Scheideler, C., Vodisek, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;. L'Aquila, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Brinkmann, F.  Meyer auf der Heide, K.  Salzwedel, C.  Scheideler, M.  Vodisek, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;, L'Aquila, Italy, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Brinkmann A, Meyer auf der Heide F, Salzwedel K, Scheideler C, Vodisek M, Rückert U (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of SSGRR 2003.  L'Aquila, Italy.</bio1>
<harvard1>Brinkmann, A., et al., 2003. Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;.  L'Aquila, Italy.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Brinkmann, et al., “Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;,  L'Aquila, Italy: 2003.</ieee>
<apa>Brinkmann, A., Meyer auf der Heide, F., Salzwedel, K., Scheideler, C., Vodisek, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt; L'Aquila, Italy.</apa>
<frontiers>Brinkmann, A., Meyer auf der Heide, F., Salzwedel, K., Scheideler, C., Vodisek, M., and Rückert, U. (2003). “Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt; (L'Aquila, Italy).</frontiers>
<mla>Brinkmann, André, Meyer auf der Heide, Friedhelm, Salzwedel, Kay, Scheideler, Christian, Vodisek, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt;. L'Aquila, Italy, 2003.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brinkmann, A., Meyer auf der Heide, F., Salzwedel, K., Scheideler, C., Vodisek, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2003). Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of SSGRR 2003&lt;/em&gt; L'Aquila, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Brinkmann, A.; Meyer auf der Heide, F.; Salzwedel, K.; Scheideler, C.; Vodisek, M.; Rückert, U. (2003): Storage Management as Means to cope with Exponential Information Growth. In: Proceedings of SSGRR 2003. L'Aquila, Italy.</wels>
<default>Brinkmann A, Meyer auf der Heide F, Salzwedel K, Scheideler C, Vodisek M, Rückert U (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of SSGRR 2003. L'Aquila, Italy.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288649</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T08:22:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>