<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288475</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Axel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Löffler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klahold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart><namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Joaquin</namePart><namePart type="family">Sitte</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart><namePart type="family">Witkowski</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The work presented in this paper deals with the development of a methodology
for resource-efficient behaviour synthesis on autonomous systems. In this context, a definition
of a maximal problem with respect to the resources of a given system is introduced. It
is elucidated by means of an exemplary implementation of the solution to such a problem
using the mini-robot Khepera as the experimental platform. The described task consists of
exploring an unknown and dynamically changing environment, collecting and transporting
objects, which are associated with light-sources, and navigating to a home-base. The critical
point is represented by the accumulated positioning errors in odometrical path-integration
due to slippage. Therefore, adaptive sensor calibration using a specific variant of Kohonen’s
algorithm is applied in two cases to extract symbolic, e.g. geometric, information from the
sub-symbolic sensor data, which is used to enhance position control by landmark mapping
and orientation. In order to successfully handle the arising complex interactions, a heterogeneous
control-architecture based on a parallel implementation of basic behaviours coupled
by a rule-based central unit is proposed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="The_Mini-Robot_Khepera_as_a_Foraging_Animate-_Synthesis_and_Analysis_of_Behaviour.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288475/2407271/The_Mini-Robot_Khepera_as_a_Foraging_Animate-_Synthesis_and_Analysis_of_Behaviour.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22884758</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>97</number></detail><extent unit="pages">93-130</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Löffler, J.  Klahold, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U. Rückert, J. Sitte, U. Witkowski), Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, Paderborn, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 93-130.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U (2001) &lt;br /&gt;The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U (Eds);97. Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn:  93-130.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In U. Rückert, J. Sitte &amp;amp; U. Witkowski (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 93-130). Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Löffler, A., Klahold, J., Rückert, U.: The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In: Rückert, U., Sitte, J., and Witkowski, U. (eds.) Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). 97, p. 93-130. Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, Paderborn, Germany (2001).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2001. “The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ulrich Rückert, Joaquin Sitte, and Ulf Witkowski, 97:93-130. Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U. The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In: Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 97. Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn;  2001: 93-130.</ama>
<default>Löffler A, Klahold J, Rückert U (2001)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Rückert U, Sitte J, Witkowski U (Eds); , 97.  Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn:  93-130.</default>
<wels>Löffler, A.; Klahold, J.; Rückert, U. (2001): The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In: Ulrich Rückert; Joaquin Sitte; Ulf Witkowski (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01). Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn. (97).  S. 93-130.</wels>
<frontiers>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., and Rückert, U. (2001). “The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, Rückert, U., Sitte, J., and Witkowski, U. eds., vol. 97, (Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn), 93-130.</frontiers>
<mla>Löffler, Axel, Klahold, Jürgen, and Rückert, Ulrich. “The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ulrich Rückert, Joaquin Sitte, and Ulf Witkowski. Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, 2001.Vol. 97. 93-130.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 97, pp. 93-130). Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2001). The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 97, pp. 93-130). Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn.</apa>
<harvard1>Löffler, A., Klahold, J., &amp;amp; Rückert, U., 2001. The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour. In U.  Rückert, J.  Sitte, &amp;amp; U.  Witkowski, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;. no.97  Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, pp. 93-130.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Löffler, J. Klahold, and U. Rückert, “The Mini-Robot Khepera as a Foraging Animate: Synthesis and Analysis of Behaviour”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Heinz Nixdorf Symposium: Autonomous Minirobots for Research and Edutainment (AMiRE01)&lt;/em&gt;, U. Rückert, J. Sitte, and U. Witkowski, eds., vol. 97,  Paderborn, Germany: Heinz Nixdorf Institut, Universität Paderborn, 2001,  pp.93-130.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288475</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T07:46:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>