<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288853</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg-Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We present an architecture for network processing nodes
based on a massively parallel processor structure. Due to its
regularity, our architecture can be easily scaled to accommodate
a range of packet processing applications with disparate
performance and throughput requirements at high reliability.
Furthermore, the composition from predefined building blocks
guarantees fast design cycles and eases system verification. For
particular resource efficiency in terms of power consumption,
computational performance, and area requirements, specialized
hardware accelerators can be embedded into the tailored processor
cluster, which have been optimized for a particular target
application. We demonstrate our approach using a real-world
network access scenario that implements a full Internet protocol
based digital subscriber line access multiplexer (IP-DSLAM) on
our architecture. For this scenario, we achieve substantial increases
of performance with only a slight area increase of less
than 0.3 %. At the same time, the processors are strongly relieved
and are thus available for the remaining tasks.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="An_Evaluation_of_the_Scalable_GigaNetIC_Architecture_for_Access_Networks.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288853/2407100/An_Evaluation_of_the_Scalable_GigaNetIC_Architecture_for_Access_Networks.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22888531</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<lncs> Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Sauer, C., Rückert, U.: An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005).  (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, Sauer, Christian, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2005. “An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks”. In &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> J.-C. Niemann, et al., “An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks”, &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;, 2005.</ieee>
<harvard1>Niemann, J.-C., et al., 2005. An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. In &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ama>Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Sauer C, Rückert U. An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. In:  &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;. 2005.</ama>
<default>Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Sauer C, Rückert U (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005).</default>
<bio1>Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Sauer C, Rückert U (2005) &lt;br /&gt;An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005). .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J. - C.  Niemann, M.  Porrmann, C.  Sauer, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Niemann, J. - C.; Porrmann, M.; Sauer, C.; Rückert, U. (2005): An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. In: Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005).</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Sauer, C., and Rückert, U. (2005). “An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks” in &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<mla>Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, Sauer, Christian, and Rückert, Ulrich. “An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks”. &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;. 2005.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Sauer, C. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). An Evaluation of the Scalable GigaNetIC Architecture for Access Networks. &lt;em&gt;Advanced Networking and Communications Hardware Workshop (ANCHOR), held in conjunction with the 32nd Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA 2005)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288853</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T09:10:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>