<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288969</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gries</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dirk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg-Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="A_Lightweight_NoC_for_the_NOVA_Packet_Processing_Platform.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288969/2407055/A_Lightweight_NoC_for_the_NOVA_Packet_Processing_Platform.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22889690</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Sauer C, Gries M, Dirk S, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U. A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. In:  &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Munich, Germany;  2006.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, Christian, Gries, Matthias, Dirk, Sebastian, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2006. “A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform”. In &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Munich, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Sauer, C., Gries, M., Dirk, S., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Rückert, U.: A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop.  Munich, Germany (2006).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, C., Gries, M., Dirk, S., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2006). A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Munich, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Sauer C, Gries M, Dirk S, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2006) &lt;br /&gt;A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop.  Munich, Germany.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Sauer, M.  Gries, S.  Dirk, J. - C.  Niemann, M.  Porrmann, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Munich, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> C. Sauer, et al., “A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform”, &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;,  Munich, Germany: 2006.</ieee>
<harvard1>Sauer, C., et al., 2006. A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. In &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;.  Munich, Germany.</harvard1>
<apa>Sauer, C., Gries, M., Dirk, S., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2006). A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt; Munich, Germany.</apa>
<wels>Sauer, C.; Gries, M.; Dirk, S.; Niemann, J. - C.; Porrmann, M.; Rückert, U. (2006): A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. In: Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop. Munich, Germany.</wels>
<frontiers>Sauer, C., Gries, M., Dirk, S., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., and Rückert, U. (2006). “A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform” in &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (Munich, Germany).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, C., Gries, M., Dirk, S., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2006). A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform. &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt; Munich, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Sauer, Christian, Gries, Matthias, Dirk, Sebastian, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. “A Lightweight NoC for the NOVA Packet Processing Plattform”. &lt;em&gt;Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Munich, Germany, 2006.</mla>
<default>Sauer C, Gries M, Dirk S, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Design, Automation and Test in Europe DATE, Future Interconnect and Network-on-Chip (NoC) Workshop. Munich, Germany.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288969</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T09:33:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>