<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288565</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dominik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Langen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg-Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, an implementation of a RISC processor core for SoC designs is presented. We analyze
the differences between a prototypical FPGA implementation and standard cell realizations
in an 0.6μm and an 0.13μm technology, respectively. The core was developed by using
the hardware description language VHDL, which offers the opportunity of adding special, optimized
hardware blocks for various operations. The effects on area and power consumption as
well as computational power are analyzed. A detailed overview of the implementation of additional
hardware multipliers and their effects on the above mentioned topics concludes this paper.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Implementation_of_a_RISC_Processor_Core_for_SoC_Designs_-_FPGA_Prototype_vs._ASIC_Implementation.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288565/2407179/Implementation_of_a_RISC_Processor_Core_for_SoC_Designs_-_FPGA_Prototype_vs._ASIC_Implementation.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22885658</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Langen, D., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Kalte, H., and Rückert, U. (2002). “Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt; (Hamburg, Germany).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Langen, D., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Kalte, H., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2002). Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt; Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Langen, Dominik, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, Kalte, Heiko, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg, Germany, 2002.</mla>
<wels>Langen, D.; Niemann, J. - C.; Porrmann, M.; Kalte, H.; Rückert, U. (2002): Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. In: Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC). Hamburg, Germany.</wels>
<default>Langen D, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Kalte H, Rückert U (2002)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC). Hamburg, Germany.</default>
<harvard1>Langen, D., et al., 2002. Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;.  Hamburg, Germany.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Langen, et al., “Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;,  Hamburg, Germany: 2002.</ieee>
<apa>Langen, D., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., Kalte, H., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2002). Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt; Hamburg, Germany.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Langen, D., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Kalte, H. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2002). Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Langen, J. - C.  Niemann, M.  Porrmann, H.  Kalte, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;, Hamburg, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Langen D, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Kalte H, Rückert U (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC).  Hamburg, Germany.</bio1>
<ama>Langen D, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Kalte H, Rückert U. Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg, Germany;  2002.</ama>
<lncs> Langen, D., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Kalte, H., Rückert, U.: Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation. Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC).  Hamburg, Germany (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Langen, Dominik, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, Kalte, Heiko, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2002. “Implementation of a RISC Processor Core for SoC Designs – FPGA Prototype vs. ASIC Implementation”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE-Workshop: Heterogeneous reconfigurable Systems on Chip (SoC)&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288565</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T08:03:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>