<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288932</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Franzmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Witkowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Cabestany</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Prieto</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">D.F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Sandoval</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In the field of explorative data analysis self-organizing maps have been used successfully for a lot of applications. In our case, we apply the self-organizing map for the analysis of semiconductor fabrication data by training recorded high dimensional data sets. Usually, the training result is displayed by using appropriate visualization techniques and the results are evaluated manually. Especially for large data sets an automated post-processing of the training result is essential. In this paper an automatic training result analysis based on specific image processing is introduced. Dependencies between components maps are calculated by structure overlapping analysis based on the segmentation of component maps. This novel method has been integrated into the data analysis software DanI, that simulates self-organizing maps for data analysis with several pre-processing and post-processing capabilities.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Explorative_Data_Analysis_Based_on_Self-Organizing_Maps_and_Automatic_Map_Analysis.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288932/2407138/Explorative_Data_Analysis_Based_on_Self-Organizing_Maps_and_Automatic_Map_Analysis.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22889320</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>3512</number></detail><extent unit="pages">725-733</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U., Witkowski, U.: Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In: Cabestany, J., Prieto, A., and Sandoval, D.F. (eds.) Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN). p. 725-733. (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Franzmeier, Marc, Rückert, Ulrich, and Witkowski, Ulf. 2005. “Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. Cabestany, A. Prieto, and D.F. Sandoval, 725-733.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Franzmeier, Marc, Rückert, Ulrich, and Witkowski, Ulf. “Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. J. Cabestany, A. Prieto, and D.F. Sandoval. 2005. 725-733.</mla>
<default>Franzmeier M, Rückert U, Witkowski U (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN). Cabestany J, Prieto A, Sandoval DF (Eds); (3512).   725-733.</default>
<ama>Franzmeier M, Rückert U, Witkowski U. Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In: Cabestany J, Prieto A, Sandoval DF, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;. 2005: 725-733.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U. &amp;amp; Witkowski, U. (2005). Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In J. Cabestany, A. Prieto &amp;amp; D.F. Sandoval (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 725-733).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U., and Witkowski, U. (2005). “Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;, Cabestany, J., Prieto, A., and Sandoval, D. F. eds. 725-733.</frontiers>
<apa>Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U., &amp;amp; Witkowski, U. (2005). Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In J.  Cabestany, A.  Prieto, &amp;amp; D. F.  Sandoval (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 725-733).</apa>
<ieee> M. Franzmeier, U. Rückert, and U. Witkowski, “Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;, J. Cabestany, A. Prieto, and D.F. Sandoval, eds., 2005,  pp.725-733.</ieee>
<wels>Franzmeier, M.; Rückert, U.; Witkowski, U. (2005): Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In: J. Cabestany; A. Prieto; D.F. Sandoval (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN).  S. 725-733.</wels>
<harvard1>Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U., &amp;amp; Witkowski, U., 2005. Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In J.  Cabestany, A.  Prieto, &amp;amp; D. F.  Sandoval, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 725-733.</harvard1>
<bio1>Franzmeier M, Rückert U, Witkowski U (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN). Cabestany J, Prieto A, Sandoval DF (Eds); 725-733.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Franzmeier, M., Rückert, U., &amp;amp; Witkowski, U. (2005). Explorative Data Analysis Based on Self-Organizing Maps and Automatic Map Analysis. In J.  Cabestany, A.  Prieto, &amp;amp; D. F.  Sandoval (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 725-733).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Franzmeier, U.  Rückert, and U.  Witkowski, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th International Work-Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (IWANN)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Cabestany, A. Prieto, D.F. Sandoval), &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 725-733.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288932</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T09:19:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>