<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2288882</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eickhoff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg-Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Achim</namePart><namePart type="family">Rettberg</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mauro C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Zanella</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Franz Josef</namePart><namePart type="family">Rammig</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Embedded Systems Symposium (IESS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Due to continuous advancements in modern technology processes which have
resulted in integrated circuits with smaller feature sizes and higher complexity, current system-on-chip designs consist of many different components such as memories, interfaces and microprocessors. To handle this growing number of components, an efficient communication structure must be provided and incorporated during system design. This work deals with the implementation of an efficient communication structure for an on-chip multiprocessor design. The internal structure of one node is proposed and specified by its requirements. Furthermore, different routing strategies are implemented. Moreover, the communication structure is mapped on a standard cell process to examine the achieved processing speed and to determine the area requirements.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ADAPTABLE_SWITCHBOXES_ASON-CHIP_ROUTING_NODES_FOR_NETWORKS-ON-CHIP.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2288882/2407088/ADAPTABLE_SWITCHBOXES_ASON-CHIP_ROUTING_NODES_FOR_NETWORKS-ON-CHIP.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Manaus, Brazil</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>From Specification to Embedded Systems Application </title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-387-27557-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22888822</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/11523277_20</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>184</number></detail><extent unit="pages">201-210</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> R. Eickhoff, et al., “Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip”, &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;, A. Rettberg, M.C. Zanella, and F.J. Rammig, eds., IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science, vol. 184,  Boston, MA: Springer, 2005,  pp.201-210.</ieee>
<harvard1>Eickhoff, R., et al., 2005. Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In A.  Rettberg, M. C.  Zanella, &amp;amp; F. J.  Rammig, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;. IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science. no.184  Boston, MA: Springer, pp. 201-210.</harvard1>
<apa>Eickhoff, R., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In A.  Rettberg, M. C.  Zanella, &amp;amp; F. J.  Rammig (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science: Vol. 184&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt; (pp. 201-210). Boston, MA: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/11523277_20" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/11523277_20&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Eickhoff, R.; Niemann, J. - C.; Porrmann, M.; Rückert, U. (2005): Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In: Achim Rettberg; Mauro C. Zanella; Franz Josef Rammig (Hrsg.):  From Specification to Embedded Systems Application . Boston, MA: Springer. (IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science, 184).  S. 201-210.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eickhoff, R., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In A.  Rettberg, M. C.  Zanella, &amp;amp; F. J.  Rammig (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science: Vol. 184&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt; (pp. 201-210). Boston, MA: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/11523277_20" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/11523277_20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Eickhoff, Ralf, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip”. &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Achim Rettberg, Mauro C. Zanella, and Franz Josef Rammig. Boston, MA: Springer, 2005.Vol. 184. IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science. 201-210.</mla>
<frontiers>Eickhoff, R., Niemann, J. - C., Porrmann, M., and Rückert, U. (2005). “Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip” in &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;, Rettberg, A., Zanella, M. C., and Rammig, F. J. eds. IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science, vol. 184, (Boston, MA: Springer), 201-210.</frontiers>
<default>Eickhoff R, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Specification to Embedded Systems Application . Rettberg A, Zanella MC, Rammig FJ (Eds);  IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science, 184.  Boston, MA: Springer:  201-210.</default>
<ama>Eickhoff R, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U. Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In: Rettberg A, Zanella MC, Rammig FJ, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;. IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science. Vol 184. Boston, MA: Springer;  2005: 201-210.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eickhoff, Ralf, Niemann, Jörg-Christian, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2005. “Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip”. In &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt;, ed. Achim Rettberg, Mauro C. Zanella, and Franz Josef Rammig, 184:201-210. IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science. Boston, MA: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Eickhoff, R., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M., Rückert, U.: Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. In: Rettberg, A., Zanella, M.C., and Rammig, F.J. (eds.) From Specification to Embedded Systems Application . IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science. 184, p. 201-210. Springer, Boston, MA (2005).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eickhoff, R., Niemann, J.-C., Porrmann, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2005). Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip (IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science). In A. Rettberg, M.C. Zanella &amp;amp; F.J. Rammig (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt; (S. 201-210). Gehalten auf der International Embedded Systems Symposium (IESS), Boston, MA: Springer. doi:10.1007/11523277_20.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Eickhoff R, Niemann J-C, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptable Switch boxes as on-chip routing nodes for networks-on-chip. &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Specification to Embedded Systems Application . Rettberg A, Zanella MC, Rammig FJ (Eds); IFIP On-Line Library in Computer Science, 184. Boston, MA: Springer:  201-210.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Eickhoff, J. - C.  Niemann, M.  Porrmann, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;From Specification to Embedded Systems Application &lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Rettberg, M.C. Zanella, F.J. Rammig), Springer, Boston, MA, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 201-210.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2288882</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T09:13:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-03T07:45:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>