<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2289121</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Teerapat</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chinapirom</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53251202</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Witkowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents a stereoscopic vision system for the
mini-robot Khepera. The vision system performs objects
detection by using the stereo disparity and stereo
correspondence. The stereoscopic vision system enhances
robot’s visual perception ability by grabbing stereo images
and analysis 3D objects, while the robot doesn’t need to
move. The simple principle of our stereo vision is the less
displacement of correspondence pixels shows that the
pixels object is far away. To realize the stereo vision and
its calculation algorithms, the mini robot needs a powerful
FPGA and micro-controller module as well as 2D color
cameras. An application of Khepera equipped with the
stereoscopic camera is robot soccer in the KheperaSot
league. In the match, the robot has to be able to detect its
environment, i.e. the ball, walls, goals and its opponent.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Steroscopic_Camera_for_Autonomous_Mini-Robots_Applied_in_KheperaSot_League.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2289121/2407243/Steroscopic_Camera_for_Autonomous_Mini-Robots_Applied_in_KheperaSot_League.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22891217</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Chinapirom T, Witkowski U, Rückert U. Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. In:  &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;. San Francisco, USA;  2007.</ama>
<harvard1>Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U., &amp;amp; Rückert, U., 2007. Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. In &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;.  San Francisco, USA.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Chinapirom, U. Witkowski, and U. Rückert, “Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League”, &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;,  San Francisco, USA: 2007.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chinapirom, Teerapat, Witkowski, Ulf, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2007. “Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League”. In &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;. San Francisco, USA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U., Rückert, U.: Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD.  San Francisco, USA (2007).</lncs>
<apa>Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt; San Francisco, USA.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;. San Francisco, USA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt; San Francisco, USA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Chinapirom, T., Witkowski, U., and Rückert, U. (2007). “Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League” in &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt; (San Francisco, USA).</frontiers>
<mla>Chinapirom, Teerapat, Witkowski, Ulf, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League”. &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;. San Francisco, USA, 2007.</mla>
<wels>Chinapirom, T.; Witkowski, U.; Rückert, U. (2007): Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. In: FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD. San Francisco, USA.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Chinapirom, U.  Witkowski, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD&lt;/em&gt;, San Francisco, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Chinapirom T, Witkowski U, Rückert U (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Stereoscopic Camera for Autonomous Mini-Robots Applied in KheperaSot League. &lt;br /&gt;In:  FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD.  San Francisco, USA.</bio1>
<default>Chinapirom T, Witkowski U, Rückert U (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  FIRA Robot World Congress 2007, on CD. San Francisco, USA.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2289121</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T10:02:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>