<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2289033</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hussmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thies</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kastens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Madhura</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Purnaprajna</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Multiprocessors enable parallel execution of a single large
application to achieve a performance improvement. An application
is split at instruction, data or task level (based on
the granularity), such that the overhead of partitioning is
minimal. Parallelization for multiprocessors is mostly restricted
to a fixed granularity. Reconfiguration enables architectural
variations to allow multiple granularities of operation
within a multiprocessor. This adaptability optimizes
resource utilization over a fixed organization.
Here, a unified hardware-software approach to design a
reconfigurable multiprocessor system called QuadroCore is
presented. In our holistic methodology, compiler-driven reconfiguration
selects from a fixed set of modes. Each mode
relies on matching program analysis to exploit the architecture
efficiently. For instance, a multiprocessor may adapt
to different parallelization paradigms. The compiler can
determine the best execution mode for each piece of code
by analyzing the parallelism in a program. A fast, singlecycle,
run-time reconfiguration between these predetermined
modes is enabled by executing special instructions which
switch coarse-grained components like instruction decoders,
ALUs and register banks. Performance is evaluated in terms
of execution cycles and achieved clock frequency. First results
indicate suitability especially in audio and video processing
applications.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="CompilerDriven_Reconfiguration_of_Multiprocessors.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2289033/2407124/CompilerDriven_Reconfiguration_of_Multiprocessors.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-22890330</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Hussmann, M., Thies, M., Kastens, U., Purnaprajna, M., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hussmann, Michael, Thies, Michael, Kastens, Uwe, Purnaprajna, Madhura, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2007. “Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hussmann, M., Thies, M., Kastens, U., Purnaprajna, M., Porrmann, M., Rückert, U.: Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007.  (2007).</lncs>
<ieee> M. Hussmann, et al., “Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;, 2007.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hussmann, M., et al., 2007. Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ama>Hussmann M, Thies M, Kastens U, Purnaprajna M, Porrmann M, Rückert U. Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;. 2007.</ama>
<default>Hussmann M, Thies M, Kastens U, Purnaprajna M, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007.</default>
<bio1>Hussmann M, Thies M, Kastens U, Purnaprajna M, Porrmann M, Rückert U (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007. .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Hussmann, M.  Thies, U.  Kastens, M.  Purnaprajna, M.  Porrmann, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hussmann, M.; Thies, M.; Kastens, U.; Purnaprajna, M.; Porrmann, M.; Rückert, U. (2007): Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007.</wels>
<mla>Hussmann, Michael, Thies, Michael, Kastens, Uwe, Purnaprajna, Madhura, Porrmann, Mario, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;. 2007.</mla>
<frontiers>Hussmann, M., Thies, M., Kastens, U., Purnaprajna, M., Porrmann, M., and Rückert, U. (2007). “Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hussmann, M., Thies, M., Kastens, U., Purnaprajna, M., Porrmann, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hussmann, M., Thies, M., Kastens, U., Purnaprajna, M., Porrmann, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2007). Compiler-Driven Reconfiguration of Multiprocessors. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on Application Specific Processors (WASP) 2007&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2289033</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-07T09:50:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>