<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2301213</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Prozessentwicklung für die Spaltung eines Muzin-Fusionsproteins durch Enterokinase</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kubitzki</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Noll</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In today's pharmacological industry, fusion proteins are used for the production of recombinant proteins of therapeutic interest. However, to obtain the therapeutically important protein in its monomeric form, the fusion partner, generally a signal peptide for translocation, needs to be removed using either chemicals or enzymes. In the latter case, the cleavage of fusion proteins can be conducted with higher specificity and under milder reaction conditions.
One of the biocatalysts used in laboratory scale is the serine protease enterokinase. In this study, enterokinase was applied in the cleavage of MUC1-IgG2a Fc for the generation of MUC1, a potential target in cancer immunotherapy.
To make enterokinase an attractive candidate for industrial fusion protein cleavage, the process for biocatalyst production by recombinant E. coli was optimized with regard to fermentation conditions and used isolation and purification techniques. By the application of a newly developed batch-binding chamber, the downstream process was simplified and the process time could be reduced by half. Furthermore, the yield of isolated biocatalyst was increased 8-fold for an inducible expression system and 14-fold with constitutive protein expression.
The enzymatic cleavage reaction needs to be economically feasible making an efficient utilization of the biocatalyst necessary. Therefore, different carrier materials for enzyme immobilization have been investigated, of which two - the porous Sepabeads® EC-HA203 and non-porous magnetic particles - gave promising results. Remaining activities for immobilized enterokinase of 60 percent could be achieved with an additional stabilizing effect when using the porous material. Enterokinase immobilized on Sepabeads® EC-HA203 was successfully applied in fusion protein cleavage receiving the desired protein MUC1, compared to the non-porous support.
Finally, enterokinase immobilized on porous support was applied in the preparative cleavage of MUC1-IgG2a Fc either in a continuous process or in repetitive utilization. According to the received process parameters, the repeated application of the enzyme-support preparation proved to be the more efficient method in fusion protein cleavage. Immobilized enterokinase was re-used 15 to 18 times for cleaving MUC1-IgG2a Fc increasing the total turnover number 419-fold compared to a single application of the biocatalyst.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">In der heutigen pharmazeutischen Industrie werden Fusionsproteine für die Herstellung von therapeutisch wichtigen, rekombinanten Proteinen eingesetzt. Um jedoch das eigentliche Zielprotein in aktiver Form zu erhalten, muss zunächst der Fusionspartner, meist ein Signalpeptid für Translokation, durch eine chemische oder enzymatische Reaktion entfernt werden. Letzteres erlaubt eine sehr spezifische Spaltung des Fusionsproteins unter milden Reaktionsbedingungen.
Ein im Labormaßstab eingesetzter Biokatalysator ist die Serinprotease Enterokinase. In dieser Arbeit wird Enterokinase für die Spaltung von MUC1-IgG2a Fc verwendet, um MUC1, ein potentielles Zielprotein für die Immuntherapie in der Krebsbehandlung, herzustellen.
Damit Enterokinase zu einem attraktiven Kandidaten für die industrielle Spaltung von Fusionsproteinen wird, fand eine Optimierung des Prozesses für die Biokatalysatorproduktion durch rekombinanten E. coli in Bezug auf die Fermentationsbedingungen und die eingesetzten Isolations- und Aufreinigungsmethoden statt. Durch eine neuartige Anbindungszelle wurde die Aufarbeitung vereinfacht und die Prozesszeit halbiert. Des Weiteren konnte die Ausbeute an isoliertem Biokatalysator um das 8fache durch ein induziertes Expressionssystem und um das 14fache durch konstitutive Expression gesteigert werden.
Um eine enzymatische Spaltungsreaktion wirtschaftlicher zu machen, muss der Biokatalysator effizienter in die Reaktion eingebracht werden. Aus diesem Grund wurden verschiedene Trägermaterialien für die Immobilisierung des Enzyms untersucht, wobei zwei - die porösen Sepabeads® EC-HA203 und die nichtporösen Magnetpartikel - vielversprechende Ergebnisse zeigten. Es konnten Restaktivitäten von 60 Prozent und eine zusätzliche Stabilisierung der Enterokinase bei Verwendung des porösen Trägers erzielt werden. MUC1-IgG2a Fc wurde erfolgreich durch auf Sepabeads® EC-HA203 immobilisierte Enterokinase gespalten. Es zeigte sich, dass poröse Stoffe eher für die Immobilisierung von einem kleinen Biokatalysator, der anschließend für die Spaltung von großen Fusionsproteinen verwendet wird, geeignet sind. Abschließend wurde das Immobilisat sowohl in einem kontinuierlichen Prozess als auch in wiederholten Spaltungsreaktionen von MUC1-IgG2a Fc eingesetzt. Die erhaltenen Prozessparameter zeigen, dass die mehrmalige Anwendung des Immobilisats eine sehr effiziente Methode zur Spaltung des Fusionsproteins darstellt. Die immobilisierte Enterokinase wurde zwischen 15 und 18mal wieder verwendet, wodurch die Katalysatorausnutzung um das 419fache, verglichen mit einer einzelnen Reaktion, gesteigert werden konnte.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Disseration_Kubitzki_2009.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2301213/2301216/Disseration_Kubitzki_2009.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>, Fusionsprotein , Enterokinase , Prozesstechnik , Immobilisierung , Fusion protein , Enterokinase , Process engineering , Immobilization</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-14884</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2009-03-29</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Kubitzki, T. (2008). Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<mla>Kubitzki, Tina. &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kubitzki, T. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kubitzki, T. (2008): Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Kubitzki T (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Kubitzki, T., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Kubitzki, &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Kubitzki, T. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kubitzki, T. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Kubitzki, &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kubitzki T (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Kubitzki T. &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2008.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kubitzki, Tina. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kubitzki, T.: Development of a process for the cleavage of a mucin fusion protein by enterokinase. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2008).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2301213</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2009-04-16T09:22:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T09:02:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>