<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302939</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hunsche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard J.</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Güntert</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Ziel dieser Dissertation ist es - basierend auf dem Prävalenzansatz - die medizinischen Kosten der Bulimie in den USA zu schätzen und in einen globalen Kontext zu stellen. Zu diesem Zweck wurde eine eingehende Literaturrecherche bezüglich der globalen epidemiologischen Evidenz zur Bulimie vorgenommen sowie - anhand einer großen amerikanischen Krankenversicherungsdatenbank - eine gesundheitsökonomische Analyse der Behandlungskosten pro Patient. Die Ergebnisse dieser beiden Forschungsansätze wurden kombiniert, um die medizinischen Kosten der Bulimie in den USA zu projizieren. Implikationen für die klinische Praxis sowie zukünftiger Forschungsbedarf werden diskutiert.
In den 80er Jahren wurde in Erhebungen die Prävalenz der Bulimie unter Erwachsenen in westlichen Ländern auf 8 Prozent - 13 Prozent geschätzt, während nach jüngsten Studien diese nur ungefähr 1 Prozent beträgt, vermutlich bedingt durch die strengeren diagnostischen Kriterien. Des Weiteren sind auch nicht westlich orientierte Länder von dieser Krankheit betroffen, wie eine begrenzte Anzahl von Studien belegt. Sehr limitierte Evidenz existiert derzeit bezüglich der Lebenszeitprävalenz, die auf mindestens 2 Prozent bei Frauen in westlichen Ländern geschätzt werden kann. Bezüglich der Inzidenz können keine verlässlichen Aussagen getroffen werden, da es zu wenige gut geplante Studien gibt.
Bei amerikanischen Patienten mit privater, vom Arbeitgeber gesponsorter Krankenversicherung wurden die jährlichen leistungsbezogenen Gesamtkosten im Jahre 2002 - einschließlich ambulanter, hospitärer und medikamentöser Behandlung der Bulimie und ihrer Komplikationen und Komorbiditäten - auf $3.577 pro Patient geschätzt. Davon waren $1.865 direkt der ambulanten und hospitären Therapie der Bulimie zurechenbar. Von den Gesamtkosten entfielen 42 Prozent auf die medikamentöse, 25 Prozent auf die ambulante und 33 Prozent auf die stationäre Therapie. Mit Hilfe eines multivariaten Regressionsmodells wurde ermittelt, dass Alter und Komorbidität einen signifikanten Einfluss auf die Höhe der täglichen Kosten haben mit einem Kostenanstieg um 1,0 Prozent pro zusätzlichem Altersjahr und 1,6 Prozent mit jeder weiteren Diagnose. Bei Patienten mit Krankenversicherungen, die ganz oder teilweise über Kopfpauschalen abrechnen, wurden die Gesamtkosten auf der Grundlange von leistungsäquivalenten Kosten auf $4.238 pro Patient pro Jahr geschätzt, von denen $2.113 direkt der Bulimie zurechenbar waren.
Die Anzahl amerikanischer Erwachsener, die im Jahre 2002 an Bulimie litten, wurde auf 0,5 bis 1,0 Millionen geschätzt und die jährlichen Behandlungskosten für Patienten mit privater Krankenversicherung auf $1,7 Milliarden, von denen $0,9 Milliarden direkt der Bulimie zurechenbar waren. Die Gesamtkosten könnten jedoch bis auf $3,5 Milliarden ansteigen, wenn alle Betroffenen, unabhängig von ihrem Krankenversicherungsstatus, diagnostiziert und therapiert würden. Da jedoch die meisten Betroffenen in den USA nicht behandelt werden, ist dieser Schätzwert eher ein Indiz für potentielle zukünftige Kosten. Weiterer Forschungsbedarf besteht derzeit bezüglich der Identifikation von Therapiebarrieren sowie Strategien zu deren Bewältigung. Des Weiteren müssten die für die Behandlung der Bulimie verfügbaren Ressourcen ermittelt werden, um den ungedeckten Bedarf bestimmen zu können. Schließlich sind Langzeitstudien erforderlich, die Aussagen über den Verlauf der Epidemiologie der Bulimie ermöglichen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The objective of this thesis is to assess the medical burden of bulimia nervosa in the U.S. using a prevalence-based approach, and to place this burden in a global context. To this aim, a thorough literature review of the global evidence on the epidemiology of bulimia nervosa was performed, as well as health economic analysis of the per-patient treatment costs in a large, U.S. claims database. Results of these two research approaches were combined to project the medical costs of bulimia nervosa in the U.S. Implications of findings for clinical practice and future research needs are discussed.
Estimates of the prevalence of bulimia nervosa in the adult population of Western countries have dropped from 8 percent - 13 percent in surveys in the 1980s to approximately 1 percent in recent studies, likely because diagnostic criteria became more stringent over time. The limited data available demonstrate that bulimia nervosa also exists in non-Western and developing countries. Estimates of a lifetime prevalence of bulimia nervosa of at least 2 percent among women in Western countries are based on a smaller evidence base than the amount of research conducted on the point prevalence. There are currently too few well-designed studies on the incidence of bulimia nervosa to draw reliable conclusions.
In patients with private employer-sponsored healthcare plans in U.S., the total annual per-patient fee-for-service treatment cost in 2002, including inpatient, outpatient, and drug treatment of bulimia nervosa as well as its complications and comorbidities, was estimated at $3,577, of which $1,865 were directly attributable to inpatient and outpatient care of the eating disorder. Pharmaceutical services accounted for 42 percent of the total costs, while inpatient and outpatient care contributed 25 percent and 33 percent, respectively. Based on a multivariate regression model, only age and comorbidity were found to be significant predictors of the daily per-patient costs, with costs increasing by 1.0 percent with each additional year of age and by 1.6 percent with each additional diagnosis. For patients with partially or fully capitated healthcare plans (encounter claims), costs had to be approximated by fee-for-service equivalents, yielding estimated per-patient annual costs of $4,238, of which $2,113 were directly attributable to the outpatient and inpatient treatment of bulimia nervosa.
Following a prevalence-based approach, it was estimated that in 2002 between 0.5 and 1.0 million adults suffered from bulimia nervosa, leading to a total annual cost of $1.7 billion in patients with private employer-based health insurance, of which $0.9 billion were directly attributable to the outpatient and inpatient treatment of bulimia nervosa. However, the burden to payers would rise to $3.5 billion if all predicted sufferers, irrespective of insurance status, were diagnosed and treated. Since most cases currently go untreated, this estimate provides an indication of potential future costs. Additional research is needed to identify barriers to care and strategies to overcome them. Determining the need for additional resources will require research to quantify healthcare resources currently available for the treatment of bulimic individuals, as well as studies to identify long-term trends in the epidemiology of bulimia nervosa.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Hunsche.Diss.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302939/2302942/Hunsche.Diss.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-10724</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-03-26</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Hunsche E (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Hunsche, Elke. &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunsche, Elke. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hunsche, E.: Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Hunsche, &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Hunsche, E., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunsche, E. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hunsche E (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<wels>Hunsche, E. (2007): Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<ieee> E. Hunsche, &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<apa>Hunsche, E. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<frontiers>Hunsche, E. (2007). Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hunsche, E. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hunsche E. &lt;em&gt;Burden of illness of bulimia nervosa in the United States : an evaluation of the prevalence, incidence, and treatment costs of bulimia nervosa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302939</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2007-03-30T11:24:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>