<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302234</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A. Veronica</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Witte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Gertraud</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Teuchert-Noodt</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Der präfrontale Kortex (PFC) gewährleistet als phylogenetisch jüngster Bereich des zentralen Nervensystems übergeordnete Funktionen wie zielgerichtete Handlungen und komplexes Sozialverhalten. Die präfrontale Integration von multimodalen Eingängen auf höchster Ebene wird durch eine sehr selektive inter- sowie intralaminäre Verschaltung zwischen anatomisch und funktionell unterschiedlichen glutamatergen Pyramidenzellen und lokalen Interneuronen in höhergestellten Modulen ermöglicht.
Die Befunde unserer ersten Langzeitstudie (Witte et al., 2007a) lassen für den Kortex erstmalig detaillierte Rückschlüsse über die zugrundeliegenden Reifungsgeschehnisse im Ausgangssystem des PFC zu. In fünf juvenilen Altersgruppen wurden die Efferenzen der präfrontalen Pyramidenzellen im ipsilateralen frontalen (FC), parietalen (PC), agranulär insulären (AIC) und dysgranulär insulären (DIC) sowie im kontralateralen präfrontalen Kortex (CON) mittels des anterograden Tracers Biocytin angefärbt und quantitativ ausgewertet. Es zeigte sich, dass die Faserdichten aus den Lamina III- und aus den Lamina V/VI-Pyramiden einen separaten und hoch dynamischen Verlauf in ihrer postnatalen Entwicklung nehmen: Das Wachstum der Lamina III-Efferenzen verharrte auf einem niedrigen Niveau bis zur Geschlechtsreife, wonach die Faserdichten signifikant im FC und DIC auf adulte Werte im jungen Erwachsenenalter am Tag 90 anstiegen. Die Lamina V/VI-Efferenzen zeigten dagegen einen Rückgang der anfangs hohen Faserdichten zwischen dem Zeitpunkt der Augenöffnung und Tag 19-24, statistisch signifikant im AIC. Im Folgenden beschrieben die Faserdichten ein erneutes Wachstum um die Geschlechtsreife, signifikant im AIC, FC und DIC. Die Befunde wurden im Hinblick auf die morphogene Wirkung der einwachsenden thalamischen glutamatergen und der mesenzephalen dopaminergen Afferenzen während selektiver Zeitfenster diskutiert.
In einer zweiten Biocytin-Studie (Witte et al., 2007b) konnte für das callosale präfrontale System erstmals nachgewiesen werden, dass diese selektive Reifung durch umweltbezogene Interventionen (1. eine frühe neurotoxische Gabe von Methamphetamin, 2. sozial isolierte Aufzucht) maßgeblich beeinträchtigt wird. Jeweils eine der Aufzuchtsinterventionen führte zu einer Absenkung der efferenten Lamina V/VI-Faserdichten im CON verglichen mit Kontrolltieren aus Gehegeaufzucht. Die kombinierte Behandlung dagegen, bestehend aus Methamphetamin-Intoxikation und deprivierter Aufzucht, invertierte diese Einzeleffekte in besonderem Maße, so dass die Lamina V/VI-Efferenzen stark erhöhte Faserdichten im CON aufwiesen; keine Beeinträchtigung war für die Lamina III-Efferenzen zu erkennen. Diese Befunde erweitern frühere Erkenntnisse an unserem Zwei-Phasen-Tiermodell zur pathologischen "Dyskonnektion" der zwei präfrontalen Ausgangssysteme als neuroanatomisches Korrelat der Funktionsstörungen bei Patienten mit Schizophrenie (Bagorda et al., 2006), was hypothetisch von Weinberger und Lispka (1995) postuliert war: Vermutlich bleibt der normale Rückgang der Lamina V/VI-Faserdichten in der dritten postnatalen Woche aufgrund der massiven Störungen durch die kombinierte Intervention aus.
In einer weiteren Langzeitstudie (Brummelte, Witte et al. 2007) habe ich die Reifung von inhibitorisch aktiven GABAergen Interneuronen in limbischen Arealen mituntersucht. Mittels immunhistochemischer Färbemethoden konnte gezeigt werden, dass die GABAergen Faserdichten im PFC nach einer ersten starken Zunahme bis zur Entwöhnung noch weiter bis ins hohe Erwachsenenalter am Tag 520 anstiegen. Dieser stetige Faserumbau könnte eine Grundlage für die Schlüsselrolle sein, die den lokalen GABA-Netzen in der Entstehung und lebenslangen Aufrechterhaltung funktioneller Netzwerke zugeschrieben wird (Hensch, 2005).
In der vierten Studie (Flöel, Witte et al., submitted) geht es um die Frage, ob die große Bedeutung der Umwelt auch auf Gehirnleistungen beim Menschen übertragbar ist. Die Erforschung von neuen, kostengünstigen Strategien, die den altersbedingten kognitiven Abbau verhindern helfen, ist von immenser klinischer Bedeutung. In dieser Querschnittsstudie konnten wir bei 420 älteren, gesunden Personen mittels neuropsychologischer Testverfahren einen signifikanten positiven Zusammenhang von einem gesunden Lebensstil (dokumentiert durch regelmäßige körperliche Aktivität, eine kalorienarme Ernährung, Nichtrauchen sowie moderater Alkoholgenuss) und einer besseren Gedächtnisfunktion unabhängig von Alter, Bildung und Geschlecht aufzeigen.
Diese Ergebnisse der angewandten Forschung beim Menschen unterstreichen den starken Einfluss der Umwelt auf die Plastizität des Kortex. Die tierexperimentellen Studien zeigen außerdem, dass bedingt durch die besonders lang andauernde präfrontale Reifung nicht nur der dopaminergen Afferenzen sondern, wie gefunden, auch der glutamatergen Efferenzen äußere Umweltfaktoren diese verzögerte Entwicklung des PFC erheblich beeinträchtigen können.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The purpose of my experiments was to examine the development and maintenance of plastic, environmental-adaptive cortical networks and in particular to analyse for the first time the postnatal maturation of the excitatory pyramidal cells in the prefrontal cortex (PFC) on a structural level.
The PFC guarantees as phylogenetic latest area of the central nervous system higher functions like purposive actions and complex social behaviours. The prefrontal integration of multimodal inputs at highest level is processed by very selective inter- as well as intralaminar circuits between anatomical and functional different glutamatergic pyramid cells and local interneurons in higher modules.
The findings of our first long-time study (Witte et al., 2007a) admit for the cortex first detailed conclusions about the basic developmental events in the output system of the PFC. In five juvenile age groups, efferents of the prefrontal pyramidal cells were labelled with the anterograde tracer biocytin and quantitatively evaluated in the ipsilateral frontal (FC), parietal (PC), agranular insular (AIC), and dysgranular insular (DIC), as well as in the contralateral prefrontal cortex (CON). Cortical fibre densities originating from prefrontal layer III- and layer V/VI-pyramids appeared to follow a separate and highly dynamic course during postnatal development: The growth of layer III-efferents paused at a low level up to sexual maturity, after which fibre densities exhibited a significant increase in the FC and DIC to adult values at young adulthood on day 90. In contrast, layer V/VI-efferents showed a decline of initial high fibre densities between the time of eye opening and day 19-24, statistically significantly in the AIC. Afterwards, fibre densities described a re-growth around sexual maturity, significantly in the AIC, FC and DIC. The findings were discussed in relation to morphogenetic effects of ingrowing thalamic glutamatergic and mesencephalic dopaminergic afferents during selective time windows.
The second biocytin study (Witte et al., 2007b) provided first-time evidence regarding the callosal prefrontal system that this selective maturation is severely impaired due to epigenetic interventions (1. an early methamphetamine intoxication, 2. socially isolated rearing). Each intervention led to reduced efferent layer V/VI-fibre densities in the CON compared to control animals from enriched rearing. The combined treatment however, consisting of methamphetamine intoxication and isolated rearing, inverted these single effects in a turn-over fashion so that layer V/VI-efferents showed highly increased fibre densities in the CON. No alteration was to be recognised regarding layer III-efferents. These findings extend former knowledge from our two-hit animal model describing a pathological "dysconnection" of the two prefrontal output systems as one neuro-anatomical correlative of the malfunctions in patients with schizophrenia (Bagorda et al., 2006), which was postulated hypothetically by Weinberger and Lispka (1995): The normal decline of layer V/VI-fibre densities in the third postnatal week is presumably missing due to massive disturbances by the combined intervention.
In another long-time study (Brummelte, Witte et al. 2007), I participated in evaluating the maturation of inhibitory GABAergic interneurons in limbic areas. By means of immunohistochemical staining methods, it has been shown that after a first strong growth up to weaning the GABAergic fibre densities in the PFC increased even further until old adult ages on day 520. This steady fibre-rebuilding could account for the key role in the establishment and lifelong maintenance of environmental-related functional networks ascribed to local GABAergic circuits (Hensch, in 2005).
The fourth study (Flöel, Witte et al., submitted) questions whether the powerful meaning of the environment is also transferable to cognitive functions in humans. The investigation of novel cost-efficient strategies which help to prevent age-related cognitive decline is of immense clinical importance. In this cross-sectional study we detected by means of neuropsychological testings in 420 healthy elderly people a significant positive association of a healthy lifestyle (documented by regular physical activity, a low-calorie diet, non-smoking, as well as moderate consumption of alcohol) and a better memory performance even after adjusting for age, education and gender.
These results of the applied human research underline the strong influence of the environment on cortical plasticity. In addition, the animal-experimental studies point out that external environmental factors can considerably affect - as a consequence of the long continuing prefrontal maturation not only regarding dopaminergic afferents but also, as found, regarding glutamatergic efferents - this prolonged development of the PFC.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_Veronica_Witte.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302234/2302237/Dissertation_Veronica_Witte.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>, Kortex , Pyramidenzellen , Entwicklung , Umwelt , Lebensweise , Cortex , Pyramidal cells , Development , Environment , Lifestyle</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-11829</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-10-22</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Witte, A. V. (2007): Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Witte, A. Veronica. &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<frontiers>Witte, A. V. (2007). Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Witte, A. V. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Witte AV (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Witte, A.V., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> A.V. Witte, &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<apa>Witte, A. V. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Witte, A.V. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>A. V.  Witte, &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Witte AV (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Witte AV. &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<lncs> Witte, A.V.: Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Witte, A. Veronica. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Dynamic changes in the development of prefrontal networks : neuroanatomical findings&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302234</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2007-11-12T10:21:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:46:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>