<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302741</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Effects of simultaneous listening and reading on L2 reading : an eye-tracking study in the range of German as a foreign language</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Li-Ying</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Essig-Shih</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Karin</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Aguado</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this study, I investigated the effects of simultaneous listening and reading on visual information processing, text comprehension, and memory performance of Chinese participants on an advanced level of German as a foreign language (L2) when reading German literary texts. Two conditions were compared: reading (R) and simultaneous listening and reading (LR). I used a binocular eye tracker to measure the eye movement parameters (i.e., reading time, number of fixations, fixation durations, and saccade durations) in both conditions with Chinese native speakers as an experimental group and German native speakers as a control group. Two questionnaires were designed to test the participants' memory performance and additionally, participants were interviewed after the experiment to gather subjective impressions on text comprehension. I found that, in comparison to the LR condition, faster reading by L2 learners in the R condition was not equal to a better L2 reading comprehension and only L2 learners with an advanced L2 knowledge benefited from LR. The analysis of eye movements indicated that the auditory input had different effects on the reading behaviour of Chinese and German readers.
The analyses of the questionnaires did not yield any differences in recall between the two groups, leading to the conclusion that the auditory input had no influence on memory performance of the participants in this experiment.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">In dieser Studie werden die Effekte des simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf die visuelle Informationsverarbeitung, das Leseverständnis und die Gedächtnisleistung chinesischer Deutschlerner mit fortgeschrittenen Fremdsprachenkenntnissen beim Lesen von deutschen literarischen Texten untersucht. Methodisch werden Eyetracking, Ja/Nein-Aussagen und Fragebögen verwendet. Die Ergebnisse des Experiments zeigen, dass sich das simultane Hören und Lesen positiv auf das Leseverständnis der L2-Lerner mit fortgeschrittenen Fremdsprachenkenntnissen auswirkt. Der auditive Input zeigt unterschiedliche Effekte auf das Leseverhalten bei den chinesischen und deutschen Lesern. Die Auswertung der Ja/Nein-Aussagen lässt keine Unterschiede in der Gedächtnisleistung zwischen Chinesen und Deutschen erkennen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation.Ying.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302741/2302744/Dissertation.Ying.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-12980</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2008-05-04</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Essig-Shih L-Y (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Essig-Shih, Li-Ying. &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Essig-Shih, Li-Ying. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Essig-Shih, L.-Y.: Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2008).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>L. - Y.  Essig-Shih, &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Essig-Shih, L. - Y. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Essig-Shih L-Y (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Essig-Shih, L.-Y., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<wels>Essig-Shih, L. - Y. (2008): Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<ieee> L.-Y. Essig-Shih, &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Essig-Shih, L. - Y. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<frontiers>Essig-Shih, L. - Y. (2008). Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Essig-Shih, L.-Y. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Essig-Shih L-Y. &lt;em&gt;Effekte simultanen Hörens und Lesens auf das L2-Lesen : eine Eyetracking-Studie im Bereich Deutsch als Fremdsprache&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2008.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302741</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2008-06-05T06:50:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>