<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302439</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Effects of culture conditions on production rates, glycosylation, and function of murine monoclonal antibody R 24</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven Eric</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kemminer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Müthing</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: The IgG molecule basically contains an asparagine-linked bi-antennary complex-type oligosaccharide on the C H 2 domain of each heavy chain, which is necessary for effector functions of the antibody. R24, a mouse IgG3 monoclonal antibody (mab) against ganglioside GD3, can block tumor growth as reported in a series of clinical trials on patients with metastatic melanoma. The purpose of this study was to explore (i) the specific rates of antibody production and (ii) the oligosaccharide profiles of mab R24 produced in bioreactor batches using three CO2/HCO3 and a HEPES buffered system.
Methods: Mab R24 (ATCC, HB8445) was produced in CO2/HCO3 (pH 6.9, 7.2, and 7.4) and HEPES (pH 7.2) buffered serum-free medium in a bubble-free aerated 2L-bioreactor using the repeated batch modus. The specific mab production rate qR24 (µg/10^6 cells x d) was determined during logarithmic growth and the IgG3 mab was purified to homogeneity (as judged by SDS/PAGE under reducing conditions) by protein A chromatography. Sialic acids (Neu5Ac und Neu5Gc) were identified as their fluorescent DMB derivatives by RP18 column chromatography. Oligosaccharides were released by hydrazinolysis and PNGaseF digest and their structures were determined by HPAEC-PAD, MALDI-TOF und ESI-QTOF mass spectrometry.
Results: Specific production rates and glycosylation pattern of mab R24 varied significantly over the extracellular pH range of 6.9 to 7.4. Maximum product yields were obtained at pH 6.9 (42.9 µg/10^6 cells x d), whereas lowest yields were obtained in pH 7.4 adjusted batches (10.8 µg/10^6 cells x d). HPAEC-PAD profiles revealed agalacto-biantennary chains as the major oligosaccharide in all preparations (40-50 percent). Considerable different amounts of fully galactosylated carbohydrate chains were detected in pH 7.4 (26 percent), pH 7.2 and pH 6.9 (both 17 percent) and HEPES (14 percent) derived material. A 3:1 molar ratio of Neu5Ac to Neu5Gc was detected in HEPES derived mab, whereas all the other preparations revealed equimolar ratios of Neu5Ac and Neu5Gc. Thus, different culture pH leads to differences in specific production rates and glycosylation pattern of murine R24 IgG3 monoclonal antibody.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Bei dem monoklonalen Maus IgG3 Antikörper (mAk) R24 aus der Maus-Maus Hybridomzelllinie HB-8445 (ATCC) handelt es sich um einen potentiellen Kandidaten für den therapeutischen Einsatz beim Menschen zur Behandlung von malignen Melanomen. Er ist gegen das Gangliosid GD3 gerichtet und in der Lage, bei metastasierenden Melanomen das Tumorwachstum zu unterbinden, was in einer ganzen Reihe von klinischen Untersuchungen nachgewiesen werden konnte.
Die vorliegende Arbeit behandelt die Auswirkungen der Produktionsbedingungen auf die Produktionsraten, Integrität und Funktionalität des mAk R24.
Die Arbeit kann in zwei Teile untergliedert werden, wobei sich der erste Teil mit der Produktion und Aufreinigung des mAk R24 unter verschiedenen Kulturbedingungen beschäftigt. Der Einfluss der Kulturbedingungen wurde dabei im SuperSpinner und in 2-Liter-Bioreaktor-Kultursystemen untersucht. Im 2-Liter-Bioreaktor fanden ein ungeregeltes HEPES-Puffersystem und geregelte CO2/HCO3- -Puffersysteme mit den pH-Werten 7,4; 7,2 und 6,9 Verwendung.
Der zweite Teil der Arbeit handelt von der Aufreinigung und Charakterisierung des produzierten R24 Antikörpers unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Glykosylierung und Funktionalität des Antikörpers. Als Grundlage zur Untersuchung der Antigen-Bindungseigenschaften des Antikörpers wurde sein Antigen, das Gangliosid GD3, aus Buttermilch isoliert, aufgereinigt und charakterisiert.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="0035.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302439/2302442/0035.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>,  , Glycoprotein , Oligosaccharides , Sialic acids , R24</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-4619</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2001-03-29</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Kemminer, S. E. (2001): Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Kemminer, Sven Eric. &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2001.</mla>
<frontiers>Kemminer, S. E. (2001). Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kemminer, S. E. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Kemminer SE (2001) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Kemminer, S.E., 2001. &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> S.E. Kemminer, &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2001.</ieee>
<apa>Kemminer, S. E. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kemminer, S.E. (2001). &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>S. E.  Kemminer, &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kemminer SE (2001) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Kemminer SE. &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2001.</ama>
<lncs> Kemminer, S.E.: Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2001).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kemminer, Sven Eric. 2001. &lt;em&gt;Auswirkungen der Kulturbedingungen auf die Produktion, Glykosylierung und Funktion des monoklonalen Maus-Antikörpers R 24&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302439</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2004-02-03T10:54:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:47:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>