<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302491</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Über die Erkennung von Objekten anhand von Teilkonturen und über die frühe Entwicklung der Konturerkennung in biologischen Systemen</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Prodöhl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Das Wavelet-Konzept der Gabor-Deskriptoren wird vorgestellt und angewendet auf das Problem der Konturerkennung und Objekterkennung. Die Methode kann sehr effizient rotierte und skalierte Konturen wiedererkennen. Des weiteren ist mit dem gleichen Ansatz auch die Objekterkennung anhand von Teilkonturen möglich.
Diese spezielle Methode liefert relative Ähnlichkeiten, die eine hohe Korrelation mit den von Menschen wahrgenommenen Objektähnlichkeiten haben.
Im zweiten Teil der Arbeit wird das erste Modell über die Grundlagen der Entwicklung der Konturverarbeitung in neuronalen biologischen Systemen vorgestellt, insbesondere die Grundlage für die Herausbildung des Gestalt-Wahrnehmungsprinzips der Kollinearität.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The wavelet concept of Gabor descriptors is introduced and applied to the problem of contour matching and object recognition. It is shown that the method can deal efficiently with the invariant recognition of scaled and rotated object contours. Furthermore the recognition of objects only by parts of their contour due to occlusions or overlapping objects can as well be done with Gabor descriptor representation.
The specific method has a high correlation with the perception of contour similarities by humans.
In the second part the first model on the foundations of the development of neuronal biological contour processing is given, especially regarding the foundation of the perception Gestalt law of collinearity.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302491/2302494/Dissertation.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Kontur , Objekterkennung , Bilderkennung , Rotationsinvarianz , Kollinearität , Robuste Konturerkennung , Formerkennung , Gabor-Deskriptoren , Object recognition , Contour , Invariant , Image processing , Shape recognition , Collinearity , Gabor descriptors</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-8285</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2005-01-23</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> C. Prodöhl, &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2004.</ieee>
<harvard1>Prodöhl, C., 2004. &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ama>Prodöhl C. &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2004.</ama>
<apa>Prodöhl, C. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prodöhl, Carsten. 2004. &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Prodöhl, C.: On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2004).</lncs>
<wels>Prodöhl, C. (2004): On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prodöhl, C. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Prodöhl, C. (2004). On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<mla>Prodöhl, Carsten. &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2004.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prodöhl, C. (2004). &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Prodöhl C (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<bio1>Prodöhl C (2004) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Prodöhl, &lt;em&gt;On the recognition of objects by contour parts and the early development of biological contour processing&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302491</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2006-03-09T13:17:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:48:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>