<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302001</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aysel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Alici</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Karsten</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Niehaus</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3855915</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">In dieser Arbeit wurden umfangreiche Proteomanalysen von Sorangium cellulosum So ce56 durchgeführt, wobei Proteine aus den verschiedenen zellulären Kompartimenten untersucht worden sind: Proteine aus dem Cytosol, sekretierte Proteine, Membran- und Vesikelproteine. Diese Untersuchungen hatten zum Ziel, Proteine in So ce56 zu identifizieren, die an morphologischen Differenzierungsprozessen, wie der Bildung von Fruchtkörpern, der Biosynthese von Sekundärmetaboliten, sowie an Transportprozessen, bei der Signaltransduktion und bei der Zellfortbewegung beteiligt sind. Die isolierten Proteine wurden unter konstanten Wachstumsbedingungen in der frühen stationären Phase elektrophoretisch aufgetrennt. Die Identifizierung der differentiell auftretenden Proteine erfolgte mittels MALDI-TOF-MS und nanoLC-ESI-MS. So wurden 115 differentielle Proteine aus der cytosolischen Fraktion identifiziert, die vorwiegend an Primärstoffwechselprozessen von So ce56 beteiligt sind. Des weiteren wurden Phasenspezifische Proteine (exponentielle und frühe stationäre Phase) mittels Differentieller Gelelektrophorese (DIGE) analysiert. Proteine, die in der Signaltransduktion involviert sind, wurden zusätzlich mit Westernblotanalysen detektiert, insbesondere die Phosphorylierungen an Tyrosin und Serin. Die Untersuchung des Sekretoms von So ce56 führte zur Identifizierung von 41 verschiedenen Proteinen, die hauptsächlich hydrolytische Funktionen aufzeigen. Um die Identifizierung und Charakterisierung des So ce56 Proteoms zu erweitern, wurden neben den cytosolischen und sekretorischen Proteinen auch die Membran- und die Vesikelproteine untersucht. Mit Hilfe von 1-D Gelen und Blue-Native Gelen konnten hydrophobische Proteine und Proteine, die in Proteinkomplexen gebunden sind, detektiert und massenspektrometrisch analysiert werden. Die Analyse der Membranproteine resultierte in 66 identifizierten Proteinen. Zusätzlich wurden durch Untersuchungen der äußeren Membran weitere 35 Proteine identifiziert. Interessant war der Fund einer Sensorkinase, die einen hohen Homologiegrad zur Sensorkinase des Jerangolid/ Ambruticin Biosyntheseclusters (So ce307 und So ce10) aufzeigte. Überdies wurden noch elektronenmikroskopische Aufnahmen von Vesikelproteinen erstellt, die möglicherweise eine wichtige Transportfunktion in So ce56 übernehmen. Durch diese Proteomarbeit von So ce56 wurden insgesamt 247 verschiedene Proteine identifiziert, die ihren funktionalen Klassen zugeordnet werden konnten.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">In this work an extensive proteomic approach for Sorangium cellulosum So ce56 was developed and applied encompassing the extraction of different subproteomes: the cytoplasmic, membrane, extracellular and outer membrane vesicle fractions of So ce56. Consequently, a proteome reference map of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56 cytosolic proteins was established. Moreover, proteome analyzes were performed for the identification of proteins involved in the regulation of secondary metabolite biosynthesis, morphogenetic differentiation (fruiting body formation), signal transduction, transport process or gliding motility activities. A 2-D proteome map of So ce56 cytoplasmic proteins expressed during stationary phase was established and analyzed by MALDI-TOF-MS. 115 different cytosolic proteins of the 300 processed protein spots were identified and classified into COG categories. As expected, a large number of identified functionally annotated cytosolic proteins (75 percent) were involved in primary metabolic pathways, e.g. glycolysis, tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle and fatty acid degradation. This finding was supported by the analysis of tyrosine and serine phosphorylated proteins via Western Blot method resulting in the detection of many proteins activated during primary metabolism. Differentially expressed cytosolic proteins of the exponential phase and stationary phase from So ce56 were identified using DIGE technology. Additionally, the use of Blue-Native PAGE from the cytosolic and membrane fraction led to the identification of proteins belonging to protein complexes which are involved in different cellular processes, e.g. secondary metabolite production. Isolation of extracellular proteins by the phenol-extraction method resulted in the identification of 41 unique extracellular proteins which were shown to be enzymes mainly involved in biomacromolecule degradation like cellulase. To overcome analytical limitations created by the hydrophobic nature of membrane proteins a specific extraction procedure was adapted. SDS-PAGE preparation and consequent nanoLC-ESI-MS/MS analysis led to the identification of 66 proteins of the entire membrane fraction. For a detailed view, the outer membrane proteins were analyzed separately, which revealed the identification of 35 proteins from the outer membrane fraction. The identification of a putative serine histidine kinase in the membrane fraction showed a significant correlation with a sensor kinase in the jerangolid or ambruticin biosynthetic gene cluster isolated from other Sorangium strains. This discovery indicates further genes nearby which might be participating in the jerangolid or ambruticin polyketide biosynthetic gene cluster. Genomic and metabolomic approaches are additionally needed to characterize this putative fifth polyketide biosynthesis. Moreover, outer membrane vesicles (OMVs) of So ce56 could be visualized via electron microscopy, which might indicate a transport system of this myxobacteria. In total about 241 different proteins originating from the different cellular localizations could be identified.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="aysel_diss.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302001/2302004/aysel_diss.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>,  , Sorangium cellulosum , SO ce56 , Myxobacteria , Proteome , Metabolome</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-12421</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-12-13</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Alici, A.: Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alici, Aysel. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Alici, Aysel. &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<default>Alici A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<ama>Alici A. &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<frontiers>Alici, A. (2007). Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alici, A. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Alici, A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> A. Alici, &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<wels>Alici, A. (2007): Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alici, A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Alici A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Alici, A., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Alici, &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive proteomics of Sorangium cellulosum So ce56&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302001</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2008-02-07T10:56:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T09:07:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>