<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302915</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Miroslav</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malesevic</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Norbert</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Sewald</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Different spectroscopic methods (FTIR, CD, NMR) have been used to study the conformational properties of cyclic hexa-, penta-, and tetrapeptides, with or without [beta]-homoproline, and to examine the influence of this [beta]-amino acid on the peptide conformation in different solvents. Combination of these three analytical techniques revealed that [beta]-homoproline is an excellent inducer of secondary structure when inserted into a cyclic peptide. This residue stabilizes a pseudo-[gamma]-turn, or less frequently a pseudo-[beta]-turn.
Twenty new cyclic peptides that mimic the VCAM-1 binding epitope (R36TQID40SPLN44) have been synthesized using Fmoc chemistry and cyclization in solution. D-amino acids, [beta]-amino acids and proline are used as secondary structure inducers for the spatial screening of the pharmacophoric groups. These peptides, designed as [alpha]4[beta]1 integrin antagonists, could have numerous medical applications and might be very useful in future studies of cell-cell and cell-extracellular matrix interactions.
A new method for cyclization in solution using two injection pumps for separate addition of peptide and coupling reagent solutions to the reaction mixture and a purification by precipitation extraction method was developed. Combination of these two methods allows any solvent to be used for peptide cyclization. HOAt as additive, a rational design of the linear peptide precursor and slow addition rate of the peptide solution to the reaction mixture suppresses dimerization and epimerization, the main side reactions of the cyclization. A [beta]-homoamino acid in a central position of the linear precursor enhances the cyclization rate, and suppresses dimerization by bringing the peptide in a proper conformation.
Two cyclic constrained peptide mimics of the invasin binding epitope in which D-amino acids were designed to lock the peptide conformation in such a way that the critical Asp residue occurs in i+1 position of the [beta]-turn were synthesized. The adhesion test shows that these peptides bind to [alpha]3[beta]1 integrin with low affinity (mM range) and inhibit binding of laminin-5 to the integrin. The third peptide is a combination of a cyclic hexapeptide with the SDMS sequence with an arginine residue connected via a linker to mimic the synergistic activity of Arg883 located 30 Å apart from the binding epitope. This peptide completely suppresses the binding of laminin-5 to the [alpha]3[beta]1 integrin and the IC50 value is in the µM range.
Five new RGD peptides were synthesized and tested as inhibitors of the interaction between OV-MZ-6 carcinoma cells with three different extracellular matrix proteins (vitronectin, fibronectin and collagen typ I). Two of them show very strong inhibitor activity toward interaction of [alpha]v[beta]3 with vitronectin.
Linear peptides with a C-terminal thioester are key intermediates for enzymatic macrocyclization using peptide synthetases. These precursors were synthesized on Kenner's sulfonamide "safety-catch" linker. N-acetylcysteamine is used for nucleophilic displacement and cleavage of the peptides from the activated linker. Cyclizations of linear precursors of the antibiotic tyrocidine A and its analogs proceed smoothly and with negligible rate of hydrolysis using isolated and purified TycC TE domain.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="0103.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302915/2302918/0103.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Cyclopeptide , Konformation , Lösungsmittel , Zirkulardichroismus , NMR-Spektroskopie , FT-IR-Spektroskopie , Aminosäuren (beta-) , Cyclisation , Peptidsynthese , [beta]-Amino acids , Integrin , VCAM-1 (Vascular cell adhesion molecule-1) , Invasin</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-2307</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2002-10-16</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Malesevic, M. (2002): [beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Malesevic, &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Malesevic, M., 2002. &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<bio1>Malesevic M (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malesevic, M. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malesevic, M. (2002). &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Malesevic, M. (2002). [beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<ama>Malesevic M. &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2002.</ama>
<ieee> M. Malesevic, &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</ieee>
<apa>Malesevic, M. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malesevic, Miroslav. 2002. &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Malesevic, M.: [beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2002).</lncs>
<default>Malesevic M (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Malesevic, Miroslav. &lt;em&gt;[beta]-Amino acids as secondary structure inducers in peptides&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302915</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-06-10T11:15:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:50:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>