<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2302060</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Wissen über das Raumschiff Erde : eine soziologische Perspektive auf die Kapazitätsentwicklung</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lou Arlette</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jappe-Heinze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Weingart</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Die vorliegende Arbeit leistet einen Beitrag zu Umweltsoziologie und Wissenschaftssoziologie. Der erste Teil präsentiert einen neuen Forschungsansatz, um die Rolle von Forschung, Technologie und Innovation (engl. STI) für eine nachhaltige Entwicklung empirisch zu untersuchen. Im Zentrum dieser Analyse steht der Begriff der STI-Kapazität. Der zweite Teil untersucht internationale Kooperation in Umweltwissenschaften. Einen Schwerpunkt bildet der Vergleich des Internationalen Geosphären-Biosphären Programms (IGBP) und des Internationalen Hydrologischen Programms (IHP) der Unesco. Diese Fälle stehen exemplarisch für neue Organisationsformen zum Aufbau globalen Umweltwissens - im doppelten Sinn globaler Umweltbeobachtung und einer weltweiten Wissensverbreitung. Derartige Kooperationsprogramme sind aus institutionalistischer Sicht jedoch bislang kaum erforscht.
Der Begriff der STI-Kapazität bezieht sich auf das Umweltpolitik-Modell von M. Jänicke. Diesem Modell zufolge umfasst umweltpolitische Kapazität die längerfristigen, strukturellen Bedingungen politischer Handlungsfähigkeit in Abgrenzung von kurzfristigen, situativen Handlungsbedingungen der Tagespolitik. Jänicke geht davon aus, dass moderne Gesellschaften ein großes Potenzial zur Steigerung ihrer umweltbezogenen Problemlösefähigkeit besitzen, auch wenn diese Fähigkeiten bislang nicht ausreichen, um zentrale Umweltprobleme dauerhaft zu lösen. Die Kapazitätsentwicklung stellt somit eine strategische Aufgabe der Umweltpolitik dar. Während Jänicke den Kapazitätsbegriff auf das politische System anwendet, geht es in der vorliegenden Arbeit um das Wissenschaftssystem und um die Innovationsfähigkeit in Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft. STI-Kapazität ist die Fähigkeit einer Gesellschaft, Wissen und technologische Neuerungen zu schaffen und anzuwenden. Der Kapazitätsaufbau ist Teil eines umfassenden gesellschaftlichen Wandels angesichts begrenzter ökologischer Lebensgrundlagen.
Im ersten Kapitel wird der Begriff der STI-Kapazität inhaltlich präzisiert. Dabei wird die These vertreten, dass sich die langfristigen Herausforderungen für Forschung und Innovation in vier große Handlungsfelder einteilen lassen: (1.) die ökologische Modernisierung und Transformation von Industrie- und Dienstleistungssektoren, (2.) das Management von Ökosystemen und Ökosystemdiensten, (3.) die Analyse und Bewertung von Umweltrisiken, und (4.) die Anpassung der Gesellschaft an irreversible Umweltveränderungen. Diese Taxonomie dient als Gliederung für einen Literaturüberblick, der bislang getrennte Forschungsansätze verbindet und dadurch aufzeigt, wie das Forschungsgebiet einer umweltsoziologischen STI-Forschung aussehen könnte. Im Anschluss daran untersucht das zweite Kapitel die methodische Operationalisierung des Kapazitätsbegriffs.
Im zweiten Teil untersuchen wir internationale Kooperation, ein wichtiges Teilgebiet der wissenschaftlichen Kapazitätsentwicklung. Denn erstens konzentriert sich die Forschungskapazität bislang in führenden Industrieländern. Dadurch ist es - von der satellitengestützten Beobachtung abgesehen - nur begrenzt möglich, Umweltveränderungen weltweit zu erforschen. Zweitens spielen internationale Programme in der Klimaforschung eine wichtige Rolle. Die Klimaforschung ist ein beeindruckendes Beispiel für den Aufbau wissenschaftlicher Kapazität seit den 1970er Jahren. Daher dienten ihre Kooperationsprogramme in der Praxis zum Teil als Modelle für andere Umweltwissenschaften.
Das dritte Kapitel untersucht den Internationalisierungsgrad umweltwissenschaftlicher Forschung zunächst auf der Feldebene, gemessen in Kopublikationen im Science Citation Index (SCI). Zentral ist hierbei eine neue theoretische Erklärung für Unterschiede im Internationalisierungsgrad, die sich auf R. Whitleys Theorie der wissenschaftlichen Arbeitsorganisation bezieht. Anhand von vier Feldern belegen wir, dass der Internationalisierungsgrad mit inhaltlichen Merkmalen des Forschungsgegenstandes zusammenhängt. Als Merkmale der kognitiven Struktur unterscheiden wir systemisch-globale von kumulativ-globalen Umweltveränderungen.
Das vierte Kapitel vergleicht die Kooperationsprogramme IGBP und Unesco-IHP aus institutionalistischer Sicht. Das IGBP ist ein disziplinübergreifendes Netzwerk der Erdsystemforschung, während das IHP als Teil der Unesco zwischen Wissenschaft und internationaler Politik angesiedelt ist. Verglichen werden Ziele, Organisationsstrukturen, internationale Beteiligung und Entwicklungsdynamik im Zeitverlauf. Die Analyse basiert auf der Auswertung von Literatur und Dokumenten, Interviews und teilnehmender Beobachtung im Rahmen eines Forschungsaufenthalts beim IHP-Sekretariat. Aus dem Fallvergleich werden allgemeine institutionelle Faktoren abgeleitet, die den Erfolg umweltwissenschaftlicher Kooperationsprogramme beeinflussen. Außerdem werden Empfehlungen zur Weiterentwicklung des IHP formuliert und wichtige Fragen für die weitere Forschung aufgeworfen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The present work makes a contribution to environmental sociology and the sociology of science. The first part presents a new approach to the empirical investigation of the role of research, technology and innovation (STI) for sustainable development. The term STI capacity forms the core of this analysis. The second part examines international cooperation in environmental sciences. The comparative analysis of the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme (IGBP) and the International Hydrological Programme (IHP) of Unesco is a main focus of this part. These cases exemplify new organisational structures to build up global environmental knowledge - in the double sense of global environmental observation and a diffusion of environment-related knowledge worldwide. Yet such collaboration programmes have hardly been researched until now from an institutionalist perspective.
Our understanding of "capacity" refers to the model of environmental policy performance of M. Jänicke. According to this model, capacity describes the longer-term structural conditions for environmental policy actions, as opposed to situative opportunities and obstacles that are part of daily politics. Jänicke assumes that modern societies possess a great potential to increase their problem solving capabilities with regard to the environment, even if these capabilities are as yet inadequate to solve central environmental problems permanently. The development of capacity thus represents a strategic task of environmental policy. While Jänicke investigates capacity with regard to the political system, the present dissertation applies the concept to the science system and the innovative ability of industry and society. STI capacity is the ability of a society to create and apply knowledge and technological innovations. Capacity building is part of a comprehensive social transition process in view of limited planetary life support systems.
In the first chapter, the content of STI capacity is clarified. Our thesis is that the long-term challenges for research and innovation can be classified in four major task domains: (1.) the ecological modernisation and transformation of industrial and service sectors, (2.) the management of ecosystems and ecosystem services, (3.) the assessment of environmental risks, and (4.) the adaptation of society to irreversible, anthropogenic environmental changes. The taxonomy of the four task domains serves as the structure for a literature review. Linking research approaches which were separate until now, we show how STI research as a field of environmental sociology could look. Following this, the second chapter investigates the methodological operationalisation of the term capacity.
In the second part, we examine international cooperation in environmental sciences. International cooperation is an important issue for scientific capacity development. Firstly, research capabilities are as yet concentrated in the leading industrialised countries. Beyond satellite-based observation, this uneven distribution of capacity makes it difficult to track environmental changes worldwide. Secondly, international programmes play a significant role in climate research. Climate research is an impressive example for the development of research capacity since the 1970s. In view of this success story, efforts have been made to implement similar programme structures in other environmental science fields also.
The third chapter examines the frequency of international cooperation in environmental research at the field level, measured in co-publications in the Science Citation Index (SCI). We offer a new theoretical explanation for differences in the degree of internationalisation across fields with reference to Richard Whitley's theory of scientific work organisation. Based on four environmental science fields, we demonstrate that the degree of internationalisation is linked with characteristics of the research object. As characteristics of the cognitive structure we differentiate globally systemic from cumulatively global environment changes.
The fourth chapter compares the cooperation programmes IGBP and Unesco-IHP from an institutionalist perspective. IGBP is a transdisciplinary network in earth system science, while IHP as a part of Unesco is positioned between the science system and international politics. The comparison includes programme targets, organisational structures, international participation and programme evolution over time. The analysis is based on sources in the literature, internal documents, interviews and participant observation during a research stay in the IHP secretariat. Institutional factors are derived which have significance for the success of multilateral cooperation programmes in general. In addition, we formulate policy recommendations for the further development of IHP and identify relevant questions for further research.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Jappe_Diss_Druckversion.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2302060/2302063/Jappe_Diss_Druckversion.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Wissenschaftssoziologie</topic><topic>Umweltforschung</topic><topic>Politische Ökologie</topic><topic>Umweltsoziologie</topic><topic>STI-Kapazität</topic><topic>Internationale Kooperation</topic><topic>Globaler Umweltwandel</topic><topic>Institutionalistische Wissenschaftsforschung</topic><topic>Environmental sociology</topic><topic>STI capacity</topic><topic>International cooperation</topic><topic>Global environmental change</topic><topic>Institutionalist sociology of science</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-11950</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-10-22</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Jappe-Heinze, Lou Arlette. &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jappe-Heinze, L. A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Jappe-Heinze, L. A. (2007). Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<wels>Jappe-Heinze, L. A. (2007): Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Jappe-Heinze LA (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<ieee> L.A. Jappe-Heinze, &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<harvard1>Jappe-Heinze, L.A., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa>Jappe-Heinze, L. A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jappe-Heinze, L.A. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Jappe-Heinze LA (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L. A.  Jappe-Heinze, &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Jappe-Heinze LA. &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<lncs> Jappe-Heinze, L.A.: Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jappe-Heinze, Lou Arlette. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Knowledge about the spaceship Earth : a sociological perspective on capacity development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2302060</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2007-12-12T08:20:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:58:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>