<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303399</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mildred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Girndt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Rainer</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Riemann</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Die vorgelegte Arbeit untersucht die Reaktionen auf rassische und ethnische Diskriminierung (RED) in indigenen Völkern Australiens und Chiles. Das TRAM-Modell, ein struktureller Zirkumplex, der vier grundlegende Reaktionsstile unterscheidet, wird postuliert. Die im TRAM-Modell verarbeiteten Merkmalsfacetten werden durch den RDQ operationalisiert, der eine neuartige psychometrische Skala darstellt und im Untersuchungsvorhaben vier empirische Studien durchläuft: Für die Testentwicklung wurden in einem Vortest (N = 8) und einer Konstruktionsstudie (N = 101) Daten von australischen Aborigines erhoben. Aus der resultierenden Fragebogen-Endversion wurden die psychometrischen Eigenschaften des RDQ ermittelt, für die jeweils Stichproben von australischen Aborigines (N = 127) und - in einer ins Kastilische übersetzten Fragebogenversion - von chilenischen Mapuche (N = 179) rekrutiert wurden. Die Ergebnisse weisen darauf hin, dass der RDQ ein valides Messinstrument der vier postulierten Reaktionsstile auf RED darstellt. Die Reliabilitätsprüfung blieb unzureichend und wird Bestandteil weiterer Untersuchungen sein. Die Bedeutung für Forschungsergebnisse und -vorhaben in den Bereichen wahrgenommene Diskriminierung, psychologischer Stress und psychisches Wohlbefinden werden diskutiert.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The present work examines responses to racial and ethnic discrimination (RED) in indigenous peoples of Australia and Chile. The TRAM model, a structural circumplex distinguishing four basic response styles, is postulated. The characteristic facets of the model are operationalized by the RDQ, a new psychometric scale that was applied in four empirical studies in the process of this investigation: In the stage of test development, data were collected from Australian Aborigines for the pretest (N=8) and the construction study (N=101). To determine the psychometric properties of the RDQ, the resulted final version of the scale was applied to a sample of Australian Aborigines (N=127). Finally, the RDQ was translated into Castilian and applied to a sample of Chilean Mapuches (N=179). Results indicate that the RDQ allows a valid measurement of the four proposed response styles to RED. Reliability assessment remained insufficient and, thus, needs to be addressed in further investigations. Implications for research concerning perceived discrimination, psychological stress, and psychological well-being are discussed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Girndt_Responses_to_Racial.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303399/2303402/Girndt_Responses_to_Racial.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Aborigines</topic><topic>Mapuche</topic><topic>Ethnische Gruppe</topic><topic>Diskriminierung</topic><topic>Rassenvorurteil</topic><topic>Reaktion</topic><topic>Psychologische Diagnostik</topic><topic>Responses to Racial and Ethnic Discrimination Questionnaire (RDQ)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-16136</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2010-01-12</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Girndt, M. (2010): Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<bio1>Girndt M (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Girndt, M., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Girndt, M. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Girndt, &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Girndt M. &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2010.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Girndt, M. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Girndt, M. (2010). Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa>Girndt, M. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> M. Girndt, &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2010.</ieee>
<lncs> Girndt, M.: Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Girndt, Mildred. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Girndt, Mildred. &lt;em&gt;Responses to racial and ethnic discrimination : a study examining indigenous people in Australia and Chile&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2010.</mla>
<default>Girndt M (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303399</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-02-12T08:15:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>