<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303645</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:630</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Estimation of airborne transmission distance for bioaerosols emitted from two types of broiler houses</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Eichenlaub</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">There is little scientific knowledge about the emission and spread of bioaerosols from farm animal houses and their impact on the environment. The term bioaerosols comprises airborne compounds of biological origin such as viable and non-viable particles including bacteria, fungi and dust as well as other components which are attached to these dust particles. Particularly high concentrations of bioaerosols are found in broiler houses. These compounds are emitted by the ventilation system into the ambient air where they are distributed over longer or shorter distances depending on their aerodynamic and biological properties, the meteorological and orographical conditions as well as further factors such as type of the animal house, ventilation system, size of the barn and animal density, factors which considerably influence emission amounts and conditions at the source. Little is presently known how far and in which amounts these bioaerosols and their components are dispersed by way of the air in the surrounding of animal barns. This study is designed to contribute to the characterisation of the distances micro-organisms, which are typical components of bioaerosols, travel in an airborne state after being emitted from two differently designed typical broiler houses. Barn A is a free ventilated barn with a capacity of nearly 40,000 fattening places. The second barn is equipped with a forced ventilation system and holds 31,000 fattening places (barn B). Sampling of airborne micro-organisms inside and outside the barns was carried out by impingement (AGI-30 impinger with glycerine phosphate buffer solution). This sampling solution allows longer sampling times as compared to the standard impinger technique.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Die Ausbreitung von Bioaerosolen aus Nutztierställen und deren Wirkungen auf die Umwelt sind noch wenig untersucht. Unter diesen Bioaerosolen werden luftgetragene Stoffe biologischen Ursprungs verstanden, zu denen belebte und unbelebte Partikel wie Bakterien, Pilze und Staub sowie weitere Stoffe, die in den Staubpartikeln vorhanden sind, zählen. Besonders hohe Konzentrationen an Bioaerosolen werden in Masthühnerställen gefunden. Diese gelangen mit der Abluft in die Stallumgebung, wo sie sich in Abhängigkeit von ihren aerodynamischen und biologischen Eigenschaften, den meteorologischen Bedingungen und den orographischen Gegebenheiten sowie weiteren Faktoren (Stalltyp, Ventilationssystem, Stallgröße, Besatzdichte), welche wesentlich die Quellbedingungen für die Emissionen beeinflussen, ausbreiten. Unklar ist, wie weit sich diese Bioaerosole oder Anteile von ihnen in welchen Mengen von einer Stallanlage ausbreiten. Die vorliegende Arbeit soll einen Beitrag zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von in diesen Bioaerosolen enthaltenen luftgetragenen Mikroorganismen aus zwei typischen Masthühnerställen leisten. Dazu wurden in und an einem frei gelüfteten Stall mit knapp 40.000 Mastplätzen (Stall A) und an einem zwangsbelüfteten Stall mit ca. 31.000 Mastplätzen (Stall B) Luftkeimmessungen durchgeführt. Als Messverfahren wurden AGI-30 Impinger mit einer Glycerin-Phosphatpuffermischung eingesetzt, wodurch die Sammelzeiten gegenüber dem Standard-Inpinger-Verfahren deutlich verlängert werden konnten.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Diss._J._Schulz_Veroeffentlichung.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303645/2303648/Diss._J._Schulz_Veroeffentlichung.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>, Bioaerosole , Keimemission , Ausbreitung , Masthühnerställe , Staphylokokken , AGI-30-Impinger , Bioaerosols , Emission , Airborne bacterial transmission , Broiler houses , Staphylococci</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-12877</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2008-04-24</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Schulz J. &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<lncs> Schulz, J.: Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulz, Jochen. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulz, J. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Schulz J (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Schulz, &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> J. Schulz, &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schulz, J., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa>Schulz, J. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<wels>Schulz, J. (2007): Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Schulz, Jochen. &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<frontiers>Schulz, J. (2007). Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulz, J. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Zur Charakterisierung der Ausbreitungsentfernung von Bioaerosolen aus Masthühnerställen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Schulz J (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303645</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2008-05-05T08:40:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:55:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>