<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303776</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susanne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brummelte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Gertraud</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Teuchert-Noodt</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Die postnatale Entwicklung ist wahrscheinlich die wichtigste Phase während des Reifungsprozesses eines jeden Lebewesens. Äußere Verhältnisse und Einflüsse wirken auf die anfängliche Verschaltung des Nervensystems ein und tragen so zur Bildung von kognitiven Fähigkeiten und Verhaltensweisen bei. Störungen während dieser entscheidenden Zeit können schädliche Effekte auf das ganze System haben, da sie zu Modifizierungen in den Nervennetzen oder sogar zur Bildung von neurologischen Krankheiten führen können.
Unsere Arbeitsgruppe hat ein Tiermodell einer frühkindlichen Schädigung entwickelt, das aus einem 2-Stufen-Modell besteht mit reizarmen Aufzuchtsbedingungen einerseits und einer einzelnen frühen Methamphetamin-Intoxikation (MA) am postnatalen Tag (PD) 14 andererseits. Vorherige Arbeiten konnten bereits zeigen, dass dieses Modell schwerwiegende und komplizierte Veränderungen in verschiedenen Transmittersystemen und Gebieten verursacht und sogar einige Befunde von schizophrenen Patienten widerspiegelt.
Die gegenwärtige Arbeit wurde durchgeführt, um weitere Aspekte bezüglich dieses potenziellen Tiermodells zur Psychose zu klären.
- Erstens: Beruhen diese Veränderungen ausschließlich auf den unausgereiften Nervennetzen während der Entwicklung, oder kann eine MA-Intoxikation im Erwachsenenalter ähnliche Modifizierungen, besonders im dopaminergen System, verursachen?
- Die zweite Frage betrifft die unterschiedliche Betroffenheit verschiedener limbischer Gebiete nach der frühen Störung, und ob die möglicherweise unterschiedlichen Entwicklungsmuster der Areale dabei eine Rolle spielen könnten.
- Schließlich interessierte ich mich für den Beitrag des GABAergen Systems zu den reaktiven oder kompensatorischen Mechanismen innerhalb der gestörten Nervennetze.
Um diese Fragen zu klären, haben wir zunächst eine vergleichbare Dosis von MA erwachsenen Rennmäusen verabreicht, um die langfristigen Effekte auf das dopaminerge System zu untersuchen. Im Gegensatz zu der frühen Intoxikation zeigte sich jedoch nur ein leichter Faserüberschuss im Nucleus accumbens shell (Brummelte et al., 2006a).
Daraufhin untersuchten wir die postnatale Entwicklung von dopaminergen und GABAergen Fasern in einer Langzeitstudie im präfrontalen Kortex (PFC), in der Amygdala und im entorhinalen Kortex (EC) vom PD 14 bis zum hohen Alter (PD720), um potenziell unterschiedliche Reifungsmuster oder alterungsbedingte Veränderungen der entsprechenden Gebiete und ihrer Transmittersysteme aufzuzeigen. Die Ergebnisse zeigen, dass diese verschiedenen Muster tatsächlich zur beobachteten Unausgewogenheit innerhalb der Nervennetze beitragen könnten und dass nur die dopaminerge Faserdichte im PFC von Alterungsprozessen betroffen ist. (Brummelte and Teuchert-Noodt 2006; Brummelte et al. akzeptiert, Brummelte and Teuchert-Noodt, eingereicht).
Um schließlich den Einfluss des GABAergen Systems bei den Umorganisationen nach den frühen Störungen zu beurteilen, untersuchten wir einerseits GABAerge Fasern und andererseits GABAerge "Boutons" an nicht angefärbten pyramidalen Zellkörpern im PFC und konnten zeigen, dass die GABAerge Inhibition anscheinend eine Verschiebung von einer starken somatischen Hemmung zu einer eher mäßigen dendritischen Hemmung der pyramidalen Neuronen erlebt, wodurch die Synchronisation ganzer pyramidaler Populationen verringert sein könnte (Brummelte et al., 2007).
Daher bestätigen diese neuen Ergebnisse weiter unsere Hypothese, dass viele Transmittersysteme eine hohe neuronale Plastizität aufweisen, und dies teilweise sogar im Erwachsenenalter. Weiterhin unterstreicht unser Ansatz einer frühkindlichen systemischen Störung die hohe Interdependenz der verschiedenen Transmittersysteme, da er zu vielen komplizierten Veränderungen in den neuroanatomischen Netzwerken führt, die wiederum zum Teil einigen beobachteten Veränderungen und Defiziten von schizophrenen Personen ähneln.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The postnatal development is probably the most important phase during the maturation process of a living creature. External circumstances and influences will stamp the initial wiring of the nervous system and therefore contribute to the establishment of cognitive functions and behavioral repertoires. Disturbances during this crucial time can have deleterious effects on the whole system and can lead to alterations in the neural networks and even to the formation of neurological diseases.
Our group has established an animal model of an early systemic challenge during development using a 2-step approach of impoverished rearing (IR) conditions and a pharmacological intoxication with methamphetamine (MA) on postnatal day (PD) 14. Previous work already revealed that this model induces severe and complex alterations in various transmitter systems and areas and even reflects some findings from schizophrenic patients.
The current work was conducted to clarify some further points concerning this potential animal model of psychosis.
- First, are these changes totally due to the immature networks during development or can an adult challenge with MA cause similar alterations, particularly in the dopaminergic system?
- The second question concerns the variations between the areas after an early challenge and if their developmental patterns might play a role in mediating this effect.
- Finally, I was interested in the contribution of the GABAergic system to the reactive or compensative mechanisms within the disturbed neural networks.
To address these questions we applied a comparable dose of MA to adult gerbils as a start and investigated the long-term effects on the dopaminergic system, which appeared to be quite different from the early challenge, with only a slight oversprouting of fibers in the nucleus accumbens shell (Brummelte et al., 2006a).
Further, we investigated the postnatal development of dopaminergic and GABAergic fibers in a long-term study in the prefrontal cortex (PFC), amygdala and entorhinal cortex (EC) from PD 14 until high age (PD720) to account for potential varying maturation patterns or ageing-sensibility of these areas or transmitter systems. We found that the different patterns might indeed contribute to the observed imbalance within the neural networks and that only the prefrontal dopaminergic fiber density is revealing ageing-related alterations (Brummelte and Teuchert-Noodt, 2006; Brummelte et al., accepted; Brummelte and Teuchert-Noodt, submitted).
To eventually estimate the participation of the GABAergic system in the rearrangements after the early disturbances, we quantified GABAergic fibers as well as boutons around pyramidal somata in the PFC and revealed that GABA is apparently undergoing a shift from strong somatic inhibition to more moderate dendritic inhibition of pyramidal neurons and therewith derogating the synchronization of whole pyramidal populations (Brummelte et al., 2007).
Thus, our results further strengthen our hypothesis that all transmitter systems show a high neuronal plasticity, partially even in adulthood and that our approach of an early systemic stress leads to several severe and complex alterations in the neuroanatomical networks, which underlines the high interdependency of the various transmitter systems and might resemble some of the changes and deficits seen in schizophrenic individuals.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_Susanne_Brummelte.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303776/2303779/Dissertation_Susanne_Brummelte.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Dopamin , Dopaminagonist , Aminobuttersäure (gamma-) , Neuronale Plastizität , Metamfetamin , Schizophrenie , Postnatale Entwicklung , Altern ,  ,</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-10426</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-02-06</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Brummelte, S.: Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus). Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brummelte, Susanne. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Brummelte, Susanne. &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<default>Brummelte S (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<wels>Brummelte, S. (2007): Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus). Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<harvard1>Brummelte, S., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<bio1>Brummelte S (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brummelte, S. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Brummelte, &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Brummelte S. &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<frontiers>Brummelte, S. (2007). Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus). Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brummelte, S. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Brummelte, S. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> S. Brummelte, &lt;em&gt;Age-dependent and reactive changes in dopaminergic and GABAergic structures in the prefrontal-limbic system of the gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus)&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303776</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2007-02-09T13:03:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:56:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>