<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303810</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Bischof</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Das neurale Zellerkennungsmolekül L1 ist ein Mitglied der Immunglobulin-Superfamilie und der Gründer der L1 Unterfamilie. Es führt wichtige Funktionen im sich entwickelnden und im adulten Nervensystem aus. Dieser Standpunkt wird bekräftigt durch die Tatsache, dass Mutationen im humanen L1 Gen eine schwere neurologische Krankheit verursachen, die CRASH genannt wird (ein Akronym für corpus callosum hypoplasia, retardation, adducted thumbs, spastic paraplegia, and hydrocephalus). X-Chromosom-gebundener Hydrocephalus ist sicherlich das markanteste Symptom des CRASH-Syndroms. Maus-Mutanten, denen das L1 Gen fehlt, entwickeln ebenfalls erweiterte Ventrikel. Diese Studie zeigt, dass erweiterte Ventrikel in L1-defizienten Mäusen weder mit einer Stenose des Aquaeductus Sylvius, noch mit ultrastrukturellen Abnormalitäten von Ependymalzellen entlang der lateralen Ventrikel und des Aquaeductes einhergehen. Dennoch wiesen einige L1-Maus-Mutanten einen schwerwiegenden Hydrocephalus auf, charakterisiert durch eine signifikante Vergrößerung des Schädels und fast vollständige Atrophie des cerebralen Cortex. Der Aquaeduct dieser stark betroffenen Tiere war vollständig verschlossen. Da mutierte Tiere aus zwei unabhängig voneinander hergestellten L1-defizienten Maus-Linien ähnliche Phänotypen aufweisen, wird die schwere Form des Hydrocephalus als eine spezifische Folge der L1-Defizienz angesehen.
Ein weiteres Mitglied der L1-Familie von Zellerkennungsmolekülen ist das "close homologue of L1" (CHL1). Dieses Protein wird von einer Vielzahl von Nervenzellen und Subpopulationen von Gliazellen in vivo expremiert und fördert Neuritenwachstum und das Überleben von Nervenzellen in vitro. Hier wird gezeigt, dass Gliazellen die Expression von CHL1 hochregulieren können als Folge einer intraorbitalen Quetschung des adulten optischen Nerven.
Die Funktionen eines dritten Mitgliedes der Ig-Superfamilie, das neurale Zelladhäsionsmolekül (NCAM), wurden ebenfalls untersucht. Es wird in Verbindung gebracht mit Zellmigration, Myelinisierung, synaptischer Plastizität und Verlängerung, Faszikulierung und Wegfindung von Axonen. In dieser Studie, werden NCAM-defiziente Mäuse verwendet, um die Funktion von NCAM während der Entwicklung des corticospinalen Traktes zu untersuchen. Es konnte eine schwere Hypoplasie des corticospinalen Traktes in adulten NCAM-defizienten Mäusen nachgewiesen werden. Anterogrades Tracen des Traktes von früh postnatalen NCAM-Mutanten zeigten ausgeprägte Wegfindungsfehler corticospinaler Axone.
Zusammengefasst weisen die Ergebnisse dieser Arbeit auf die Bedeutung von L1 und NCAM für die normale Entwicklung des Nervensystems hin. Sie deuten auch eine wichtige Funktion von CHL1 im lädierten zentralen Nervensystem an.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The neural adhesion molecule L1 is a member of the immunoglobulin superfamily and the founder of the L1 subfamily of cell recognition molecules. It performs important functions in the developing and adult nervous system. This view is confirmed by the fact that mutations in the human L1 gene cause a severe neurological disease, termed CRASH (acronym for: corpus callosum hypoplasia, retardation, adducted thumbs, spastic paraplegia, and hydrocephalus). X-linked hydrocephalus is certainly the most prominent symptom of CRASH syndrome. Mouse mutants deficient in L1 also develop enlarged ventricles. This study demonstrates that ventricular dilation in L1-deficient mice is not correlated with stenosis of the aqueduct of Sylvius nor with ultrastructural abnormalities of ependymal cells lining the lateral ventricles or the aqueduct. However, a few L1 mutant mice displayed severe hydrocephalus, characterized by a significant enlargement of the skull and an almost complete atrophy of the cerebral cortex. The aqueduct of these severely affected animals was completely closed. Since mutant animals from two independently generated L1-deficient mouse lines displayed a similar phenotype, severe hydrocephalus is considered as a specific consequence of L1-deficiency.
Another member of the L1 family of cell recognition molecules is the close homologue of L1 (CHL1). This protein is expressed by a variety of nerve cell types and subpopulations of glial cells in vivo and promotes elongation of neurites and survival of nerve cells in vitro. This study demonstrates that glial cells up-regulate expression of CHL1 in response to an intraorbital crush of the adult mouse optic nerve.
The functions of a third member of the Ig superfamily, the neural cell adhesion molecule (NCAM), were also investigated. NCAM is implicated in cell migration, myelination, synaptic plasticity, and elongation, fasciculation and pathfinding of axons. In the present study, NCAM-deficient mice were used to investigate the role of NCAM in the development of the corticospinal tract. A severe hypoplasia of the corticospinal tract in adult NCAM mutants is demonstrated. Anterograde tracing of the tract of early postnatal NCAM mutants revealed pronounced pathfinding errors of corticospinal axons.
Together the findings of this study demonstrate the importance of L1 and NCAM for the normal development of the nervous system. They also suggest a critical role for CHL1 in the lesioned central nervous system.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="0081.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303810/2303813/0081.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Neurales Zell-Adhäsionsmolekül , Funktionsanalyse ,  , Cell adhesion , Hydrocephalus , Regeneration , Pathfinding</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-2064</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2002-07-10</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Rolf, B. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<lncs> Rolf, B.: Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rolf, Bettina. 2002. &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> B. Rolf, &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</ieee>
<harvard1>Rolf, B., 2002. &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ama>Rolf B. &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2002.</ama>
<default>Rolf B (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<bio1>Rolf B (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Rolf, &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Rolf, B. (2002): Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Rolf, Bettina. &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rolf, B. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Rolf, B. (2002). Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rolf, B. (2002). &lt;em&gt;Functional analysis of the cell adhesion molecules L1, CHL1 and NCAM in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303810</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-05-26T14:05:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:56:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>