<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303996</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bishnu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Simkhada</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Traunspurger</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685511</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Kieselalgen wurden in verschiedenen Mikrohabitaten von Hochgebirgsseen in der Region von Gosainkunda, Langtang National Park, in Teichen und kleinen Seen des Kathmandu Tales im mittleren Bergland, und in Teichen der Region von Koshi Tappu im nepalesischen Tiefland untersucht.
Temperatur, Leitfähigkeit und pH wurden vor Ort gemessen und Wasserproben für die chemische Analyse von Kationen und Anionen entnommen. In Gosainkunda und im Kathmandu Tal wurden Proben des Oberflächenwassers, und in Koshi Tappu wurden Proben des Oberflächen- und des Interstitialwassers genommen. Gleichzeitig wurde eine Untersuchung des Habitatcharakters der Seen und Teiche bezüglich der Substratbeschaffenheit und der Gewässervegetation sowie der Uferregion bezüglich der Substratzusammensetzung, des Uferprofils, der terrestrischen Vegetation und der Landnutzung in unmittelbarer Umgebung durchgeführt.
Die Kieselalgengemeinschaften der verschiedenen Mikrohabitate in Teichen und Seen aus drei Regionen Nepals unterschiedlichen Charakters sind gute Indikatoren für Umweltveränderungen als Folge von landwirtschaftlicher Intensivierung, Industrialisierung und Verstädterung. Dieser Wandel wird sich in Zukunft beschleunigen mit zunehmender Beanspruchung von Wasserressourcen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Diatoms were collected from different microhabitats in high altitude lakes of Gosainkunda, Langtang National Park, in ponds and small lakes of the Kathmandu Valley in the Middle Hills, and in lowland ponds of Koshi Tappu, Nepal.
Temperature, conductivity and pH were measured at the same time and water samples taken for the analysis of major cations and anions. Water samples were taken from the surface water in Gosainkunda and the Kathmandu Valley sites, and from the surface and the interstitial water in Koshi Tappu. Habitat surveys were also conducted to assess the character of the lakes and ponds with respect to substrate types and aquatic vegetation, of the banks with respect to substrate types, bank profile and vegetation, and to assess land use in the immediate catchments.
Studies of benthic diatoms from a range of microhabitats in ponds and lakes in the three eco-regions of Nepal have revealed that diatoms are sensitive indicators of environmental change resulting from the intensification of agriculture, industrialisation and urbanisation. These changes are likely to accelerate with increasing pressure on water resources.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PhD_THESIS_BISHNU.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303996/2303999/PhD_THESIS_BISHNU.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Nepal , Stehendes Gewässer , Kieselalgen , Umweltindikator ,  , Diatoms , Nepal , Lakes , Ponds , Indicators</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-9338</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2006-07-02</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> B. Simkhada, &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2006.</ieee>
<apa>Simkhada, B. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Simkhada, B. (2006). &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Simkhada, B. (2006). Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<ama>Simkhada B. &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2006.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Simkhada, &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Simkhada, B., 2006. &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<bio1>Simkhada B (2006) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Simkhada, B. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Simkhada, B. (2006): Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Simkhada B (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Simkhada, Bishnu. &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2006.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Simkhada, Bishnu. 2006. &lt;em&gt;Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Simkhada, B.: Diatoms as indicators of environmental change in lakes and ponds of the lowlands, Middle Hills and High Himalaya of Nepal. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2006).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303996</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2006-09-05T13:20:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:36:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>