<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303415</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tickenbrock</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Jörg-Walter</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Bartsch</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The main topic of this thesis is the tumor suppressor protein APC (Adenomatous Polyposis Coli) and its many different functions. Only little is known about the structural architecture of the 2843 amino acids APC protein. A stable and trypsin-resistent domain close to the N-terminal end, termed APC129-250, could be identified. The crystal structure of APC129-250 could be solved. The domain is monomeric and consists of three [alpha]-helices forming two separate anti-parallel coiled coils. APC129-250 includes the nuclear export signal NES(165-174) at the C-terminal end of the first helix. Interestingly, the conserved hydrophobic amino acids of NES(165-174), which are necessary for the nuclear export activity, are buried in one of the coiled coils. Therefore these residues are not freely accessible for interaction partners. Nevertheless, APC129-250 is able to directly interact with the nuclear export factor Crm1. This interaction is even enhanced by the small GTPase Ran in its activated GTP-bound form and also by a double mutation in APC129-250, which deletes two amino acids forming two of the major hydrophobic interactions within the coiled coil. These results hint to a regulatory mechanism of the APC nuclear export activity by NES masking.
The most important interaction partner of the APC protein is the proto-oncoprotein [beta]-Catenin. Together with other proteins of the Wnt-signaling pathway, APC regulates the intracellular concentration and localization of the [beta]-Catenin protein. Several repetitive motifs within the APC sequence are necessary for this interaction, at least three homologous stretches of 15 amino acids and seven homologous stretches of 20 amino acids. Biophysical measurements show that the third recombinantly expressed non-phosphorylated 20-amino acid repeat of the APC protein is able to bind to [beta]-Catenin in vitro. Surprisingly, phosphorylation is not necessary for the binding itself. Nevertheless, phosphorylation of conserved serines within the repetitive motifs, which was simulated by site-directed mutagenesis of serines to aspartates, increases the affinity of the APC protein to [beta]-Catenin significantly. Though the functional interaction between APC and [beta]-Catenin has been characterized on the cellular level in detail, the stoichiometric relation of this binding is still not known. Biochemical data of this study indicate a 1:1 binding stoichiometry between [beta]-Catenin and the homologous motifs within the APC sequence. The 20-amino acid repeats have similar binding affinities and do not influence each other in their binding to [beta]-Catenin.
Altogether this study answers several important questions around the APC protein and its interaction partners by biophysical and biochemical experiments.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Der Verlust des Tumorsuppressor-Gens APC (Adenomatöse Polyposis Coli) ist ein entscheidendes Ereignis in der Entstehung und Progression eines Darmtumors. Liegt in Darmepithelzellen nur verkürztes APC-Protein vor, kann dieses Tumorsuppressor-Protein seine antiproliferative und tumorsuppressive Aufgabe nicht mehr erfüllen.
In dieser Arbeit konnte die Struktur einer funktionellen Domäne des APC-Proteins gelöst werden. Hierbei handelt sich um das stabile tryptische Proteinfragment APC129-250, in dem ein nukleäres Export Signal (NES) lokalisiert ist. Die APC129-250 Struktur besteht aus drei [alpha]-Helices, die wiederum in zwei Coiled coil Regionen angeordnet sind. Interessanterweise sind die hydrophoben konservierten Aminosäurereste der NES(165-174)-Sequenz, die notwendig für die Exportaktivität sind, in einer der Coiled coil Regionen vergraben. Mit Hilfe von in vitro Präzipitations-Experimenten wurde die direkte Interaktion von APC129-250 mit Crm1 nachgewiesen. Die Interaktion wird durch die Zugabe von aktivem RanGTP und außerdem durch den Austausch zweier Leucinreste, die verantwortlich für die hydrophoben Wechselwirkungen der Coiled coil sind, verstärkt. Dies weist für die Bindung von APC129-250 und Crm1 auf einen Demaskierungsmechanismus hin. So wird die Interaktion durch Auflösung der Coiled coil Struktur verbessert, wodurch die konservierten Reste des NES(165-174)-Motivs frei zugänglich werden.
Im zweiten Teil der Arbeit wurde die Interaktion von APC mit dem Proto-Onkoprotein [beta]-Catenin untersucht. Entscheidend für diese Bindung sind repetitive homologe Sequenzmotive in der APC-Sequenz: mindestens drei Motive von 15 Aminosäuren und sieben Motive von 20 Aminosäuren. Es wurde festgestellt, dass unphosphorylierte, rekombinant exprimierte 20-Aminosäure-Repetitionen des APC-Proteins an [beta]-Catenin binden können. Außerdem konnte die lange unklare Frage der Stöchiometrie bezüglich dieser APC-Repetitionen und [beta]-Catenin gelöst werden. Eine 20-Aminosäure-Repetition kann ein [beta]-Catenin binden, während zwei Repetitionen zwei [beta]-Catenine binden können. Des weiteren konnte die Bedeutung der Phosphorylierung für diese Bindung gezeigt werden. Dafür wurden die Phosphorylierungen durch Phospho-Serin-Simulierung in einem 20-Aminosäure-Bindungsmotiv des APC-Proteins auf die Bindung an [beta]-Catenin untersucht. Dabei konnte eine 20-fach stärkere Bindung der beiden Interaktionspartner beobachtet werden.
Zusammengefasst konnten in dieser Arbeit zahlreiche wichtige Fragen rund um das APC-Protein und seinen Interaktionspartnern in biochemischen und biophysikalischen Experimenten gelöst werden.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="0091.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303415/2303418/0091.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>, APC (Adenomatöse Polyposis Coli) , [beta]-Catenin , NES (Nukleäres Export Signal) , Wnt-Signalweg ,</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-2099</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2002-11-07</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Tickenbrock, Lara. &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</mla>
<default>Tickenbrock L (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<lncs> Tickenbrock, L.: Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tickenbrock, Lara. 2002. &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Tickenbrock, L. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> L. Tickenbrock, &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</ieee>
<ama>Tickenbrock L. &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2002.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tickenbrock, L. (2002). &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Tickenbrock, L. (2002). Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tickenbrock, L. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Tickenbrock L (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Tickenbrock, L., 2002. &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Tickenbrock, &lt;em&gt;Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Tickenbrock, L. (2002): Das Tumorsuppressor-Protein APC : strukturelle und biochemische Aspekte. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303415</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-05-28T08:50:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:53:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>