<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303687</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:430</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lüngen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Dafydd</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Gibbon</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015421</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Die Dissertation entwirft eine zeichenbasierte Theorie der Morphologie des Deutschen. Die allgemeine Strategie ist, die existierenden, zum Teil widersprüchlichen Ansätze zum Lexikon in der Head-Driven Phrase Structure Grammar einerseits und zur Morphologie andererseits kritisch zu evaluieren und die Ergebnisse im Rahmen der HPSG kompatibel zu machen. Hierzu werden die benötigten Merkmalsdeklarationen, Typenhierarchien, Prinzipien und Schemata hergeleitet. Es wird argumentiert, dass ein Morphologisches Kopfmerkmalsprinzip für Derivation und Komposition im Deutschen gilt. In der Flektion hingegen werden die syntaktischen Kopfmerkmale durch ein neu eingeführtes Flektionsmarkierungsprinzip kombiniert. Weiterhin werden ein morphologisches Subkategorisierungsprinzip, die Hierarchie lexikalischer Typen und Kontinuationsschemata entwickelt, wobei Lösungen für spezielle Probleme wie die Hierarchie von Ablautklassen in der Flektion und den morphologisch bedingten Umlaut entwickelt werden. Die wichtigsten Teile der Theorie wurden als eine Definite Clause Grammar kodiert, ein morphologischer Parser und Klassifizierer wurde in Prolog implementiert und anhand der Verbmobil-Lexikondatenbank evaluiert.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The dissertation presents a sign-based theory of the morphology of German. The general strategy is to evaluate the existing controversial literature on the lexicon in Head-Driven Phrase Structure Grammar on the one hand and on morphology on the other hand, and to make the results compatible by formulating the necessary feature declarations, type hierarchies, principles and schemata in HPSG. It is argued that a Morphological Head Feature Principle holds for morphological and syntactic head features in German derivation and compounding. In inflection, though, syntactic head features are combined via a newly introduced Inflectional Marking Principle. Furthermore, a morphological subcategorisation principle, the hierarchy of lexical types, and continuation schemata for morphology are established, with solutions for specific problems such as ablaut classes in inflection and umlaut in derivation and inflection. Substantial parts of the theory have been encoded as a Definite Clause grammar, and a morphological parser and classifier has been implemented in Prolog and evaluated on the Verbmobil lexical database.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="luengen.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303687/2303690/luengen.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Deutsch</topic><topic>Generative Grammatik</topic><topic>Morphologie (Linguistik)</topic><topic>Head-driven phrase structure grammar</topic><topic>Lexikologie</topic><topic>Morphologie</topic><topic>Deutsch</topic><topic>HPSG</topic><topic>Lexikon</topic><topic>Morphology</topic><topic>German</topic><topic>Head-driven phrase structure grammar</topic><topic>Lexicon</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-4215</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2002-10-25</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Lüngen, Harald. &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</mla>
<default>Lüngen H (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<lncs> Lüngen, H.: A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lüngen, Harald. 2002. &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Lüngen, H. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> H. Lüngen, &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2002.</ieee>
<ama>Lüngen H. &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2002.</ama>
<frontiers>Lüngen, H. (2002). A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lüngen, H. (2002). &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lüngen, H. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Lüngen H (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Lüngen, H., 2002. &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Lüngen, &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Lüngen, H. (2002): A hierarchical model of German morphology in a spoken language lexicon environment. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303687</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2004-01-19T09:42:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>