<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2303530</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nahid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Khoshraftar Yazdi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Elke</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Zimmermann</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10027</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Patellofemoral pain syndrome (PFPS) is a term for a variety of pathologies or anatomical abnormalities leading to a type of anterior knee pain and is the most common single diagnosis among runners and in sport medicine centers. Despite this high incidence, the exact cause of these disorders remains enigmatic.
The major complain of patients with PFPS is retropatellar pain during activities such as running, squatting, going up and down stairs, prolonged sitting, cycling, and jumping.
Some of risk factors in athletes with PFPS were considered and compared with athletes without PFPS in the present study. In addition, since Tai Chi (TC) helps or reduces the load on the lower limbs joints, particularly in knee, a TC group was chosen to compare with the two other groups.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Tesis_2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2303530/2303533/Tesis_2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Kniescheibe</topic><topic>Chondropathia patellae</topic><topic>Patella</topic><topic>Patellofemoral pain syndrome (PFPS)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-17272</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2010-07-11</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Khoshraftar Yazdi, N. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> N. Khoshraftar Yazdi, &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2010.</ieee>
<ama>Khoshraftar Yazdi N. &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2010.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Khoshraftar Yazdi, N. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Khoshraftar Yazdi, N. (2010). Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<bio1>Khoshraftar Yazdi N (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Khoshraftar Yazdi, N., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Khoshraftar Yazdi, N. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Khoshraftar Yazdi, &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Khoshraftar Yazdi, N. (2010): Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Khoshraftar Yazdi, Nahid. &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2010.</mla>
<default>Khoshraftar Yazdi N (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<lncs> Khoshraftar Yazdi, N.: Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Khoshraftar Yazdi, Nahid. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Comparison of electrical activity of lateral and medial stabilizers of the patella and further diagnostically relevant risk factors in athletes with and without patellofemoral pain and in a Tai Chi group&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2303530</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-07-14T14:46:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>