<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2304651</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Model studies on the function of acidic matrix proteins in biomineralization</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fricke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Volkmer</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17964</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this work model studies on the oriented growth of CaCO3 at biomimetic interfaces were performed. The primary structure of acidic proteins which control the texture of biogenic CaCO3 were mimicked with oligoacids based on calixarenes, resorcarenes and peptides. Crystallization studies underneath Langmuir monolayers have shown that macrocyclic oligoacids act as templates for CaCO3 crystal growth. Systematic structural variations of various organic matrices and investigations on the influence of these on the growth of CaCO3 have shown that the average charge density of the organic template is the dominant factor which fixes the selection of the CaCO3 polymorphs and the growth direction of the inorganic constituents. Crystallization of CaCO3 in the presence of acidic oligopeptides yield truncated calcite rhombohedra with specifically inhibited crystal faces which has been reported before exclusively for natural acidic proteins. Since conformationally flexible peptides stabilize two energetically different crystal faces, the results point to the influence of electrostatic effects. Therefore, an epitaxial correlation is ruled out for all presented examples.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Im Mittelpunkt der Arbeit stehen Modellstudien zum gerichteten Wachstum von CaCO3 an biomimetisch strukturierten Grenzflächen. Die Primärstruktur saurer Proteine, die die Textur biogener Kristallphasen von CaCO3 steuern, wurde mit Oligosäuren auf Basis von Calixarenen, Resorcarenen und Peptiden imitiert. Die Ergebnisse der Kristallisationsstudien unter Langmuir-Monoschichten haben gezeigt, dass die makrozyklischen Oligosäuren eine Templatwirkung auf das Wachstum von CaCO3 ausüben. Über das Moleküldesign wurden die molekularen Eigenschaften so angepasst, dass der Einfluss der Molekülgröße, der Koordinationsgeometrie und der Ladungsträgerdichte auf die Templat-induzierte Kristallisation von CaCO3 bestimmt werden konnte. Die mittlere Ladungsträgerdichte in der Monoschicht kontrolliert sowohl das orientierte Kristallwachstum von CaCO3 als auch die Polymorphselektion. In Gegenwart saurer Oligopeptide führte die Kristallisation von CaCO3 zu trunkierten Calcitrhomboedern mit spezifisch inhibierten Kristallflächen, die zuvor ausschließlich von natürlichen Proteinen induziert wurden. Da zwei energetisch unterschiedliche Kristallflächen von konformativ flexiblen Peptiden stabilisiert wurden, deuten die Ergebnisse erneut auf den Einfluss ungerichteter elektrostatischer Effekte hin. Eine epitaktische Beziehung wurde daher für alle vorgestellten Beispiele ausgeschlossen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_Marc_Fricke.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2304651/2304654/Dissertation_Marc_Fricke.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Biomineralisation , Calciumcarbonat , Amphiphile Verbindungen , Modellverbindung , Matrixproteine , Calixarene , Peptide , Monoschichten , Kristall-Engineering , Calciumcarbonat , Biomineralisation , Supramolekulare Chemie , Calixarenes , Peptides , Monolayers , Crystal engineering , Calcium carbonate , Biomineralization</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-5828</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2004-05-13</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Fricke, M. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> M. Fricke, &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2004.</ieee>
<ama>Fricke M. &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2004.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fricke, M. (2004). &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Fricke, M. (2004). Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<bio1>Fricke M (2004) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Fricke, M., 2004. &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fricke, M. (2004).  &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Fricke, &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Fricke, M. (2004): Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<mla>Fricke, Marc. &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2004.</mla>
<default>Fricke M (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<lncs> Fricke, M.: Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2004).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fricke, Marc. 2004. &lt;em&gt;Modellstudien zur Funktion saurer Matrixproteine in der Biomineralisation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2304651</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2004-10-27T08:22:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:39:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>