<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2304239</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koesling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">In einer Serie korrelierter Experimente mit ansteigender Komplexität wurde die visuelle Wahrnehmung und Beurteilung fundamentaler Objekteigenschaften in verschiedenen Vergleichsszenarien untersucht. Unter Berücksichtigung von Objektähnlichkeit und raum-zeitlichen Objektrelationen stand dabei die Betrachtung der Einflüsse von peripherer Objektposition und der Länge und Orientierung von Liniensegmenten auf sequentielle und simultane Vergleichsprozesse im Mittelpunkt. Die Analyse von Blickbewegungsdaten gab Aufschluss über die perzeptiven und kognitiven Prozesse, die derartige Vergleichsoperationen steuern. Die Ergebnisse der empirischen Untersuchungen bildeten die Grundlage für die entsprechende Implementierung computergestützter Modellsimulationen. Diese können dann etwa zur Steuerung von künstlichen visuellen Systemen eingesetzt werden.
Zunächst wurden Exzentrizitätseffekte im Rahmen des Paradigmas eines blick-kontingenten, sequentiellen Vergleichsszenarios untersucht. In einem ersten Experiment sollten Versuchspersonen die Position eines Zielmarkers in einem bestimmten Exzentrizitätsbereich beurteilen. In ähnlichen Szenarien wurde die periphere Wahrnehmung der Länge und Orientierung von Liniensegmenten untersucht. Die Ergebnisse zeigten eine hohe Korrelation zwischen dem Beurteilungsfehler der peripher wahrgenommenen Längen bzw. Orientierungen von Liniensegmenten und der Fehllokalisation der Markerposition. Die empirischen Daten gaben Anlass zu der Hypothese, dass die Lokalisation der Endpunkte eines Liniensegments und die "Berechnung" ihrer Distanz einen grundlegenden Mechanismus für die periphere Längen- und Orientierungswahrnehmung darstellen. Ein auf dieser Annahme basierender probabilistischer Modellansatz konnte die empirischen Ergebnisse zumindest für die Längenbeurteilung erfolgreich reproduzieren und unterstützt damit den Schluss auf die vermutlich zugrunde liegenden Wahrnehmungsprinzipien.
Anschließend wurden Ähnlichkeitseffekte im Rahmen des Paradigmas eines simultanen Vergleichsszenarios untersucht. Dabei lieferte eine Eyetracker-Apparatur die relevanten Blickbewegungsparameter, um die Bedeutung visueller Aufmerksamkeitsprozesse während Objektvergleichen nachzuvollziehen. In Abhängigkeit von der Diskriminierungsschwierigkeit zeigte die Analyse der Blickbewegungsdaten entweder eine holistische oder eine analytische Verarbeitungsstrategie, die sich in typischen Blickbewegungsmustern manifestierte. Die holistische Strategie ist offensichtlich ein peripherer Prozess per se. Im Gegensatz dazu ist die analytische Wahrnehmung gekennzeichnet durch ein charakteristisches Muster fovealer visueller Aufmerksamkeit, beeinflusst von peripheren Wahrnehmungsprinzipien. So stellt ein sakkadisches "visuelles Abmessen" von Längen, verbunden mit effizienten Fixationsmustern, die nur Teile von Liniensegmenten foveal scannen und die verbleibenden offensichtlich nur peripher wahrnehmen, die Basis für die Manipulation von korrespondierenden mentalen Repräsentationen von Liniensegmenten dar. Die Ergebnisse führten weiterhin zu einem besseren Verständnis spezieller visueller Phänomene wie z.B. der Horizontalen-Vertikalen-Täuschung. So lässt sich diese vermutlich auf das ungenaue Abmessen der beteiligten Liniensegmente bereits auf sensomotorischer Ebene zurückführen. Unter Einbezug von Komponenten des "Exzentrizitätsmodells" konnte schließlich ein erweitertes Computermodell entwickelt werden. Dieses war in der Lage, die von den Versuchspersonen gezeigten Strategien der Längenwahrnehmung erfolgreich zu reproduzieren.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">One of the most common tasks in life is probably that of visual object recognition and comparison. We often have to decide, for example, which of two objects is smaller, longer or, in general, more suitable for an intended use. This task might considerably be complicated when objects are quite alike, located far apart or not being visible at the same time. The comparison process is thus not only influenced by the relevant intrinsic object attributes, but also by object similarity and the objects' spatial and temporal relations to each other.
This PhD thesis documents a comprehensive investigation of the visual assessment of typical attributes of abstract stimuli in different comparison scenarios, taking similarity and relational aspects into account as well. The analysis of data recorded in eye-tracking experiments provided insight into underlying perceptive and cognitive processes during such object comparison tasks, focussing on characteristic stimulus features such as positional eccentricity, line segment length and orientation. The empirical findings then led to the implementation of corresponding computational models that can be employed in machine-vision systems.
In principle, the focal points of the investigations that are presented here were guided by the cognitive structure of visual comparison tasks. This structure can be characterised by the following processing steps: Assessment, memorisation, comparison. The validity of two fundamental hypotheses was tested in order to explore these processes in detail.
The first hypothesis addressed the decomposition of length and orientation assessment: Can the assessment of line segment length or orientation be accomplished by assessing the locations of the end points of a line segment and the subsequent "fusion" of the location data to yield line segment length or orientation? The hypothesis was investigated in a gaze-contingent comparison scenario with sequential stimulus presentation. Results demonstrated a high correlation between the assessment error of peripherally perceived lengths or orientations of line segments and the mislocation of marker positions, depending on eccentricity. The empirical data generally supports the hypothesis: The assessment of a line segment can be formalised as the localisation of line segment end points and the computation of their distance to yield line segment length. In analogy, the computation of the spatial relation of end points yields line segment orientation. An accordingly implemented, probabilistic computational model successfully reproduced the empirical findings and thus yielded further support for the proposed underlying perception principles.
The second hypothesis formulated the existence of two distinct visual processing strategies when assessing line segment length in a free gaze, simultaneous comparison scenario: Depending on the discrimination difficulty, either holistic or analytic visual processing strategies are pursued. These strategies should manifest in characteristic eye-movement patterns. Results show that the holistic strategy is apparently a peripheral process as such: Length is mentally represented as the distance between a fixated and a peripherally perceived end point of a line segment. In contrast, a specific pattern of foveal visual attention is characteristic for the analytic perception strategy, influenced by peripheral length perception. Saccadic "visual measurement" constitutes the basis for the memorisation and manipulation of the corresponding mental line segment representations. If the mental representations are not sufficiently accurate to solve the given comparison task - Which of two line segments is the longer one? - assessment and mental mapping are re-iterated. The findings also helped to better understand visual phenomena such as the horizontal-vertical illusion which appears to be induced by inaccurate measurement at a oculomotor level already. Integrating components of the "eccentricity model", in particular stimulus decomposition, a comprehensive computational model could be developed. It takes into account the visual length assessment strategies and convincingly reproduces the empirical data. This yields further support for the involvement of the proposed mechanisms in the assessment of line segment attributes in the chosen comparison scenarios.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="diss.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2304239/2304242/diss.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Visuelles System , Blickbewegung , Szenenanalyse , Mustervergleich , Konturfindung , Lokalisation ,  , Eye movement , Cognitive processes , Visual perception , Object dimension</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-2441</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2003-06-15</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Koesling H (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Koesling, Hendrik. &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2003.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koesling, Hendrik. 2003. &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Koesling, H.: Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2003).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Koesling, &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Koesling H (2003) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Koesling, H., 2003. &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koesling, H. (2003).  &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Koesling, H. (2003): Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<ieee> H. Koesling, &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2003.</ieee>
<apa>Koesling, H. (2003).  &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<frontiers>Koesling, H. (2003). Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koesling, H. (2003). &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Koesling H. &lt;em&gt;Visual perception of location, orientation and length : an eye-movement approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2003.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2304239</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-06-24T09:56:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:36:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>