<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2304609</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Konstantin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Wienands</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Signale des B-Zell-Antigenrezeptors (BZR) regeln sowohl die Aktivierung pathogenspezifischer B-Lymphozyten als auch die Eliminierung selbstreaktiver B-Lymphozyten. Das Ergebnis der BZR-Stimulation kann von Apoptose bis zu Proliferation der B-Lymphozyten reichen. Unpassende Signale können deshalb zu einer Unausgewogenheit zwischen der humoralen Immunität und Selbsttoleranz führen. Folglich hängt die B-Lymphozyten-Aktivierung von einem komplizierten Wechselspiel zwischen positiven und negativen Signalelementen ab. Der Anstieg der zytosolischen Kalziumionen (Ca2+)-Konzentration ist ein zentraler Schritt in der B-Lymphozyten-Aktivierung. Die zeitliche Form des Ca2+ Signals trägt zur differentiellen Aktivierung von Transkriptionsfaktoren bei, welche dann das Schicksal der Zelle beeinflussen. Das Adaptorprotein Grb2 hemmt BZR-vermittelte Ca2+-Mobilisierung. Während meiner Arbeit identifizierte Björn Stork in unserem Labor Dok-3 als ein weiteres Adaptorprotein, das Ca2+ Mobilisierung in B-Zellen hemmt.
In dieser Arbeit habe ich die molekularen Mechanismen der hemmenden Funktion der zwei Adaptorproteine untersucht. Dafür wurden DT40 B-Zellen verwendet, deren Gene für Grb2 oder Dok-3 inaktiviert worden sind. Damit konnte gezeigt werden, dass beide Proteine die Aktivierung des Ca2+-mobilisierenden Enzyms PLC-[gamma]2 durch Btk hemmen. Dies zeigte sich durch eine erhöhte BZR-vermittelte Phosphorylierung von PLC-[gamma]2 an einer spezifischen Btk-Phosphorylierungsstelle in der Abwesenheit von Dok-3 oder Grb2. Dieser Befund wurde durch erhöhte IP3-Produktion und einen stärkeren Grad der Entleerung der intrazellulären Ca2+-Speicher nach BZR-Stimulation unterstützt. Der beobachtete Einfluss der zwei Adaptorproteine auf der Aktivierung von Ca2+-Kanälen in der Plasmamembran verschwindet, wenn die Speicher künstlich entleert sind. Daher scheinen die beiden Adaptorproteine ausschließlich die Ca2+-Mobilisierung aus intrazellulären Speichern zu beeinflussen. Obwohl beide Proteine einen ternären Komplex mit dem hemmenden Lipidphosphatase SHIP bilden, scheint diese Wechselwirkung für die Dok-3-Funktion nicht notwendig zu sein. Eher scheint SHIP die Dok-3-Phosphorylierung zu fördern. Koquervernetzung von Fc[gamma]RIIb mit dem BZR führt zu starker SHIP-Aktivierung und ich konnte zeigen, dass dies auch zu verstärkter Dok-3-Phosphorylierung führt. Diese Studie zeigt Einblicke in die molekularen Mechanismen, durch die die zytosolischen Adaptorproteine Dok-3 und Grb2 BZR-Signale regeln und identifiziert Fc[gamma]RIIb als Regulator des Dok-3-Grb2-Moduls.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Signals emanating from the B cell antigen receptor (BCR) regulate both the activation of pathogen-specific B lymphocytes as well as removal of self-reactive B lymphocytes. The outcome of BCR stimulation can range from induction of apoptosis to proliferation. Inappropriate signals can therefore lead to an imbalance between humoral immunity and self tolerance. Consequently, B lymphocyte activation depends on a complex interplay between positive and negative signaling elements. The rise of the cytosolic Ca2+ concentration is a central step in B lymphocyte activation. The temporal shape of the Ca2+ signal contributes to the differential activation of transcription factors, which then affects cell fate decisions.
The adaptor protein Grb2 has previously been shown to inhibit BCR-induced Ca2+ mobilization. During my work Björn Stork in our lab identified Dok-3 to be another adaptor protein inhibiting Ca2+ mobilization in B cells. In this study I investigated the molecular mechanisms of the inhibitory function of the two adaptor proteins.
Using DT40 B cells that were rendered deficient for Grb2 or Dok-3 expression it could be shown that both proteins inhibit activation of the Ca2+ mobilizing enzyme PLC-[gamma]2 by Btk. This was evident from enhanced BCR-induced phosphorylation of PLC-[gamma]2 at a specific Btk phosphorylation site in the absence of Dok-3 or Grb2. This finding was supported by enhanced IP3 production and a stronger degree of depletion of Ca2+ from the ER stores in response to BCR ligation. An impact of the two adaptor proteins on the activation of plasma membrane Ca2+ channels could be excluded by uncoupling the release of Ca2+ from the ER from Ca2+ influx across the membrane. Although both proteins seem to form a ternary complex with the inhibitory lipid phosphatase SHIP, this interaction could be shown not to be essential for Dok-3 function. Rather, SHIP seems to promote Dok-3 phosphorylation. Fc[gamma]RIIb coligation to the BCR strongly activates SHIP and this could be shown to also enhance Dok-3 phosphorylation.
Together, this study reveals insights in the molecular mechanism by which the cytosolic adaptor proteins Dok-3 and Grb2 regulate BCR signaling and identifies Fc[gamma]RIIb as an upstream regulator.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="DissKNeumann.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2304609/2304612/DissKNeumann.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>B-Lymphozyt , Adaptorproteine , Signaltransduktion , Dok-3 (Downstream of kinase 3) , Grb2 (Growth factor receptor-bound protein 2) , B-Zell-Antigenrezeptor , Fc[gamma]RIIb , Signal transduction , B cell antigen receptor</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-14572</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2009-02-08</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, K. (2008). &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Neumann, &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Neumann K (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Neumann K. &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2008.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, Konstantin. 2008. &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Neumann, K.: On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2008).</lncs>
<wels>Neumann, K. (2008): On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<frontiers>Neumann, K. (2008). On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<mla>Neumann, Konstantin. &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, K. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Neumann K (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Neumann, K., 2008. &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> K. Neumann, &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Neumann, K. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;On adaptor proteins shaping Ca2+ signals in activated B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2304609</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2009-03-23T12:23:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:39:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>