<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2304982</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Axel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haasch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Jan Nikolaus</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Fritsch</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Robots that are used to support humans in dangerous environments, e.g., in manufacture facilities, are established for decades. Now, a new generation of service robots is focus of current research and about to be introduced. These intelligent service robots are intended to support humans in everyday life. To achieve a most comfortable human-robot interaction with non-expert users it is, thus, imperative for the acceptance of such robots to provide interaction interfaces that we humans are accustomed to in comparison to human-human communication. Consequently, intuitive modalities like gestures or spontaneous speech are needed to teach the robot previously unknown objects and locations. Then, the robot can be entrusted with tasks like fetch-and-carry orders even without an extensive training of the user. In this context, this dissertation introduces the multimodal Object Attention System which offers a flexible integration of common interaction modalities in combination with state-of-the-art image and speech processing techniques from other research projects. To prove the feasibility of the approach the presented Object Attention System has successfully been integrated in different robotic hardware. In particular, the mobile robot BIRON and the anthropomorphic robot BARTHOC of the Applied Computer Science Group at Bielefeld University. Concluding, the aim of this work, to acquire a qualitative Scene Model by a modular component offering object attention mechanisms, has been successfully achieved as demonstrated on numerous occasions like reviews for the EU-integrated Project COGNIRON or demos.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Haasch_Dissertation.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2304982/2304985/Haasch_Dissertation.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Mensch-Maschine-Kommunikation , Multimodales System , Objekt (Informatik) , Aufmerksamkeit , Topologie , Szenenanalyse , Modell ,  , Multimodal object attention system , Human-robot interaction , Qualitative scene model , Topology , Iconic scene memory</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-11604</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2007-05-21</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haasch, Axel. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Haasch, A.: Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2007).</lncs>
<default>Haasch A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Haasch, Axel. &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<wels>Haasch, A. (2007): Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Haasch, &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haasch, A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Haasch A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Haasch, A., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haasch, A. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Haasch, A. (2007). Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<ama>Haasch A. &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2007.</ama>
<ieee> A. Haasch, &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<apa>Haasch, A. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Attention-controlled acquisition of a qualitative scene model for mobile robots&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2304982</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2007-09-13T08:48:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:41:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>