<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2305508</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Hochempfindliche fluoreszente Messmethoden zur Detektion und Aktivitätsbestimmung von Enzymen am Beispiel spezifischer Hydrolasen</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sigrun</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Henkenjohann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">In sehr vielen biologischen und medizinischen Prozessen nehmen Enzyme eine wichtige Schlüsselfunktion ein, auf die Einfluss genommen werden kann, wenn die betreffenden Enzyme gesteuert werden können. Dies jedoch verlangt nach einem genauen Verständnis der enzymatischen Vorgänge, welches mithilfe der Fluoreszensmikroskopie verbessert werden kann. In dieser Arbeit werden zwei unterschiedliche Ansätze zur fluoreszenten Enzymologie für die Carboxypeptidase A und vier verschiedene Nukleasen vorgestellt und ausgewertet.
Der erste dieser Ansätze nutzt fluoreszierende Enzymsubstrate, die sich die intrinsischen elektronspendenden Eigenschaften der natürlich vorkommenden Aminosäure Tryptophan und der Nukleinsäure Guanosin zu Nutze machen.
Verschiedene Peptidsubstrate für die Untersuchung der Carboxypeptidase A und zwei Gruppen von sogenannten "smart probes" für die Untersuchung der DNaseI, DNaseII, S1-Nuklease und der DNaseX werden vorgestellt, charakterisiert und im weiteren Verlauf für die Analyse spezifischer Enzymeigenschaften angewandt. Schon kleine Unterschiede in Amino- und Nukleinsäuresequenzen dieser Substrate führen zu großen Veränderungen der relativen Quantenausbeuten, des Hitzeverhaltens der Substrate und des Enzymumsatzes. Die fluoreszenten Substrate werden genutzt, um den Effekt des angebrachten Farbstoffs auf die Akzeptanz und die Umsatzgeschwindigkeit durch das Enzym zu bestimmen. In dieser Arbeit werden außerdem Untersuchungen zu thermischen Eigenschaften der Carboxypeptidase A, der DNaseI und der DNaseX anhand einzelner Messungen bei unterschiedlichen Temperaturen und durch eine innovative Methode, die sich lange stetige Phasen in der Enzymkinetik zu Nutze macht, vorgestellt. Weiterhin wird die Anwendbarkeit fluoreszenter Substrate für die Ermittlung von Michaelis-Menten Parametern und für Messungen auf Einzelmolekülebene sowie in lebenden Zellen belegt.
Der zweite vorgestellte Ansatz macht von der Enzym-Immunofärbung Gebrauch. Hier wird eine optimierte Färbemethode für die Detektion und Lokalisierung eines spezifischen Enzyms in einer Vielzahl nativer Zelllinien angewandt. Außerdem wird eine modifizierte Nieren-Zelllinie in ihrem spezifischen Enzym-Expressionsverhalten mithilfe der konfokalen Fluoreszenzmikroskopie sowie durch die hochauflösende dSTORM Methode untersucht.
Die vorgestellten fluoreszenten Methoden unterscheiden sich sehr stark in ihrem Wesen, ihrer Anwendbarkeit und in ihren möglichen Ergebnissen. Nichts desto trotz können sie effizient kombiniert werden und somit die Untersuchung einer Vielzahl biologischer und medizinischer Fragestellungen ermöglichen, was in dieser Arbeit erfolgreich präsentiert wird.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Enzymes engage key roles in a wide variety of important physical and medical processes, which thus can be altered by manipulating the behavior of enzymes in charge. The capability for manipulation requires an exact understanding of enzymatic operation modes though, which can be increased by employing fluorescence microscopy. In this work, two approaches for fluorescence based enzyme research are presented and evaluated for Carboxypeptidase A and four different nucleases.
The first presented approach uses fluorescent enzyme substrates, which take advantage of intrinsic electron donating properties of the naturally occurring amino acid tryptophan and the nucleic acid guanosine.
Several peptide substrates for Carboxypeptidase A and two sets of smart probes for DNaseI, DNaseII, S1-Nuclease and DNaseX are introduced, characterized and, furthermore, utilized for the investigation of specific enzyme characteristics. Even small amino and nucleic acid sequence alterations of these substrates are found to result in strong differences concerning relative fluorescence quantum yields, thermal substrate behaviors and enzyme procession velocities. With these fluorescent substrates, the effect of the attached label on enzyme acceptance and velocities is examined. Furthermore, evaluations of the thermal characteristics of Carboxypeptidase A, DNaseI and DNaseX are presented by means of single measurements at various temperatures and by a novel approach, utilizing long steady state kinetics. Additionally, the suitability of fluorescent substrates for the determination of Michaelis-Menten parameters and for enzyme examinations on a single molecule scale and in living cells is proved.
The presented second approach is established on the method of enzyme immunolabeling. Here, an optimized labeling method is utilized for the detection and localization of a specific enzyme in a variety of native cell lines. Furthermore, a modified kidney cell line is examined in its specific enzyme expression characteristics with confocal fluorescence microscopy as well as with the high resolution dSTORM method.
The demonstrated fluorescent approaches vary distinctly in their nature, suitability and obtainable results. Still, they can be efficiently combined to diminish any disadvantage and allow research on a wide range of biological and medical questions, which will first be described in this work.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="DissertationSHenkenjohannk.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2305508/2305511/DissertationSHenkenjohannk.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Enzym</topic><topic>Fluoreszenzmikroskopie</topic><topic>Carboxypeptidasen</topic><topic>Nucleasen</topic><topic>Proteasen</topic><topic>Immunfärbung</topic><topic>DNaseX</topic><topic>DNaseI</topic><topic>Carboxypeptidase A (CPA)</topic><topic>Immunolabeling</topic><topic>Direct Stochastic optical reconstruction microscopy (dSTORM)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-16098</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2009-12-07</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Henkenjohann, Sigrun. &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2009.</mla>
<default>Henkenjohann S (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<lncs> Henkenjohann, S.: Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henkenjohann, Sigrun. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Henkenjohann, S. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> S. Henkenjohann, &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2009.</ieee>
<ama>Henkenjohann S. &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2009.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henkenjohann, S. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Henkenjohann, S. (2009). Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henkenjohann, S. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Henkenjohann S (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Henkenjohann, S., 2009. &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Henkenjohann, &lt;em&gt;Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Henkenjohann, S. (2009): Highly sensitive fluorescent methods for the detection of enzymes and the determination of their activity by means of specific hydrolases. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2305508</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-01-14T14:34:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>