<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2305111</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Eine molekulare Grundlage für differentielle Ca2+ Signale in B-Lymphozyten</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Björn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stork</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Wienands</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Die Generierung Antigen-spezifischer B-Lymphozyten ist essentiell für die humorale Immunantwort. Die Aktivierung von B-Zellen ist von Signalen abhängig, die über den B-Zell-Antigenrezeptor (BCR) vermittelt werden. Cytoplasmatische Protein-Tyrosinkinasen (PTKs) sind BCR-proximale Effektorproteine, die cytoplasmatische und transmembrane Adapterproteine wie SLP-65 oder NTAL phosphorylieren. Phosphoryliertes SLP-65 bildet das Gerüst für die Assemblierung und Aktivierung eines Proteinkomplexes, der die Ca2+-Freisetzung aus intrazellulären Speichern initiiert. Dieser Ca2+-Initiationskomplex besteht mindestens aus Brutons Tyrosinkinase (Btk) und Phospholipase C-[gamma]2 (PLC-[gamma]2). Die BCR-induzierte Ca2+-Mobilisierung beinhaltet sowohl die Freisetzung aus intrazellulären Ca2+-Speichern als auch den Einstrom über die Plasmamembran. Das Ausmaß der Ca2+-Mobilisierung aus diesen beiden Speichern hängt von dem Entwicklungsstadium des B-Lymphozyten ab. Die räumliche und zeitliche Veränderung von Ca2+-Profilen kann zu verschiedenen B-Zell-Antworten führen, d.h. Proliferation, Differenzierung, Anergie oder Apoptose. Gegenwärtig sind zentrale Fragen in der BCR-induzierten Ca2+-Mobilisierung: (1) wie wird der Ca2+-Initiationskomplex an die Membran rekrutiert, (2) was ist der exakte Mechanismus der BCR-vermittelten PLC-[gamma]2 Aktivierung, (3) wie ist die intrazelluläre Ca2+-Freisetzung mit dem Ca2+-Einstrom über die Plasmamembran verbunden, und (4) wie erfolgt die differentielle Regulierung der Ca2+-Mobilisierung während der B-Zell-Lymphopoese? In dieser Studie wurden diese Fragen mittels zielgerichteter Gen-Inaktivierung und nachfolgenden Rekonstitutionen analysiert. Es konnte gezeigt werden, dass der SH2/SH3-Adapter Grb2 die Ca2+-Mobilisierung aus intra- und extrazellulären Quellen negativ reguliert. Diese Funktion ist von der zentralen SH2- und der C-terminalen SH3-Domäne abhängig. Tyrosin-phosphoryliertes NTAL wirkt dieser Funktion durch die Grb2-Rekrutierung in lipid rafts entgegen. Es konnte des weiteren gezeigt werden, dass das NTAL/Grb2-Modul nicht den Phosphorylierungsgrad der zentralen Komponenten des Ca2+-Initiationskomplexes, d.h. SLP-65 oder PLC-[gamma]2, beeinflusst. Allerdings scheinen NTAL/Grb2 die PLC-[gamma]2-Aktivierung und/oder dessen Retention an der Plasmamembran zu kontrollieren. Es konnte im Rahmen dieser Arbeit herausgefunden werden, dass das Hauptphosphoprotein in DT40 das Grb2-Effektorprotein ist. Nachfolgend wurde dieses als das cytosolische Adapterprotein Dok-3 identifiziert. Die Phosphorylierung von Dok-3 durch Lyn ist abhängig von Grb2 und benötigt dessen zentrale SH2- und die C-terminale SH3-Domäne. Zusammenfassend deuten diese Studien darauf hin, dass Grb2 ein molekularer Schalter in der BCR-induzierten Ca2+-Mobilisierung ist. Die SH2-Domänen-abhängige Bindung von Grb2 an entweder Tyrosin-phosphoryliertes NTAL oder Dok-3 führt letztendlich zur positiven bzw. negativen Modulation der Antigenrezeptor-induzierten Ca2+-Mobilisierung in B-Zellen. In dieser Studie wurde ein neuer Ca2+-Regulationsmechanismus identifiziert. Die Adapter-vermittelte Modulation der Ca2+-Mobilisierung könnte durch die Unterstützung von entweder Aktivierung oder Toleranzinduktion die B-Zell-Signaltransduktion kritisch beeinflussen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">The generation of antigen-specific B lymphocytes is essential for the humoral immune response. B cell activation depends on signals generated upon engagement of the B cell antigen receptor (BCR). Proximal BCR effector proteins are cytoplasmic protein tyrosine kinases (PTKs) which phosphorylate cytoplasmic and transmembrane adaptor proteins such as SLP-65 or NTAL, respectively. Phosphorylated SLP-65 forms the scaffold for the assembly and activation of a protein complex which initiates Ca2+ release from intracellular stores. This Ca2+ initiation complex is composed of at least Bruton's tyrosine kinase (Btk) and phospholipase C-[gamma]2 (PLC-[gamma]2). BCR-induced Ca2+ mobilization arises by both release from intracellular Ca2+ stores, and Ca2+ influx through plasma membrane channels. The extent of Ca2+ mobilization from these two sources varies depending on the developmental stage of the B lymphocyte. Shaping Ca2+ profiles in the dimensions of space and time can determine different B cell responses, i.e. proliferation, differentiation, anergy or apoptosis. Currently, central questions of BCR-induced Ca2+ mobilization are: (1) how the Ca2+ initiation complex is targeted to the plasma membrane, (2) what is the exact mechanism of BCR-triggered PLC-[gamma]2 activation, (3) how the intracellular Ca2+ release is connected to Ca2+ influx across the plasma membrane, and (4) how Ca2+ mobilization is differentially regulated during B cell lymphopoiesis. In this study, these questions were addressed by gene targeting experiments and subsequent reconstitutions in the chicken B cell line DT40. It was demonstrated that the SH2/SH3 adaptor Grb2 negatively regulates Ca2+ mobilization from intra- and extracellular sources. This function depends on the central SH2 and the C-terminal SH3 domain. Tyrosine-phosphorylated NTAL counter-acts Grb2 by recruiting it into lipid rafts. It was further shown that the NTAL/Grb2 module does not affect the phosphorylation state of the central components of the Ca2+ initiation complex, i.e. SLP-65 or PLC-[gamma]2. However, it appeared that PLC-[gamma]2 activation and/or retention at the plasma membrane are controlled by NTAL/Grb2. The downstream effector of Grb2 was determined to be the major tyrosine phosphorylated protein in DT40 B cells, and was subsequently identified as the cytosolic adaptor Dok-3. Phosphorylation of Dok-3 by Lyn depends on Grb2 and requires its central SH2 and C-terminal SH3 domain. Collectively, Grb2 seems to be a molecular switch in BCR-induced Ca2+ mobilization. The SH2 domain-dependent binding of Grb2 to either tyrosine phosphorylated NTAL or Dok-3 ultimately leads to positive or negative modulation of antigen receptor-induced Ca2+ mobilization in B cells. Thus, in this study a novel Ca2+ regulation pathway in B lymphocytes was identified. The adaptor-mediated modulation of Ca2+ mobilization may critically influence B cell signalling by supporting either activation or tolerance induction.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_BStork.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2305111/2305114/Dissertation_BStork.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Calcium , Adapter , Anergie (Immunologie) , B-Lymphozyten-Rezeptor , Lymphozyt , Signaltransduktion , Phospholipase C , Plasmamembran , B-Zellen , Grb2 (Growth factor receptor-bound protein 2) , Dok3 (Downstream of tyrosine kinase 3) , B cells , Adaptor</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-9917</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2006-08-21</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Stork, B.: A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stork, Björn. 2006. &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Stork, Björn. &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2006.</mla>
<default>Stork B (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<wels>Stork, B. (2006): A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<bio1>Stork B (2006) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Stork, B., 2006. &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stork, B. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Stork, &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Stork B. &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2006.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stork, B. (2006). &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Stork, B. (2006). A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa>Stork, B. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> B. Stork, &lt;em&gt;A molecular basis for differential Ca2+ signalling in B lymphocytes&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2006.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2305111</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2006-11-02T13:03:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:41:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>