<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2305763</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Datengetriebenes Lernen der Perzeptiven Gruppierung im Competitive Layer Model</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weng</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The present work describes the treatment of several grouping or segmentation problems from the field of automatic image processing. It is motivated by natural grouping principles which can be observed in human visual perception, like the Gestalt laws of proximity, similarity and closture.
These principles are implemented by pairwise interactions between elementary data structures in a recurrent neural network architecture, the so called Competitive Layer Model (CLM). The main result of the work is the development of an automatic learning method which extracts suitable interaction patterns from exemplary target groupings.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">In der vorliegenden Arbeit werden unter dem Begriff der Perzeptiven Gruppierung verschiedene Gruppierungs- bzw. Segmentierungsprobleme der maschinellen Bildverarbeitung behandelt. Als Vorbild dienen dabei natürliche Gruppierungsprinzipien der menschlichen visuellen Wahrnehmung, wie bspw. die Gestalt-Gesetze der Nähe, der Ähnlichkeit oder der Verbundenheit.
Diese Prinzipien werden in einer rekurrenten Neuronalen Netz-Architektur, dem Competitive Layer Model (CLM), durch paarweise Interaktionen zwischen elementaren Datenstrukturen implementiert. Der Schwerpunkt der Arbeit liegt in der Entwicklung eines automatischen Lernverfahrens, mit dem sich aus Beispielgruppierungen geeignete Interaktionsmuster extrahieren lassen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="dissertation_sweng_2005.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2305763/2305766/dissertation_sweng_2005.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-8275</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2006-01-22</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Weng, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2005.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weng, S. (2005).  &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Weng, S. (2005). Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<wels>Weng, S. (2005): Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Weng S (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Weng, S., 2005. &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Weng, &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2005.</ieee>
<apa>Weng, S. (2005).  &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weng, S. (2005). &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Weng, &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Weng S (2005) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Weng S. &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2005.</ama>
<lncs> Weng, S.: Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weng, Sebastian. 2005. &lt;em&gt;Data driven learning for feature binding and perceptual grouping with the Competitive Layer Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2305763</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2006-02-21T10:29:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>