<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2306427</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Shu-Chuan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tseng</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Dafydd</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Gibbon</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Two questions are asked in this thesis: 1) How are speech disfluencies produced from the linguistic point of view, focusing especially on the syntactic and prosodic features? 2) Do regular internal relations exist within speech disfluencies and if so, what do they look like? These two questions are examined by means of empirical studies and formal models. With respect to the first question, a corpus analysis is carried out to investigate the production of disfluencies from the syntactic point of view. The acoustic-prosodic features of selected types of disfluencies are also examined. A further syntactic analysis is undertaken to secure the syntactic features found in the speaker-independent corpus analysis is refound in the speaker-dependent data which are used in the signal analysis. Furthermore, the empirical results of the corpus analysis and signal analysis should provide empirical evidence for the existence of regular internal relations within speech disfluencies as asked in the second question. Finite state techniques are used for describing this regularity.
The results of the corpus analysis show a highly significant syntactic regularity when disfluencies are produced. The results of the signal analysis show that the production of disfluencies is also prosodically marked. Furthermore, according to the results obtained by the speaker-independent and -dependent syntactic analyses as well as the speaker-dependent acoustic-prosodic analysis, a clear mapping from the syntactic level to the prosodic level was found. This means that one can find both syntactic and prosodic cues at specific positions within or around speech disfluencies.
Thus, the hypothesis that there exist specific phrase-internal disfluency relations has been empirically supported. Based on the empirical results, a formal description system is developed to cover the majority of the disfluencies produced in the corpus. The disfluency relations found are subsequently modelled by means of three disfluency models which also demonstrate the progress of investigating internal structures of disfluencies. Both syntactic and prosodic features are integrated into the final model and the relationship between syntax and prosody with respect to disfluencies is established. These relations are formally described in terms of finite state automata.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="0001.ps">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2306427/2306430/0001.ps</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/ps</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sprechpause</topic><topic>Sprachreparaturen</topic><topic>Gesprochene Dialoge</topic><topic>Prosodie</topic><topic>Deutsch</topic><topic>Dialog</topic><topic>Intonation (Linguistik)</topic><topic>Finite state modelling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-1792</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">1999-03-30</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Tseng, S.-C.: Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (1999).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tseng, Shu-Chuan. 1999. &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Tseng, Shu-Chuan. &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, 1999.</mla>
<default>Tseng S-C (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</default>
<ama>Tseng S-C. &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University; 1999.</ama>
<frontiers>Tseng, S. - C. (1999). Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tseng, S.-C. (1999). &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Tseng, S. - C. (1999).  &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</apa>
<ieee> S.-C. Tseng, &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, 1999.</ieee>
<wels>Tseng, S. - C. (1999): Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tseng, S. - C. (1999).  &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Tseng S-C (1999) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Tseng, S.-C., 1999. &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S. - C.  Tseng, &lt;em&gt;Grammar, prosody and speech disfluencies in spoken dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2306427</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-05-14T08:22:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T09:00:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>