<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2306545</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer-Fujara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rieser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11749</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart><namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bernhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Jung</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft (KogWis99)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Metonymies are known as ways of conceptualizing entities and situations of various sorts. For example, users of PCs usually call the icon depicting a waste paper basket 'basket'. They thus use the name of the depicted object for referring to the depicting object. We use a model airplane ("Baufix" airplane) as the paradigm case for investigating the semiotics of depictional metonymies and the role they are put to in construction dialogue. The airplane's structure is described in a GPSG format and given a model-theoretic semantics. We also describe how aggregates of the toy model are given depictional interpretations in the course of the construction dialogue. The coordinating role of metonymic language use is illustrated. It is also shown how cognition can be integrated into the model developed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="meyerfujara.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2306545/2306549/meyerfujara.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Infix-Verl.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Bildersprache</topic><topic>Metonymie</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-89601-014-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-3962</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">256-261</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Meyer-Fujara, J., and Rieser, H. (1999). “Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue” in &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;, Wachsmuth, I., and Jung, B. eds. (St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.), 256-261.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer-Fujara, J. &amp;amp; Rieser, H. (1999). Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In I. Wachsmuth &amp;amp; B. Jung (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt; (S. 256-261). Gehalten auf der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft (KogWis99), St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Meyer-Fujara J, Rieser H. Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In: Wachsmuth I, Jung B, eds. &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;. St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.;  1999: 256-261.</ama>
<ieee> J. Meyer-Fujara and H. Rieser, “Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue”, &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;, I. Wachsmuth and B. Jung, eds.,  St. Augustin: Infix-Verl., 1999,  pp.256-261.</ieee>
<apa>Meyer-Fujara, J., &amp;amp; Rieser, H. (1999). Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; B.  Jung (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 256-261). St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.</apa>
<wels>Meyer-Fujara, J.; Rieser, H. (1999): Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In: Ipke Wachsmuth; Bernhard Jung (Hrsg.):  KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft. St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.  S. 256-261.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Meyer-Fujara, and H.  Rieser, in &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Wachsmuth, B. Jung), Infix-Verl., St. Augustin, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 256-261.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer-Fujara, J., &amp;amp; Rieser, H. (1999). Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; B.  Jung (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 256-261). St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Meyer-Fujara J, Rieser H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. &lt;br /&gt;In:  KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft. Wachsmuth I, Jung B (Eds); St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.:  256-261.</bio1>
<harvard1>Meyer-Fujara, J., &amp;amp; Rieser, H., 1999. Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; B.  Jung, eds. &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;.  St. Augustin: Infix-Verl., pp. 256-261.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer-Fujara, Josef, and Rieser, Hannes. 1999. “Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue”. In &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Bernhard Jung, 256-261. St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Meyer-Fujara, J., Rieser, H.: Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue. In: Wachsmuth, I. and Jung, B. (eds.) KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft. p. 256-261. Infix-Verl., St. Augustin (1999).</lncs>
<default>Meyer-Fujara J, Rieser H (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft. Wachsmuth I, Jung B (Eds);  St. Augustin: Infix-Verl.:  256-261.</default>
<mla>Meyer-Fujara, Josef, and Rieser, Hannes. “Non-literal language use and coordination in dialogue”. &lt;em&gt;KogWis99 : Proceedings der 4. Fachtagung der Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Bernhard Jung. St. Augustin: Infix-Verl., 1999. 256-261.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2306545</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2003-11-20T10:26:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-15T15:40:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>