<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2306130</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Austenfeld</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Beyschlag</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685201</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Eine allgemeine Entwicklungsumgebung wurde für die Analyse und Simulation von räumlich-zeitlichen Phänomenen in ökologischen Systemen entwickelt. Die gesamte Plattform basiert auf einer "Rich-Client-Platform" (RCP), die neue Konzepte der Modularisierung und allgemeinen Programmarchitektur mitbringt. Damit bietet sie die Grundlage für eine nachhaltige Weiterentwicklung und ist somit eine solide Basis für eine integrierte Entwicklungsumgebung für ökologische Modelle. Die Integration verschiedener statistischer Werkzeuge, Methoden der Bildverarbeitung und spezielle Visualisierungen qualifizieren diese Umgebung besonders für die Analyse der oben genannten räumlich-zeitlichen Prozesse.
Aufgrund ihrer vergleichsweise geringen Komplexität wurden Sandlebensräume wiederholt für Studien von Vegetationsmustern und ihrer zugrunde liegenden biotischen Interaktionen genutzt. Für einen integrativen Überblick und weitere integrative Ansätze mit Hilfe von Simulationsmodellen wurde die oben genannte Plattform genutzt, um eine individuenbasierte Modellstruktur für die Analyse von Langzeiteffekten aufgrund von Umweltveränderungen auf die Stabilität von Sandlebensräumen zu entwickeln, die typischerweise von zwei Pionierarten, Corynephorus canescens und Polytrichum piliferum, dominiert werden. Das Modell wurde mit experimentellen Daten verifiziert, und die vom Modell erzeugten räumlich-zeitlichen Muster zeigten eine hohe Übereinstimmung mit natürlich gemessenen Mustern.
Das Modell wurde dann genutzt, um Langzeiteffekte von Veränderungen der Temperatur, Nährstoffversorgung und Störungsraten in diesem System zu untersuchen. Die Ergebnisse zeigten eine generell hohe Stabilität des Systems unter veränderten Temperatur- und Nährstoffbedingungen, wobei temporal wiederkehrende, kleinräumige Störungen als Grundlage notwendig waren.
Schließlich wurde noch eine Untersuchung über die Auswirkungen von Herbivorie und Konkurrenz auf Corynephorus canescens durchgeführt. In einem kontrollierten Freilandexperiment wurden die Auswirkungen von entfernter Biomasse von Blättern sowie die An- oder Abwesenheit eines intraspezifischen und interspezifischen Konkurrenten (Hieracium pilosella) auf die überirdische und unterirdische Allokation von Biomasse in der folgenden Regenerationsphase analysiert. Die Ergebnisse zeigten, dass Corynephorus canescens die Fähigkeit besitzt, leichte bis mittlere Blattverluste (die typische natürliche Herbivorie von Kaninchen und Paarhufern simulieren sollten) zu kompensieren, ohne dabei an Konkurrenzstärke zu verlieren. Unterirdisch konnten keine Auswirkungen der simulierten Herbivorie bzw. Konkurrenz festgestellt werden. Aufgrund dieser zu vernachlässigenden Effekte wurde Herbivorie nicht in dem Modell berücksichtigt.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">A generic modeling environment for the analysis and simulation of spatio-temporal phenomena in ecosystems was developed. This framework was built upon a Rich Client Platform (RCP) which uses new concepts of extensibility and software architecture for sustainable development and provides a solid basis for an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for ecological models. The integration of various statistical tools, imaging routines and several specialized drawing panels makes this environment particularly suitable for the analysis of the above mentioned spatio-temporal ecological processes.
Because of their comparatively low complexity, dry acidic grassland ecosystems have been repeatedly used for studying vegetation pattern formation and the underlying biotic interactions. In order to obtain an integrative view of the existing knowledge as well as to provide a possibility for further integrative analysis with the help of model simulations, the above described platform was used to develop an individual based Model structure for the investigation of long term effects of environmental changes on the stability of early successional stages of such dry acidic grasslands which are typically dominated by the two pioneer species Corynephorus canescens and Polytrichum piliferum. The model was validated with experimental data and the spatio-temporal patterns created by the model were in good accordance with the measured natural patterns.
The model was then used to analyze the effect of changes in temperature, nutrient supply and disturbance rate on the long term behavior of this ecosystem. The results showed an overall high stability of this system under different temperature and nutrient scenarios as long as an intermediate disturbance frequency is assured.
Finally, an experimental study on the effect of herbivory and competition on the Corynephorus canescens was conducted. In a controlled field experiment, the effects of the removal of various amounts of aboveground biomass on the above and belowground biomass allocation during the following regeneration phase was analyzed in the presence or absence of an intraspecific and interspecific competitor (Hieracium pilosella). The results show a rather high ability of C. canescens to compensate low to medium amounts of foliage loss (reflecting the typical natural herbivory induced by grasshoppers and rabbits) without significant changes in its competitive ability. Belowground, no biomass effects of foliage removal and/or competition could be detected. Because of these negligible effects, herbivory was not implemented in the above described model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_Marcel_Austenfeld.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2306130/2306133/Dissertation_Marcel_Austenfeld.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>, Sandlebensraum , Vegetationsdynamik , Ökologische Modellierung , Individuenbasiertes Simulationsmodell , Herbivorie , Corynephorus canescens , Sand ecosystems , Vegetation dynamics , Ecological modeling , Simulation framework , Individual-based simulation model , Herbivory</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-16109</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2010-01-14</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Austenfeld, M. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Austenfeld, M. (2009). Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<ama>Austenfeld M. &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University; 2009.</ama>
<ieee> M. Austenfeld, &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2009.</ieee>
<apa>Austenfeld, M. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</apa>
<wels>Austenfeld, M. (2009): Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Austenfeld, &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany), &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Austenfeld, M. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Austenfeld M (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<harvard1>Austenfeld, M., 2009. &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Austenfeld, Marcel. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Austenfeld, M.: Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations. Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (Germany) (2009).</lncs>
<default>Austenfeld M (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Austenfeld, Marcel. &lt;em&gt;Spatio-temporal analysis of vegetation dynamics of selected successional stages of dry acidic grasslands : experimental studies and model simulations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld (Germany): Bielefeld University, 2009.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2306130</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-03-03T10:03:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-11T08:58:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>