<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315272</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tomoo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kikuchi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper analyzes the world economy model presented in Matsuyama (2002) with the help of numerical methods. We exhibit that his necessary and sufficient conditions for the asymmetric steady states do not cover all possible cases when the world interest rate is determined endogenously in the international financial market. Additional asymptotically stable asymmetric steady states emerge. Borrowing constraints can be binding for all countries in symmetric as well as asymmetric steady states. All countries converge to symmetric steady states if they are not credit rationed initially, if their initial conditions are sufficiently similar or if the sum of their initial conditions is sufficiently high, so that the productivity of investment project allows the capital accumulation of countries to adjust to the same level via the international financial market. In other words, the international financial market can function as an equalizing force as well as magnifying inequality.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="DP509.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315272/2315345/DP509.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Financial market imperfections</topic><topic>Convergence</topic><topic>Symmetry-breaking</topic><topic>World economy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-3794</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>509</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kikuchi T (2003)  Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Kikuchi, Tomoo. &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2003. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kikuchi, Tomoo. 2003. &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kikuchi, T.: A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2003).</lncs>
<ieee> T. Kikuchi, &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;, Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2003.</ieee>
<apa>Kikuchi, T. (2003).  &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kikuchi, T. (2003). &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kikuchi, T. (2003). A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market. &lt;em&gt;Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<ama>Kikuchi T. &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2003.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Kikuchi, &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kikuchi T (2003) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kikuchi, T. (2003).  &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kikuchi, T., 2003. &lt;em&gt;A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market&lt;/em&gt;, Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<wels>Kikuchi, T. (2003): A note on symmetry breaking in a world economy with an international financial market. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315272</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-11T14:13:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>