<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315563</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thiemo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller-Kalthoff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wild</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34497</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Monika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rammert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anita</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Siegmund</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Judith</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gerber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Whereas the influence of the school learning environment on students' motivational development has been the subject of much empirical research, the role of the home environment has been somewhat neglected. As part of a longitudinal project initiated to identify opportunities for enhancing self-determined forms of learning motivation at home and in school, this study with a sample of N = 137 students tested how parental support of student learning influences the development of learning motivation in mathematics. At three points of measurement (grades 5, 6, and 7), students were surveyed on four dimensions of their parents' learning-related attitudes and behavior: autonomy support, emotional support, domain-specific structure, and achievement pressure. In addition, their learning motivation was assessed by scales measuring external vs. identified motivation, interest vs. aversion, and willingness to exert effort. Findings confirmed that parental autonomy support and emotional support were conducive to learning, whereas controlling behaviors had dysfunctional effects. Similar - though somewhat weaker - patterns of results emerged from the longitudinal analyses and when mathematics achievement and social background were controlled.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Anders als die Rolle der schulischen Lernumwelt wurde die Rolle des Elternhauses für die Motivationsentwicklung von Schülern bisher etwas vernachlässigt. Im Rahmen einer längsschnittlich angelegten Studie zur Förderung selbst bestimmter Formen der Lernmotivation in Elternhaus und Schule wurde an N = 137 Schülern überprüft, wie sich das elterliche Instruktionsverhalten auf die Entwicklung der Lernmotivation im Fach Mathematik auswirkt. Dazu wurden die Schüler zu drei Messzeitpunkten (in der 5., 6. und 7. Klasse) bezüglich verschiedener Einstellungs- und Verhaltensmuster ihrer Eltern befragt, die sich den vier Dimensionen Autonomieunterstützung, emotionale Unterstützung, bereichsspezifische Struktur und leistungsorientierter Druck zuordnen lassen. Die Lernmotivation der Schüler wurde über Skalen zur externalen vs. identifizierten Motivation, zu Interesse vs. Abneigung und zur Anstrengungsbereitschaft erfasst. Zusammenfassend stützen die Ergebnisse die Vorteile einer elterlichen Autonomie- und emotionalen Unterstützung und weisen ein kontrollierendes Instruktionsverhalten der Eltern als dysfunktional aus. Dies gilt - etwas abgeschwächt - selbst im Längsschnitt und bei Kontrolle der Leistungsfähigkeit und der sozialen Herkunft der Schüler.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="muellerKalthoff_et_al_parental_support_jan_2008_bieson.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315563/2319815/muellerKalthoff_et_al_parental_support_jan_2008_bieson.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Parental support</topic><topic>Learning motivation</topic><topic>Motivational development</topic><topic>Self-determination theory</topic><topic>Interest theory</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-12385</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> T. Müller-Kalthoff, et al., &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2006.</ieee>
<harvard1>Müller-Kalthoff, T., et al., 2006. &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<ama>Müller-Kalthoff T, Wild E, Rammert M, Siegmund A, Gerber J. &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2006.</ama>
<apa>Müller-Kalthoff, T., Wild, E., Rammert, M., Siegmund, A., &amp;amp; Gerber, J. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller-Kalthoff, Thiemo, Wild, Elke, Rammert, Monika, Siegmund, Anita, and Gerber, Judith. 2006. &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Müller-Kalthoff, T., Wild, E., Rammert, M., Siegmund, A., Gerber, J.: Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2006).</lncs>
<wels>Müller-Kalthoff, T.; Wild, E.; Rammert, M.; Siegmund, A.; Gerber, J. (2006): Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<mla>Müller-Kalthoff, Thiemo, Wild, Elke, Rammert, Monika, Siegmund, Anita, and Gerber, Judith. &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2006.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller-Kalthoff, T., Wild, E., Rammert, M., Siegmund, A., &amp;amp; Gerber, J. (2006).  &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Müller-Kalthoff, T., Wild, E., Rammert, M., Siegmund, A., and Gerber, J. (2006). Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller-Kalthoff, T., Wild, E., Rammert, M., Siegmund, A. &amp;amp; Gerber, J. (2006). &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Müller-Kalthoff T, Wild E, Rammert M, Siegmund A, Gerber J (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<bio1>Müller-Kalthoff T, Wild E, Rammert M, Siegmund A, Gerber J (2006) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Müller-Kalthoff, E.  Wild, M.  Rammert, A.  Siegmund, and J.  Gerber, &lt;em&gt;Parental support of student learning and the development of learning motivation in mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315563</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-12T14:29:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>