<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315241</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wenzelburger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper develops an adaptive learning scheme for an asset market with heterogeneous traders. We introduce the concept of a perfect forecasting rule for fundamentalists which generates rational expectations in the presence of chartists whose expectations are not necessarily rational. In the case when traders have linear mean-variance preferences and chartists base their decisions on simple technical trading rules, perfect forecasting rules are approximated by successively estimating the excess supply function from historical data. Conditions are given under which trajectories generated by this adaptive learning scheme converge to trajectories with rational expectations for fundamentalists.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="477.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315241/2315338/477.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-869</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>477</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Wenzelburger, &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wenzelburger, J. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Wenzelburger, J., 2001. &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wenzelburger J (2001) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<wels>Wenzelburger, J. (2001): Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<ieee> J. Wenzelburger, &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2001.</ieee>
<apa>Wenzelburger, J. (2001).  &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<frontiers>Wenzelburger, J. (2001). Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous. &lt;em&gt;Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wenzelburger, J. (2001). &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wenzelburger J. &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2001.</ama>
<default>Wenzelburger J (2001)  Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Wenzelburger, Jan. &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2001. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wenzelburger, Jan. 2001. &lt;em&gt;Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wenzelburger, J.: Learning to predict rationally when beliefs are heterogeneous. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2001).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315241</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-11T13:18:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>