<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315456</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schuhmacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benteng</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this article we extend the recent literature on overlapping generations with a pollution sector by allowing generations to have a certain pollution perception with regards to the stock of pollution. Pollution perception, assumed to be part of the generations' preferences, can be either a concern for the flow of pollution only, or for the stock, or anything in between. We analyse the different steady states for their implications on intergenerational equity.
Our main result is that if generations are only partly concerned with the actual stock of pollution, then periodic cycling will occur. We use the concept of Intergenerational Moral Intuition to analyse this periodic cycling. Our main policy conclusion is that decision makers who would like to achieve intergenerational equitable outcomes must either use the maximin criterion or take decisions spanning several generations in order to avoid the period cycling effect.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="371.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315456/2319793/371.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Pollution</topic><topic>Welfare analysis</topic><topic>Overlapping generations</topic><topic>Flip bifurcation</topic><topic>Intergenerational equity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-7822</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>371</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schuhmacher, I., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2005).  &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 371). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Schuhmacher, I., and Zou, B. (2005). Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 371, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<mla>Schuhmacher, Ingmar, and Zou, Benteng. &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2005. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 371.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schuhmacher, I. &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2005). &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Schuhmacher, I.; Zou, B. (2005): Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<bio1>Schuhmacher I, Zou B (2005) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 371.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Schuhmacher, and B.  Zou, &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Schuhmacher I, Zou B (2005)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 371.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<ama>Schuhmacher I, Zou B. &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 371. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2005.</ama>
<ieee> I. Schuhmacher and B. Zou, &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 371,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2005.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schuhmacher, I., &amp;amp; Zou, B., 2005. &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.371, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<lncs> Schuhmacher, I., Zou, B.: Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 371. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schuhmacher, Ingmar, and Zou, Benteng. 2005. &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 371. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Schuhmacher, I., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2005).  &lt;em&gt;Pollution perception. An inquiry into intergenerational equity&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 371). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315456</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-12T11:46:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>