<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315866</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böhm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">80680</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">George</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vachadze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The paper analyzes the consequences of joining markets of government discount bonds between identical economies when, in each country, there exists a positive probability of the government to default. In autarky such economies of overlapping generations of consumers with capital accumulation converge to a unique positive steady state under certain conditions. When two identical economies of this type open their markets for bonds to the consumers of the other country, diversification in portfolio demand by consumers leads to the existence of a world equilibrium with a uniform bond price in every period. Under such circumstances a symmetric stationary world equilibrium with lower risk per country exists, supported by the same level of capital and income as under autarky. However, due to the interaction of dynamic spill over effects between the bond market and the domestic markets for capital investment, the symmetric steady state may become unstable and stable asymmetric steady states appear, implying symmetry breaking in the sense of Matsuyama (2004). The paper identifies a set of assumptions on consumer and production characteristics together with a range of values of the government's default parameters, such that instability occurs and asymmetric steady states become locally stable.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WPM3544.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315866/2319846/WPM3544.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Capital accumulation</topic><topic>Sovereign risk</topic><topic>International bond markets</topic><topic>Nonconvergence</topic><topic>Symmetry-breaking</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-15040</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>576</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Böhm, V., and Vachadze, G. (2008). Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence. &lt;em&gt;Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V. &amp;amp; Vachadze, G. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Böhm V, Vachadze G. &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2008.</ama>
<ieee> V. Böhm and G. Vachadze, &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;, Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Vachadze, G. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<wels>Böhm, V.; Vachadze, G. (2008): Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Böhm, and G.  Vachadze, &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Vachadze, G. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt; (Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Böhm V, Vachadze G (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<harvard1>Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Vachadze, G., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;, Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, Volker, and Vachadze, George. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Böhm, V., Vachadze, G.: Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<default>Böhm V, Vachadze G (2008)  Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Böhm, Volker, and Vachadze, George. &lt;em&gt;Sovereign risk in international bond markets and nonconvergence&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008. Discussion paper / Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315866</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-15T09:38:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>