<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2315962</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herzberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">For a continuous-time financial market with a single agent, we establish equilibrium pricing formulae under the assumption that the dividends follow an exponential Lévy process. The agent is allowed to consume a lump at the terminal date; before, only flow consumption is allowed. The agent's utility function is assumed to be additive, defined via strictly increasing, strictly concave smooth felicity functions which are bounded below (thus, many CRRA and CARA utility functions are included). For technical reasons we require that only pathwise continuous trading strategies are permitted in the demand set.
The resulting equilibrium prices depend on the agent's risk-aversion through the felicity functions. It turns out that these prices will be the (stochastic) exponential of a Lévy process essentially only if this process is geometric Brownian motion.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="406.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2315962/2319848/406.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Asset pricing</topic><topic>Financial equilibrium</topic><topic>Lévy processes</topic><topic>Representative agent models</topic><topic>Nonstandard analysis</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">rn:nbn:de:hbz:361-14203</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>406</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, Frederik. 2008. &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 406. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herzberg, F.: On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 406. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<default>Herzberg F (2008)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 406.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Herzberg, Frederik. &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 406.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2008). &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Herzberg, F. (2008). On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 406, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<ama>Herzberg F. &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 406. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2008.</ama>
<ieee> F. Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 406,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Herzberg, F. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 406). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<wels>Herzberg, F. (2008): On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Herzberg, F., 2008. &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.406, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Herzberg F (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 406.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;On the foundations of Lévy finance. Equilibrium for a single-agent financial market with jumps&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 406). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2315962</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-15T10:08:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>