<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2316957</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gersbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wenzelburger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper provides a macroeconomic perspective for government interventions in banking crises. We illustrate how vulnerabilities of the banking sector may build up over time and thus destabilize a banking system. A crisis occurs when a large number of banks fail to meet capital requirements or are insolvent. Based on a macroeconomic model with financial intermediation, our reasoning suggests that in good and moderate times strict enforcement of capital adequate rules suffices. Interest rate intervention or cartelization and restructuring of the banking industry becomes necessary in critical times. These policies should be reenforced by random bail-outs and subsidies in bad times.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="490.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2316957/2319885/490.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Banking regulation</topic><topic>Financial intermediation</topic><topic>Macroeconomic risks</topic><topic>Banking crises</topic><topic>Deposit insurance</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48271</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>490</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Gersbach H, Wenzelburger J. &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften; 2002.</ama>
<lncs> Gersbach, H., Wenzelburger, J.: The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Bielefeld (2002).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gersbach, Hans, and Wenzelburger, Jan. 2002. &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gersbach, H. &amp;amp; Wenzelburger, J. (2002). &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Gersbach H, Wenzelburger J (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Gersbach, and J.  Wenzelburger, &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Fak. Für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> H. Gersbach and J. Wenzelburger, &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, 2002.</ieee>
<harvard1>Gersbach, H., &amp;amp; Wenzelburger, J., 2002. &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</harvard1>
<apa>Gersbach, H., &amp;amp; Wenzelburger, J. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gersbach, H., &amp;amp; Wenzelburger, J. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Gersbach, H., and Wenzelburger, J. (2002). The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective. &lt;em&gt;Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</frontiers>
<mla>Gersbach, Hans, and Wenzelburger, Jan. &lt;em&gt;The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, 2002. Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.</mla>
<wels>Gersbach, H.; Wenzelburger, J. (2002): The workout of banking crises. A macroeconomic perspective. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</wels>
<default>Gersbach H, Wenzelburger J (2002)  Diskussionspapier - Fakultät für Wirtschaftswissenschaften, Universität Bielefeld.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, Fak. für Wirtschaftswissenschaften.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2316957</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-16T14:32:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>