<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2316427</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">170941</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies the properties of convexity (concavity) and strategic complements (substitutes) in network formation and the implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks. First, different definitions of convexity (concavity) in own links from the literature are put into the context of diminishing marginal utility of own links. Second, it is shown that there always exists a pairwise stable network as long as the utility function of each player satisfies convexity in own links and strategic complements. For network societies with a profile of utility functions satisfying concavity in own links and strategic complements, a local uniqueness property of pairwise stable networks is derived. The results do neither require any specification on the utility function nor any other additional assumptions such as homogeneity.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="423.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2316427/2319865/423.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Existence</topic><topic>Stability</topic><topic>Uniqueness</topic><topic>Supermodularity</topic><topic>Increasing differences</topic><topic>Networks</topic><topic>Game theory</topic><topic>Network formation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-47758</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>423</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Hellmann, Tim. &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 423.</mla>
<default>Hellmann T (2009)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 423.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<lncs> Hellmann, T.: Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 423. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, Tim. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 423. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Hellmann, T., 2009. &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.423, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, T. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 423). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hellmann T (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 423.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hellmann, &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hellmann, T. (2009): Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa>Hellmann, T. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 423). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> T. Hellmann, &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 423,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009.</ieee>
<ama>Hellmann T. &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 423. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2009.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, T. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hellmann, T. (2009). Convexity and complementarity in network formation. Implications for the structure of pairwise stable networks. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 423, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2316427</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-16T07:26:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>