<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2316445</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trockel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62508</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9827-6424</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper provides four axioms that uniquely characterize the sequential Raiffa solution proposed by Raiffa (1951, 1953) for two-person bargaining games. Three of these axioms are standard and are shared by several popular bargaining solutions. They suffice to characterize these solutions on TU-bargaining games where they coincide. The fourth axiom is a weakening of Kalai's (1977) axiom of step-by-step negotiating and turns out to be sort of a dual condition to a weaker version of Nash's IIA-axiom that together with the three standard axioms suffices to characterize the Nash bargaining solution due to Nash (1950). A conclusion of this axiomatization is that in contrast to all other known bargaining solutions the sequential Raiffa solution does not represent just another kind of fairness or equity condition in addition to the three standard axioms but rather is determined by indefinite repeated application of the three standard axioms.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="425.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2316445/2319869/425.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Nash solution</topic><topic>Axiomatization</topic><topic>Raiffa solution</topic><topic>Bargaining games</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-47829</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>425</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Trockel W. &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 425. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2009.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, W. (2009). &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Trockel, W. (2009). An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 425, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<apa>Trockel, W. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 425). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> W. Trockel, &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 425,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009.</ieee>
<wels>Trockel, W. (2009): An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, W. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 425). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Trockel W (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 425.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<harvard1>Trockel, W., 2009. &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.425, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Trockel, &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Trockel, W.: An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 425. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trockel, Walter. 2009. &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 425. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Trockel, Walter. &lt;em&gt;An axiomatization of the sequential Raiffa solution&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2009. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 425.</mla>
<default>Trockel W (2009)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 425.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2316445</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-16T08:01:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>