<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2316137</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Marchiori</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patrice</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pieretti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benteng</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">How do high and low skilled migration affect fertility and human capital in migrants' origin countries? This question is analyzed within an overlapping generations model where parents choose the number of high and low skilled children they would like to have. Individuals migrate with a certain probability and remit to their parents. It is shown that a brain drain induces parents to have more high and less low educated children. Under certain conditions fertility may either rise or decline due to a brain drain. Low skilled emigration leads to reversed results, while the overall impact on human capital of either type of migration remains ambiguous. Subsequently, the model is calibrated on a developing economy. It is found that increased high skilled emigration reduces fertility and fosters human capital accumulation, while low skilled emigration induces higher population growth and a lower level of education.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="409.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2316137/2319850/409.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Fertility</topic><topic>Migration</topic><topic>Human capital</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-14185</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>409</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Marchiori L, Pieretti P, Zou B. &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 409. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2008.</ama>
<ieee> L. Marchiori, P. Pieretti, and B. Zou, &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 409,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</ieee>
<harvard1>Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P., &amp;amp; Zou, B., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.409, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Marchiori, Luca, Pieretti, Patrice, and Zou, Benteng. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 409. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P., Zou, B.: Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 409. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<apa>Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 409). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<mla>Marchiori, Luca, Pieretti, Patrice, and Zou, Benteng. &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 409.</mla>
<frontiers>Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P., and Zou, B. (2008). Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 409, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 409). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Marchiori, L., Pieretti, P. &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Marchiori, L.; Pieretti, P.; Zou, B. (2008): Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<bio1>Marchiori L, Pieretti P, Zou B (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 409.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Marchiori, P.  Pieretti, and B.  Zou, &lt;em&gt;Migration and human capital in an endogenous fertility model&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Marchiori L, Pieretti P, Zou B (2008)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 409.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2316137</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-15T11:02:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>