<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2316258</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jäger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koch-Metzger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7584609</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4244291</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4291-6610</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015251</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study a communication game of common interest in which the sender observes one of infinite types and sends one of finite messages which is interpreted by the receiver. In equilibrium there is no full separation but types are clustered into convex categories. We give a full characterization of the strict Nash equilibria of this game by representing these categories by Voronoi languages. As the strategy set is infinite static stability concepts for finite games such as ESS are no longer sufficient for Lyapunov stability in the replicator dynamics. We give examples of unstable strict Nash equilibria and stable inefficient Voronoi languages. We derive efficient Voronoi languages with a large number of categories and numerically illustrate stability of some Voronoi languages with large message spaces and non-uniformly distributed types.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="420.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2316258/2319858/420.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Communication game</topic><topic>Dynamic stability</topic><topic>Cheap talk</topic><topic>Voronoi tesselation</topic><topic>Signaling game</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-15602</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>420</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Jäger G, Koch-Metzger L, Riedel F (2008)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 420.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Jäger, Gerhard, Koch-Metzger, Lars, and Riedel, Frank. &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 420.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jäger, Gerhard, Koch-Metzger, Lars, and Riedel, Frank. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 420. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L., Riedel, F.: Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 420. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<ieee> G. Jäger, L. Koch-Metzger, and F. Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 420,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 420). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<frontiers>Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L., and Riedel, F. (2008). Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 420, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L. &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Jäger G, Koch-Metzger L, Riedel F. &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 420. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2008.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Jäger, L.  Koch-Metzger, and F.  Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L., &amp;amp; Riedel, F., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.420, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Jäger G, Koch-Metzger L, Riedel F (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 420.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jäger, G., Koch-Metzger, L., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 420). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Jäger, G.; Koch-Metzger, L.; Riedel, F. (2008): Voronoi languages. Equilibria in cheap-talk games with high-dimensional types and few signals. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2316258</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-15T12:11:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>