<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2317235</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Faist</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">151480</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">107034251</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Academic and public debates on the migration-development nexus often raise the question whether and in what ways social scientific research may form a basis for rational political decisions. The main thesis of this article is that such questions are misleading. Social scientific research may instead offer crucial stimuli for describing, understanding and explaining the migration-development nexus. This means that sociological analysis of the theory-praxis link should go beyond the focus on research and policy and bring in much more forcefully social scientists’ role in the public sphere.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_71_Faist.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2317235/2319903/workingpaper_71_Faist.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48521</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Faist, T. (2010). Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<mla>Faist, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faist, T. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Faist, T. (2010): Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<default>Faist T (2010)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<ieee> T. Faist, &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010.</ieee>
<harvard1>Faist, T., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<apa>Faist, T. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faist, T. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Faist T (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Faist, &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Faist T. &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2010.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faist, Thomas. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Faist, T.: Academic knowledge, policy and the public role of social scientists. The case of migration and development. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 71. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2317235</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T09:02:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>