<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2317281</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gabriele</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tomei</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Strength of ties and amplitude/frequency of contacts with other natives (living at home and/or abroad), are generally considered the main proxy indicators of a transnational structuration of migrant groups and the principal evidences of a diaspora. Despite of this evidence, there are (at least) other three cultural and sociological conditions that make this outcomes possible or not: (i) belonging of the migrant group members to a wider transnational network, (ii) sharing a common sense of community with its members, (iii) participating with a common project that involve all the community.
The paper discusses the main outputs of an on-line survey between young foreigners attendingthe University of Pisa, with the aim to investigate how "sense of community" (McMillan and Chavis, 1986), "social capital" (Van der Gaag-Snijders, 2004) and co-development orientation between members of the same ethnic groups (living in Italy or abroad), could help researcher to identify, conceptualize and measure everyday and informal transnational relationship becoming to a new definition of the concept of diaspora (Cohen, 1997; Cohen, Vertovec, 1999).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_59_tomei.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2317281/2319908/workingpaper_59_tomei.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48646</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Tomei, G., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<ieee> G. Tomei, &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Tomei, G. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<mla>Tomei, Gabriele. &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59.</mla>
<frontiers>Tomei, G. (2008). Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tomei, G. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Tomei, G. (2008): Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<default>Tomei G (2008)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<ama>Tomei G. &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2008.</ama>
<lncs> Tomei, G.: Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tomei, Gabriele. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tomei, G. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Tomei, &lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Tomei G (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diasporic identity and orientation to co-development. A survey on foreign students attending the University of Pisa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 59.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2317281</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T10:06:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>