<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2317210</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bruno</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dupeyron</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Methodological nationalism restricts the focus on transnational migrants in Europe, in particular in the Upper-Rhine border area (France-Germany-Switzerland). Three main limitations can be underlined: to start with, the ignorance of nationalism in contemporary social science research, including in migration and border studies; moreover, the naturalization of the nation-state that contributes to shape numerous social science biases; finally, territorial limitations that constrain research topics (Wimmer and Glick Schiller 2002).
To overcome those issues, this research combines three methodological perspectives: first, a socio-historical analysis of transnational migrants in the Rhineland area, in order to comprehend past and contemporary dynamics; second, a socio-political approach that stresses the migrants’ "ways of being" (Glick Schiller 2005), including their activism and rhetoric, e.g. direct observations and interviews in multiple sites; third, a pluri-scalar approach that implies several levels of analysis, e.g. local, regional, cross-border, transnational and supra-national.
The analysis of transnational migrants’ public action in the Rhineland Valley suggests a triple hypothesis: those transnational migrants’ activists elaborate a public  iscourse against a specific political and social stigmatization (Becker [1963] 1997); they also institutionalize and reinforce social movements with highly trained lawyers that defend their interests at the highest European jurisdictional level; they create empirically an original form of transnational quasi-trade unions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_79_Dupeyron.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2317210/2319895/workingpaper_79_Dupeyron.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48449</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>79</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dupeyron, B. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 79). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Dupeyron B (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers; 79.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dupeyron, B., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, no.79, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Dupeyron, &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Dupeyron, B. (2010): Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<apa>Dupeyron, B. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 79). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<ieee> B. Dupeyron, &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, vol. 79,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010.</ieee>
<ama>Dupeyron B. &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. Vol 79. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2010.</ama>
<frontiers>Dupeyron, B. (2010). Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers&lt;/em&gt;, 79, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dupeyron, B. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Dupeyron, Bruno. &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. 79.</mla>
<default>Dupeyron B (2010)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers; 79.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<lncs> Dupeyron, B.: Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 79. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dupeyron, Bruno. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Transnational migrants in Europe. Stigmatization, juridicization and trade union activism&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 79. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2317210</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T08:24:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T12:32:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>