<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2317229</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David Scott</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fitzgerald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Building on the transnationalism literature, I argue for multi-sited fieldwork in countries of migrants’ origin and destination and the removal of national blinders so that both domestic and international migrations are brought into the same frame for comparison. Such an approach can move beyond description alone by amending the extended case method to engage theoretical research programs in ways that attend to the representativeness of a case study. The analytical fruit of these strategies is demonstrated with examples from the migration literature and ten years of ethnographic and survey fieldwork among Mexican migrants.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_73_Fitzgerald.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2317229/2319901/workingpaper_73_Fitzgerald.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48501</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Fitzgerald, D. S. (2010): Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<mla>Fitzgerald, David Scott. &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fitzgerald, D. S. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Fitzgerald, D. S. (2010). Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<default>Fitzgerald DS (2010)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<ieee> D.S. Fitzgerald, &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010.</ieee>
<harvard1>Fitzgerald, D.S., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<apa>Fitzgerald, D. S. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fitzgerald, D.S. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Fitzgerald DS (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D. S.  Fitzgerald, &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Fitzgerald DS. &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2010.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fitzgerald, David Scott. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Fitzgerald, D.S.: Mixing methods and crossing boundaries in the study of international migration. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 73. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2317229</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T08:51:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>