<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2317216</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabeth</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Scheibelhofer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_77_Scheibelhofer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2317216/2319897/workingpaper_77_Scheibelhofer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48463</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Scheibelhofer E (2010)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<mla>Scheibelhofer, Elisabeth. &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Scheibelhofer, Elisabeth. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Scheibelhofer, E.: Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Scheibelhofer, &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Scheibelhofer, E., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Scheibelhofer, E. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Scheibelhofer E (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<wels>Scheibelhofer, E. (2010): Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<ieee> E. Scheibelhofer, &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010.</ieee>
<apa>Scheibelhofer, E. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<frontiers>Scheibelhofer, E. (2010). Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Scheibelhofer, E. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Scheibelhofer E. &lt;em&gt;Space-sensible sociology of migration. How migration research can profit of socio-spatial theories&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 77. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2010.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2317216</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T08:32:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>