<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2318212</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The focus of this article is the exploration of the impact of the Diasporic Identity of second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany working in the field of Information and Communication Technology (ICT) on their entrepreneurial behaviour and here particularly, on their business engagement in Turkey. One obvious rational reason for business engagement in Turkey is the overall business climate and the promising profit maximising opportunities. Purely intuitive reasoning, thus feelings directly steered from "Diasporic Identity", refers to an overall emotional attachment and nationalistic attempts such as the strong desire to contribute to the development of the home country. Additionally, Turkish language skills and cultural sensitivity incorporate some elements that are rooted in "Diasporic Identity" that turn into rational competitive advantages. Finally, second generation entrepreneurs are distinct from their first generation counterparts. Differences include educational and professional skills and abilities, the transnational nature of the ICT business and opportunities to cross borders on physical, symbolic, virtual and mental ways.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_56_schulte.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2318212/2319911/workingpaper_56_schulte.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48672</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Schulte B. &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2008.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulte, B. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Schulte, B. (2008). Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<apa>Schulte, B. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<ieee> B. Schulte, &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008.</ieee>
<wels>Schulte, B. (2008): Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<harvard1>Schulte, B., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<bio1>Schulte B (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulte, B. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Schulte, &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Schulte, B.: Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schulte, Bettina. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Schulte, Bettina. &lt;em&gt;Second generation entrepreneurs of Turkish origin in Germany. Diasporic identity and business engagement&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56.</mla>
<default>Schulte B (2008)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 56.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2318212</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T11:47:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>