<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2318221</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jary</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Saraswati</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">More than 10,5 million Indonesians are seeking work. Neither under-qualification for labour nor discouragement is to blame for this high unemployment, but rather the low productive investment rate and unhealthy investment climate. Facing the 9.75 percent unemployment rate and increasing poverty, Indonesia’s government has tried to develop the potential of TKI (Indonesian Migrant Worker) programme seriously since 2004. TKI programme contributes around half a million occupations per year. Indonesian government registered a substantial rate of foreign income from this sector. Yet behind these nice figures, migrant workers have to face numerous problems and – in many cases – abuse. In 2002 alone, there were at least 1.3 million cases of migrant workers, e.g. death (by falling from buildings), sexual harassment/ abuse, confinement, extortion, document fraud, underpayment/unpaid wages and illegal placement. Human trafficking has been also found amongst illegal placement of migrant workers. Most victims are women and children. Indonesian government has tried several policies to improve the protection of migrant workers and to simplify the placement procedures. Illegal and criminal brokerage as well as insufficient bilateral agreements with employer countries are identified as major problems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_53_saraswati.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2318221/2319914/workingpaper_53_saraswati.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48703</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Saraswati, J.: "Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saraswati, Jary. 2008. &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Saraswati, Jary. &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53.</mla>
<default>Saraswati J (2008)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<ama>Saraswati J. &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2008.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saraswati, J. (2008). &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Saraswati, J. (2008). "Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<apa>Saraswati, J. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<ieee> J. Saraswati, &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008.</ieee>
<wels>Saraswati, J. (2008): "Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<harvard1>Saraswati, J., 2008. &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<bio1>Saraswati J (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saraswati, J. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 53). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Saraswati, &lt;em&gt;"Where we can go?" Indonesia’s struggle against unemployment and man-power export phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2318221</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T11:58:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>