<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2318336</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mundt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_30_Mundt.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2318336/2319938/workingpaper_30_Mundt.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48932</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Mundt, H. - W. (2007): Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<bio1>Mundt H-W (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<harvard1>Mundt, H.-W., 2007. &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mundt, H. - W. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>H. - W.  Mundt, &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Mundt H-W. &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2007.</ama>
<frontiers>Mundt, H. - W. (2007). Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options? &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mundt, H.-W. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Mundt, H. - W. (2007).  &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<ieee> H.-W. Mundt, &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2007.</ieee>
<lncs> Mundt, H.-W.: Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options? COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mundt, Hans-Werner. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Mundt, Hans-Werner. &lt;em&gt;Development-oriented activities of immigrant communities in Germany. What do we know? What are the policy options?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2007. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30.</mla>
<default>Mundt H-W (2007)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 30.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2318336</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T13:58:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>