<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2318238</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingrid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jungwirth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, the question of social change for women as actors of migration is examined. Apart from feminist theory and international gender studies, this topic is located in migration studies and social theory as well. It is proposed to analyse the transformation of gender norms in processes of migration in connection with the changes taking place in the domain of labour, namely the increasing tertiarisation in post-industrial societies on the one hand, and a globalising economy and international distribution of labour following from this on the other. A concept for transnational gender orders is outlined, proposing that, along with these economic and structural processes, normative requirements and ascriptions for social actors are emerging as well. They target the gender performance of women as actors of migration, insofar as an assumed universal gender socialisation as women is becoming a qualification and resource in an international distribution of labour.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_48_jungwirth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2318238/2319919/workingpaper_48_jungwirth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48755</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Jungwirth I (2008)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<mla>Jungwirth, Ingrid. &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jungwirth, Ingrid. 2008. &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jungwirth, I.: The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2008).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Jungwirth, &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jungwirth, I. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Jungwirth, I., 2008. &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<bio1>Jungwirth I (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<wels>Jungwirth, I. (2008): The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<ieee> I. Jungwirth, &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Jungwirth, I. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<frontiers>Jungwirth, I. (2008). The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jungwirth, I. (2008). &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Jungwirth I. &lt;em&gt;The change of normative gender orders in the process of migration. A transnational perspective&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 48. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2008.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2318238</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-17T12:22:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>