<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2319711</id><setSpec>book_editor</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:book</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_editorFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>






<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Faist</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">151480</identifier></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Pirkko</namePart><namePart type="family">Pitkänen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart><namePart type="family">Gerdes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7585135</identifier></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eveline</namePart><namePart type="family">Reisenauer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5641662</identifier></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">107034251</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Media and Citizenship: Transnational Television Cultures Reshaping Political Identity in the European Union</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_87_TRANS_NET.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2319711/2319968/workingpaper_87_TRANS_NET.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-48367</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>87</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Faist T., Pitkänen P., Gerdes J., &amp;amp; Reisenauer E. (Eds.) (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 87). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faist, Thomas, Pitkänen, Pirkko, Gerdes, Jürgen, and Reisenauer, Eveline, eds. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 87. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Faist, T., Pitkänen, P., Gerdes, J., Reisenauer, E. eds: Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 87. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
<ieee> T. Faist, et al., eds., &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, vol. 87,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010.</ieee>
<harvard1>T.  Faist, et al., eds., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, no.87, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<ama>Faist T, Pitkänen P, Gerdes J, Reisenauer E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. Vol 87. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2010.</ama>
<default>Faist T, Pitkänen P, Gerdes J, Reisenauer E (Eds) (2010)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers; 87.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
<bio1>Faist T, Pitkänen P, Gerdes J, Reisenauer E (Eds) (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers; 87.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>&lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Thomas Faist; Pirkko Pitkänen; Jürgen Gerdes; Eveline Reisenauer (Hrsg.) (2010): Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<frontiers>Faist, T., Pitkänen, P., Gerdes, J., and Reisenauer, E. eds. (2010). Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers&lt;/em&gt;, 87, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faist T., Pitkänen P., Gerdes J., &amp;amp; Reisenauer E. (Eds.) (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers, 87). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Thomas Faist, Pirkko Pitkänen, Jürgen Gerdes, and Eveline Reisenauer, eds. &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2010. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers. 87.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers). (2010). &lt;em&gt;Transnationalisation and Institutional Transformations. Collected Working Papers from the TRANS-NET Project&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - working papers).  (T. Faist, P. Pitkänen, J. Gerdes &amp;amp; E. Reisenauer, Hrsg.). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2319711</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-23T07:27:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:52:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>