<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2400506</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">McCrae</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15477100</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7227-1331</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mauricio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Espinoza</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Montiel-Ponsoda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Guadalupe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aguado-de-Cea</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paper_3.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2400506/2526058/paper_3.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24005060</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">116-125</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>McCrae, John, Espinoza, Mauricio, Montiel-Ponsoda, Elena, Aguado-de-Cea, Guadalupe, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011. 116-125.</mla>
<default>McCrae J, Espinoza M, Montiel-Ponsoda E, Aguado-de-Cea G, Cimiano P (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5).  116-125.</default>
<lncs> McCrae, J., Espinoza, M., Montiel-Ponsoda, E., Aguado-de-Cea, G., Cimiano, P.: Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5). p. 116-125. (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;McCrae, John, Espinoza, Mauricio, Montiel-Ponsoda, Elena, Aguado-de-Cea, Guadalupe, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2011. “Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;, 116-125.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>McCrae, J., Espinoza, M., Montiel-Ponsoda, E., Aguado-de-Cea, G., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2011). Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;, 116-125.</apa>
<ieee> J. McCrae, et al., “Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;, 2011,  pp.116-125.</ieee>
<ama>McCrae J, Espinoza M, Montiel-Ponsoda E, Aguado-de-Cea G, Cimiano P. Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011: 116-125.</ama>
<frontiers>McCrae, J., Espinoza, M., Montiel-Ponsoda, E., Aguado-de-Cea, G., and Cimiano, P. (2011). “Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt; 116-125.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;McCrae, J., Espinoza, M., Montiel-Ponsoda, E., Aguado-de-Cea, G. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2011). Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 116-125).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>McCrae J, Espinoza M, Montiel-Ponsoda E, Aguado-de-Cea G, Cimiano P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5).  116-125.</bio1>
<harvard1>McCrae, J., et al., 2011. Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 116-125.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;McCrae, J., Espinoza, M., Montiel-Ponsoda, E., Aguado-de-Cea, G., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2011). Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;, 116-125.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  McCrae, M.  Espinoza, E.  Montiel-Ponsoda, G.  Aguado-de-Cea, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 116-125.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>McCrae, J.; Espinoza, M.; Montiel-Ponsoda, E.; Aguado-de-Cea, G.; Cimiano, P. (2011): Combining statistical and semantic approaches to the translation of ontologies and taxonomies. In: Proceedings of the Fifth workshop on Syntax, Structure and Semantics in Statistical Translation (SSST-5).  S. 116-125.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2400506</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-10-12T09:44:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>