<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2427822</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sheik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stefanini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neftci</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Indiveri</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In the past recent years several research groups have proposed neuromorphic Very Large Scale Integration (VLSI) devices that implement event-based sensors or biophysically realistic networks of spiking neurons. It has been argued that these devices can be used to build event-based systems, for solving real-world applications in real-time, with efficiencies and robustness that cannot be achieved with conventional computing technologies. In order to implement complex event-based neuromorphic systems it is necessary to interface the neuromorphic VLSI sensors and devices among each other, to robotic platforms, and to workstations (e.g. for data-logging and analysis). This apparently simple goal requires painstaking work that spans multiple levels of complexity and disciplines: from the custom layout of microelectronic circuits and asynchronous printed circuit boards, to the development of object oriented classes and methods in software; from electrical engineering and physics for analog/digital circuit design to neuroscience and computer science for neural computation and spike-based learning methods. Within this context, we present a framework we developed to simplify the configuration of multi-chip neuromorphic VLSI systems, and automate the mapping of neural network model parameters to neuromorphic circuit bias values.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Systematic_configuration_and_automatic_tuning_of_neuromorphic_systems.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2427822/2459878/Systematic_configuration_and_automatic_tuning_of_neuromorphic_systems.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Rio de Janeiro, Brasil</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>VLSI</topic><topic>neural nets</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4244-9473-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24278222</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">873-876</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, E. &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2011). Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems (S. 873-876). Gehalten auf der International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS). doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Sheik S, Stefanini F, Neftci E, Chicca E, Indiveri G (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Sheik, F.  Stefanini, E.  Neftci, E.  Chicca, and G.  Indiveri, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 873-876.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Sheik S, Stefanini F, Neftci E, Chicca E, Indiveri G. Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.</ama>
<lncs> Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G.: Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, Elisabetta, and Indiveri, G. 2011. “Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems”. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil , 873-876.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., and Indiveri, G. (2011).“Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems”. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.</frontiers>
<mla>Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, Elisabetta, and Indiveri, G. “Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems”. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil, 2011.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2011). &lt;em&gt;Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Sheik, S.; Stefanini, F.; Neftci, E.; Chicca, E.; Indiveri, G. (2011): Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems.  S. 873-876.</wels>
<default>Sheik S, Stefanini F, Neftci E, Chicca E, Indiveri G (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.</default>
<ieee> S. Sheik, et al., “Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems”, Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil, 2011.</ieee>
<harvard1>Sheik, S., et al., 2011. Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.</harvard1>
<apa>Sheik, S., Stefanini, F., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2011). &lt;em&gt;Systematic configuration and automatic tuning of neuromorphic systems&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Rio de Janeiro, Brasil. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/ISCAS.2011.5937705&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2427822</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-11-24T13:44:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>