<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2427661</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beyeler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stefanini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Proske</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Galizia</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Olfactory stimuli are represented in a high-
dimensional space by neural networks of the olfactory system.
A great deal of research in olfaction has focused on this
representation within the first processing stage, the olfactory bulb
(vertebrates) or antennal lobe (insects) glomeruli. In particular
the mapping of chemical stimuli onto olfactory glomeruli and
the relation of this mapping to perceptual qualities have been
investigated. While a number of studies have illustrated the
importance of inhibitory networks within the olfactory bulb or
the antennal lobe for the shaping and processing of olfactory
information, it is not clear how exactly these inhibitory networks
are organized to provide filtering and contrast enhancement
capabilities. In this work the aim is to study the topology
of the proposed networks by using software simulations and
hardware implementation. While we can study the dependence
of the activity on each parameter of the theoretical models
with the simulations, it is important to understand whether the
models can be used in robotic applications for real-time odor
recognition. We present the results of a linear simulation, a
spiking simulation with I&amp;F neurons and a real-time hardware
emulation using neuromorphic VLSI chips. We used an input
data set of neurophysiological recordings from olfactory receptive
neurons of insects, especially Drosophila.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Exploring_Olfactory_Sensory_Networks__Simulations_and_Hardware_Emulation.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2427661/2459884/Exploring_Olfactory_Sensory_Networks__Simulations_and_Hardware_Emulation.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Paphos</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4244-7269-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24276610</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">270-273</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Beyeler, M.; Stefanini, F.; Proske, H.; Galizia, G.; Chicca, E. (2010): Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation.  S. 270-273.</wels>
<bio1>Beyeler M, Stefanini F, Proske H, Galizia G, Chicca E (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos.</bio1>
<harvard1>Beyeler, M., et al., 2010. Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Beyeler, F.  Stefanini, H.  Proske, G.  Galizia, and E.  Chicca, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 270-273.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Beyeler M, Stefanini F, Proske H, Galizia G, Chicca E. Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos.</ama>
<frontiers>Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., and Chicca, E. (2010).“Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G. &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2010). Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation (S. 270-273). Gehalten auf der Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS). doi:10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2010.5709623&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> M. Beyeler, et al., “Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation”, Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos, 2010.</ieee>
<lncs> Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., Chicca, E.: Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., and Chicca, Elisabetta. 2010. “Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos , 270-273.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Beyeler, M., Stefanini, F., Proske, H., Galizia, G., and Chicca, Elisabetta. “Exploring Olfactory Sensory Networks: Simulations and Hardware Emulation”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos, 2010.</mla>
<default>Beyeler M, Stefanini F, Proske H, Galizia G, Chicca E (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Paphos.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2427661</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-11-24T13:25:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>