<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2427789</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H.-P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Indiveri</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T. J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sejnowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Spike-time based coding of neural information, in contrast to rate coding, requires that neurons reliably and precisely fire spikes in response to repeated identical inputs, despite a high degree of noise from stochastic synaptic firing and extraneous background inputs. We investigated the degree of reliability and precision achievable in various noisy background conditions using real-time neuromorphic VLSI hardware which models integrate-and-fire spiking neurons and dynamic synapses. To do so, we varied two properties of the inputs to a single neuron, synaptic weight and synchrony magnitude (number of synchronously firing pre-synaptic neurons). Thanks to the realtime response properties of the VLSI system we could carry out extensive exploration of the parameter space, and measure the neurons firing rate and reliability in real-time. Reliability of output spiking was primarily influenced by the amount of synchronicity of synaptic input, rather than the synaptic weight of those synapses. These results highlight possible regimes in which real-time neuromorphic systems might be better able to reliably compute with spikes despite noisy input.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Reliable_Computation_in_Noisy_Backgrounds_Using_Real-Time_Neuromorphic_Hardware.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2427789/2459946/Reliable_Computation_in_Noisy_Backgrounds_Using_Real-Time_Neuromorphic_Hardware.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Montreal, Que.</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>stochastic processes</topic><topic>reliability</topic><topic>real-time systems</topic><topic>VLSI</topic><topic>neural chips</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4244-1524-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24277896</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">71-74</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Wang H-P, Chicca E, Indiveri G, Sejnowski TJ (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que.</default>
<mla>Wang, H.-P., Chicca, Elisabetta, Indiveri, G., and Sejnowski, T. J. “Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que., 2007.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, H.-P., Chicca, Elisabetta, Indiveri, G., and Sejnowski, T. J. 2007. “Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que. , 71-74.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wang, H.-P., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G., Sejnowski, T.J.: Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que. (2007).</lncs>
<ieee> H.-P. Wang, et al., “Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware”, Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que., 2007.</ieee>
<apa>Wang, H. - P., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G., &amp;amp; Sejnowski, T. J. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<frontiers>Wang, H. - P., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G., and Sejnowski, T. J. (2007).“Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware”. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, H.-P., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G. &amp;amp; Sejnowski, T.J. (2007). Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware (S. 71-74). Gehalten auf der Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS). doi:10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wang H-P, Chicca E, Indiveri G, Sejnowski TJ. Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H. - P.  Wang, E.  Chicca, G.  Indiveri, and T. J.  Sejnowski, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 71-74.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Wang, H.-P., et al., 2007. Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, H. - P., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G., &amp;amp; Sejnowski, T. J. (2007). &lt;em&gt;Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/BIOCAS.2007.4463311&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Wang H-P, Chicca E, Indiveri G, Sejnowski TJ (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BIOCAS), Montreal, Que.</bio1>
<wels>Wang, H. - P.; Chicca, E.; Indiveri, G.; Sejnowski, T. J. (2007): Reliable Computation in Noisy Backgrounds Using Real-Time Neuromorphic Hardware.  S. 71-74.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2427789</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-11-24T13:29:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>