<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2445268</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emily</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Finne</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14402624</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-6736-0022</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bucksch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19648218</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lampert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kolip</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14955037</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1052-5869</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21334</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Physical activity (PA) shows a marked decline during adolescence. Some studies have pointed to
pubertal status or timing as possible PA determinants in this age group. Furthermore, it was supposed that the
impact of pubertal changes on PA might be mediated by psychological variables like body dissatisfaction (BDS).
Methods: The 11- to 17-year-old subsample of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS) was
used (n = 6 813; 51.3% male, response rate = 66.6%). Through sex-specific sequential multinomial logistic
regressions we analysed the univariate and independent associations of chronological age, absolute pubertal
status, relative pubertal timing, and BDS with the frequency of PA.
Results: Chronological age showed a significantly negative association with PA in both sexes, independent of
puberty. The odds of inactivity in contrast to nearly daily PA increased about 70% in boys and 35% in girls for each
year of age, respectively. Adjusted for age and other possible confounders, inactivity was significantly less likely for
boys in late pubertal stages (OR = 0.27, 95% CI = 0.09-0.78). The risk of inactivity was more than doubled in boys
maturing earlier than peers in terms of relative pubertal timing (OR = 2.20, 95% CI = 1.36-3.56). No clear significant
puberty effects were found in girls, but the inactivity was more likely for those with irregular menstruation (OR =
1.71, 95% CI = 1.06-2.75). BDS also contributed to the prediction of PA in both sexes. It partially mediated puberty
effects in boys but not in girls.
Conclusions: Overall, chronological age was a far more important predictor of PA in German adolescents than
absolute pubertal status or relative pubertal timing. Further possible explanatory variables like sociocultural
influences, social support or increasing time requirements for education should be analysed in conjunction with
chronological age in future studies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1479-5868-8-119.finne.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2445268/2467314/1479-5868-8-119.finne.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>adolescents</topic><topic>physical activity</topic><topic>pubertal timing</topic><topic>sexual maturation</topic><topic>body dissatisfaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1479-5868</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">22032266</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000297706500001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24452687</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-8-119</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Finne, E.; Bucksch, J.; Lampert, T.; Kolip, P. (2011): Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS) &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;,8:(1):119</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Finne, J.  Bucksch, T.  Lampert, and P.  Kolip, “Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS)”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, : 119.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Finne, E., et al., 2011. Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1): 119.</harvard1>
<bio1>Finne E, Bucksch J, Lampert T, Kolip P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS).&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 8(1): 119.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Finne, E., Bucksch, J., Lampert, T., &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2011). Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 119. doi:10.1186/1479-5868-8-119&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Finne, E., Bucksch, J., Lampert, T., and Kolip, P. (2011). Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt; 8:119.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Finne, E., Bucksch, J., Lampert, T. &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2011). Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 119. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1479-5868-8-119.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Finne E, Bucksch J, Lampert T, Kolip P. Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;. 2011;8(1): 119.</ama>
<ieee> E. Finne, et al., “Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS)”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2011, : 119.</ieee>
<apa>Finne, E., Bucksch, J., Lampert, T., &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2011). Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 119. doi:10.1186/1479-5868-8-119</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Finne, Emily, Bucksch, Jens, Lampert, Thomas, and Kolip, Petra. 2011. “Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS)”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt; 8 (1): 119.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Finne, E., Bucksch, J., Lampert, T., Kolip, P.: Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS). International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity. 8, : 119 (2011).</lncs>
<default>Finne E, Bucksch J, Lampert T, Kolip P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt; 8(1): 119.</default>
<mla>Finne, Emily, Bucksch, Jens, Lampert, Thomas, and Kolip, Petra. “Age, puberty, body dissatisfaction, and physical activity decline in adolescents. Results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey (KiGGS)”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&lt;/em&gt; 8.1 (2011): 119.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2445268</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-12T12:38:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-02T06:05:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>