<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2452128</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard-Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brüning</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8052516</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schnier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20814347</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8408393</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart><namePart type="family">Heylen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrizia</namePart><namePart type="family">Paggio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Kipp</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015530</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Multimodal Interaction (ICMI): Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Maschine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In order to understand and model the non-verbal communicative behavior of humans, qualitative techniques, such as Conversation Analysis, and quantitative techniques, such as 3D motion capturing, need to be combined. Although there has been some recent progress in annotation tools like ELAN or Anvil, there is still a lack of appropriate tool support that enables a concise simultaneous access to both types of data and that shows the relationship between them. Within this work, we present a pre- annotation tool that takes the results from off-the-shelf optical tracking systems, automatically fits an articulated skeleton model, and detects motion segments of individual joints. A sophisticated user interface easily allows the annotating person to find correlations between different joints, analyze the corresponding 3D pose in a reconstructed virtual environment, and to export combined qualitative and quantitative annotations to standard annotation tools. Using this technique we are able to examine complex setups with three persons in tight conversion or largely unconstrained engagement situations of humans and robots.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Brueningetal_header.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2452128/2452136/Brueningetal_header.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Alicante, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>annotation</topic><topic>Motion capturing</topic><topic>Motion segmentation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24521285</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2011). Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In D.  Heylen, P.  Paggio, &amp;amp; M.  Kipp (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ieee> B.-A. Brüning, et al., “Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;, D. Heylen, P. Paggio, and M. Kipp, eds., 2011.</ieee>
<ama>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S. Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In: Heylen D, Paggio P, Kipp M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2011). Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In D. Heylen, P. Paggio &amp;amp; M. Kipp (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Multimodal Interaction (ICMI): Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Maschine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., and Wachsmuth, S. (2011). “Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;, Heylen, D., Paggio, P., and Kipp, M. eds.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2011). Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In D.  Heylen, P.  Paggio, &amp;amp; M.  Kipp (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future. Heylen D, Paggio P, Kipp M (Eds);.</bio1>
<harvard1>Brüning, B.-A., et al., 2011. Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In D.  Heylen, P.  Paggio, &amp;amp; M.  Kipp, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>B. - A.  Brüning, C.  Schnier, K.  Pitsch, and S.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Heylen, P. Paggio, M. Kipp), &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Brüning, B. - A.; Schnier, C.; Pitsch, K.; Wachsmuth, S. (2011): Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In: Dirk Heylen; Patrizia Paggio; Michael Kipp (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future.</wels>
<mla>Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Pitsch, Karola, and Wachsmuth, Sven. “Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dirk Heylen, Patrizia Paggio, and Michael Kipp. 2011.</mla>
<default>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future. Heylen D, Paggio P, Kipp M (Eds); .</default>
<lncs> Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., Wachsmuth, S.: Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis. In: Heylen, D., Paggio, P., and Kipp, M. (eds.) Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future.  (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Pitsch, Karola, and Wachsmuth, Sven. 2011. “Automatic detection of motion sequences for motion analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICMI Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning: Taking Stock and Roadmapping the Future&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dirk Heylen, Patrizia Paggio, and Michael Kipp.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2452128</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-21T10:35:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>