<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2458719</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arjan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hogenaar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tjalsma</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Priddy</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Meier zu Verl</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart><namePart type="family">Horstmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The social sciences and the humanities taken together contain a heterogeneous range of research disciplines. Almost all existing methods of research can be found within these two domains. Data handling (collecting, processing, selecting, preserving) and publication methods differ greatly. Attitudes in the field towards Open Access of publications as well to research data vary
as well.
It is not possible to cover the total fullness, and complexity, of all the disciplines within these two domains. Our observations will therefore be based upon a number of case studies. Taken together these case studies give a fairly representative picture of the domains, at least of the most common research environments. The main dividing line is between those disciplines creating empirical data, such as survey data in the social sciences and those, especially in the humanities, using existing source material, such as history or text studies. This source material can either be of an analogous or a digital nature. As will be shown in the case studies in many disciplines a mix of created and existing is often combined.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="chapter_E.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2458719/2460458/chapter_E.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universitätsbibliothek</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>archaeology</topic><topic>archives</topic><topic>datasets</topic><topic>open access</topic><topic>research data</topic><topic>social sciences</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-943363-00-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24587199</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.2390/PUB-2011-7</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">165-213</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H., &amp;amp; Priddy, M. (2011). Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 165-213). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-7</apa>
<ieee> A. Hogenaar, H. Tjalsma, and M. Priddy, “Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences”, &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, C. Meier zu Verl and W. Horstmann, eds.,  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2011,  pp.165-213.</ieee>
<ama>Hogenaar A, Tjalsma H, Priddy M. Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In: Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek;  2011: 165-213.</ama>
<frontiers>Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H., and Priddy, M. (2011). “Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences” in &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, Meier zu Verl, C., and Horstmann, W. eds. (Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek), 165-213.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H. &amp;amp; Priddy, M. (2011). Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In C. Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W. Horstmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (S. 165-213). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-7.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H., &amp;amp; Priddy, M., 2011. Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, pp. 165-213.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H., &amp;amp; Priddy, M. (2011). Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 165-213). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-7&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hogenaar A, Tjalsma H, Priddy M (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W (Eds); Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek:  165-213.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Hogenaar, H.  Tjalsma, and M.  Priddy, in &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Meier zu Verl, W. Horstmann), Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 165-213.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hogenaar, A.; Tjalsma, H.; Priddy, M. (2011): Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In: Christian Meier zu Verl; Wolfram Horstmann (Hrsg.):  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.  S. 165-213.</wels>
<mla>Hogenaar, Arjan, Tjalsma, Heiko, and Priddy, Mike. “Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences”. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Christian Meier zu Verl and Wolfram Horstmann. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2011. 165-213.</mla>
<default>Hogenaar A, Tjalsma H, Priddy M (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W (Eds);  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek:  165-213.</default>
<lncs> Hogenaar, A., Tjalsma, H., Priddy, M.: Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences. In: Meier zu Verl, C. and Horstmann, W. (eds.) Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. p. 165-213. Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hogenaar, Arjan, Tjalsma, Heiko, and Priddy, Mike. 2011. “Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences”. In &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Christian Meier zu Verl and Wolfram Horstmann, 165-213. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2458719</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-12T11:06:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>