<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2458733</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Climate Research</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ilse</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hamann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Meier zu Verl</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart><namePart type="family">Horstmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The findings described in the following sections of this chapter are to a large extent based on an analysis of documents available to me at the institution where I work, i.e. in the Data Management department (DM) of the German Climate Computing Centre (DKRZ, Deutsches Klimarechenzentrum), or are part of websites of other institutions in the climate research community. Additional information about aspects of the research infrastructure in climate science comes from what I could glean from the literature and by receiving answers to a questionnaire from senior scientists working at six different institutes in teams conducting research or providing service(s) in this field. In the next sections, frequent reference is made to these information sources, and many of the diagrams and figures shown have been prepared by my colleagues and by the principal investigators of large research projects for a variety of purposes. The figures include depictions of workflows, organisational diagrams highlighting collaborative aspects and easy-to-grasp displays of pathways of information, data and scientific results within the research cycle.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="chapter_F.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2458733/2460424/chapter_F.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universitätsbibliothek</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>climate data</topic><topic>climate modelling</topic><topic>meteorological data</topic><topic>research infrastructure</topic><topic>open access</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-943363-00-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24587339</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.2390/PUB-2011-8</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">215-309</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Hamann I. Climate Research. In: Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek;  2011: 215-309.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hamann, I. (2011). Climate Research. In C. Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W. Horstmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (S. 215-309). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hamann, I. (2011). “Climate Research” in &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, Meier zu Verl, C., and Horstmann, W. eds. (Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek), 215-309.</frontiers>
<apa>Hamann, I. (2011). Climate Research. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 215-309). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-8</apa>
<ieee> I. Hamann, “Climate Research”, &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, C. Meier zu Verl and W. Horstmann, eds.,  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2011,  pp.215-309.</ieee>
<wels>Hamann, I. (2011): Climate Research. In: Christian Meier zu Verl; Wolfram Horstmann (Hrsg.):  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.  S. 215-309.</wels>
<harvard1>Hamann, I., 2011. Climate Research. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, pp. 215-309.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hamann I (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Climate Research. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W (Eds); Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek:  215-309.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hamann, I. (2011). Climate Research. In C.  Meier zu Verl &amp;amp; W.  Horstmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 215-309). Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.2390/PUB-2011-8&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Hamann, in &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Meier zu Verl, W. Horstmann), Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 215-309.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Hamann, I.: Climate Research. In: Meier zu Verl, C. and Horstmann, W. (eds.) Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. p. 215-309. Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hamann, Ilse. 2011. “Climate Research”. In &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Christian Meier zu Verl and Wolfram Horstmann, 215-309. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hamann, Ilse. “Climate Research”. &lt;em&gt;Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Christian Meier zu Verl and Wolfram Horstmann. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2011. 215-309.</mla>
<default>Hamann I (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies on Subject-Specific Requirements for Open Access Infrastructure. Meier zu Verl C, Horstmann W (Eds);  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek:  215-309.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2458733</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-12T11:09:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>