<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2459234</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andy</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lücking</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">158294</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ptock</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16571617</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eleni</namePart><namePart type="family">Efthimiou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Georgios</namePart><namePart type="family">Kouroupetroglou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator According 
to Thomann, is a software tool for assessing the degree of agreement of multiple segmentations of some time-related data (e.g., gesture phases or sign language constituents). The software implements an assessment procedure developed by Bruno Thomann and will be made publicly available. The article discusses the rationale of the agreement assessment procedure and points at future extensions of Staccato.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="LueckingPtockBergmann2011_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2459234/2534556/LueckingPtockBergmann2011_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-34181-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24592340</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_12</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">129-138</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Lücking, S.  Ptock, and K.  Bergmann, in &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Efthimiou, G. Kouroupetroglou), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 129-138.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lücking A, Ptock S, Bergmann K (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G (Eds); Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  129-138.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, A., Ptock, S. &amp;amp; Bergmann, K. (2012). Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In E. Efthimiou &amp;amp; G. Kouroupetroglou (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 129-138). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_12.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, Andy, Ptock, Sebastian, and Bergmann, Kirsten. 2012. “Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann”. In &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eleni Efthimiou and Georgios Kouroupetroglou, 129-138. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lücking, A., Ptock, S., Bergmann, K.: Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In: Efthimiou, E. and Kouroupetroglou, G. (eds.) Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. p. 129-138. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany (2012).</lncs>
<ama>Lücking A, Ptock S, Bergmann K. Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In: Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer;  2012: 129-138.</ama>
<default>Lücking A, Ptock S, Bergmann K (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G (Eds);  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer:  129-138.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, A., Ptock, S., &amp;amp; Bergmann, K. (2012). Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In E.  Efthimiou &amp;amp; G.  Kouroupetroglou (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-138). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_12&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Lücking, A., Ptock, S., and Bergmann, K. (2012). “Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann” in &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Efthimiou, E., and Kouroupetroglou, G. eds. (Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer), 129-138.</frontiers>
<mla>Lücking, Andy, Ptock, Sebastian, and Bergmann, Kirsten. “Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann”. &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eleni Efthimiou and Georgios Kouroupetroglou. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2012. 129-138.</mla>
<wels>Lücking, A.; Ptock, S.; Bergmann, K. (2012): Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In: Eleni Efthimiou; Georgios Kouroupetroglou (Hrsg.):  Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer.  S. 129-138.</wels>
<apa>Lücking, A., Ptock, S., &amp;amp; Bergmann, K. (2012). Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In E.  Efthimiou &amp;amp; G.  Kouroupetroglou (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-138). Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_12</apa>
<harvard1>Lücking, A., Ptock, S., &amp;amp; Bergmann, K., 2012. Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann. In E.  Efthimiou &amp;amp; G.  Kouroupetroglou, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, pp. 129-138.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Lücking, S. Ptock, and K. Bergmann, “Assessing Agreement on Segmentations by Means of Staccato, the Segmentation Agreement Calculator according to Thomann”, &lt;em&gt;Gestures in Embodied Communication and Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, E. Efthimiou and G. Kouroupetroglou, eds.,  Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer, 2012,  pp.129-138.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2459234</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-17T14:26:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>