<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2460200</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:810</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Astrid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6141670</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8628-8129</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eleftheria</namePart><namePart type="family">Arapoglu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mónika</namePart><namePart type="family">Fodor</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jopi</namePart><namePart type="family">Nyman</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38670945</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2014_HAAS_Monroe.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2460200/2937837/2014_HAAS_Monroe.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Routledge</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-415-82305-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24602008</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4324/9780203487730</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30-42</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://www.routledge.com/products/9780415823050</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Haas, “Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America”, &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;, E. Arapoglu, M. Fodor, and J. Nyman, eds., Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature, vol. 18,  New York: Routledge, 2014,  pp.30-42.</ieee>
<harvard1>Haas, A., 2014. Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In E.  Arapoglu, M.  Fodor, &amp;amp; J.  Nyman, eds. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature. no.18  New York: Routledge, pp. 30-42.</harvard1>
<ama>Haas A. Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In: Arapoglu E, Fodor M, Nyman J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature. Vol 18. New York: Routledge;  2014: 30-42.</ama>
<apa>Haas, A. (2014). Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In E.  Arapoglu, M.  Fodor, &amp;amp; J.  Nyman (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature: Vol. 18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 30-42). New York: Routledge. doi:10.4324/9780203487730</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haas, Astrid. 2014. “Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America”. In &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eleftheria Arapoglu, Mónika Fodor, and Jopi Nyman, 18:30-42. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature. New York: Routledge.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Haas, A.: Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In: Arapoglu, E., Fodor, M., and Nyman, J. (eds.) Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature. 18, p. 30-42. Routledge, New York (2014).</lncs>
<wels>Haas, A. (2014): Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In: Eleftheria Arapoglu; Mónika Fodor; Jopi Nyman (Hrsg.):  Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation. New York: Routledge. (Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature, 18).  S. 30-42.</wels>
<frontiers>Haas, A. (2014). “Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America” in &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;, Arapoglu, E., Fodor, M., and Nyman, J. eds. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature, vol. 18, (New York: Routledge), 30-42.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haas, A. (2014). Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. In E.  Arapoglu, M.  Fodor, &amp;amp; J.  Nyman (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature: Vol. 18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 30-42). New York: Routledge. doi:10.4324/9780203487730&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Haas, Astrid. “Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America”. &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eleftheria Arapoglu, Mónika Fodor, and Jopi Nyman. New York: Routledge, 2014.Vol. 18. Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature. 30-42.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haas, A. (2014). Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America (Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature). In E. Arapoglu, M. Fodor &amp;amp; J. Nyman (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt; (S. 30-42). New York: Routledge. doi:10.4324/9780203487730.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Haas A (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation. Arapoglu E, Fodor M, Nyman J (Eds);  Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature, 18.  New York: Routledge:  30-42.</default>
<bio1>Haas A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Between Monroe Doctrine and Manifest Destiny: Spanish American Travel Narratives of Jacksonian America. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation. Arapoglu E, Fodor M, Nyman J (Eds); Routledge interdisciplinary perspectives on literature, 18. New York: Routledge:  30-42.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Haas, in &lt;em&gt;Mobile Narratives: Travel, Migration, and Transculturation&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Arapoglu, M. Fodor, J. Nyman), Routledge, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 30-42.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2460200</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-20T17:27:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-11T19:11:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>