<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2464345</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zehe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26222947</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großhauser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10261456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4th International Workshop on Sensor Networks and Ambient Intelligence (SeNAmI 2012)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present BRIX, a novel modular hardware prototyping platform for applications in mobile, wearable and stationary sensing, data streaming and feedback. The system consists of three different types of compact stack- able modules, which can adapt to various applications and scenarios. The core of BRIX is a base module that contains basic motion sensors, a processor and a wireless interface. A battery module provides power for the system and makes it a mobile device. Different types of extension modules can be stacked onto the base module to extend its scope of functions by sensors, actuators and interactive elements. BRIX allows a very intuitive, inexpensive and expeditious prototyping that does not require knowledge in electronics or hardware design. In an example application, we demonstrate how BRIX can be used to track human body movements.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ZeheGrosshauserHermann2012-BAE-SENAMI.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2464345/2655741/ZeheGrosshauserHermann2012-BAE-SENAMI.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Lugano, Switzerland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>ad-hoc</topic><topic>actuator</topic><topic>physical computing</topic><topic>wearable</topic><topic>sensor network</topic><topic>sensor</topic><topic>toolkit</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4673-0905-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24643453</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/PerComW.2012.6197624</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">817-822</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zehe, S., Großhauser, T. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2012). BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 817-822). Gehalten auf der 4th International Workshop on Sensor Networks and Ambient Intelligence (SeNAmI 2012), Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE. doi:10.1109/PerComW.2012.6197624.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Zehe S, Großhauser T, Hermann T (2012) &lt;br /&gt;BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings.  Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE:  817-822.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Zehe, T.  Großhauser, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Lugano, Swizerland, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 817-822.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Zehe S, Großhauser T, Hermann T. BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. In:  &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE;  2012: 817-822.</ama>
<lncs> Zehe, S., Großhauser, T., Hermann, T.: BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings. p. 817-822. IEEE, Lugano, Swizerland (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zehe, Sebastian, Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. 2012. “BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit”. In &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, 817-822. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Zehe, S.; Großhauser, T.; Hermann, T. (2012): BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. In: Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE.  S. 817-822.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zehe, S., Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2012). BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, 817-822. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE. doi:10.1109/PerComW.2012.6197624&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Zehe, S., Großhauser, T., and Hermann, T. (2012). “BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit” in &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE), 817-822.</frontiers>
<mla>Zehe, Sebastian, Großhauser, Tobias, and Hermann, Thomas. “BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit”. &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE, 2012. 817-822.</mla>
<default>Zehe S, Großhauser T, Hermann T (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE:  817-822.</default>
<ieee> S. Zehe, T. Großhauser, and T. Hermann, “BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit”, &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;,  Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE, 2012,  pp.817-822.</ieee>
<harvard1>Zehe, S., Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2012. BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. In &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.  Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE, pp. 817-822.</harvard1>
<apa>Zehe, S., Großhauser, T., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2012). BRIX - An Easy-to-Use Modular Sensor and Actuator Prototyping Toolkit. &lt;em&gt;Tenth Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, Workshop Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, 817-822. Lugano, Swizerland: IEEE. doi:10.1109/PerComW.2012.6197624</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2464345</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-02-01T07:16:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>