<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2473510</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Corneil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sonnleithner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emre</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neftci</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthew</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cook</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giacomo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Indiveri</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rodney</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Douglas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The ongoing motor output of the brain depends on its remarkable ability to rapidly transform and fuse a variety of sensory streams in real-time. The brain processes these data using networks of neurons that communicate by asynchronous spikes, a technology that is dramatically different from conventional electronic systems. We report here a step towards constructing electronic systems with analogous performance to the brain. Our VLSLI spiking neural network combines in real-time three distinct sources of input data; each is place-encoded on an individual neuronal population that expresses soft Winner-Take-All dynamics. These arrays are combined according to a user-specified function that is embedded in the reciprocal connections between the soft Winner-Take-All populations and an intermediate shared population. The overall network is able to perform function approximation (missing data can be inferred from the available streams) and cue integration (when all input streams are present they enhance one another synergistically). The network performs these tasks with about 80% and 90% reliability, respectively. Our results suggest that with further technical improvement, it may be possible to implement more complex probabilistic models such as Bayesian networks in neuromorphic electronic systems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Real-time_inference_in_a_VLSI_spiking_neural_network.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2473510/2553142/Real-time_inference_in_a_VLSI_spiking_neural_network.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Corneil_etal12.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2473510/2934807/Corneil_etal12.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess"/>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text"> Seoul, South Korea </placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn"> 978-1-4673-0218-0 </identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24735102</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ISCAS.2012.6271788</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">2425-2428</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Corneil, Dane, Sonnleithner, Daniel, Neftci, Emre, Chicca, Elisabetta, Cook, Matthew, Indiveri, Giacomo, and Douglas, Rodney. 2012. “Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network”. In &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 2425-2428. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Corneil, D., Sonnleithner, D., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Cook, M., Indiveri, G., Douglas, R.: Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. 2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems. p. 2425-2428. IEEE, Piscataway, NJ (2012).</lncs>
<ama>Corneil D, Sonnleithner D, Neftci E, et al. Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. In:  &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE;  2012: 2425-2428.</ama>
<bio1>Corneil D, Sonnleithner D, Neftci E, Chicca E, Cook M, Indiveri G, Douglas R (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  2425-2428.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Corneil, D.  Sonnleithner, E.  Neftci, E.  Chicca, M.  Cook, G.  Indiveri, and R.  Douglas, in &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Piscataway, NJ, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 2425-2428.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Corneil, D., Sonnleithner, D., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Cook, M., Indiveri, G. &amp;amp; Douglas, R. (2012). Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 2425-2428). Gehalten auf der International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2012.6271788.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Corneil, D., Sonnleithner, D., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Cook, M., Indiveri, G., &amp;amp; Douglas, R. (2012). Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 2425-2428. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2012.6271788</apa>
<ieee> D. Corneil, et al., “Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network”, &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;,  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2012,  pp.2425-2428.</ieee>
<harvard1>Corneil, D., et al., 2012. Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. In &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, pp. 2425-2428.</harvard1>
<default>Corneil D, Sonnleithner D, Neftci E, Chicca E, Cook M, Indiveri G, Douglas R (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  2425-2428.</default>
<wels>Corneil, D.; Sonnleithner, D.; Neftci, E.; Chicca, E.; Cook, M.; Indiveri, G.; Douglas, R. (2012): Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. In: 2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.  S. 2425-2428.</wels>
<mla>Corneil, Dane, Sonnleithner, Daniel, Neftci, Emre, Chicca, Elisabetta, Cook, Matthew, Indiveri, Giacomo, and Douglas, Rodney. “Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network”. &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2012. 2425-2428.</mla>
<frontiers>Corneil, D., Sonnleithner, D., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Cook, M., Indiveri, G., and Douglas, R. (2012). “Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network” in &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Piscataway, NJ: IEEE), 2425-2428.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Corneil, D., Sonnleithner, D., Neftci, E., Chicca, E., Cook, M., Indiveri, G., &amp;amp; Douglas, R. (2012). Real-time inference in a VLSI spiking neural network. &lt;em&gt;2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 2425-2428. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2012.6271788&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2473510</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-02-27T05:08:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-25T07:49:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>