<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2473495</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sheik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Indiveri</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Axonal delays are used in neural computation to implement faithful models of biological neural systems, and in spiking neural networks models to solve computationally demanding tasks. While there is an increasing number of software simulations of spiking neural networks that make use of axonal delays, only a small fraction of currently existing hardware neuromorphic systems supports them. In this paper we demonstrate a strategy to implement temporal delays in hardware spiking neural networks distributed across multiple Very Large Scale Integration (VLSI) chips. This is achieved by exploiting the inherent device mismatch present in the analog circuits that implement silicon neurons and synapses inside the chips, and the digital communication infrastructure used to configure the network topology and transmit the spikes across chips. We present an example of a recurrent VLSI spiking neural network that employs axonal delays and demonstrate how the proposed strategy efficiently implements them in hardware.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Exploiting_Device_Mismatch_in_Neuromorphic_VLSI_Systems_to_Implement_Axonal_Delays.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2473495/2553139/Exploiting_Device_Mismatch_in_Neuromorphic_VLSI_Systems_to_Implement_Axonal_Delays.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Brisbane, Australia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2161-4393</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24734951</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ijcnn.2012.6252636</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1940-1945</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Chicca, E., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia. doi:10.1109/ijcnn.2012.6252636&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Sheik S, Chicca E, Indiveri G (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia.</bio1>
<harvard1>Sheik, S., Chicca, E., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G., 2012. Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Sheik, E.  Chicca, and G.  Indiveri, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1940-1945.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Sheik, S.; Chicca, E.; Indiveri, G. (2012): Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays.  S. 1940-1945.</wels>
<mla>Sheik, S., Chicca, Elisabetta, and Indiveri, G. “Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays”. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia, 2012.</mla>
<apa>Sheik, S., Chicca, E., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia. doi:10.1109/ijcnn.2012.6252636</apa>
<ieee> S. Sheik, E. Chicca, and G. Indiveri, “Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays”, Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia, 2012.</ieee>
<default>Sheik S, Chicca E, Indiveri G (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia.</default>
<ama>Sheik S, Chicca E, Indiveri G. Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia.</ama>
<lncs> Sheik, S., Chicca, E., Indiveri, G.: Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia (2012).</lncs>
<frontiers>Sheik, S., Chicca, E., and Indiveri, G. (2012).“Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays”. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Chicca, E. &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2012). Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays (S. 1940-1945). Gehalten auf der International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). doi:10.1109/ijcnn.2012.6252636.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sheik, S., Chicca, Elisabetta, and Indiveri, G. 2012. “Exploiting Device Mismatch in Neuromorphic VLSI Systems to Implement Axonal Delays”. Presented at the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Brisbane, Australia , 1940-1945.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2473495</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-02-27T04:49:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>