<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2477687</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kavi J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Littlewood</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">152704</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dominique</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">York</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zoellner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Systemic hypertension often accompanies chronic renal failure and can accelerate its progression to endstage
renal disease (ESRD). Adjunctive moxonidine appeared to have benefits versus adjunctive nitrendipine, in a
randomised double-blind six-month trial in hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure. To understand the longer
term effects and costs of moxonidine, a decision analytic model was developed and a cost-effectiveness analysis performed.
Methods: A Markov model was used to extrapolate results from the trial over three years. All patients started in a non-
ESRD state. After each cycle, patients with a glomerular filtration rate below 15 ml/min had progressed to an ESRD state.
The cost-effectiveness analysis was based on the Dutch healthcare perspective. The main outcome measure was
incremental cost per life-year gained. The percentage of patients progressing to ESRD and cumulative costs were also
compared after three years. In the base case analysis, all patients with ESRD received dialysis.
Results: The model predicted that after three years, 38.9% (95%CI 31.8–45.8) of patients treated with nitrendipine
progressed to ESRD compared to 7.5% (95%CI 3.5–12.7) of patients treated with moxonidine. Treatment with standard
antihypertensive therapy and adjunctive moxonidine was predicted to reduce the number of ESRD cases by 81% over three
years compared to adjunctive nitrendipine.
The cumulative costs per patient were significantly lower in the moxonidine group €9,858 (95% CI 5,501–16,174) than in
the nitrendipine group €37,472 (95% CI 27,957–49,478).
The model showed moxonidine to be dominant compared to nitrendipine, increasing life-years lived by 0.044 (95%CI
0.020–0.070) years and at a cost-saving of €27,615 (95%CI 16,894–39,583) per patient.
Probabilistic analyses confirmed that the moxonidine strategy was dominant over nitrendipine in over 98.9% of cases. The
cumulative 3-year costs and LYL continued to favour the moxonidine strategy in all sensitivity analyses performed.
Conclusion: Treatment with standard antihypertensive therapy and adjunctive moxonidine in hypertensive patients with
advanced renal failure was predicted to reduce the number of new ESRD cases over three years compared to adjunctive
nitrendipine. The model showed that adjunctive moxonidine could increase life-years lived and provide long term cost
savings.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="adjunctive_treatment_greiner.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2477687/2477692/adjunctive_treatment_greiner.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Nephrology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2369</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17645811</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24776872</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2369-8-9</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Littlewood, Kavi J., Greiner, Wolfgang, Baum, Dominique, and Zoellner, York. “Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt; 8.1 (2007): 9.</mla>
<default>Littlewood KJ, Greiner W, Baum D, Zoellner Y (2007) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt; 8(1): 9.</default>
<lncs> Littlewood, K.J., Greiner, W., Baum, D., Zoellner, Y.: Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. BMC Nephrology. 8, : 9 (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Littlewood, Kavi J., Greiner, Wolfgang, Baum, Dominique, and Zoellner, York. 2007. “Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt; 8 (1): 9.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Littlewood, K. J., Greiner, W., Baum, D., &amp;amp; Zoellner, Y. (2007). Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 9. doi:10.1186/1471-2369-8-9</apa>
<ieee> K.J. Littlewood, et al., “Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2007, : 9.</ieee>
<ama>Littlewood KJ, Greiner W, Baum D, Zoellner Y. Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;8(1): 9.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Littlewood, K.J., Greiner, W., Baum, D. &amp;amp; Zoellner, Y. (2007). Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 9. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1186/1471-2369-8-9.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Littlewood, K. J., Greiner, W., Baum, D., and Zoellner, Y. (2007). Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt; 8:9.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Littlewood, K.J., et al., 2007. Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1): 9.</harvard1>
<bio1>Littlewood KJ, Greiner W, Baum D, Zoellner Y (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Nephrology 8(1): 9.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Littlewood, K. J., Greiner, W., Baum, D., &amp;amp; Zoellner, Y. (2007). Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 9. doi:10.1186/1471-2369-8-9&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>K. J.  Littlewood, W.  Greiner, D.  Baum, and Y.  Zoellner, “Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, : 9.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Littlewood, K. J.; Greiner, W.; Baum, D.; Zoellner, Y. (2007): Adjunctive treatment with moxonidine versus nitrendipine for hypertensive patients with advanced renal failure: a cost-effectiveness analysis &lt;em&gt;BMC Nephrology&lt;/em&gt;,8:(1):9</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2477687</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-03-09T14:01:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>