<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2480165</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:550</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Shiraiwa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfrang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koop</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">104033</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7571-3684</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pöschl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17980</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We present a novel kinetic multi-layer model for gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP) that treats explicitly all steps of mass transport and chemical reaction of semi-volatile species partitioning between gas phase, particle surface and particle bulk. KM-GAP is based on the PRA model framework (Pöschl-Rudich-Ammann, 2007), and it includes gas phase diffusion, reversible adsorption, surface reactions, bulk diffusion and reaction, as well as condensation, evaporation and heat transfer. The size change of atmospheric particles and the temporal evolution and spatial profile of the concentration of individual chemical species can be modeled along with gas uptake and accommodation coefficients. Depending on the complexity of the investigated system and the computational constraints, unlimited numbers of semi-volatile species, chemical reactions, and physical processes can be treated, and the model shall help to bridge gaps in the understanding and quantification of multiphase chemistry and microphysics in atmospheric aerosols and clouds.

In this study we demonstrate how KM-GAP can be used to analyze, interpret and design experimental investigations of changes in particle size and chemical composition in response to condensation, evaporation, and chemical reaction. For the condensational growth of water droplets, our kinetic model results provide a direct link between laboratory observations and molecular dynamic simulations, confirming that the accommodation coefficient of water at ~270 K is close to unity (Winkler et al., 2006). Literature data on the evaporation of dioctyl phthalate as a function of particle size and time can be reproduced, and the model results suggest that changes in the experimental conditions like aerosol particle concentration and chamber geometry may influence the evaporation kinetics and can be optimized for efficient probing of specific physical effects and parameters. With regard to oxidative aging of organic aerosol particles, we illustrate how the formation and evaporation of volatile reaction products like nonanal can cause a decrease in the size of oleic acid particles exposed to ozone.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Shiraiwa et al._Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics_2012.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2480165/2908346/Shiraiwa et al._Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics_2012.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Copernicus GmbH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1680-7324</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1680-7324</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000301547500034</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24801650</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.5194/acp-12-2777-2012</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">2777-2794</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Shiraiwa, M.; Pfrang, C.; Koop, T.; Pöschl, U. (2012): Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;,12:(5): 2777-2794.</wels>
<harvard1>Shiraiwa, M., et al., 2012. Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, 12(5), p 2777-2794.</harvard1>
<bio1>Shiraiwa M, Pfrang C, Koop T, Pöschl U (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water.&lt;br /&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics 12(5): 2777-2794.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, T., &amp;amp; Pöschl, U. (2012). Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2777-2794. doi:10.5194/acp-12-2777-2012&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Shiraiwa, C.  Pfrang, T.  Koop, and U.  Pöschl, “Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water”, &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 2777-2794.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Shiraiwa M, Pfrang C, Koop T, Pöschl U. Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;. 2012;12(5):2777-2794.</ama>
<frontiers>Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, T., and Pöschl, U. (2012). Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 12, 2777-2794.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, T. &amp;amp; Pöschl, U. (2012). Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2777-2794. Copernicus GmbH. doi:10.5194/acp-12-2777-2012.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, T., &amp;amp; Pöschl, U. (2012). Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2777-2794. doi:10.5194/acp-12-2777-2012</apa>
<ieee> M. Shiraiwa, et al., “Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water”, &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2012,  pp. 2777-2794.</ieee>
<lncs> Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, T., Pöschl, U.: Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 12, 2777-2794 (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, Thomas, and Pöschl, U. 2012. “Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water”. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 12 (5): 2777-2794.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Shiraiwa, M., Pfrang, C., Koop, Thomas, and Pöschl, U. “Kinetic multi-layer model of gas-particle interactions in aerosols and clouds (KM-GAP): linking condensation, evaporation and chemical reactions of organics, oxidants and water”. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 12.5 (2012): 2777-2794.</mla>
<default>Shiraiwa M, Pfrang C, Koop T, Pöschl U (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 12(5): 2777-2794.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2480165</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-03-15T15:06:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>