<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2481768</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hahn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4927430</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Menke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4930713</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015553</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Corpus Linguistics 2011</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We introduce the multimodal Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment (SaGA) corpus, its design, structure, and approaches to a data-driven development and validation of a gesture typology.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="abs-108.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2481768/2652125/abs-108.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Birmingham, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24817689</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> F. Hahn and P. Menke, “Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus”, &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;, 2011.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hahn, F., &amp;amp; Menke, P., 2011. Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. In &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ama>Hahn F, Menke P. Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. In:  &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.</ama>
<apa>Hahn, F., &amp;amp; Menke, P. (2011). Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<lncs> Hahn, F., Menke, P.: Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK).  (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hahn, Florian, and Menke, Peter. 2011. “Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus”. In &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Hahn, F.; Menke, P. (2011): Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. In: Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK).</wels>
<frontiers>Hahn, F., and Menke, P. (2011). “Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus” in &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<mla>Hahn, Florian, and Menke, Peter. “Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus”. &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hahn, F., &amp;amp; Menke, P. (2011). Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hahn, F. &amp;amp; Menke, P. (2011). Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Corpus Linguistics 2011.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Hahn F, Menke P (2011)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK).</default>
<bio1>Hahn F, Menke P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;Corpus-driven development of a Gesture Typology based on the Bielefeld Speech and Gesture Alignment Corpus. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK). .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Hahn, and P.  Menke, in &lt;em&gt;Online Proceedings of the Corpus Linguistics 2011 Conference, Birmingham (UK)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2481768</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-03-16T09:42:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-15T11:50:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>