<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2487085</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wienke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20991629</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4517-5368</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klotz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">24220737</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jens</namePart><namePart type="family">Edlund</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart><namePart type="family">Heylen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrizia</namePart><namePart type="family">Paggio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Humanoids with auditory and visual abilities in populated spaces</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">In this work we present a conceptual framework for the creation of multimodal data sets which combine human-robot interaction with system-level data from the robot platform. The framework is based on the assumption that perception, interaction modeling and system integration need to be treated jointly in order to improve human-robot interaction capabilities of current robots. To demonstrate the feasibility of the framework, we describe how it has been realized for the recording of a data set with the humanoid robot NAO.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="lrec2012mmc.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2487085/2681128/lrec2012mmc.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Istanbul, Turkey</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>human-robot interaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24870854</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Wienke, D.  Klotz, and S.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Edlund, D. Heylen, P. Paggio), &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wienke J, Klotz D, Wrede S (2012) &lt;br /&gt;A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. &lt;br /&gt;In:  LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning. Edlund J, Heylen D, Paggio P (Eds);.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J., Klotz, D. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In J. Edlund, D. Heylen &amp;amp; P. Paggio (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Wienke, J., Klotz, D., Wrede, S.: A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In: Edlund, J., Heylen, D., and Paggio, P. (eds.) LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning.  (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, Johannes, Klotz, David, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2012. “A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective”. In &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jens Edlund, Dirk Heylen, and Patrizia Paggio.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Wienke J, Klotz D, Wrede S. A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In: Edlund J, Heylen D, Paggio P, eds. &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</ama>
<default>Wienke J, Klotz D, Wrede S (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning. Edlund J, Heylen D, Paggio P (Eds); .</default>
<mla>Wienke, Johannes, Klotz, David, and Wrede, Sebastian. “A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective”. &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jens Edlund, Dirk Heylen, and Patrizia Paggio. 2012.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J., Klotz, D., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In J.  Edlund, D.  Heylen, &amp;amp; P.  Paggio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Wienke, J., Klotz, D., and Wrede, S. (2012). “A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective” in &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, Edlund, J., Heylen, D., and Paggio, P. eds.</frontiers>
<wels>Wienke, J.; Klotz, D.; Wrede, S. (2012): A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In: Jens Edlund; Dirk Heylen; Patrizia Paggio (Hrsg.):  LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning.</wels>
<apa>Wienke, J., Klotz, D., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In J.  Edlund, D.  Heylen, &amp;amp; P.  Paggio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Wienke, J., Klotz, D., &amp;amp; Wrede, S., 2012. A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective. In J.  Edlund, D.  Heylen, &amp;amp; P.  Paggio, eds. &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Wienke, D. Klotz, and S. Wrede, “A Framework for the Acquisition of Multimodal Human-Robot Interaction Data Sets with a Whole-System Perspective”, &lt;em&gt;LREC 2012 Workshop on Multimodal Corpora for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, J. Edlund, D. Heylen, and P. Paggio, eds., 2012.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2487085</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-03-29T09:40:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:52:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>