<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2487031</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zofia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malisz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17538112</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wlodarczak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17662039</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015145</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In a previous study (Buschmeier et al., INTERSPEECH-2011) we investigated properties of communicative feedback produced by attentive and non-attentive listeners in dialogue. Distracted listeners were found to produce less feedback communicating understanding. Here, we assess the role of prosody in differentiating between feedback functions. We find significant differences across all studied prosodic dimensions as well as influences of lexical form and phonetic structure on feedback function categorisation. We also show that differences in prosodic features between attentiveness states exist, e.g., in overall intensity.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Malisz-etal-2012-LISTA.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2487031/2493315/Malisz-etal-2012-LISTA.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Edinburgh, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Engagement</topic><topic>Attention</topic><topic>Communicative Feedback</topic><topic>Prosody</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24870311</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">36-39</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Malisz Z, Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Wagner P. Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;. Edinburgh, UK;  2012: 36-39.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malisz, Zofia, Wlodarczak, Marcin, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Wagner, Petra. 2012. “Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;, 36-39. Edinburgh, UK.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Malisz, Z., Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., Wagner, P.: Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions. p. 36-39. Edinburgh, UK (2012).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malisz, Z., Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt; (S. 36-39). Gehalten auf der The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions, Edinburgh, UK.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Malisz Z, Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Wagner P (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions.  Edinburgh, UK:  36-39.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>Z.  Malisz, M.  Wlodarczak, H.  Buschmeier, S.  Kopp, and P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;, Edinburgh, UK, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 36-39.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> Z. Malisz, et al., “Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;,  Edinburgh, UK: 2012,  pp.36-39.</ieee>
<harvard1>Malisz, Z., et al., 2012. Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;.  Edinburgh, UK, pp. 36-39.</harvard1>
<apa>Malisz, Z., Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;, 36-39. Edinburgh, UK.</apa>
<mla>Malisz, Zofia, Wlodarczak, Marcin, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Wagner, Petra. “Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;. Edinburgh, UK, 2012. 36-39.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malisz, Z., Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt;, 36-39. Edinburgh, UK.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Malisz, Z., Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., and Wagner, P. (2012). “Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions&lt;/em&gt; (Edinburgh, UK), 36-39.</frontiers>
<wels>Malisz, Z.; Wlodarczak, M.; Buschmeier, H.; Kopp, S.; Wagner, P. (2012): Prosodic characteristics of feedback expressions in distracted and non-distracted listeners. In: Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions. Edinburgh, UK.  S. 36-39.</wels>
<default>Malisz Z, Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Wagner P (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of The Listening Talker. An Interdisciplinary Workshop on Natural and Synthetic Modification of Speech in Response to Listening Conditions. Edinburgh, UK:  36-39.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2487031</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-03-29T08:20:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>