<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2490164</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Busch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030423</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688208</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The study examines micro-level determinants of the occupational gender segregation, analyzing work values and their effects on gender (a)typical occupational preferences of adolescents. Human capital theory assumes that women develop higher preferences for a good work/life balance in youth, whereas men develop higher extrinsic work values. Socialization theory predicts that female adolescents form higher preferences for social work content. This gender typicality in work values is expected to affect preferences for gender typical occupations. Additionally, parental gender role models are explored as important determinants for the development of gender (a)typical occupational preferences. Analyses of adolescents in the German Socio-economic Panel Study show that work values of a good work/life balance do not differ between women and men. Furthermore, those work values increase men’s preference for male, not female, occupations. This result challenges traditional economic approaches taking into account only resource oriented explanations. The strongest explanatory power comes from social work values. These are more important for women and increase preferences for female occupations for both genders. Therefore, this work value formed in youth still plays an important role for gender (a)typical occupational paths. Parental role models also partly explain gender (a)typical occupational preferences, primarily for male adolescents having a good relationship to their parents.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0002_Busch.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2490164/2490165/SFB_882_WP_0002_Busch.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>preferences</topic><topic>work values</topic><topic>human capital</topic><topic>adolescents</topic><topic>socialization</topic><topic>supply-side theories</topic><topic>Occupational gender segregation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24901647</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Busch, A. (2011). Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 2, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Busch, A. (2011). &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Busch A. &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 2. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2011.</ama>
<ieee> A. Busch, &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 2,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2011.</ieee>
<apa>Busch, A. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 2). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<wels>Busch, A. (2011): Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Busch, &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Busch, A., 2011. &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.2, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<bio1>Busch A (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Busch, A. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 2). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Busch, Anne. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 2. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Busch, A.: Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 2. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<default>Busch A (2011)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Busch, Anne. &lt;em&gt;Determinants of Occupational Gender Segregation : Work Values and Gender (A)Typical Occupational Preferences of Adolescents&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2011. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 2.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2490164</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-04-12T11:12:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>