<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2490155</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Diewald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">124110</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Faist</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">151480</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26712902</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="fre">Les différents domaines de la recherche sur les inégalités, tels que la sociologie de
l’éducation et la sociologie de la mobilité sociale, sont féconds aussi bien du point de vue théorique
qu’empirique. Ils sont à l’origine d’une série d’études sectorielles sur différents aspects de
l’inégalité. Cette fécondité s’accompagne toutefois d’une fragmentation thématique et théorique de
la recherche sur les inégalités en plusieurs lignes de recherche communiquant à peine les unes avec
les autres. Par ailleurs, il n’existe pas d’état des lieux complet des recherches synthétisant les
résultats des études empiriques sur le développement des inégalités. Ainsi la recherche sur les
inégalités a besoin d’une réorientation conceptuelle. les tentatives allant dans ce sens devraient tirer
parti des progrès théoriques et méthodiques considérables réalisés par la recherche sur les inégalités
dans des domaines aussi variés que l’éducation, le marché du travail, la justice sociale, les
migrations ou le genre. la proposition soumise dans cet article repose sur deux piliers:
premièrement, une distinction nette entre hétérogénéités et inégalités; deuxièmement, une tentative
d’identification et de systématisation des mécanismes sociaux transformant de simples
hétérogénéités en inégalités sociales. nous considérons les hétérogénéités comme le point de départ
de ces mécanismes et les inégalités comme leur point d’aboutissement. À titre d’exemple, les
approches basées sur les phénomènes de „démarcation“ (boundary making) offrent des points
d’appui pour le programme esquissé.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Various fields of research on social inequality, such as studies in education and social
mobility, pursue sophisticated theoretical and methodological approaches and have produced a
wealth of relevant empirical findings on specific aspects. Nonetheless, research on social
inequalities is nowadays extremely fragmented along theoretical, conceptual and methodological
lines across which there is little communication and cross-fertilization. There are no comprehensive
accounts which would bundle the numerous empirical findings. Therefore, inequality research in
the social sciences needs to be conceptually reoriented. Towards that end we have to take advantage
of the significant theoretical and methodological advances in the different fields, such as education,
labor markets, justice, migration and gender. Our programmatic contribution rests on two pillars.
First, we go beyond the conflation of heterogeneities and inequalities and draw a clear conceptual
distinction, whereby both terms are always used in the plural. Second, we identify and systematize
social mechanisms. The concept of social mechanisms helps to track the genesis of inequalities out
of heterogeneities. In this way heterogeneities constitute the point of departure, and inequalities the
outcome of a social mechanismic approach. Social mechanisms can be fruitfully connected to
approaches such as boundary making.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0001_Diewald_Faist.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2490155/2490156/SFB_882_WP_0001_Diewald_Faist.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Hétérogénéité</topic><topic>Mécanismes sociaux</topic><topic>Social inequalities</topic><topic>Social mechanisms</topic><topic>inégalité sociale</topic><topic>Heterogeneities</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24901550</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Diewald M, Faist T (2011)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 1.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<bio1>Diewald M, Faist T (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 1.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Diewald, and T.  Faist, &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Diewald, M.; Faist, T. (2011): From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<frontiers>Diewald, M., and Faist, T. (2011). From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 1, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diewald, M., &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 1). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Diewald, Martin, and Faist, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2011. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 1.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diewald, M. &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2011). &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Diewald, M., &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 1). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diewald, Martin, and Faist, Thomas. 2011. &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 1. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Diewald, M., Faist, T.: From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 1. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<ieee> M. Diewald and T. Faist, &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 1,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2011.</ieee>
<harvard1>Diewald, M., &amp;amp; Faist, T., 2011. &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.1, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ama>Diewald M, Faist T. &lt;em&gt;From Heterogeneities to Inequalities : Looking at Social Mechanisms as an Explanatory Approach to the Generation of Social Inequalities&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 1. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2011.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2490155</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-04-12T09:25:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>