<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2493008</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reuter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15477912</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Events play a prominent role in our lives, such that many social media documents describe or are related to some event. Organizing social media documents with respect to events thus seems a promising approach to better manage and organize the ever-increasing amount of content in social media applications. A challenge is to automatize this process so that incoming documents can be assigned to their corresponding event without any user intervention. We present a system that is able to classify a stream of social media data into a growing and evolving set of events. By doing this, we successfully address two key problems that arise in this context: i) scaling to the data sizes and rates encountered in social media applications, and ii) tackling the new event detection problem, i.e. the problem of determining whether an incoming data item belongs to a new or a known event. We successfully address these problems by i) including a candidate retrieval step that retrieves a set of event candidates that the incoming data point is likely to belong to and ii) by including a function trained using machine learning techniques to determine whether the incoming data item belongs to the top scoring candidate or rather to a new event. We show that our system addresses the above mentioned challenging issues successfully and that it outperforms other state-of-the-art approaches in terms of quality and scalability.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2493008_Reuter_EventbasedClassification.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2493008/2686732/2493008_Reuter_EventbasedClassification.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Clustering</topic><topic>Classification</topic><topic>SVMs</topic><topic>Event Identification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24930083</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Reuter, T., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2012). Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Reuter, T., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2012. Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Reuter and P. Cimiano, “Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;, 2012.</ieee>
<default>Reuter T, Cimiano P (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012).</default>
<frontiers>Reuter, T., and Cimiano, P. (2012). “Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reuter, T., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2012). Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Reuter, Timo, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</mla>
<wels>Reuter, T.; Cimiano, P. (2012): Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. In: Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012).</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reuter, Timo, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2012. “Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Reuter, T., Cimiano, P.: Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012).  (2012).</lncs>
<ama>Reuter T, Cimiano P. Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Reuter, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Reuter T, Cimiano P (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012). .</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reuter, T. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2012). Event-based Classification of Social Media Streams. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR 2012)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2493008</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-04-30T08:33:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>