<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497605</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blohm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart><namePart type="family">Mönnich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kai-Uwe</namePart><namePart type="family">Kühnberger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Blohm_Learning_Patter_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497605/2525173/Blohm_Learning_Patter_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Osnabrück</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Osnabrück, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24976057</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2006. “Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract”. In &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Uwe Mönnich and Kai-Uwe Kühnberger. Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Blohm, S., Cimiano, P.: Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In: Mönnich, U. and Kühnberger, K.-U. (eds.) OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007.  University of Osnabrück, Osnabrück, Germany (2006).</lncs>
<ama>Blohm S, Cimiano P. Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In: Mönnich U, Kühnberger K-U, eds. &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;. Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück;  2006.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Blohm, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U. Mönnich, K.-U. Kühnberger), University Of Osnabrück, Osnabrück, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Blohm S, Cimiano P (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. &lt;br /&gt;In:  OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007. Mönnich U, Kühnberger K-U (Eds); Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2006). Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In U. Mönnich &amp;amp; K.-U. Kühnberger (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation, Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2006). Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In U.  Mönnich &amp;amp; K. - U.  Kühnberger (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt; Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.</apa>
<harvard1>Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2006. Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In U.  Mönnich &amp;amp; K. - U.  Kühnberger, eds. &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;.  Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Blohm and P. Cimiano, “Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract”, &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;, U. Mönnich and K.-U. Kühnberger, eds.,  Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück, 2006.</ieee>
<default>Blohm S, Cimiano P (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007. Mönnich U, Kühnberger K-U (Eds);  Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.</default>
<wels>Blohm, S.; Cimiano, P. (2006): Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In: Uwe Mönnich; Kai-Uwe Kühnberger (Hrsg.):  OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007. Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.</wels>
<mla>Blohm, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract”. &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Uwe Mönnich and Kai-Uwe Kühnberger. Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück, 2006.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2006). Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract. In U.  Mönnich &amp;amp; K. - U.  Kühnberger (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt; Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Blohm, S., and Cimiano, P. (2006). “Learning Patterns from the Web - Evaluating the Evaluation Functions - Extended Abstract” in &lt;em&gt;OTT’06 - Ontologies in Text Technology: Approaches to Extract Semantic KnowledInformation. Publications of the Institute of Cognitive Science, 1-2007&lt;/em&gt;, Mönnich, U., and Kühnberger, K. - U. eds. (Osnabrück, Germany: University of Osnabrück).</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497605</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>