<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497720</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Steffen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staab</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Chris</namePart><namePart type="family">Biemann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gerhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Paas</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cimiano_Learning_Concep_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497720/2525546/Cimiano_Learning_Concep_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bonn, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24977200</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Staab, S. (2005): Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In: Chris Biemann; Gerhard Paas (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods. Bonn.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, and S.  Staab, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Biemann, G. Paas), Bonn, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In C.  Biemann &amp;amp; G.  Paas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt; Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Staab S (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods. Biemann C, Paas G (Eds); Bonn.</bio1>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Staab, S., 2005. Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In C.  Biemann &amp;amp; G.  Paas, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;.  Bonn.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., and Staab, S. (2005). “Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;, Biemann, C., and Paas, G. eds. (Bonn).</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, and Staab, Steffen. 2005. “Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Chris Biemann and Gerhard Paas. Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In C. Biemann &amp;amp; G. Paas (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods, Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Cimiano P, Staab S. Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In: Biemann C, Paas G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;. Bonn;  2005.</ama>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Staab, S.: Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In: Biemann, C. and Paas, G. (eds.) Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods.  Bonn (2005).</lncs>
<ieee> P. Cimiano and S. Staab, “Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;, C. Biemann and G. Paas, eds.,  Bonn: 2005.</ieee>
<default>Cimiano P, Staab S (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods. Biemann C, Paas G (Eds);  Bonn.</default>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, and Staab, Steffen. “Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Chris Biemann and Gerhard Paas. Bonn, 2005.</mla>
<apa>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Concept Hierarchies from Text with a Guided Agglomerative Clustering Algorithm. In C.  Biemann &amp;amp; G.  Paas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICML 2005 Workshop on Learning and Extending Lexical Ontologies with Machine Learning Methods&lt;/em&gt; Bonn.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497720</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>