<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497396</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Clustering of Polysemic Words</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Laurent</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cicurel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bloehdorn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Reinhold</namePart><namePart type="family">Decker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart><namePart type="family">Lenz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cicurel_Clustering_of_P_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497396/2525051/Cicurel_Clustering_of_P_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Berlin, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-70980-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24973960</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-70981-7_68</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">595-602</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P.: Clustering of Polysemic Words. In: Decker, R. and Lenz, H.-J. (eds.) Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. p. 595-602. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, New York (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cicurel, Laurent, Bloehdorn, Stephan, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2007. “Clustering of Polysemic Words”. In &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Reinhold Decker and Hans-Joachim Lenz, 595-602. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Cicurel, Laurent, Bloehdorn, Stephan, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Clustering of Polysemic Words”. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Reinhold Decker and Hans-Joachim Lenz. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer, 2007. 595-602.</mla>
<default>Cicurel L, Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Decker R, Lenz H-J (Eds);  Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer:  595-602.</default>
<wels>Cicurel, L.; Bloehdorn, S.; Cimiano, P. (2007): Clustering of Polysemic Words. In: Reinhold Decker; Hans-Joachim Lenz (Hrsg.):  Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer.  S. 595-602.</wels>
<harvard1>Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2007. Clustering of Polysemic Words. In R.  Decker &amp;amp; H. - J.  Lenz, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer, pp. 595-602.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2007). Clustering of Polysemic Words. In R.  Decker &amp;amp; H. - J.  Lenz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 595-602). Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-70981-7_68&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Cicurel L, Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Clustering of Polysemic Words. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Decker R, Lenz H-J (Eds); Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer:  595-602.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Cicurel, S.  Bloehdorn, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Decker, H.-J. Lenz), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 595-602.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Cicurel L, Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P. Clustering of Polysemic Words. In: Decker R, Lenz H-J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer;  2007: 595-602.</ama>
<frontiers>Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S., and Cimiano, P. (2007). “Clustering of Polysemic Words” in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, Decker, R., and Lenz, H. - J. eds. (Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer), 595-602.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2007). Clustering of Polysemic Words. In R. Decker &amp;amp; H.-J. Lenz (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (S. 595-602). Gehalten auf der 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl), Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-70981-7_68.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Cicurel, L., Bloehdorn, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2007). Clustering of Polysemic Words. In R.  Decker &amp;amp; H. - J.  Lenz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 595-602). Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-70981-7_68</apa>
<ieee> L. Cicurel, S. Bloehdorn, and P. Cimiano, “Clustering of Polysemic Words”, &lt;em&gt;Advances in Data Analysis: Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, R. Decker and H.-J. Lenz, eds.,  Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer, 2007,  pp.595-602.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497396</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>