<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497272</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haase</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Qiu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ji</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Teofilos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mailis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stamou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stoilos</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Duc Thanh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tran</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vassilis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tzouvaras</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2008_1789_Cimiano_Reasoning_with_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497272/2525477/2008_1789_Cimiano_Reasoning_with_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24972724</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, P.  Haase, Q.  Ji, T.  Mailis, G.  Stamou, G.  Stoilos, D. T.  Tran, and V.  Tzouvaras, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Haase P, Ji Q, Mailis T, Stamou G, Stoilos G, Tran DT, Tzouvaras V (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense. .</bio1>
<default>Cimiano P, Haase P, Ji Q, Mailis T, Stamou G, Stoilos G, Tran DT, Tzouvaras V (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Ji, Q., Mailis, T., Stamou, G., Stoilos, G., Tran, D.T. &amp;amp; Tzouvaras, V. (2008). Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Ji, Q., Mailis, T., Stamou, G., Stoilos, G., Tran, D. T., and Tzouvaras, V. (2008). “Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Ji, Q., Mailis, T., Stamou, G., Stoilos, G., Tran, D. T., et al. (2008). Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Haase, Peter, Ji, Qiu, Mailis, Teofilos, Stamou, Giorgos, Stoilos, Giorgos, Tran, Duc Thanh, and Tzouvaras, Vassilis. “Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;. 2008.</mla>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Haase, P.; Ji, Q.; Mailis, T.; Stamou, G.; Stoilos, G.; Tran, D. T.; Tzouvaras, V. (2008): Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. In: Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Haase, Peter, Ji, Qiu, Mailis, Teofilos, Stamou, Giorgos, Stoilos, Giorgos, Tran, Duc Thanh, and Tzouvaras, Vassilis. 2008. “Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Ji, Q., Mailis, T., Stamou, G., Stoilos, G., Tran, D.T., Tzouvaras, V.: Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense.  (2008).</lncs>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Ji, Q., Mailis, T., Stamou, G., Stoilos, G., Tran, D. T., et al. (2008). Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ama>Cimiano P, Haase P, Ji Q, et al. Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;. 2008.</ama>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., et al., 2008. Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, et al., “Reasoning with Large A-Boxes in Fuzzy Description Logics using DL reasoners: An Experimental Evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESWC Workshop on Advancing Reasoning on the Web: Scalability and Commonsense&lt;/em&gt;, 2008.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497272</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>