<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497403</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Erdmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ladwig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we present an approach which, given a knowledge base and an appropriate text corpus, automatically induces patterns which can be used to query the knowledge base. We do not only consider simple questions but text problems consisting of several sentences. Answers to complex text problems are determined by an inference process which computes the answer on the basis of the background knowledge in the knowledge base (KB) as well as the textual description of the problem. The question formulated in natural language thus needs to be translated into appropriate KB structures and queries. Our approach to translating the natural language question uses an underlying corpus and the knowledge base to derive meaningful and relevant patterns which can then be used to process the questions and capture their meaning with respect to the underlying knowledge base. We apply our approach to advanced placement (AP) questions in three areas: physics, chemistry and biology. We report results of a first evaluation of the translation procedure for the three domains.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Corpus-based_Pa_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497403/2525059/Corpus-based_Pa_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Irvine, CA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-7695-2997-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24974032</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ICSC.2007.34</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">671-678</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Erdmann, Michael, and Ladwig, Günter. “Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE Computer Society, 2007. 671-678.</mla>
<default>Cimiano P, Erdmann M, Ladwig G (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007). IEEE Computer Society:  671-678.</default>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M., Ladwig, G.: Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007). p. 671-678. IEEE Computer Society (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Erdmann, Michael, and Ladwig, Günter. 2007. “Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;, 671-678. IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M., &amp;amp; Ladwig, G. (2007). Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;, 671-678. IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/ICSC.2007.34</apa>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, M. Erdmann, and G. Ladwig, “Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE Computer Society, 2007,  pp.671-678.</ieee>
<ama>Cimiano P, Erdmann M, Ladwig G. Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE Computer Society;  2007: 671-678.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M. &amp;amp; Ladwig, G. (2007). Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 671-678). Gehalten auf der First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007), IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/ICSC.2007.34.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M., and Ladwig, G. (2007). “Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt; (IEEE Computer Society), 671-678.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M., &amp;amp; Ladwig, G. (2007). Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;, 671-678. IEEE Computer Society. doi:10.1109/ICSC.2007.34&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Erdmann M, Ladwig G (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007).  IEEE Computer Society:  671-678.</bio1>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., Erdmann, M., &amp;amp; Ladwig, G., 2007. Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;.  IEEE Computer Society, pp. 671-678.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, M.  Erdmann, and G.  Ladwig, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007)&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee Computer Society, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 671-678.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Erdmann, M.; Ladwig, G. (2007): Corpus-based Pattern Induction for a Knowledge-based Question Answering Approach. In: Proceedings of the First IEEE International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC 2007). IEEE Computer Society.  S. 671-678.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497403</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>