<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497439</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haase</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heizmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">David N.</namePart><namePart type="family">Chin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michelle X.</namePart><namePart type="family">Zhou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tessa A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Lau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Angel R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Puerta</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>12th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="iui07.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497439/2524824/iui07.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACM</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Honolulu, HI, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">1-59593-481-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24974394</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1145/1216295.1216330</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">180-189</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Haase, P.; Heizmann, J. (2007): Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In: David N. Chin; Michelle X. Zhou; Tessa A. Lau; Angel R. Puerta (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. ACM.  S. 180-189.</wels>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., Haase, P., &amp;amp; Heizmann, J., 2007. Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In D. N.  Chin, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;.  ACM, pp. 180-189.</harvard1>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Haase P, Heizmann J (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. Chin DN, Zhou MX, Lau TA, Puerta AR (Eds); ACM:  180-189.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Haase, P., &amp;amp; Heizmann, J. (2007). Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In D. N.  Chin, M. X.  Zhou, T. A.  Lau, &amp;amp; A. R.  Puerta (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 180-189). ACM. doi:10.1145/1216295.1216330&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, P.  Haase, and J.  Heizmann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D.N. Chin, M.X. Zhou, T.A. Lau, A.R. Puerta), Acm, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 180-189.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Cimiano P, Haase P, Heizmann J. Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In: Chin DN, Zhou MX, Lau TA, Puerta AR, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;. ACM;  2007: 180-189.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Haase, P. &amp;amp; Heizmann, J. (2007). Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In D.N. Chin, M.X. Zhou, T.A. Lau &amp;amp; A.R. Puerta (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; (S. 180-189). Gehalten auf der 12th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces, ACM. doi:10.1145/1216295.1216330.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Haase, P., and Heizmann, J. (2007). “Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;, Chin, D. N., Zhou, M. X., Lau, T. A., and Puerta, A. R. eds. (ACM), 180-189.</frontiers>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Haase, P., &amp;amp; Heizmann, J. (2007). Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In D. N.  Chin, M. X.  Zhou, T. A.  Lau, &amp;amp; A. R.  Puerta (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 180-189). ACM. doi:10.1145/1216295.1216330</apa>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, P. Haase, and J. Heizmann, “Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;, D.N. Chin, et al., eds., ACM, 2007,  pp.180-189.</ieee>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Haase, P., Heizmann, J.: Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System. In: Chin, D.N., Zhou, M.X., Lau, T.A., and Puerta, A.R. (eds.) Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. p. 180-189. ACM (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Haase, Peter, and Heizmann, Jörg. 2007. “Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;, ed. David N. Chin, Michelle X. Zhou, Tessa A. Lau, and Angel R. Puerta, 180-189. ACM.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Haase, Peter, and Heizmann, Jörg. “Porting Natural Language Interfaces between Domains: An Experimental User Study with the ORAKEL System”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. David N. Chin, Michelle X. Zhou, Tessa A. Lau, and Angel R. Puerta. ACM, 2007. 180-189.</mla>
<default>Cimiano P, Haase P, Heizmann J (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. Chin DN, Zhou MX, Lau TA, Puerta AR (Eds);  ACM:  180-189.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497439</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>