<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497673</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wenderoth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Timothy</namePart><namePart type="family">Baldwin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anna</namePart><namePart type="family">Korhonen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Aline</namePart><namePart type="family">Villavicencio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="pci_qualia.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497673/2525428/pci_qualia.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24976738</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">28-37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, and Wenderoth, Johanna. “Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Timothy Baldwin, Anna Korhonen, and Aline Villavicencio. Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2005. 28-37.</mla>
<default>Cimiano P, Wenderoth J (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition. Baldwin T, Korhonen A, Villavicencio A (Eds);  Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics:  28-37.</default>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Wenderoth, J.: Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In: Baldwin, T., Korhonen, A., and Villavicencio, A. (eds.) Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition. p. 28-37. Association for Computational Linguistics, Ann Arbor, Michigan (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, and Wenderoth, Johanna. 2005. “Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Timothy Baldwin, Anna Korhonen, and Aline Villavicencio, 28-37. Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Wenderoth, J. (2005). Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In T.  Baldwin, A.  Korhonen, &amp;amp; A.  Villavicencio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 28-37). Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<ieee> P. Cimiano and J. Wenderoth, “Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;, T. Baldwin, A. Korhonen, and A. Villavicencio, eds.,  Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2005,  pp.28-37.</ieee>
<ama>Cimiano P, Wenderoth J. Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In: Baldwin T, Korhonen A, Villavicencio A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics;  2005: 28-37.</ama>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., and Wenderoth, J. (2005). “Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;, Baldwin, T., Korhonen, A., and Villavicencio, A. eds. (Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics), 28-37.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Wenderoth, J. (2005). Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In T. Baldwin, A. Korhonen &amp;amp; A. Villavicencio (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt; (S. 28-37). Gehalten auf der ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition, Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Wenderoth, J., 2005. Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In T.  Baldwin, A.  Korhonen, &amp;amp; A.  Villavicencio, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;.  Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 28-37.</harvard1>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Wenderoth J (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition. Baldwin T, Korhonen A, Villavicencio A (Eds); Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics:  28-37.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Wenderoth, J. (2005). Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In T.  Baldwin, A.  Korhonen, &amp;amp; A.  Villavicencio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 28-37). Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, and J.  Wenderoth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Baldwin, A. Korhonen, A. Villavicencio), Association For Computational Linguistics, Ann Arbor, Michigan, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 28-37.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Wenderoth, J. (2005): Automatically Learning Qualia Structures from the Web. In: Timothy Baldwin; Anna Korhonen; Aline Villavicencio (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Deep Lexical Acquisition. Ann Arbor, Michigan: Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 28-37.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497673</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>