<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497075</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eleni</namePart><namePart type="family">Efthimiou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Georgios</namePart><namePart type="family">Kouroupetroglou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stavroula-Evita</namePart><namePart type="family">Fotinea</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Referring to objects using multimodal deictic expressions is an important form of communication. This work addresses the question on how pragmatic factors affect content distribution between the modalities speech and gesture. This is done by analyzing a study on deictic pointing gestures to objects under two conditions: with and without speech. The relevant pragmatic factor was the distance to the referent object. As one main result two strategies were identified which were used by participants to adapt their gestures to the condition. This knowledge can be used, e.g., to improve the naturalness of pointing gestures employed by embodied conversational agents.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2012_-_Pfeiffer_-_Interaction_between_Speech_and_Gesture.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497075/2602524/2012_-_Pfeiffer_-_Interaction_between_Speech_and_Gesture.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag GmbH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Athens, Greece</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Multimodal Communication</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0302-9743</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-34181-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24970755</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_22</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">238-249</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Pfeiffer, T.: Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In: Efthimiou, E., Kouroupetroglou, G., and Fotinea, S.-E. (eds.) Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011. p. 238-249. Springer-Verlag GmbH, Berlin, Heidelberg (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, Thies. 2012. “Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects”. In &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eleni Efthimiou, Georgios Kouroupetroglou, and Stavroula-Evita Fotinea, 238-249. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Pfeiffer, Thies. “Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects”. &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eleni Efthimiou, Georgios Kouroupetroglou, and Stavroula-Evita Fotinea. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH, 2012. 238-249.</mla>
<default>Pfeiffer T (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011. Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G, Fotinea S-E (Eds);  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH:  238-249.</default>
<wels>Pfeiffer, T. (2012): Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In: Eleni Efthimiou; Georgios Kouroupetroglou; Stavroula-Evita Fotinea (Hrsg.):  Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH.  S. 238-249.</wels>
<harvard1>Pfeiffer, T., 2012. Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In E.  Efthimiou, G.  Kouroupetroglou, &amp;amp; S. - E.  Fotinea, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH, pp. 238-249.</harvard1>
<bio1>Pfeiffer T (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011. Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G, Fotinea S-E (Eds); Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH:  238-249.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T. (2012). Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In E.  Efthimiou, G.  Kouroupetroglou, &amp;amp; S. - E.  Fotinea (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 238-249). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_22&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Pfeiffer, in &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Efthimiou, G. Kouroupetroglou, S.-E. Fotinea), Springer-Verlag Gmbh, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 238-249.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Pfeiffer T. Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In: Efthimiou E, Kouroupetroglou G, Fotinea S-E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH;  2012: 238-249.</ama>
<frontiers>Pfeiffer, T. (2012). “Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects” in &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;, Efthimiou, E., Kouroupetroglou, G., and Fotinea, S. - E. eds. (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH), 238-249.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T. (2012). Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In E. Efthimiou, G. Kouroupetroglou &amp;amp; S.-E. Fotinea (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt; (S. 238-249). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_22.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Pfeiffer, T. (2012). Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects. In E.  Efthimiou, G.  Kouroupetroglou, &amp;amp; S. - E.  Fotinea (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 238-249). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34182-3_22</apa>
<ieee> T. Pfeiffer, “Interaction between Speech and Gesture: Strategies for Pointing to Distant Objects”, &lt;em&gt;Gestures and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction and Embodied Communication, 9th International Gesture Workshop, GW 2011&lt;/em&gt;, E. Efthimiou, G. Kouroupetroglou, and S.-E. Fotinea, eds.,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag GmbH, 2012,  pp.238-249.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497075</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T08:50:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>