<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497590</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bloehdorn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hotho</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Myra</namePart><namePart type="family">Spiliopoulou</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart><namePart type="family">Kruse</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart><namePart type="family">Nürnberger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Borgelt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart><namePart type="family">Gaul</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bloehdorn_Learning_Ontolo_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497590/2525157/Bloehdorn_Learning_Ontolo_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Magdeburg, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-31313-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24975904</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">334-341</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Hotho, A. (2006). Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In M.  Spiliopoulou, R.  Kruse, A.  Nürnberger, C.  Borgelt, &amp;amp; W.  Gaul (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 334-341). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bloehdorn, Stephan, Cimiano, Philipp, and Hotho, Andreas. “Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification”. &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Myra Spiliopoulou, Rudolf Kruse, Andreas Nürnberger, Christian Borgelt, and Wolfgang Gaul. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2006. 334-341.</mla>
<frontiers>Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P., and Hotho, A. (2006). “Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification” in &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, Spiliopoulou, M., Kruse, R., Nürnberger, A., Borgelt, C., and Gaul, W. eds. (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 334-341.</frontiers>
<wels>Bloehdorn, S.; Cimiano, P.; Hotho, A. (2006): Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In: Myra Spiliopoulou; Rudolf Kruse; Andreas Nürnberger; Christian Borgelt; Wolfgang Gaul (Hrsg.):  From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.  S. 334-341.</wels>
<default>Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P, Hotho A (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Spiliopoulou M, Kruse R, Nürnberger A, Borgelt C, Gaul W (Eds);  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  334-341.</default>
<harvard1>Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Hotho, A., 2006. Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In M.  Spiliopoulou, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 334-341.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Bloehdorn, P. Cimiano, and A. Hotho, “Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification”, &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, M. Spiliopoulou, et al., eds.,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2006,  pp.334-341.</ieee>
<apa>Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Hotho, A. (2006). Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In M.  Spiliopoulou, R.  Kruse, A.  Nürnberger, C.  Borgelt, &amp;amp; W.  Gaul (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 334-341). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Hotho, A. (2006). Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In M. Spiliopoulou, R. Kruse, A. Nürnberger, C. Borgelt &amp;amp; W. Gaul (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (S. 334-341). Gehalten auf der 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005), Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Bloehdorn, P.  Cimiano, and A.  Hotho, in &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Spiliopoulou, R. Kruse, A. Nürnberger, C. Borgelt, W. Gaul), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 334-341.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P, Hotho A (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. Spiliopoulou M, Kruse R, Nürnberger A, Borgelt C, Gaul W (Eds); Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  334-341.</bio1>
<ama>Bloehdorn S, Cimiano P, Hotho A. Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In: Spiliopoulou M, Kruse R, Nürnberger A, Borgelt C, Gaul W, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2006: 334-341.</ama>
<lncs> Bloehdorn, S., Cimiano, P., Hotho, A.: Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification. In: Spiliopoulou, M., Kruse, R., Nürnberger, A., Borgelt, C., and Gaul, W. (eds.) From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization. p. 334-341. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bloehdorn, Stephan, Cimiano, Philipp, and Hotho, Andreas. 2006. “Learning Ontologies to Improve Text Clustering and Classification”. In &lt;em&gt;From Data and Information Analysis to Knowledge Engineering: Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the German Classification Society (GfKl 2005). Studies in Classification, Data Analysis, and Knowledge Organization&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Myra Spiliopoulou, Rudolf Kruse, Andreas Nürnberger, Christian Borgelt, and Wolfgang Gaul, 334-341. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497590</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>