<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497534</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ratsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cimiano_Finding_the_App_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497534/2525138/Cimiano_Finding_the_App_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ELRA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Genoa, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24975343</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">161-169</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Ratsch, E. (2006). Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;, 161-169. ELRA.</apa>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, M. Hartung, and E. Ratsch, “Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;, ELRA, 2006,  pp.161-169.</ieee>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Ratsch, E., 2006. Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;.  ELRA, pp. 161-169.</harvard1>
<default>Cimiano P, Hartung M, Ratsch E (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC). ELRA:  161-169.</default>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Hartung, M.; Ratsch, E. (2006): Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. In: Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC). ELRA.  S. 161-169.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Ratsch, E. (2006). Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;, 161-169. ELRA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Hartung, Matthias, and Ratsch, E. “Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;. ELRA, 2006. 161-169.</mla>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Hartung, M., and Ratsch, E. (2006). “Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt; (ELRA), 161-169.</frontiers>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Hartung, M., Ratsch, E.: Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC). p. 161-169. ELRA (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Hartung, Matthias, and Ratsch, E. 2006. “Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;, 161-169. ELRA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Cimiano P, Hartung M, Ratsch E. Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;. ELRA;  2006: 161-169.</ama>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Hartung M, Ratsch E (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC).  ELRA:  161-169.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, M.  Hartung, and E.  Ratsch, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt;, Elra, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 161-169.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Hartung, M. &amp;amp; Ratsch, E. (2006). Finding the Appropriate Generalization Level for Binary Relations Extracted from the Genia Corpus. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 161-169). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC), ELRA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497534</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>