<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497687</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aleksander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pivk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmidt-Thieme</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Steffen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staab</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Buitelaar</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart><namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bernardo</namePart><namePart type="family">Magnini</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cimiano_Learning_Taxono_2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497687/2526198/Cimiano_Learning_Taxono_2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IOS Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24976871</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">59-73</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Pivk, Aleksander, Schmidt-Thieme, Lars, and Staab, Steffen. 2005. “Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence”. In &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Paul Buitelaar, Philipp Cimiano, and Bernardo Magnini, 59-73. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123. Amsterdam: IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Pivk, A., Schmidt-Thieme, L., Staab, S.: Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In: Buitelaar, P., Cimiano, P., and Magnini, B. (eds.) Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123. p. 59-73. IOS Press, Amsterdam (2005).</lncs>
<default>Cimiano P, Pivk A, Schmidt-Thieme L, Staab S (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications. Buitelaar P, Cimiano P, Magnini B (Eds);  Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123.  Amsterdam: IOS Press:  59-73.</default>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Pivk, Aleksander, Schmidt-Thieme, Lars, and Staab, Steffen. “Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence”. &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Paul Buitelaar, Philipp Cimiano, and Bernardo Magnini. Amsterdam: IOS Press, 2005. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123. 59-73.</mla>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Pivk, A., Schmidt-Thieme, L., and Staab, S. (2005). “Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence” in &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, Buitelaar, P., Cimiano, P., and Magnini, B. eds. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123 (Amsterdam: IOS Press), 59-73.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Pivk, A., Schmidt-Thieme, L. &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence (Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123). In P. Buitelaar, P. Cimiano &amp;amp; B. Magnini (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (S. 59-73). Amsterdam: IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Cimiano P, Pivk A, Schmidt-Thieme L, Staab S. Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In: Buitelaar P, Cimiano P, Magnini B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123. Amsterdam: IOS Press;  2005: 59-73.</ama>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, et al., “Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence”, &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, P. Buitelaar, P. Cimiano, and B. Magnini, eds., Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123,  Amsterdam: IOS Press, 2005,  pp.59-73.</ieee>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Pivk, A., Schmidt-Thieme, L., &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In P.  Buitelaar, P.  Cimiano, &amp;amp; B.  Magnini (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-73). Amsterdam: IOS Press.</apa>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Pivk, A.; Schmidt-Thieme, L.; Staab, S. (2005): Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In: Paul Buitelaar; Philipp Cimiano; Bernardo Magnini (Hrsg.):  Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications. Amsterdam: IOS Press. (Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123, ).  S. 59-73.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, A.  Pivk, L.  Schmidt-Thieme, and S.  Staab, in &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Buitelaar, P. Cimiano, B. Magnini), Ios Press, Amsterdam, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 59-73.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., et al., 2005. Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In P.  Buitelaar, P.  Cimiano, &amp;amp; B.  Magnini, eds. &lt;em&gt;Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123.  Amsterdam: IOS Press, pp. 59-73.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Pivk, A., Schmidt-Thieme, L., &amp;amp; Staab, S. (2005). Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. In P.  Buitelaar, P.  Cimiano, &amp;amp; B.  Magnini (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-73). Amsterdam: IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Pivk A, Schmidt-Thieme L, Staab S (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Taxonomic Relations from Heterogeneous Sources of Evidence. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Ontology Learning from Text: Methods, Evaluation and Applications. Buitelaar P, Cimiano P, Magnini B (Eds); Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence; 123,  Amsterdam: IOS Press:  59-73.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497687</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>