<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497733</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Victoria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Uren</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Enrico</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Motta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dzbor</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Clark</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Guus</namePart><namePart type="family">Schreiber</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="pci_Publications_kcap05.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497733/2525435/pci_Publications_kcap05.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACM Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Banff, Alberta, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">1-59593-163-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24977336</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">75-82</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Uren, Victoria, Motta, Enrico, Dzbor, Martin, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Peter Clark and Guus Schreiber. ACM Press, 2005. 75-82.</mla>
<default>Uren V, Motta E, Dzbor M, Cimiano P (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05). Clark P, Schreiber G (Eds);  ACM Press:  75-82.</default>
<lncs> Uren, V., Motta, E., Dzbor, M., Cimiano, P.: Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In: Clark, P. and Schreiber, G. (eds.) Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05). p. 75-82. ACM Press (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Uren, Victoria, Motta, Enrico, Dzbor, Martin, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2005. “Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Peter Clark and Guus Schreiber, 75-82. ACM Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Uren, V., Motta, E., Dzbor, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2005). Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In P.  Clark &amp;amp; G.  Schreiber (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 75-82). ACM Press.</apa>
<ieee> V. Uren, et al., “Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;, P. Clark and G. Schreiber, eds., ACM Press, 2005,  pp.75-82.</ieee>
<ama>Uren V, Motta E, Dzbor M, Cimiano P. Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In: Clark P, Schreiber G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;. ACM Press;  2005: 75-82.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Uren, V., Motta, E., Dzbor, M. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2005). Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In P. Clark &amp;amp; G. Schreiber (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 75-82). Gehalten auf der 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05), ACM Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Uren, V., Motta, E., Dzbor, M., and Cimiano, P. (2005). “Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;, Clark, P., and Schreiber, G. eds. (ACM Press), 75-82.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Uren, V., et al., 2005. Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In P.  Clark &amp;amp; G.  Schreiber, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt;.  ACM Press, pp. 75-82.</harvard1>
<bio1>Uren V, Motta E, Dzbor M, Cimiano P (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05). Clark P, Schreiber G (Eds); ACM Press:  75-82.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Uren, V., Motta, E., Dzbor, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2005). Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In P.  Clark &amp;amp; G.  Schreiber (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 75-82). ACM Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Uren, E.  Motta, M.  Dzbor, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Clark, G. Schreiber), Acm Press, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 75-82.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Uren, V.; Motta, E.; Dzbor, M.; Cimiano, P. (2005): Browsing for Information by Highlighting Automatically Generated Annotations: a user study and evaluation. In: Peter Clark; Guus Schreiber (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'05). ACM Press.  S. 75-82.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497733</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>