<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497198</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blohm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart><namePart type="family">Adrian</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Günter</namePart><namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart><namePart type="family">Troussov</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Borislav</namePart><namePart type="family">Popov</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2008_1836_Blohm_Scaling_up_Patt_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497198/2525470/2008_1836_Blohm_Scaling_up_Patt_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24971986</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Blohm, S., Cimiano, P.: Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In: Adrian, B., Neumann, G., Troussov, A., and Popov, B. (eds.) Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems.  (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2008. “Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Benjamin Adrian, Günter Neumann, Alexander Troussov, and Borislav Popov.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Blohm, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Benjamin Adrian, Günter Neumann, Alexander Troussov, and Borislav Popov. 2008.</mla>
<default>Blohm S, Cimiano P (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems. Adrian B, Neumann G, Troussov A, Popov B (Eds); .</default>
<wels>Blohm, S.; Cimiano, P. (2008): Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In: Benjamin Adrian; Günter Neumann; Alexander Troussov; Borislav Popov (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems.</wels>
<bio1>Blohm S, Cimiano P (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems. Adrian B, Neumann G, Troussov A, Popov B (Eds);.</bio1>
<harvard1>Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2008. Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In B.  Adrian, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2008). Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In B.  Adrian, G.  Neumann, A.  Troussov, &amp;amp; B.  Popov (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Blohm, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Adrian, G. Neumann, A. Troussov, B. Popov), &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Blohm S, Cimiano P. Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In: Adrian B, Neumann G, Troussov A, Popov B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;. 2008.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blohm, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2008). Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In B. Adrian, G. Neumann, A. Troussov &amp;amp; B. Popov (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Blohm, S., and Cimiano, P. (2008). “Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Adrian, B., Neumann, G., Troussov, A., and Popov, B. eds.</frontiers>
<apa>Blohm, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2008). Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining. In B.  Adrian, G.  Neumann, A.  Troussov, &amp;amp; B.  Popov (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ieee> S. Blohm and P. Cimiano, “Scaling up Pattern Induction for Web Relation Extraction through Frequent Itemset Mining”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the KI 2008 Workshop on Ontology-Based Information Extraction Systems&lt;/em&gt;, B. Adrian, et al., eds., 2008.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497198</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>