<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497824</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stumme</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hotho</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julien</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tane</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter W.</namePart><namePart type="family">Eklund</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis (ICFCA 04)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="pci_icfca04.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497824/2525726/pci_icfca04.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Sydney, Australia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-21043-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24978249</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-24651-0_18</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">189-207</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, Stumme, Gerd, Hotho, Andreas, and Tane, Julien. “Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies”. &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Peter W. Eklund. Springer, 2004. 189-207.</mla>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., Stumme, G., Hotho, A., and Tane, J. (2004). “Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies” in &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;, Eklund, P. W. ed. (Springer), 189-207.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Stumme, G., Hotho, A., &amp;amp; Tane, J. (2004). Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In P. W.  Eklund (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 189-207). Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-24651-0_18&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Stumme, G.; Hotho, A.; Tane, J. (2004): Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In: Peter W. Eklund (Hrsg.):  Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961. Springer.  S. 189-207.</wels>
<default>Cimiano P, Stumme G, Hotho A, Tane J (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961. Eklund PW (Ed);  Springer:  189-207.</default>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., et al., 2004. Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In P. W.  Eklund, ed. &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;.  Springer, pp. 189-207.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Cimiano, et al., “Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies”, &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;, P.W. Eklund, ed., Springer, 2004,  pp.189-207.</ieee>
<apa>Cimiano, P., Stumme, G., Hotho, A., &amp;amp; Tane, J. (2004). Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In P. W.  Eklund (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 189-207). Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-24651-0_18</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., Stumme, G., Hotho, A. &amp;amp; Tane, J. (2004). Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In P.W. Eklund (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt; (S. 189-207). Gehalten auf der Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis (ICFCA 04), Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-24651-0_18.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, G.  Stumme, A.  Hotho, and J.  Tane, in &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: P.W. Eklund), Springer, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 189-207.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Stumme G, Hotho A, Tane J (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961. Eklund PW (Ed); Springer:  189-207.</bio1>
<ama>Cimiano P, Stumme G, Hotho A, Tane J. Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In: Eklund PW, ed. &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;. Springer;  2004: 189-207.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, Stumme, Gerd, Hotho, Andreas, and Tane, Julien. 2004. “Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies”. In &lt;em&gt;Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Peter W. Eklund, 189-207. Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Stumme, G., Hotho, A., Tane, J.: Conceptual Knowledge Processing with Formal Concept Analysis and Ontologies. In: Eklund, P.W. (ed.) Concept Lattices, Second International Conference on Formal Concept Analysis, ICFCA 2004, Sydney, Australia, February 23-26, 2004, Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2961. p. 189-207. Springer (2004).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497824</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>