<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497530</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reyle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Brandon</namePart><namePart type="family">Bennett</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart><namePart type="family">Fellbaum</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Formal Ontology in Information Systems (FOIS)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fois06.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497530/2525273/fois06.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IOS Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Baltimore, MD, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-58603-685-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24975309</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">51-62</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, and Reyle, Uwe. “Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -”. &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Brandon Bennett and Christiane Fellbaum. IOS Press, 2006. 51-62.</mla>
<default>Cimiano P, Reyle U (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150. Bennett B, Fellbaum C (Eds);  IOS Press:  51-62.</default>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Reyle, U.: Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In: Bennett, B. and Fellbaum, C. (eds.) Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150. p. 51-62. IOS Press (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, and Reyle, Uwe. 2006. “Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -”. In &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Brandon Bennett and Christiane Fellbaum, 51-62. IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Reyle U (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150. Bennett B, Fellbaum C (Eds); IOS Press:  51-62.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Reyle, U. (2006). Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In B.  Bennett &amp;amp; C.  Fellbaum (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 51-62). IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Reyle, U., 2006. Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In B.  Bennett &amp;amp; C.  Fellbaum, eds. &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;.  IOS Press, pp. 51-62.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, and U.  Reyle, in &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Bennett, C. Fellbaum), Ios Press, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 51-62.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Reyle, U. (2006): Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In: Brandon Bennett; Christiane Fellbaum (Hrsg.):  Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150. IOS Press.  S. 51-62.</wels>
<apa>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Reyle, U. (2006). Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In B.  Bennett &amp;amp; C.  Fellbaum (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 51-62). IOS Press.</apa>
<ieee> P. Cimiano and U. Reyle, “Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -”, &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;, B. Bennett and C. Fellbaum, eds., IOS Press, 2006,  pp.51-62.</ieee>
<ama>Cimiano P, Reyle U. Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In: Bennett B, Fellbaum C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;. IOS Press;  2006: 51-62.</ama>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., and Reyle, U. (2006). “Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -” in &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt;, Bennett, B., and Fellbaum, C. eds. (IOS Press), 51-62.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Reyle, U. (2006). Towards Foundational Semantics - Ontological Semantics Revisited -. In B. Bennett &amp;amp; C. Fellbaum (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Formal Ontology in Information Systems, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference, FOIS 2006. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence and Applications, 150&lt;/em&gt; (S. 51-62). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Formal Ontology in Information Systems (FOIS), IOS Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497530</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>