<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497644</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Völker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">G.</namePart><namePart type="family">Angelova</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">K.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bontcheva</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Mitkov</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">N.</namePart><namePart type="family">Nicolov</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="pci_Publications_ranlp05.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497644/2525708/pci_Publications_ranlp05.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>INCOMA Ltd.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Borovets, Bulgaria</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24976440</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">166-172</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Völker, J., 2005. Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In G.  Angelova, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;.  INCOMA Ltd., pp. 166-172.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Cimiano and J. Völker, “Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;, G. Angelova, et al., eds., INCOMA Ltd., 2005,  pp.166-172.</ieee>
<ama>Cimiano P, Völker J. Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In: Angelova G, Bontcheva K, Mitkov R, Nicolov N, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;. INCOMA Ltd.;  2005: 166-172.</ama>
<apa>Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Völker, J. (2005). Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In G.  Angelova, K.  Bontcheva, R.  Mitkov, &amp;amp; N.  Nicolov (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 166-172). INCOMA Ltd.</apa>
<lncs> Cimiano, P., Völker, J.: Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In: Angelova, G., Bontcheva, K., Mitkov, R., and Nicolov, N. (eds.) Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP). p. 166-172. INCOMA Ltd. (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, Philipp, and Völker, Johanna. 2005. “Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. G. Angelova, K. Bontcheva, R. Mitkov, and N. Nicolov, 166-172. INCOMA Ltd.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Cimiano, P.; Völker, J. (2005): Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In: G. Angelova; K. Bontcheva; R. Mitkov; N. Nicolov (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP). INCOMA Ltd.  S. 166-172.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Völker, J. (2005). Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In G. Angelova, K. Bontcheva, R. Mitkov &amp;amp; N. Nicolov (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 166-172). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP), INCOMA Ltd.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Völker, J. (2005). Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. In G.  Angelova, K.  Bontcheva, R.  Mitkov, &amp;amp; N.  Nicolov (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 166-172). INCOMA Ltd.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Cimiano, P., and Völker, J. (2005). “Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;, Angelova, G., Bontcheva, K., Mitkov, R., and Nicolov, N. eds. (INCOMA Ltd.), 166-172.</frontiers>
<mla>Cimiano, Philipp, and Völker, Johanna. “Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. G. Angelova, K. Bontcheva, R. Mitkov, and N. Nicolov. INCOMA Ltd., 2005. 166-172.</mla>
<default>Cimiano P, Völker J (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP). Angelova G, Bontcheva K, Mitkov R, Nicolov N (Eds);  INCOMA Ltd.:  166-172.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Cimiano, and J.  Völker, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G. Angelova, K. Bontcheva, R. Mitkov, N. Nicolov), Incoma Ltd., &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 166-172.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cimiano P, Völker J (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Towards large-scale, open-domain and ontology-based named entity classification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP). Angelova G, Bontcheva K, Mitkov R, Nicolov N (Eds); INCOMA Ltd.:  166-172.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497644</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>