<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2497444</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Duc Thanh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tran</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anupriya</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ankolekar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Wallace</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Angelides</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">P.</namePart><namePart type="family">Mylonas</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Various adaptive hypermedia systems have been proposed to alleviate information overload on the Web by personalising the delivery of information and resources to the user. These systems have however been afflicted with difficulties in the acquisition of an accurate user model, a limited degree of customization offered to the user as well as general lack of user control on and transparency of the systems’ adaptive behavior. In this chapter, we argue that the use of rules on top on ontologies can enable adaptive functionality that is transparent and controllable for users. To this end, we present ODAS, a domain ontology for adaptive hypermedia systems, and a model for the specification of ODAS-based adaptation rules. We demonstrate the use of this model by showing how it can be instantiated within a knowledge portal to arrive at rules that exploit ODAS semantics to perform meaningful personalization.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2007_1630_Tran_A_Rule-based_Ad_1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2497444/2525504/2007_1630_Tran_A_Rule-based_Ad_1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1860-949X</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">9783540763598</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24974443</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-76361_6</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">117-135</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Tran, D. T.; Cimiano, P.; Ankolekar, A. (2008): A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In: M. Wallace; M. Angelides; P. Mylonas (Hrsg.):  Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. (Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93, ).  S. 117-135.</wels>
<bio1>Tran DT, Cimiano P, Ankolekar A (2008) &lt;br /&gt;A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization. Wallace M, Angelides M, Mylonas P (Eds); Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  117-135.</bio1>
<harvard1>Tran, D.T., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Ankolekar, A., 2008. A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In M.  Wallace, M.  Angelides, &amp;amp; P.  Mylonas, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 117-135.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tran, D. T., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Ankolekar, A. (2008). A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In M.  Wallace, M.  Angelides, &amp;amp; P.  Mylonas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 117-135). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-76361_6&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>D. T.  Tran, P.  Cimiano, and A.  Ankolekar, in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Wallace, M. Angelides, P. Mylonas), Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 117-135.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Tran DT, Cimiano P, Ankolekar A. A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In: Wallace M, Angelides M, Mylonas P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;  2008: 117-135.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tran, D.T., Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Ankolekar, A. (2008). A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization (Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93). In M. Wallace, M. Angelides &amp;amp; P. Mylonas (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt; (S. 117-135). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-76361_6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Tran, D. T., Cimiano, P., and Ankolekar, A. (2008). “A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization” in &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;, Wallace, M., Angelides, M., and Mylonas, P. eds. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93 (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer), 117-135.</frontiers>
<apa>Tran, D. T., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Ankolekar, A. (2008). A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In M.  Wallace, M.  Angelides, &amp;amp; P.  Mylonas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 117-135). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-540-76361_6</apa>
<ieee> D.T. Tran, P. Cimiano, and A. Ankolekar, “A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization”, &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;, M. Wallace, M. Angelides, and P. Mylonas, eds., Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008,  pp.117-135.</ieee>
<lncs> Tran, D.T., Cimiano, P., Ankolekar, A.: A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization. In: Wallace, M., Angelides, M., and Mylonas, P. (eds.) Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93. p. 117-135. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tran, Duc Thanh, Cimiano, Philipp, and Ankolekar, Anupriya. 2008. “A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization”. In &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;, ed. M. Wallace, M. Angelides, and P. Mylonas, 117-135. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Tran, Duc Thanh, Cimiano, Philipp, and Ankolekar, Anupriya. “A Rule-based Adaption Model for Ontology-based Personalization”. &lt;em&gt;Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. M. Wallace, M. Angelides, and P. Mylonas. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, 2008. Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93. 117-135.</mla>
<default>Tran DT, Cimiano P, Ankolekar A (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Advances in Semantic Media Adaptation and Personalization. Wallace M, Angelides M, Mylonas P (Eds);  Studies in Computational Intelligence; 93.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer:  117-135.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2497444</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-16T10:26:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>