<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2498997</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tscherepanow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">128602</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Petra</namePart><namePart type="family">Perner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Incremental on-line learning is an important branch of machine learning. One class of approaches particularly well-suited to such tasks are Adaptive Resonance Theory (ART) neural networks. This paper presents a novel ART network combining the ability of noise-insensi\-tive, incremental clustering and topology learning at different levels of detail from TopoART with Euclidean similarity measures and hyperspherical categories from Hypersphere ART. As a result of the modified internal representations, several limitations of the original TopoART network are lifted. In particular, the presented network can process arbitrarily scaled values even if their range is not entirely known in advance.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="tscherepanow.marko2012incremental-ICDM.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2498997/2517690/tscherepanow.marko2012incremental-ICDM.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ibai-publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Berlin, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Incremental learning</topic><topic>Hierarchical clustering</topic><topic>TopoART</topic><topic>Adaptive Resonance Theory</topic><topic>On-line learning</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1864-9734</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-942952-17-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-24989977</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">22-34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Tscherepanow M (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM). Perner P (Ed); Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing:  22-34.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Tscherepanow, in &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: P. Perner), Ibai-Publishing, Fockendorf, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 22-34.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Tscherepanow M (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM). Perner P (Ed);  Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing:  22-34.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M. (2012). Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In P.  Perner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 22-34). Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Tscherepanow, Marko. “Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories”. &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Petra Perner. Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing, 2012. 22-34.</mla>
<frontiers>Tscherepanow, M. (2012). “Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories” in &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;, Perner, P. ed. (Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing), 22-34.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M. (2012). Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In P. Perner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 22-34). Gehalten auf der Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Tscherepanow, M. (2012): Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In: Petra Perner (Hrsg.):  Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM). Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing.  S. 22-34.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, Marko. 2012. “Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories”. In &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Petra Perner, 22-34. Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Tscherepanow, M.: Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In: Perner, P. (ed.) Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM). p. 22-34. ibai-publishing, Fockendorf, Germany (2012).</lncs>
<apa>Tscherepanow, M. (2012). Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In P.  Perner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 22-34). Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing.</apa>
<ama>Tscherepanow M. Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In: Perner P, ed. &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;. Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing;  2012: 22-34.</ama>
<ieee> M. Tscherepanow, “Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories”, &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;, P. Perner, ed.,  Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing, 2012,  pp.22-34.</ieee>
<harvard1>Tscherepanow, M., 2012. Incremental On-line Clustering with a Topology-Learning Hierarchical ART Neural Network Using Hyperspherical Categories. In P.  Perner, ed. &lt;em&gt;Poster and Industry Proceedings of the Industrial Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)&lt;/em&gt;.  Fockendorf, Germany: ibai-publishing, pp. 22-34.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2498997</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-05-29T11:30:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>