<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2510942</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wlodarczak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17662039</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zofia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malisz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17538112</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015145</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We report on the functional and timing relations between head movements and the overlapping verbal-vocal feedback expressions. We investigate the effect of a distraction task on head gesture behaviour and the co-occurring verbal feedback. The results show that head movements overlapping with verbal expressions in a distraction task differ in terms of several features from a default, non-perturbed conversational situations, e.g.: frequency and type of movement and verbal to nonverbal display ratios.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="feedback_workshop2012_paper_OFFICIAL-VERSION.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2510942/2525693/feedback_workshop2012_paper_OFFICIAL-VERSION.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stevenson, WA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>distraction task</topic><topic>attentiveness</topic><topic>dialogue</topic><topic>communicative feedback</topic><topic>head gestures</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25109425</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">93-96</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Malisz, Z., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 93-96. Stevenson, WA.</apa>
<ieee> M. Wlodarczak, et al., “Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;,  Stevenson, WA: 2012,  pp.93-96.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wlodarczak, M., et al., 2012. Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;.  Stevenson, WA, pp. 93-96.</harvard1>
<default>Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Malisz Z, Kopp S, Wagner P (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. Stevenson, WA:  93-96.</default>
<wels>Wlodarczak, M.; Buschmeier, H.; Malisz, Z.; Kopp, S.; Wagner, P. (2012): Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. In: Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. Stevenson, WA.  S. 93-96.</wels>
<frontiers>Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Malisz, Z., Kopp, S., and Wagner, P. (2012). “Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (Stevenson, WA), 93-96.</frontiers>
<mla>Wlodarczak, Marcin, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Malisz, Zofia, Kopp, Stefan, and Wagner, Petra. “Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Stevenson, WA, 2012. 93-96.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Malisz, Z., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 93-96. Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wlodarczak, Marcin, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Malisz, Zofia, Kopp, Stefan, and Wagner, Petra. 2012. “Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 93-96. Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Malisz, Z., Kopp, S., Wagner, P.: Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. p. 93-96. Stevenson, WA (2012).</lncs>
<ama>Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Malisz Z, Kopp S, Wagner P. Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Stevenson, WA;  2012: 93-96.</ama>
<bio1>Wlodarczak M, Buschmeier H, Malisz Z, Kopp S, Wagner P (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop.  Stevenson, WA:  93-96.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Wlodarczak, H.  Buschmeier, Z.  Malisz, S.  Kopp, and P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Stevenson, WA, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 93-96.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wlodarczak, M., Buschmeier, H., Malisz, Z., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2012). Listener head gestures and verbal feedback expressions in a distraction task. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (S. 93-96). Gehalten auf der Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2510942</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-05T14:21:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>