<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2510937</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Spyridon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kousidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31490072</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zofia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malisz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17538112</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015145</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27003888</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents ongoing work on the design, deployment and evaluation of a multimodal data acquisition architecture
which utilises minimally invasive motion, head, eye and gaze tracking alongside high-quality audiovisual recording of
human interactions. The different data streams are centrally collected and visualised at a single point and in real time by
means of integration in a virtual reality (VR) environment. The overall aim of this endeavour is the implementation of a
multimodal data acquisition facility for the purpose of studying non-verbal phenomena such as feedback gestures,
hand and pointing gestures and multi-modal alignment. In the first part of this work that is described here, a series of tests
were performed in order to evaluate the feasibility of tracking feedback head gestures using the proposed architecture.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ISWS12dsgFINAL.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2510937/2644741/ISWS12dsgFINAL.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stevenson, WA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Multimodal Communication</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25109377</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">39-42</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, Spyridon, Pfeiffer, Thies, Malisz, Zofia, Wagner, Petra, and Schlangen, David. 2012. “Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data.”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 39-42. Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kousidis, S., Pfeiffer, T., Malisz, Z., Wagner, P., Schlangen, D.: Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. p. 39-42. Stevenson, WA (2012).</lncs>
<default>Kousidis S, Pfeiffer T, Malisz Z, Wagner P, Schlangen D (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. Stevenson, WA:  39-42.</default>
<mla>Kousidis, Spyridon, Pfeiffer, Thies, Malisz, Zofia, Wagner, Petra, and Schlangen, David. “Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data.”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Stevenson, WA, 2012. 39-42.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S., Pfeiffer, T., Malisz, Z., Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (S. 39-42). Gehalten auf der Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kousidis, S., Pfeiffer, T., Malisz, Z., Wagner, P., and Schlangen, D. (2012). “Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data.” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (Stevenson, WA), 39-42.</frontiers>
<ama>Kousidis S, Pfeiffer T, Malisz Z, Wagner P, Schlangen D. Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Stevenson, WA;  2012: 39-42.</ama>
<ieee> S. Kousidis, et al., “Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data.”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;,  Stevenson, WA: 2012,  pp.39-42.</ieee>
<apa>Kousidis, S., Pfeiffer, T., Malisz, Z., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 39-42. Stevenson, WA.</apa>
<wels>Kousidis, S.; Pfeiffer, T.; Malisz, Z.; Wagner, P.; Schlangen, D. (2012): Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. In: Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop. Stevenson, WA.  S. 39-42.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kousidis, T.  Pfeiffer, Z.  Malisz, P.  Wagner, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Stevenson, WA, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 39-42.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kousidis S, Pfeiffer T, Malisz Z, Wagner P, Schlangen D (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop.  Stevenson, WA:  39-42.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S., Pfeiffer, T., Malisz, Z., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, 39-42. Stevenson, WA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kousidis, S., et al., 2012. Evaluating a minimally invasive laboratory architecture for recording multimodal conversational data. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Workshop on Feedback Behaviors in Dialog, INTERSPEECH2012 Satellite Workshop&lt;/em&gt;.  Stevenson, WA, pp. 39-42.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2510937</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-05T14:18:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-24T10:23:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>