<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2512954</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nhung</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nguyen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5107126</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thora</namePart><namePart type="family">Tenbrink</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jan Malte</namePart><namePart type="family">Wiener</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christophe</namePart><namePart type="family">Claramunt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015432</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This chapter introduces a model which connects representations of the space surrounding a virtual humanoid's body with the space it shares with several interaction partners. This work intends to support virtual humans (or humanoid robots) in near space interaction and is inspired by studies from cognitive neurosciences on the one hand and social interaction studies on the other hand. We present our work on learning the body structure of an articulated virtual human by using data from virtual touch and proprioception sensors. The results are utilized for a representation of its reaching space, the so-called peripersonal space. In interpersonal interaction involving several partners, their peripersonal spaces may overlap and establish a shared reaching space. We define it as their interaction space, where cooperation takes place and where actions to claim or release spatial areas have to be adapted, to avoid obstructions of the other's movements. Our model of interaction space is developed as an extension of Kendon's F-formation system, a foundational theory of how humans orient themselves in space when communicating. Thus, interaction space allows for measuring not only the spatial arrangement (i.e., body posture and orientation) between multiple interaction partners, but also the extent of space they share. Peripersonal and interaction space are modeled as potential fields to control the virtual human's behaviour strategy. As an example we show how the virtual human can relocate object positions toward or away from locations reachable for all partners, and thus facilitating cooperation in an interaction task.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="C1_OUP_NguyenWachsmuth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2512954/2633271/C1_OUP_NguyenWachsmuth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>body schema</topic><topic>interaction space</topic><topic>multi-person interaction</topic><topic>peripersonal space</topic><topic>spatial arrangement</topic><topic>virtual humans</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-19-967991-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25129543</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199679911.003.0008</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><extent unit="pages">147-168</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Nguyen, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Tenbrink, J.M. Wiener, C. Claramunt), Oxford University Press, Oxford, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 147-168.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Nguyen N, Wachsmuth I (2013) &lt;br /&gt;A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models. Tenbrink T, Wiener JM, Claramunt C (Eds); Explorations in language and space, 8. Oxford: Oxford University Press:  147-168.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nguyen, N. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans (Explorations in language and space). In T. Tenbrink, J.M. Wiener &amp;amp; C. Claramunt (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt; (S. 147-168). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199679911.003.0008.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nguyen, Nhung, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2013. “A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans”. In &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Thora Tenbrink, Jan Malte Wiener, and Christophe Claramunt, 8:147-168. Explorations in language and space. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Nguyen, N., Wachsmuth, I.: A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In: Tenbrink, T., Wiener, J.M., and Claramunt, C. (eds.) Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models. Explorations in language and space. 8, p. 147-168. Oxford University Press, Oxford (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Nguyen N, Wachsmuth I. A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In: Tenbrink T, Wiener JM, Claramunt C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;. Explorations in language and space. Vol 8. Oxford: Oxford University Press;  2013: 147-168.</ama>
<default>Nguyen N, Wachsmuth I (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models. Tenbrink T, Wiener JM, Claramunt C (Eds);  Explorations in language and space, 8.  Oxford: Oxford University Press:  147-168.</default>
<wels>Nguyen, N.; Wachsmuth, I. (2013): A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In: Thora Tenbrink; Jan Malte Wiener; Christophe Claramunt (Hrsg.):  Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models. Oxford: Oxford University Press. (Explorations in language and space, 8).  S. 147-168.</wels>
<mla>Nguyen, Nhung, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans”. &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Thora Tenbrink, Jan Malte Wiener, and Christophe Claramunt. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2013.Vol. 8. Explorations in language and space. 147-168.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nguyen, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In T.  Tenbrink, J. M.  Wiener, &amp;amp; C.  Claramunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Explorations in language and space: Vol. 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 147-168). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199679911.003.0008&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Nguyen, N., and Wachsmuth, I. (2013). “A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans” in &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;, Tenbrink, T., Wiener, J. M., and Claramunt, C. eds. Explorations in language and space, vol. 8, (Oxford: Oxford University Press), 147-168.</frontiers>
<apa>Nguyen, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In T.  Tenbrink, J. M.  Wiener, &amp;amp; C.  Claramunt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Explorations in language and space: Vol. 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 147-168). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199679911.003.0008</apa>
<harvard1>Nguyen, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2013. A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans. In T.  Tenbrink, J. M.  Wiener, &amp;amp; C.  Claramunt, eds. &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;. Explorations in language and space. no.8  Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. 147-168.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Nguyen and I. Wachsmuth, “A computational model of cooperative spatial behaviour for virtual humans”, &lt;em&gt;Representing Space in Cognition: Interrelations of behaviour, language, and formal models&lt;/em&gt;, T. Tenbrink, J.M. Wiener, and C. Claramunt, eds., Explorations in language and space, vol. 8,  Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2013,  pp.147-168.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2512954</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-11T12:07:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>