<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2514553</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:400</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="W12-1806.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2514553/2514554/W12-1806.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACL</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Montreal, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25145530</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">11-12</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Schlangen D (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data. ACL:  11-12.</default>
<mla>Schlangen, David. “The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;. ACL, 2012. 11-12.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, David. 2012. “The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;, 11-12. ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schlangen, D.: The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data. p. 11-12. ACL (2012).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;, Acl, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 11-12.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Schlangen, D., 2012. The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;.  ACL, pp. 11-12.</harvard1>
<bio1>Schlangen D (2012) &lt;br /&gt;The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data.  ACL:  11-12.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, D. (2012). The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;, 11-12. ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Schlangen, D. (2012): The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. In: Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data. ACL.  S. 11-12.</wels>
<ieee> D. Schlangen, “The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;, ACL, 2012,  pp.11-12.</ieee>
<apa>Schlangen, D. (2012). The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;, 11-12. ACL.</apa>
<frontiers>Schlangen, D. (2012). “The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt; (ACL), 11-12.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlangen, D. (2012). The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt; (S. 11-12). Gehalten auf der NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data, ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schlangen D. The Future of Spoken Dialogue Systems is in their Past: Long-Term Adaptive, Conversational Assistants. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2012 Workshop on Future Directions and Needs in the Spoken Dialog Community: Tools and Data&lt;/em&gt;. ACL;  2012: 11-12.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2514553</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-17T11:56:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>