<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2516071</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:020</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anouar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Boulal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Iordanidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andres</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Quast</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schirrwagen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7323749</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0458-1004</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Within the last decade, the concept of enhanced publications has become more and
more prominent. It promises the prospect of more comprehensive communication
among scientists. By using electronic publication infrastructures, scientists can
provide their colleagues with online access to their published manuscripts - along
with various kinds of associated materials.
Among the latter we find research data, visualizations or instructive materials.
Ideally, those enhanced publications provide more complete research results,
thoroughly improve accessibility and facilitate the verification and re-use of
scientific information. 
A website presenting the publication and all its associated materials as hyperlinks
seems to be appropriate and adequate from a human's point of view. 
Mere technology and machines cannot interpret information given in a web page the
same way human scientists do. For example, search engines cannot distinguish
between raw data and an instructive video that is to be found at the end of a
conventional hyperlink without additional semantic information. Hence, in order to
give scientists the most sufficient and easy access to the information provided by
these new forms of publications, the automated processing of enhanced publications
becomes an essential desideratum. New mechanisms are required allowing software
systems to interpret inherent relations.
Expressing the relations within all parts of an enhanced publication is a strong
requirement. Descriptive and technical metadata are common tools that provide this
data to information systems. The OAI-ORE standard provides a useful framework to
describe relations and manage the content of enhanced publications. However,
practical implementations within existing infrastructures are not well established
yet. This is why practical approaches are addressed by the eco4r project.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="eco4r_report_compoundobjects_draft.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2516071/2558195/eco4r_report_compoundobjects_draft.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25160718</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Boulal, A., Iordanidis, M., Quast, A., Schirrwagen, J.: Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures. (2010).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Boulal, Anouar, Iordanidis, Martin, Quast, Andres, and Schirrwagen, Jochen. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Boulal A, Iordanidis M, Quast A, Schirrwagen J. &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.; 2010.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Boulal, M.  Iordanidis, A.  Quast, and J.  Schirrwagen, &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Boulal A, Iordanidis M, Quast A, Schirrwagen J (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Boulal, A., Iordanidis, M., Quast, A. &amp;amp; Schirrwagen, J. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Boulal, A., Iordanidis, M., Quast, A., &amp;amp; Schirrwagen, J. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.</apa>
<harvard1>Boulal, A., et al., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;,</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Boulal, et al., &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;, 2010.</ieee>
<default>Boulal A, Iordanidis M, Quast A, Schirrwagen J (2010) .</default>
<wels>Boulal, A.; Iordanidis, M.; Quast, A.; Schirrwagen, J. (2010): Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures.</wels>
<frontiers>Boulal, A., Iordanidis, M., Quast, A., and Schirrwagen, J. (2010). Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures.</frontiers>
<mla>Boulal, Anouar, Iordanidis, Martin, Quast, Andres, and Schirrwagen, Jochen. &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;. 2010.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Boulal, A., Iordanidis, M., Quast, A., &amp;amp; Schirrwagen, J. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Report on Enhancing Interoperability between existing Open Access Publication Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2516071</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-24T10:59:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>