<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2517110</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wienke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20991629</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4517-5368</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nordmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18384284</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Itsuki</namePart><namePart type="family">Noda</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Noriaki</namePart><namePart type="family">Ando</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Davide</namePart><namePart type="family">Brugali</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">James</namePart><namePart type="family">Kuffner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>SIMPAR 2012</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Adaptive Modular Architecture for Rich Motor Skills</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>
<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Humanoids with auditory and visual abilities in populated spaces</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">The emerging availability of high-quality software repositories for robotics promises to speed up the construction process of robotic systems through systematic reuse of software components. However, to reuse components without modification, compatibility at the interface level needs to be created, which is particularly hard if components were implemented in different robotic frameworks. In this paper we propose an approach using model-based techniques for improving component reusability. We specifically address data type compatibility in a structured way through the development of a generic meta-model capable of representing data types from different frameworks and their relations. Based on this model a code generator emits serialization code which makes it possible to seamlessly reuse the existing data types of different frameworks. The application of this approach is exemplified by connecting the YARP-based iCub simulation with a component architecture using a current robotics middleware. Based on our experiences we describe requirements on robotics frameworks to further increase the level of interoperability between available components.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="main.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2517110/2912323/main.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Tsukuba, Japan</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-34326-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25171102</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-34327-8_30</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7628</number></detail><extent unit="pages">323-334</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Wienke, A.  Nordmann, and S.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Noda, N. Ando, D. Brugali, J. Kuffner), Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 323-334.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wrede S (2012) &lt;br /&gt;A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Noda I, Ando N, Brugali D, Kuffner J (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 7628. Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  323-334.</bio1>
<default>Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wrede S (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Noda I, Ando N, Brugali D, Kuffner J (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 7628.  Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  323-334.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J., Nordmann, A. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In I. Noda, N. Ando, D. Brugali &amp;amp; J. Kuffner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (S. 323-334). Gehalten auf der SIMPAR 2012, Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34327-8_30.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., and Wrede, S. (2012). “A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks” in &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, Noda, I., Ando, N., Brugali, D., and Kuffner, J. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 7628, (Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg), 323-334.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In I.  Noda, N.  Ando, D.  Brugali, &amp;amp; J.  Kuffner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 7628&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 323-334). Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34327-8_30&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wienke, Johannes, Nordmann, Arne, and Wrede, Sebastian. “A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks”. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Itsuki Noda, Noriaki Ando, Davide Brugali, and James Kuffner. Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2012.Vol. 7628. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 323-334.</mla>
<wels>Wienke, J.; Nordmann, A.; Wrede, S. (2012): A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In: Itsuki Noda; Noriaki Ando; Davide Brugali; James Kuffner (Hrsg.):  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 7628).  S. 323-334.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, Johannes, Nordmann, Arne, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2012. “A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks”. In &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Itsuki Noda, Noriaki Ando, Davide Brugali, and James Kuffner, 7628:323-334. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wrede, S.: A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In: Noda, I., Ando, N., Brugali, D., and Kuffner, J. (eds.) Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 7628, p. 323-334. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin (2012).</lncs>
<apa>Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2012). A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In I.  Noda, N.  Ando, D.  Brugali, &amp;amp; J.  Kuffner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 7628&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 323-334). Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-34327-8_30</apa>
<ama>Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wrede S. A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In: Noda I, Ando N, Brugali D, Kuffner J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 7628. Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg;  2012: 323-334.</ama>
<harvard1>Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., &amp;amp; Wrede, S., 2012. A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks. In I.  Noda, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.7628  Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, pp. 323-334.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Wienke, A. Nordmann, and S. Wrede, “A Meta-Model and Toolchain for Improved Interoperability of Robotic Frameworks”, &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, I. Noda, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 7628,  Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2012,  pp.323-334.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2517110</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-07-31T13:00:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:52:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>