<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2519221</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tscherepanow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">128602</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kühnel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">107427</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sören</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riechers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Vincent</namePart><namePart type="family">Lemaire</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jean-Charles</namePart><namePart type="family">Lamirel</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Pascal</namePart><namePart type="family">Cuxac</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33707</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI), Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, an extension of the unsupervised topology-learning TopoART neural network is presented. Like TopoART, it is capable of stable incremental on-line clustering of real-valued data. However, it incorporates temporal information in such a way that consecutive input vectors with a low distance in the input space are summarised to episode-like clusters. Inspired by natural memory systems, we propose two recall methods enabling the selection and retrieval of these episodes. They are demonstrated at the example of a video stream recorded in a natural environment.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="tscherepanow.marko2012episodic-ail.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2519221/2519230/tscherepanow.marko2012episodic-ail.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Montpellier, France</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Adaptive Resonance Theory</topic><topic>On-line learning</topic><topic>TopoART</topic><topic>Episodic memory</topic><topic>Incremental learning</topic><topic>Clustering</topic><topic>Neural networks</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25192218</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">24-29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S., &amp;amp; Riechers, S. (2012). Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In V.  Lemaire, J. - C.  Lamirel, &amp;amp; P.  Cuxac (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 24-29).</apa>
<ieee> M. Tscherepanow, S. Kühnel, and S. Riechers, “Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;, V. Lemaire, J.-C. Lamirel, and P. Cuxac, eds., 2012,  pp.24-29.</ieee>
<harvard1>Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S., &amp;amp; Riechers, S., 2012. Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In V.  Lemaire, J. - C.  Lamirel, &amp;amp; P.  Cuxac, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 24-29.</harvard1>
<default>Tscherepanow M, Kühnel S, Riechers S (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL). Lemaire V, Lamirel J-C, Cuxac P (Eds);   24-29.</default>
<mla>Tscherepanow, Marko, Kühnel, Sina, and Riechers, Sören. “Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Vincent Lemaire, Jean-Charles Lamirel, and Pascal Cuxac. 2012. 24-29.</mla>
<frontiers>Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S., and Riechers, S. (2012). “Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;, Lemaire, V., Lamirel, J. - C., and Cuxac, P. eds. 24-29.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S., &amp;amp; Riechers, S. (2012). Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In V.  Lemaire, J. - C.  Lamirel, &amp;amp; P.  Cuxac (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 24-29).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Tscherepanow, M.; Kühnel, S.; Riechers, S. (2012): Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In: Vincent Lemaire; Jean-Charles Lamirel; Pascal Cuxac (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL).  S. 24-29.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, Marko, Kühnel, Sina, and Riechers, Sören. 2012. “Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Vincent Lemaire, Jean-Charles Lamirel, and Pascal Cuxac, 24-29.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S., Riechers, S.: Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In: Lemaire, V., Lamirel, J.-C., and Cuxac, P. (eds.) Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL). p. 24-29. (2012).</lncs>
<ama>Tscherepanow M, Kühnel S, Riechers S. Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In: Lemaire V, Lamirel J-C, Cuxac P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2012: 24-29.</ama>
<bio1>Tscherepanow M, Kühnel S, Riechers S (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL). Lemaire V, Lamirel J-C, Cuxac P (Eds); 24-29.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Tscherepanow, S.  Kühnel, and S.  Riechers, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: V. Lemaire, J.-C. Lamirel, P. Cuxac), &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 24-29.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tscherepanow, M., Kühnel, S. &amp;amp; Riechers, S. (2012). Episodic Clustering of Data Streams Using a Topology-Learning Neural Network. In V. Lemaire, J.-C. Lamirel &amp;amp; P. Cuxac (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ECAI Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 24-29). Gehalten auf der European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI), Workshop on Active and Incremental Learning (AIL).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2519221</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-08-13T08:48:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>