<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2522306</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friederike Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eyssel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">140331</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4978-8922</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marilyn</namePart><namePart type="family">Walker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Neff</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ana</namePart><namePart type="family">Paiva</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Yukiko</namePart><namePart type="family">Nakano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">First impressions of others are fundamental for the further develop- ment of a relationship and are thus of major importance for the design of vir- tual agents, too. We addressed the question whether there is a second chance for first impressions with regard to the major dimensions of social cognition–warmth and competence. We employed a novel experimental set-up that combined agent appearance (robot-like vs. human-like) and agent behavior (gestures present vs. absent) of virtual agents as between-subject factors with a repeated measures de- sign. Results indicate that ratings of warmth depend on interaction effects of time and agent appearance, while evaluations of competence seem to depend on the interaction of time and nonverbal behavior. Implications of these results for basic and applied research on intelligent virtual agents will be discussed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bergmann_Eyssel_Kopp_IVA2012_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2522306/2534545/Bergmann_Eyssel_Kopp_IVA2012_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Santa Cruz, CA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-33196-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25223067</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-33197-8_13</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">126-138</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F. A., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2012). A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In M.  Walker, M.  Neff, A.  Paiva, &amp;amp; Y.  Nakano (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 126-138). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33197-8_13&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, Eyssel, Friederike Anne, and Kopp, Stefan. “A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Marilyn Walker, Michael Neff, Ana Paiva, and Yukiko Nakano. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2012. 126-138.</mla>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F. A., and Kopp, S. (2012). “A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Walker, M., Neff, M., Paiva, A., and Nakano, Y. eds. (Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer), 126-138.</frontiers>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Eyssel, F. A.; Kopp, S. (2012): A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In: Marilyn Walker; Michael Neff; Ana Paiva; Yukiko Nakano (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.  S. 126-138.</wels>
<default>Bergmann K, Eyssel FA, Kopp S (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Walker M, Neff M, Paiva A, Nakano Y (Eds);  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  126-138.</default>
<ieee> K. Bergmann, F.A. Eyssel, and S. Kopp, “A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, M. Walker, et al., eds.,  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2012,  pp.126-138.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F.A., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2012. A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In M.  Walker, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;.  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 126-138.</harvard1>
<apa>Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F. A., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2012). A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In M.  Walker, M.  Neff, A.  Paiva, &amp;amp; Y.  Nakano (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 126-138). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33197-8_13</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F.A. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2012). A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In M. Walker, M. Neff, A. Paiva &amp;amp; Y. Nakano (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (S. 126-138). Gehalten auf der 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents, Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33197-8_13.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Eyssel FA, Kopp S (2012) &lt;br /&gt;A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. Walker M, Neff M, Paiva A, Nakano Y (Eds); Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  126-138.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, F. A.  Eyssel, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Walker, M. Neff, A. Paiva, Y. Nakano), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 126-138.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Bergmann K, Eyssel FA, Kopp S. A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In: Walker M, Neff M, Paiva A, Nakano Y, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer;  2012: 126-138.</ama>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Eyssel, F.A., Kopp, S.: A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time. In: Walker, M., Neff, M., Paiva, A., and Nakano, Y. (eds.) Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents. p. 126-138. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, Eyssel, Friederike Anne, and Kopp, Stefan. 2012. “A second chance to make a first impression? How appearance and nonverbal behavior affect perceived warmth and competence of virtual agents over time”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Marilyn Walker, Michael Neff, Ana Paiva, and Yukiko Nakano, 126-138. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2522306</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-08-27T08:57:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>