<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2524325</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kramer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Amber</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Leahey</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Humphrey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Southall</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vompras</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18935713</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8224-2884</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wackerow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26712853</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This document focuses on how best to relate Resource Description Framework (RDF)-described datasets to
other related resources and objects (publications, geographies, organizations, people, etc.) in the Semantic
Web. This includes a description of what would be needed to make these types of relationships most useful,
including which RDF vocabularies should be used, potential link predicates, and possible data sources. RDF
provides a good model for describing social science data because it supports formal semantics that provide a
dependable basis for reasoning about the meaning of an RDF expression. In particular, it supports defined
notions of entailment which provide a basis for defining reliable rules of inference in RDF data.

Our findings are discussed in the context of social science data and more specifically, how to leverage
existing metadata models to use alongside linked data. We provide a case for leveraging the Data
Documentation Initiative (DDI) to enable semantic linking of social science data to other data and related
resources on the Web. This document is organized into five use cases, which we consider in turn. Use cases
include: linking related publications to data, linking data about people and organizations to research data,
linking geography, linking to related studies, and linking data to licenses. We briefly discuss emerging or
known issues surrounding the potential use of linked data within each of the defined use cases. Following
these, we list more topics that could develop into additional use cases. Appendix A lists elements from the DDI-Codebook and DDI-Lifecycle specifications that are relevant to each use case.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="UsingRDFToDescribeAndLinkSocialScienceDataToRelatedResourcesOnTheWeb.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2524325/2524326/UsingRDFToDescribeAndLinkSocialScienceDataToRelatedResourcesOnTheWeb.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DDI Alliance</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Semantic Web</topic><topic>DDI Matadata Standard</topic><topic>Data Documentation in Social Sciences</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2153-8247</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25243250</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3886/DDISemanticWeb01</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kramer S, Leahey A, Southall H, Vompras J, Wackerow J (2012)  DDI Working Paper Series.&lt;br /&gt;Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.</default>
<bio1>Kramer S, Leahey A, Southall H, Vompras J, Wackerow J (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;. DDI Working Paper Series.&lt;br /&gt;Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kramer, A.  Leahey, H.  Southall, J.  Vompras, and J.  Wackerow, &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;, Ddi Alliance, Dagstuhl, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Kramer, S.; Leahey, A.; Southall, H.; Vompras, J.; Wackerow, J. (2012): Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web. Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.</wels>
<frontiers>Kramer, S., Leahey, A., Southall, H., Vompras, J., and Wackerow, J. (2012). Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web. &lt;em&gt;DDI Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kramer, S., Leahey, A., Southall, H., Vompras, J., &amp;amp; Wackerow, J. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt; (DDI Working Paper Series). Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance. doi:10.3886/DDISemanticWeb01&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kramer, Stefan, Leahey, Amber, Southall, Humphrey, Vompras, Johanna, and Wackerow, Joachim. &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;. Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance, 2012. DDI Working Paper Series.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kramer, S., Leahey, A., Southall, H., Vompras, J. &amp;amp; Wackerow, J. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt; (DDI Working Paper Series). Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance. doi:10.3886/DDISemanticWeb01.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kramer, S., Leahey, A., Southall, H., Vompras, J., &amp;amp; Wackerow, J. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt; (DDI Working Paper Series). Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance. doi:10.3886/DDISemanticWeb01</apa>
<lncs> Kramer, S., Leahey, A., Southall, H., Vompras, J., Wackerow, J.: Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web. DDI Working Paper Series. DDI Alliance, Dagstuhl, Germany (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kramer, Stefan, Leahey, Amber, Southall, Humphrey, Vompras, Johanna, and Wackerow, Joachim. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;. DDI Working Paper Series. Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> S. Kramer, et al., &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;, DDI Working Paper Series,  Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance, 2012.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kramer, S., et al., 2012. &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;, DDI Working Paper Series, Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance.</harvard1>
<ama>Kramer S, Leahey A, Southall H, Vompras J, Wackerow J. &lt;em&gt;Using RDF to Describe and Link Social Science Data to Related Resources on the Web&lt;/em&gt;. DDI Working Paper Series. Dagstuhl, Germany: DDI Alliance; 2012.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2524325</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-09-03T14:02:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>