<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2528073</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:360</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huhn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26045935</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Central America has the reputation of being a violent region with high crime rates, youth
gangs, drug traffic, and ubiquitous insecurity. Politicians, the media, and social scientists
in and outside the region often claim that the societies are in complete agreement with
their judgment of the situation and that all society members are calling for law and order
and social segregation. Focusing on Costa Rica, El Salvador, and Nicaragua, the paper analyzes
the social perception of violence and crime. On the basis of essays written by secondary
school students and interviews with citizens from all walks of life in the three countries,
the paper points out how elite arguments on violence and crime are translated into
everyday life, and what society members suggest be done to deal with these problems.
The sources prove that there are noticeable hegemonic discourses on violence and crime in
Costa Rica, El Salvador, and Nicaragua. Simultaneously, a majority of the respondents call
for social and integrative solutions rather than the so-called “iron fist.” The repressive
trend in Central American policies therefore does not necessarily receive the presumed affirmation
asserted by many authorities on and in the region.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="http___www.giga-hamburg.de_dl_download.php_d__content_publikationen_pdf_wp81_huhn.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2528073/2528082/http___www.giga-hamburg.de_dl_download.php_d__content_publikationen_pdf_wp81_huhn.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>GIGA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>public discourse</topic><topic>crime</topic><topic>Central America</topic><topic>violence</topic><topic>social perception</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25280730</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>81</number></detail><extent unit="pages">31</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, Sebastian. 2008. &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 81. GIGA Working Papers. Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Huhn, S.: Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life. GIGA Working Papers, 81. GIGA, Hamburg (2008).</lncs>
<default>Huhn S (2008)  GIGA Working Papers; 81.&lt;br /&gt;Hamburg: GIGA.</default>
<mla>Huhn, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg: GIGA, 2008. GIGA Working Papers. 81.</mla>
<wels>Huhn, S. (2008): Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life. Hamburg: GIGA.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Huhn, &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;, Giga, Hamburg, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Huhn S (2008) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;. GIGA Working Papers; 81.&lt;br /&gt;Hamburg: GIGA.</bio1>
<harvard1>Huhn, S., 2008. &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;, GIGA Working Papers, no.81, Hamburg: GIGA.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, S. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers, 81). Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Huhn, S. (2008). Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life. &lt;em&gt;GIGA Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 81, Hamburg: GIGA.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, S. (2008). &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers). Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Huhn S. &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;. GIGA Working Papers. Vol 81. Hamburg: GIGA; 2008.</ama>
<ieee> S. Huhn, &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;, GIGA Working Papers, vol. 81,  Hamburg: GIGA, 2008.</ieee>
<apa>Huhn, S. (2008).  &lt;em&gt;Discourses on violence in Costa Rica, El Salvador and Nicaragua: Social Perceptions in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers, 81). Hamburg: GIGA.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2528073</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-09-20T19:09:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>