<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2528670</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:360</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huhn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26045935</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The Costa Rican talk of crime is fundamentally based on the assumption that crime rates have increased significantly in recent years and that there is today a vast and alarming amount of crime. On the basis of this assumption, fear of crime, the call for the “iron fist,” and drastic law enforcement actions are continually increasing. While crime statistics are the logical basis for the hypothesis on the far-reaching extent of delinquency, they are used in a problematic way in the talk of crime. In this paper I discuss Costa Rican crime statis-tics, their development, and their utilization in the talk of crime against the background of criminological theory. The theses of the paper are that a) the informative value of crime statistics regarding Costa Rican reality is far more questionable than the common utiliza-tion of them implies and b) when they are used as argumentation, these crime statistics do not provide evidence of the oft-proclaimed rising crime wave.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wp104_huhn.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2528670/2528671/wp104_huhn.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>GIGA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>crime statistics</topic><topic>social order</topic><topic>crime</topic><topic>Costa Rica</topic><topic>violence</topic><topic>public discourse</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25286708</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>104</number></detail><extent unit="pages">44</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Huhn, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;. Hamburg: GIGA, 2009. GIGA Working Papers. 104.</mla>
<default>Huhn S (2009)  GIGA Working Papers; 104.&lt;br /&gt;Hamburg: GIGA.</default>
<lncs> Huhn, S.: Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement. GIGA Working Papers, 104. GIGA, Hamburg (2009).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, Sebastian. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 104. GIGA Working Papers. Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Huhn, S., 2009. &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;, GIGA Working Papers, no.104, Hamburg: GIGA.</harvard1>
<bio1>Huhn S (2009) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;. GIGA Working Papers; 104.&lt;br /&gt;Hamburg: GIGA.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, S. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers, 104). Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Huhn, &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;, Giga, Hamburg, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Huhn, S. (2009): Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement. Hamburg: GIGA.</wels>
<apa>Huhn, S. (2009).  &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers, 104). Hamburg: GIGA.</apa>
<ieee> S. Huhn, &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;, GIGA Working Papers, vol. 104,  Hamburg: GIGA, 2009.</ieee>
<ama>Huhn S. &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;. GIGA Working Papers. Vol 104. Hamburg: GIGA; 2009.</ama>
<frontiers>Huhn, S. (2009). Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement. &lt;em&gt;GIGA Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 104, Hamburg: GIGA.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huhn, S. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Culture of Fear and Control in Costa Rica (I). Crime Statistics and Law Enforcement&lt;/em&gt; (GIGA Working Papers). Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2528670</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-09-25T19:52:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>