<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2535177</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yemi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Akegbejo-Samsons</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="workingpaper_99_akegbejo-samsons.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2535177/2535178/workingpaper_99_akegbejo-samsons.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25351776</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Akegbejo-Samsons Y. &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development; 2011.</ama>
<frontiers>Akegbejo-Samsons, Y. (2011). People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Akegbejo-Samsons, Y. (2011). &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Akegbejo-Samsons, Y. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</apa>
<ieee> Y. Akegbejo-Samsons, &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99,  Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2011.</ieee>
<wels>Akegbejo-Samsons, Y. (2011): People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Akegbejo-Samsons, Y. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99). Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Akegbejo-Samsons Y (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</bio1>
<harvard1>Akegbejo-Samsons, Y., 2011. &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99, Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>Y.  Akegbejo-Samsons, &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;, Comcad - Center On Migration, Citizenship And Development, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Akegbejo-Samsons, Y.: People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99. COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Akegbejo-Samsons, Yemi. 2011. &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Akegbejo-Samsons, Yemi. &lt;em&gt;People and Culture: Evolving a Model for Water Resources Management and Sustainable Livelihood in Africa&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development, 2011. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99.</mla>
<default>Akegbejo-Samsons Y (2011)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 99.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: COMCAD - Center on Migration, Citizenship and Development.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2535177</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-11-03T13:10:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>