<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2536426</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bassam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mokbel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18880650</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gross</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lux</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51526921</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Niels</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pinkwart</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nadia</namePart><namePart type="family">Mana</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Friedhelm</namePart><namePart type="family">Schwenker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Edmondo</namePart><namePart type="family">Trentin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">48167073</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2536426__2_.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2536426/2554501/2536426__2_.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Trento, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-33211-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25364263</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-33212-8_1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7477</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1-13</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B., Gross, S., Lux, M., Pinkwart, N. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2012). How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In N. Mana, F. Schwenker &amp;amp; E. Trentin (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-13). Gehalten auf der 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012, Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33212-8_1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Mokbel, S.  Gross, M.  Lux, N.  Pinkwart, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Mana, F. Schwenker, E. Trentin), Springer Berlin Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-13.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Mokbel B, Gross S, Lux M, Pinkwart N, Hammer B (2012) &lt;br /&gt;How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings. Mana N, Schwenker F, Trentin E (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 7477. Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  1-13.</bio1>
<ama>Mokbel B, Gross S, Lux M, Pinkwart N, Hammer B. How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In: Mana N, Schwenker F, Trentin E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Vol 7477. Springer Berlin Heidelberg;  2012: 1-13.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, Bassam, Gross, Sebastian, Lux, Markus, Pinkwart, Niels, and Hammer, Barbara. 2012. “How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning?”. In &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Nadia Mana, Friedhelm Schwenker, and Edmondo Trentin, 7477:1-13. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Springer Berlin Heidelberg.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Mokbel, B., Gross, S., Lux, M., Pinkwart, N., Hammer, B.: How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In: Mana, N., Schwenker, F., and Trentin, E. (eds.) Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 7477, p. 1-13. Springer Berlin Heidelberg (2012).</lncs>
<mla>Mokbel, Bassam, Gross, Sebastian, Lux, Markus, Pinkwart, Niels, and Hammer, Barbara. “How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning?”. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Nadia Mana, Friedhelm Schwenker, and Edmondo Trentin. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2012.Vol. 7477. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 1-13.</mla>
<frontiers>Mokbel, B., Gross, S., Lux, M., Pinkwart, N., and Hammer, B. (2012). “How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning?” in &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Mana, N., Schwenker, F., and Trentin, E. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 7477, (Springer Berlin Heidelberg), 1-13.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B., Gross, S., Lux, M., Pinkwart, N., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2012). How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In N.  Mana, F.  Schwenker, &amp;amp; E.  Trentin (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 7477&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-13). Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33212-8_1&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Mokbel, B.; Gross, S.; Lux, M.; Pinkwart, N.; Hammer, B. (2012): How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In: Nadia Mana; Friedhelm Schwenker; Edmondo Trentin (Hrsg.):  Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings. Springer Berlin Heidelberg. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 7477).  S. 1-13.</wels>
<default>Mokbel B, Gross S, Lux M, Pinkwart N, Hammer B (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings. Mana N, Schwenker F, Trentin E (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 7477.  Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  1-13.</default>
<harvard1>Mokbel, B., et al., 2012. How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In N.  Mana, F.  Schwenker, &amp;amp; E.  Trentin, eds. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. no.7477  Springer Berlin Heidelberg, pp. 1-13.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Mokbel, et al., “How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning?”, &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, N. Mana, F. Schwenker, and E. Trentin, eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 7477, Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2012,  pp.1-13.</ieee>
<apa>Mokbel, B., Gross, S., Lux, M., Pinkwart, N., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2012). How to Quantitatively Compare Data Dissimilarities for Unsupervised Machine Learning? In N.  Mana, F.  Schwenker, &amp;amp; E.  Trentin (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 7477&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial Neural Networks in Pattern Recognition. 5th INNS IAPR TC 3 GIRPR Workshop, ANNPR 2012. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-13). Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33212-8_1</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2536426</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-11-07T17:35:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>