<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2537561</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lohse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herwin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van Welbergen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Ro-Man 2012. 21st IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="position_paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2537561/2537564/position_paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Paris</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25375618</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Lohse, M., &amp;amp; van Welbergen, H. (2012). Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ieee> M. Lohse and H. van Welbergen, “Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots.”, &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;, 2012.</ieee>
<harvard1>Lohse, M., &amp;amp; van Welbergen, H., 2012. Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. In &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<default>Lohse M, van Welbergen H (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lohse, M., &amp;amp; van Welbergen, H. (2012). Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Lohse, Manja, and van Welbergen, Herwin. “Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots.”. &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</mla>
<frontiers>Lohse, M., and van Welbergen, H. (2012). “Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots.” in &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<wels>Lohse, M.; van Welbergen, H. (2012): Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. In: Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner.</wels>
<lncs> Lohse, M., van Welbergen, H.: Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner.  (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lohse, Manja, and van Welbergen, Herwin. 2012. “Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots.”. In &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Lohse M, van Welbergen H. Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. In:  &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</ama>
<bio1>Lohse M, van Welbergen H (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner. .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Lohse, and H.  van Welbergen, in &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lohse, M. &amp;amp; van Welbergen, H. (2012). Designing Appropriate Feedback for Virtual Agents and Robots. &lt;em&gt;Position paper at RO-MAN 2012 Workshop Robot Feedback in Human-Robot Interaction. How to Make a Robot Readable for a Human Interaction Partner&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Ro-Man 2012. 21st IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2537561</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-11-09T20:10:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>