<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2538835</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Peldszus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eva</namePart><namePart type="family">Hajičová</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2862170</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Coling 2012 Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PeldszusSchlangen_ColingWS12.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2538835/2543814/PeldszusSchlangen_ColingWS12.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Mumbai, India</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25388354</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Peldszus A, Schlangen D. Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In: Hajičová E, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;. 2012.</ama>
<harvard1>Peldszus, A., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2012. Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In E.  Hajičová, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Peldszus and D. Schlangen, “Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;, E. Hajičová, ed., 2012.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peldszus, Andreas, and Schlangen, David. 2012. “Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Eva Hajičová.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Peldszus, A., Schlangen, D.: Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In: Hajičová, E. (ed.) Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects.  (2012).</lncs>
<apa>Peldszus, A., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In E.  Hajičová (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peldszus, A. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In E. Hajičová (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Coling 2012 Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Peldszus, A., and Schlangen, D. (2012). “Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;, Hajičová, E. ed.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peldszus, A., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2012). Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In E.  Hajičová (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Peldszus, Andreas, and Schlangen, David. “Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Eva Hajičová. 2012.</mla>
<wels>Peldszus, A.; Schlangen, D. (2012): Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. In: Eva Hajičová (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Peldszus, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: E. Hajičová), &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Peldszus A, Schlangen D (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Incremental Construction of Robust but Deep Semantic Representations for Use in Responsive Dialogue Systems. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects. Hajičová E (Ed);.</bio1>
<default>Peldszus A, Schlangen D (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Coling Workshop on Advances in Discourse Analysis and its Computational Aspects. Hajičová E (Ed); .</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2538835</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-11-18T21:20:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-24T10:24:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>