<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2542199</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Amelina</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">159866</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Basak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bilecen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6023853</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karolina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barglowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29706264</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Faist</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">151480</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688781</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0006_Amelina_Bilecen_Barglowski_Faist.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2542199/2542200/SFB_882_WP_0006_Amelina_Bilecen_Barglowski_Faist.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>transnationality</topic><topic>ego-centric network analysis</topic><topic>inequality</topic><topic>Informal protection</topic><topic>remittances</topic><topic>care</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25421994</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Amelina A, Bilecen B, Barglowski K, Faist T. &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 6. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2012.</ama>
<lncs> Amelina, A., Bilecen, B., Barglowski, K., Faist, T.: Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 6. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Amelina, Anna, Bilecen, Basak, Barglowski, Karolina, and Faist, Thomas. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 6. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Amelina, A., Bilecen, B., Barglowski, K. &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Amelina A, Bilecen B, Barglowski K, Faist T (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 6.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Amelina, B.  Bilecen, K.  Barglowski, and T.  Faist, &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> A. Amelina, et al., &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 6,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2012.</ieee>
<harvard1>Amelina, A., et al., 2012. &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.6, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa>Amelina, A., Bilecen, B., Barglowski, K., &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 6). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Amelina, A., Bilecen, B., Barglowski, K., &amp;amp; Faist, T. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 6). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Amelina, Anna, Bilecen, Basak, Barglowski, Karolina, and Faist, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2012. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 6.</mla>
<frontiers>Amelina, A., Bilecen, B., Barglowski, K., and Faist, T. (2012). Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 6, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Amelina, A.; Bilecen, B.; Barglowski, K.; Faist, T. (2012): Ties That Protect? The Significance of Transnationality for the Distribution of Informal Social Protection in Migrant Networks. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<default>Amelina A, Bilecen B, Barglowski K, Faist T (2012)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 6.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2542199</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-11-27T14:05:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>