<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2543607</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:100</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Models as Make-Believe</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Adam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Toon</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">12973653</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R</namePart><namePart type="family">Frigg</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">MC</namePart><namePart type="family">Hunter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10024</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper I propose an account of representation for scientific models based on Kendall Walton’s “make-believe” theory of representation in art. I first set out the problem of scientific representation and respond to a recent argument due to Craig Callender and Jonathan Cohen, which aims to show that the problem may be easily dismissed. I then introduce my account of models as props in games of make-believe and show how it offers a solution to the problem. Finally, I demonstrate an important advantage my account has over other theories of scientific representation. All existing theories analyze scientific representation in terms of relations, such as similarity or denotation. By contrast, my account does not take representation in modeling to be essentially relational. For this reason, it can accommodate a group of models often ignored in discussions of scientific representation, namely models which are representational but which represent no actual object.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Final draft - Models as Make-believe.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2543607/2916194/Final draft - Models as Make-believe.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-90-481-3850-0</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000278489400005</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25436070</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-90-481-3851-7_5</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>262</number></detail><extent unit="pages">71-96</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Toon, Adam. 2010. “Models as Make-Believe”. In &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;, ed. R Frigg and MC Hunter, 262:71-96. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science. Dordrecht: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Toon, A.: Models as Make-Believe. In: Frigg, R. and Hunter, M.C. (eds.) Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science. 262, p. 71-96. Springer, Dordrecht (2010).</lncs>
<default>Toon A (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science. Frigg R, Hunter MC (Eds);  Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science, 262.  Dordrecht: Springer:  71-96.</default>
<mla>Toon, Adam. “Models as Make-Believe”. &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. R Frigg and MC Hunter. Dordrecht: Springer, 2010.Vol. 262. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science. 71-96.</mla>
<wels>Toon, A. (2010): Models as Make-Believe. In: R Frigg; MC Hunter (Hrsg.):  Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science. Dordrecht: Springer. (Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science, 262).  S. 71-96.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Toon, in &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Frigg, M.C. Hunter), Springer, Dordrecht, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 71-96.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Toon, A., 2010. Models as Make-Believe. In R.  Frigg &amp;amp; M. C.  Hunter, eds. &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science. no.262  Dordrecht: Springer, pp. 71-96.</harvard1>
<bio1>Toon A (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Models as Make-Believe. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science. Frigg R, Hunter MC (Eds); Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science, 262. Dordrecht: Springer:  71-96.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Toon, A. (2010). Models as Make-Believe. In R.  Frigg &amp;amp; M. C.  Hunter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science: Vol. 262&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-96). Dordrecht: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-90-481-3851-7_5&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Toon, A. (2010). “Models as Make-Believe” in &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;, Frigg, R., and Hunter, M. C. eds. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science, vol. 262, (Dordrecht: Springer), 71-96.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Toon, A. (2010). Models as Make-Believe (Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science). In R. Frigg &amp;amp; M.C. Hunter (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt; (S. 71-96). Dordrecht: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-90-481-3851-7_5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Toon A. Models as Make-Believe. In: Frigg R, Hunter MC, eds. &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;. Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science. Vol 262. Dordrecht: Springer;  2010: 71-96.</ama>
<ieee> A. Toon, “Models as Make-Believe”, &lt;em&gt;Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt;, R. Frigg and M.C. Hunter, eds., Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science, vol. 262,  Dordrecht: Springer, 2010,  pp.71-96.</ieee>
<apa>Toon, A. (2010). Models as Make-Believe. In R.  Frigg &amp;amp; M. C.  Hunter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Boston Studies in the Philosophy of Science: Vol. 262&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Beyond Mimesis And Convention: Representation In Art And Science&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-96). Dordrecht: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-90-481-3851-7_5</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2543607</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-12-03T06:34:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>