<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2546957</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">draft</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Richard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Power</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7346775</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8778-1273</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Background: Electronic Patient Records (EPRs) contain vast amounts of information in the form of texts, such as letters sent from a hospital to the patient’s local doctor (GP). The ability to extract data reliably from these texts would yield advances both in medical research and in individual patient care. In developing effective extraction methods, a crucial step is to create corpora that align samples of the relevant texts with a formal encoding of their meanings. To compile such corpora by human annotation is expensive and time-consuming; the more the task can be automated, the better.

Results: We propose a solution in which the results of an extraction algorithm are corrected using a transparent and fully reliable Natural Language Interface. Information Extraction records are transcoded to a Description Logic A-box and presented through a generated ‘feedback text’, which a medical expert can edit using the Conceptual Authoring technology.

Conclusions: At present we achieve a weak alignment between the encoded meaning and the original text (i.e., a set of records for the whole text); the next step is to achieve a strong alignment that links each phrase in the original text with the entity in the A-box that encodes its meaning. This technology has a wide range of potential applications, for instance as an editing tool for the Semantic Web.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="power-pietsch-07.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2546957/2546958/power-pietsch-07.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Conceptual Authoring</topic><topic>Ontologies</topic><topic>NLG</topic><topic>What You See Is What You Meant</topic><topic>WYSIWYM</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25469573</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Power, Richard, and Pietsch, Christian. “Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface”. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore, Draft.</mla>
<default>Power R, Pietsch C (Draft)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</default>
<lncs> Power, R., Pietsch, C.: Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore (Draft).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Power, Richard, and Pietsch, Christian. Draft. “Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface”. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Power, R., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (Draft). &lt;em&gt;Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</apa>
<ieee> R. Power and C. Pietsch, “Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface”, Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore, Draft.</ieee>
<ama>Power R, Pietsch C. Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</ama>
<frontiers>Power, R., and Pietsch, C. (Draft).“Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface”. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Power, R. &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (Draft). Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface. Gehalten auf der Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Power, R., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C. (Draft). &lt;em&gt;Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Power R, Pietsch C (Draft) &lt;br /&gt;Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</bio1>
<harvard1>Power, R., &amp;amp; Pietsch, C., Draft. Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface. Presented at the Accepted for presentation at the 2nd International Symposium on Languages in Biology and Medicine (LBM) 2007, Matrix, Biopolis, Singapore.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Power, and C.  Pietsch, &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Power, R.; Pietsch, C. (Draft): Editing Medical Data Records with a Natural Language Interface.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2546957</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-12-11T22:19:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>