<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2549190</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rabe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191159</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">178620</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc Erich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Latoschik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8937325</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marc Erich</namePart><namePart type="family">Latoschik</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart><namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Workshop Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes the configuration of a cost-efficient monolithic render server aimed at multi-screen Virtual Reality display devices. The system uses common Of-The-Shelf (OTS) PC components and feeds up to 6 independent screens via 3 graphics pipes with the potential to feed up to 12 screens. The internal graphics accelerators each use at least 8 PCIe lanes which results in sufficient bandwidth. Performance measurements are provided for several benchmarks which compare the system's performance to well established network based render clusters.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Rabe2007-LowCostImageGeneration-VRAR07-CameraReady.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2549190/2549196/Rabe2007-LowCostImageGeneration-VRAR07-CameraReady.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Shaker</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Weimar</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Low-cost image generation</topic><topic>render hardware</topic><topic>multi-screen rendering</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-8322-6367-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25491906</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">65-76</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Rabe F, Fröhlich C, Latoschik ME (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Latoschik ME, Fröhlich B (Eds); Aachen, Germany: Shaker:  65-76.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Rabe, C.  Fröhlich, and M. E.  Latoschik, in &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M.E. Latoschik, B. Fröhlich), Shaker, Aachen, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 65-76.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Rabe F, Fröhlich C, Latoschik ME (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Latoschik ME, Fröhlich B (Eds);  Aachen, Germany: Shaker:  65-76.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C., &amp;amp; Latoschik, M. E. (2007). Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In M. E.  Latoschik &amp;amp; B.  Fröhlich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 65-76). Aachen, Germany: Shaker.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Rabe, Felix, Fröhlich, Christian, and Latoschik, Marc Erich. “Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments”. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Marc Erich Latoschik and Bernd Fröhlich. Aachen, Germany: Shaker, 2007. 65-76.</mla>
<frontiers>Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C., and Latoschik, M. E. (2007). “Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments” in &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, Latoschik, M. E., and Fröhlich, B. eds. (Aachen, Germany: Shaker), 65-76.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C. &amp;amp; Latoschik, M.E. (2007). Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In M.E. Latoschik &amp;amp; B. Fröhlich (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (S. 65-76). Gehalten auf der Workshop Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität, Aachen, Germany: Shaker.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Rabe, F.; Fröhlich, C.; Latoschik, M. E. (2007): Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In: Marc Erich Latoschik; Bernd Fröhlich (Hrsg.):  Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. Aachen, Germany: Shaker.  S. 65-76.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, Felix, Fröhlich, Christian, and Latoschik, Marc Erich. 2007. “Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments”. In &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Marc Erich Latoschik and Bernd Fröhlich, 65-76. Aachen, Germany: Shaker.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C., Latoschik, M.E.: Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In: Latoschik, M.E. and Fröhlich, B. (eds.) Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR. p. 65-76. Shaker, Aachen, Germany (2007).</lncs>
<apa>Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C., &amp;amp; Latoschik, M. E. (2007). Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In M. E.  Latoschik &amp;amp; B.  Fröhlich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 65-76). Aachen, Germany: Shaker.</apa>
<ama>Rabe F, Fröhlich C, Latoschik ME. Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In: Latoschik ME, Fröhlich B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;. Aachen, Germany: Shaker;  2007: 65-76.</ama>
<ieee> F. Rabe, C. Fröhlich, and M.E. Latoschik, “Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments”, &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;, M.E. Latoschik and B. Fröhlich, eds.,  Aachen, Germany: Shaker, 2007,  pp.65-76.</ieee>
<harvard1>Rabe, F., Fröhlich, C., &amp;amp; Latoschik, M.E., 2007. Low-Cost Image Generation for Immersive Multi-Screen Environments. In M. E.  Latoschik &amp;amp; B.  Fröhlich, eds. &lt;em&gt;Virtuelle und Erweiterte Realität – 4. Workshop der GI-Fachgruppe VR/AR&lt;/em&gt;.  Aachen, Germany: Shaker, pp. 65-76.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2549190</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-01-08T11:19:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>