<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2550534</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Miriam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bröckel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030353</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Busch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030423</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katrin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Golsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16281346</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688208</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This article examines the extent to which people’s partners’ social capital and processes that take place at the inner couple level influence gender-specific probabilities of obtaining a leadership position.
First, well-established theories are examined that offer different assumptions as to how a partner’s resources can influence occupational career. This article adds to research by applying a relational perspective on partners’ resources beyond looking only at the individual’s and partner’s resources. To resolve the research question, data from the German Socio-Economic Panel Study (waves 1984 to 2010) were used in a longitudinal design employing event history analysis (N=11,050 men and N=8,988 women). The results show different outcomes for women and for men. For women, the relation of resources between partners plays a significant role in their promotion to the top, espe-cially their own comparative advantage; whereas for men, their own resources—independent of women’s resources—seem to be more relevant.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0014_Broeckel_Busch_Golsch.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2550534/2550536/SFB_882_WP_0014_Broeckel_Busch_Golsch.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>social capital</topic><topic>couples</topic><topic>Labor market</topic><topic>inequality</topic><topic>gender</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25505347</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bröckel, Miriam, Busch, Anne, and Golsch, Katrin. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 14. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bröckel, M., Busch, A., Golsch, K.: Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany? SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 14. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<default>Bröckel M, Busch A, Golsch K (2013)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 14.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Bröckel, Miriam, Busch, Anne, and Golsch, Katrin. &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 14.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bröckel, M., Busch, A. &amp;amp; Golsch, K. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bröckel, M., Busch, A., and Golsch, K. (2013). Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany? &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 14, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Bröckel M, Busch A, Golsch K. &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 14. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2013.</ama>
<ieee> M. Bröckel, A. Busch, and K. Golsch, &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 14,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Bröckel, M., Busch, A., &amp;amp; Golsch, K. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 14). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<wels>Bröckel, M.; Busch, A.; Golsch, K. (2013): Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Bröckel, A.  Busch, and K.  Golsch, &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bröckel M, Busch A, Golsch K (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 14.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bröckel, M., Busch, A., &amp;amp; Golsch, K., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.14, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bröckel, M., Busch, A., &amp;amp; Golsch, K. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Headwind or Tailwind — Do Partner’s Resources Support or Restrict a Promotion to a Leadership Position in Germany?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 14). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2550534</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-01-16T15:11:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>