<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2554434</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Clemens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18006844</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heinemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper combines the Aiyagari/Huggett-type standard incomplete markets model with the Arrow/Romer approach to growth to analyze feedback effects between growth and inequality, both endogenously determined in equilibrium. We derive conditions on existence/ nonexistence of balanced growth paths. Major results include that growth, inequality, and risk are positively related in our model, but we also identify a hump-shaped relationship between welfare and risk, indicating a tradeoff relationship between risk-pooling and growth in the determination of welfare. We discuss transitory dynamics and policy implications. A growth policy simultaneously reduces wealth inequality in the economy. The benefits and burdens of the underlying policy are unequally distributed, which raises the issue of politico-economic equilibria. We provide results on majority voting, finding that that the median voter prefers less than optimal subsidies on investment. Interestingly, the society might even vote against a policy providing full insurance against idiosyncratic risk, because welfare losses of lower growth more than offset welfare gains from lower risk.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WorkingPaper01_12.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2554434/2559600/WorkingPaper01_12.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>endogenous growth</topic><topic>idiosyncratic risk</topic><topic>borrowing constraints</topic><topic>heterogeneous agents</topic><topic>wealth distribution</topic><topic>optimal policy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25544341</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2554434</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>01-2012</number></detail><extent unit="pages">32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Clemens C, Heinemann M. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 01-2012. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2012.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Clemens, C. &amp;amp; Heinemann, M. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2554434.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Clemens, C., and Heinemann, M. (2012). Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 01-2012, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Clemens, C., &amp;amp; Heinemann, M. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2012). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2554434</apa>
<ieee> C. Clemens and M. Heinemann, &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 01-2012,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2012.</ieee>
<wels>Clemens, C.; Heinemann, M. (2012): Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Clemens C, Heinemann M (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2012.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Clemens, C., &amp;amp; Heinemann, M. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2012). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2554434&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Clemens, C., &amp;amp; Heinemann, M., 2012. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.01-2012, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Clemens, and M.  Heinemann, &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Clemens, C., Heinemann, M.: Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2012. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Clemens, Christiane, and Heinemann, Maik. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 01-2012. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Clemens, Christiane, and Heinemann, Maik. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous Growth, the Distribution of Wealth, and Optimal Policy under Incomplete Markets and Idiosyncratic Risk&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2012. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 01-2012.</mla>
<default>Clemens C, Heinemann M (2012)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2012.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2554434</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-02-07T08:44:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>