<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2556267</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joseph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoffman</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23351084</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5895-8949</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael As</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thorne</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philip N</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trathan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jaume</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Forcada</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">BACKGROUND: Transcriptomes are powerful resources, providing a window on the expressed portion of the genome that can be generated rapidly and at low cost for virtually any organism. However, because many genes have tissue-specific expression patterns, developing a complete transcriptome usually requires a 'discovery pool' of individuals to be sacrificed in order to harvest mRNA from as many different types of tissue as possible. This hinders transcriptome development in large, charismatic and endangered species, many of which stand the most to gain from such approaches. To circumvent this problem in a model pinniped species, we 454 sequenced cDNA from testis, heart, spleen, intestine, kidney and lung tissues obtained from nine adult male Antarctic fur seals (Arctocephalus gazella) that died of natural causes at Bird Island, South Georgia. RESULTS: After applying stringent quality control criteria based on length and annotation, we obtained 12,397 contigs which, in combination with 454 data previously obtained from skin, gave a total of 23,096 unique contigs. Homology was found to 77.0% of dog (Canis lupus familiaris) transcripts, suggesting that the combined assembly represents a substantial proportion of this species' transcriptome. Moreover, only 0.5% of transcripts revealed sequence similarity to bacteria, implying minimal contamination, and the percentage of transcripts involved in cell death was low at 2.6%. Transcripts with immune-related annotations were almost five-fold enriched relative to skin and represented 13.2% of all spleen-specific contigs. By reference to the dog, we also identified transcripts revealing homology to five class I, ten class II and three class III genes of the Major Histocompatibility Complex and derived the putative genomic distribution of 17,121 contigs, 2,119 in silico mined microsatellites and 9,382 single nucleotide polymorphisms. CONCLUSIONS: Our findings suggest that transcriptome development based on samples collected post mortem may greatly facilitate genomic studies, not only of marine mammals but also more generally of species that are of conservation concern.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="hoffman.1471-2164-14-52.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2556267/2556273/hoffman.1471-2164-14-52.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Genomics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2164</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23347513</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000314630800001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25562671</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-14-52</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Hoffman, Joseph, Thorne, Michael As, Trathan, Philip N, and Forcada, Jaume. “Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14.1 (2013): 52.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoffman, J., Thorne, M. A., Trathan, P. N., &amp;amp; Forcada, J. (2013). Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 52. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-52&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hoffman, J., Thorne, M. A., Trathan, P. N., and Forcada, J. (2013). Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14:52.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoffman, J., Thorne, M.A., Trathan, P.N. &amp;amp; Forcada, J. (2013). Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1): 52. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-52.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Hoffman, J.; Thorne, M. A.; Trathan, P. N.; Forcada, J. (2013): Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,14:(1):52</wels>
<bio1>Hoffman J, Thorne MA, Trathan PN, Forcada J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 14(1): 52.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hoffman, M. A.  Thorne, P. N.  Trathan, and J.  Forcada, “Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;, : 52.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Hoffman J, Thorne MA, Trathan PN, Forcada J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14(1): 52.</default>
<ama>Hoffman J, Thorne MA, Trathan PN, Forcada J. Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;14(1): 52.</ama>
<ieee> J. Hoffman, et al., “Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 14, 2013, : 52.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hoffman, J., et al., 2013. Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, 14(1): 52.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoffman, Joseph, Thorne, Michael As, Trathan, Philip N, and Forcada, Jaume. 2013. “Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14 (1): 52.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hoffman, J., Thorne, M.A., Trathan, P.N., Forcada, J.: Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. BMC Genomics. 14, : 52 (2013).</lncs>
<apa>Hoffman, J., Thorne, M. A., Trathan, P. N., &amp;amp; Forcada, J. (2013). Transcriptome of the dead: characterisation of immune genes and marker development from necropsy samples in a free-ranging marine mammal. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 52. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-52</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2556267</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-02-15T06:55:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>