<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2559629</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mühlheußer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6234333</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">42173282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In contexts such as education and sports, skill-accumulation of individuals over time crucially depends on the amount of training they receive, which is often allocated on the basis of repeated selection. We analyze optimal selection policies in a model of endogenous skill formation where, apart from their ability to transform training into skills, individuals also differ with respect to relative age. The latter has been identified by recent empirical research as a major determinant for performance differentials within cohorts. We find that the optimal policy is pro-competitive at later selection stages in the sense of selecting the individuals with the higher skill signals. All eventual corrections due to relative age occur at early stages, where selection is either counter-competitive (i.e. individuals with low skill signals are selected) or even avoided at all. Thereby, the induced selection quality is non-monotone in the degree of ex-ante asymmetry due to relative age. Finally, the (empirical) observation of persistent relative age effects does in general not hint at suboptimal selection policies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WorkingPaper02_12.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2559629/2559636/WorkingPaper02_12.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Training</topic><topic>Human Capital</topic><topic>Heterogeneity</topic><topic>Education</topic><topic>Skill Formation</topic><topic>Selection</topic><topic>Age Effects</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25596294</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2559629</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>02-2012</number></detail><extent unit="pages">41</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2915320</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Dawid H, Mühlheußer G. &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 02-2012. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2012.</ama>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., and Mühlheußer, G. (2012). Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 02-2012, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H. &amp;amp; Mühlheußer, G. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2559629.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Mühlheußer, G. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2012). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2559629</apa>
<ieee> H. Dawid and G. Mühlheußer, &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 02-2012,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2012.</ieee>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Mühlheußer, G. (2012): Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Mühlheußer, G. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2012). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2559629&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Dawid H, Mühlheußer G (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2012.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Mühlheußer, G., 2012. &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.02-2012, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, and G.  Mühlheußer, &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Mühlheußer, G.: Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2012. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, and Mühlheußer, Gerd. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 02-2012. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, and Mühlheußer, Gerd. &lt;em&gt;Repeated Selection with Heterogenous Individuals and Relative Age Effects&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2012. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 02-2012.</mla>
<default>Dawid H, Mühlheußer G (2012)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2012.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2559629</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-02-28T15:25:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>