<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2559970</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rabe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191159</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Masaaki</namePart><namePart type="family">Kurosu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>HCI International 2013</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Have you ever found yourself in front of a computer and asking it aloud: “Why?” We have constructed a cognitively motivated episodic memory system that enables a virtual guide to respond to this question. The guide, a virtual agent based on a belief–desire–intention (BDI) architecture, is employed in a Virtual Reality (VR) scenario where he accompanies a human visitor on a tour through a city. In this paper we explain how the agents memorizes events and episodes according to an event-indexing model and how the interaction is enhanced by using these memories. We argue that due to the cognitively motivated nature of the event-indexing model every interaction situation can be described, memorized, recalled and explained by the agent.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Rabe_Wachsmuth-Enhancing_HCI_with_Episodic_Memory-preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2559970/2631518/Rabe_Wachsmuth-Enhancing_HCI_with_Episodic_Memory-preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Las Vegas, NV, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Episodic Memory</topic><topic>Virtual Guide</topic><topic>Event Indexing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0302-9743</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-39330-3</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-39329-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25599708</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-39330-3_13</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8007</number></detail><extent unit="pages">117-125</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Rabe, F.; Wachsmuth, I. (2013): Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In: Masaaki Kurosu (Hrsg.):  Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013. Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8007).  S. 117-125.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Rabe, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Kurosu), Springer, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 117-125.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Rabe F, Wachsmuth I (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013. Kurosu M (Ed); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8007. Heidelberg: Springer:  117-125.</bio1>
<harvard1>Rabe, F., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2013. Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In M.  Kurosu, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8007  Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 117-125.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, F., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In M.  Kurosu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 117-125). Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39330-3_13&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, F. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In M. Kurosu (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt; (S. 117-125). Gehalten auf der HCI International 2013, Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39330-3_13.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Rabe, F., and Wachsmuth, I. (2013). “Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide” in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;, Kurosu, M. ed. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8007, (Heidelberg: Springer), 117-125.</frontiers>
<ama>Rabe F, Wachsmuth I. Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In: Kurosu M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8007. Heidelberg: Springer;  2013: 117-125.</ama>
<ieee> F. Rabe and I. Wachsmuth, “Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide”, &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;, M. Kurosu, ed., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8007,  Heidelberg: Springer, 2013,  pp.117-125.</ieee>
<apa>Rabe, F., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In M.  Kurosu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 117-125). Heidelberg: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39330-3_13</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rabe, Felix, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2013. “Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide”. In &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Masaaki Kurosu, 8007:117-125. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rabe, F., Wachsmuth, I.: Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide. In: Kurosu, M. (ed.) Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8007, p. 117-125. Springer, Heidelberg (2013).</lncs>
<default>Rabe F, Wachsmuth I (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013. Kurosu M (Ed);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8007.  Heidelberg: Springer:  117-125.</default>
<mla>Rabe, Felix, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Enhancing human computer interaction with episodic memory in a virtual guide”. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction: Interaction Modalities and Techniques, Part IV, HCII 2013&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Masaaki Kurosu. Heidelberg: Springer, 2013.Vol. 8007. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 117-125.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2559970</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-03-04T11:04:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>