<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2561929</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6564614</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33056</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5842-9991</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015523</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ESANN</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present a novel approach to model perceptual grouping based on phase and frequency synchronization in a network of coupled Kuramoto oscillators. Transferring the grouping concept from the Competitive Layer Model (CLM) to a network of Kuramoto oscillators, we preserve the excellent grouping capabilities of the CLM, while dramatically improving the convergence rate, robustness to noise, and computational performance, which is verified in a series of artificial grouping experiments.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="esann_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2561929/2561930/esann_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>d-side</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bruges (Belgium)</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="ISI">000338403800009</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25619294</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2014.02.011</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H. Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. In:  &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges (Belgium): d-side;  2013.</ama>
<lncs> Meier, M., Haschke, R., Ritter, H.: Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN).  d-side, Bruges (Belgium) (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, Martin, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. 2013. “Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks”. In &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges (Belgium): d-side.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, M., Haschke, R. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2013). Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der ESANN, Bruges (Belgium): d-side. doi:10.1016/j.neucom.2014.02.011.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. &lt;br /&gt;In:  European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN).  Bruges (Belgium): d-side.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Meier, R.  Haschke, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;, D-Side, Bruges (Belgium), &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> M. Meier, R. Haschke, and H. Ritter, “Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks”, &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;,  Bruges (Belgium): d-side, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2013. Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. In &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;.  Bruges (Belgium): d-side.</harvard1>
<apa>Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2013). Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt; Bruges (Belgium): d-side. doi:10.1016/j.neucom.2014.02.011</apa>
<mla>Meier, Martin, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. “Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks”. &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges (Belgium): d-side, 2013.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2013). Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt; Bruges (Belgium): d-side. doi:10.1016/j.neucom.2014.02.011&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Meier, M., Haschke, R., and Ritter, H. (2013). “Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks” in &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)&lt;/em&gt; (Bruges (Belgium): d-side).</frontiers>
<wels>Meier, M.; Haschke, R.; Ritter, H. (2013): Perceptual Grouping through Competition in Coupled Oscillator Networks. In: European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN). Bruges (Belgium): d-side.</wels>
<default>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN). Bruges (Belgium): d-side.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2561929</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-03-14T15:50:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>