<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2561569</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manuela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfinder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16213569</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton E</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kunst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinhold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Feldmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van Eijsden</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tanja G. M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vrijkotte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">BACKGROUND: Inconsistent data on the association between prenatal alcohol exposure and a range of pregnancy outcomes, such as preterm birth (PTB) and small for gestational age (SGA) raise new questions. This study aimed to assess whether the association between low-moderate prenatal alcohol exposure and PTB and SGA differs according to maternal education, maternal mental distress or maternal smoking. METHODS: The Amsterdam Born Children and their Development (ABCD) Study (N=5,238) and the German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Children and Adolescents (KiGGS) (N=16,301) are both large studies. Women provide information on alcohol intake in early pregnancy, 3 months postpartum and up to 17 years retrospectively. Multivariate logistic regression analyses and stratified regression analyses were performed to examine the association between prenatal alcohol exposure and PTB and SGA, respectively. RESULTS: No association was found between any level of prenatal alcohol exposure (non-daily, daily, non-abstaining) and SGA. The offspring of daily drinkers and non-abstainers had a lower risk of PTB [ABCD: odds ratio (OR) 0.31, 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.13, 0.77; KiGGS: OR 0.75, 95% CI 0.57, 0.99]. Interactions with maternal education, maternal distress or maternal smoking were not significant. CONCLUSIONS: Although these results should be interpreted with caution, both studies showed no adverse effects of low-moderate prenatal alcohol exposure on PTB and SGA, not even in the offspring of women who were disadvantaged in terms of low education, high levels of distress, or smoking during pregnancy.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1471-2393-13-49.pfinder.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2561569/2564147/1471-2393-13-49.pfinder.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2393</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23433310</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000316722000001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25615694</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2393-13-49</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Pfinder, Manuela, Kunst, Anton E, Feldmann, Reinhold, van Eijsden, Manon, and Vrijkotte, Tanja G. M. “Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 13.1 (2013): 49.</mla>
<default>Pfinder M, Kunst AE, Feldmann R, van Eijsden M, Vrijkotte TGM (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 13(1): 49.</default>
<lncs> Pfinder, M., Kunst, A.E., Feldmann, R., van Eijsden, M., Vrijkotte, T.G.M.: Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth. 13, : 49 (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, Manuela, Kunst, Anton E, Feldmann, Reinhold, van Eijsden, Manon, and Vrijkotte, Tanja G. M. 2013. “Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 13 (1): 49.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Pfinder, M., et al., 2013. Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, 13(1): 49.</harvard1>
<bio1>Pfinder M, Kunst AE, Feldmann R, van Eijsden M, Vrijkotte TGM (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth 13(1): 49.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M., Kunst, A. E., Feldmann, R., van Eijsden, M., &amp;amp; Vrijkotte, T. G. M. (2013). Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 49. doi:10.1186/1471-2393-13-49&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Pfinder, A. E.  Kunst, R.  Feldmann, M.  van Eijsden, and T. G. M.  Vrijkotte, “Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, : 49.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Pfinder, M.; Kunst, A. E.; Feldmann, R.; van Eijsden, M.; Vrijkotte, T. G. M. (2013): Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;,13:(1):49</wels>
<apa>Pfinder, M., Kunst, A. E., Feldmann, R., van Eijsden, M., &amp;amp; Vrijkotte, T. G. M. (2013). Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 49. doi:10.1186/1471-2393-13-49</apa>
<ieee> M. Pfinder, et al., “Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 13, 2013, : 49.</ieee>
<ama>Pfinder M, Kunst AE, Feldmann R, van Eijsden M, Vrijkotte TGM. Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;13(1): 49.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M., Kunst, A.E., Feldmann, R., van Eijsden, M. &amp;amp; Vrijkotte, T.G.M. (2013). Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1): 49. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1471-2393-13-49.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pfinder, M., Kunst, A. E., Feldmann, R., van Eijsden, M., and Vrijkotte, T. G. M. (2013). Preterm birth and small for gestational age in relation to alcohol consumption during pregnancy: stronger associations among vulnerable women? Results from two large Western-European studies. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 13:49.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2561569</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-03-08T13:31:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>