<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2562664</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emily J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blanchard</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tatyana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chesnokova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Willmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26488631</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper explores the role of pooled-producer, e.g. private label, trade intermediation in shaping the range and diversity of exports. Direct sales maintain a firm's unique product characteristics ('brand equity'), whereas trade through an intermediary can take two forms - either a wholesaling arrangement that (also) maintains the exporter's unique brand but imposes a higher marginal cost (via double marginalization), or a 'private label' contract
under which the firm's product is pooled with other firms' output and re-sold under a new private label brand created by the intermediary. This paper focuses on the latter, and shows that the availability of the private label option results in greater total export volumes and
lower average prices for consumers, but fewer independent varieties available in equilibrium. Welfare implications are mixed: consumers trade variety for volume, firms face greater competition from the new pooled-products, and intermediaries capture much of the gains from trade.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_02_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2562664/2915368/wpaper_02_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Intermediaries</topic><topic>Heterogeneous Firms</topic><topic>Private Labels</topic><topic>International Retailers</topic><topic>Export Mode</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25626644</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2562664</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>02-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">26</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blanchard, Emily J., Chesnokova, Tatyana, and Willmann, Gerald. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 02-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Blanchard, E.J., Chesnokova, T., Willmann, G.: Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Blanchard EJ, Chesnokova T, Willmann G. &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 02-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>E. J.  Blanchard, T.  Chesnokova, and G.  Willmann, &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Blanchard EJ, Chesnokova T, Willmann G (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blanchard, E.J., Chesnokova, T. &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562664.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Blanchard, E. J., Chesnokova, T., &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562664</apa>
<harvard1>Blanchard, E.J., Chesnokova, T., &amp;amp; Willmann, G., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.02-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> E.J. Blanchard, T. Chesnokova, and G. Willmann, &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 02-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<default>Blanchard EJ, Chesnokova T, Willmann G (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<wels>Blanchard, E. J.; Chesnokova, T.; Willmann, G. (2013): Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<mla>Blanchard, Emily J., Chesnokova, Tatyana, and Willmann, Gerald. &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 02-2013.</mla>
<frontiers>Blanchard, E. J., Chesnokova, T., and Willmann, G. (2013). Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 02-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Blanchard, E. J., Chesnokova, T., &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Private Labels and International Trade: Trading Variety for Volume&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562664&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2562664</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-03-20T12:34:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>