<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2562662</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We present a monetary endogenous growth model and analyze the effects of fiscal and monetary policy with real money as an argument in the utility function. We show that a balanced government budget gives a higher balanced growth rate and lower inflation than a situation with permanent public deficits. It also leads to higher welfare compared to a situation with permanent deficits where the overnment does not put a high weight on stabilizing debt. However, when governments run deficits with a high weight on stabilizing debt, comparative welfare effects depend on the
initial conditions with respect to public debt. Further, for a given monetary policy a stricter debt policy yields higher growth, lower inflation and higher welfare. A
rise in the nominal money supply can compensate the negative growth effects of a loose debt policy up to a certain point but only at the cost of higher inflation and
lower welfare.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_10_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2562662/2915400/wpaper_10_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>monetary policy</topic><topic>inter-temporal budget constraint</topic><topic>Public debt</topic><topic>economicgrowth</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25626629</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2562662</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Greiner A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562662.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 10-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Greiner, A.: Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 10-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<default>Greiner A (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<wels>Greiner, A. (2013): Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Greiner, A. (2013). Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 10-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562662&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 10-2013.</mla>
<apa>Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2562662</apa>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.10-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal and monetary policy in a basic endogenous growth model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 10-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2562662</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-03-20T12:29:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>