<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2565267</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard-Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brüning</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8052516</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schnier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20814347</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8408393</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nicoletta</namePart><namePart type="family">Calzolari</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Khalid</namePart><namePart type="family">Choukri</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thierry</namePart><namePart type="family">Declerck</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mehmet</namePart><namePart type="family">Uğur Doğan</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bente</namePart><namePart type="family">Maegaard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Joseph</namePart><namePart type="family">Mariani</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jan</namePart><namePart type="family">Odijk</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stelios</namePart><namePart type="family">Piperidis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015530</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In order to understand and model the non-verbal communicative conduct of humans, it seems fruitful to combine qualitative methods (Conversation Analysis) and quantitative techniques (motion capturing). A tool for data visualization and annotation is important as it constitutes a central interface between different research approaches and methodologies. We have developed the pre-annotation tool “PAMOCAT” that detects motion segments of individual joints. A sophisticated user interface enables the annotating person to easily find correlations between different joints and to export combined qualitative and quantitative annotations to standard annotation tools. Using this technique we are able to examine complex setups with three persons in tight conversation. A functionality to search for special postures of interest and display the frames in an overview makes it easy to analyze different phenomena in Conversation Analysis.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="LREC_BernhardChrsitianKarolaSven-Paper_V30.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2565267/2674919/LREC_BernhardChrsitianKarolaSven-Paper_V30.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Istanbul, Turkey</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Motion capturing</topic><topic>Motion segmentation</topic><topic>posture retrieval</topic><topic>Motion decomposition.</topic><topic>annotation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-2-9517408-7-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25169684</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">4143-4148</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Pitsch, Karola, and Wachsmuth, Sven. “PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Nicoletta Calzolari, Khalid Choukri, Thierry Declerck, Mehmet Uğur Doğan, Bente Maegaard, Joseph Mariani, Jan Odijk, and Stelios Piperidis. European Language Resources Association (ELRA), 2012. 4143-4148.</mla>
<default>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012). Calzolari N, Choukri K, Declerck T, Uğur Doğan M, Maegaard B, Mariani J, Odijk J, Piperidis S (Eds);  European Language Resources Association (ELRA):  4143-4148.</default>
<lncs> Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., Wachsmuth, S.: PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In: Calzolari, N., Choukri, K., Declerck, T., Uğur Doğan, M., Maegaard, B., Mariani, J., Odijk, J., and Piperidis, S. (eds.) Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012). p. 4143-4148. European Language Resources Association (ELRA) (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, Bernhard-Andreas, Schnier, Christian, Pitsch, Karola, and Wachsmuth, Sven. 2012. “PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Nicoletta Calzolari, Khalid Choukri, Thierry Declerck, Mehmet Uğur Doğan, Bente Maegaard, Joseph Mariani, Jan Odijk, and Stelios Piperidis, 4143-4148. European Language Resources Association (ELRA).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2012). PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In N.  Calzolari, K.  Choukri, T.  Declerck, M.  Uğur Doğan, B.  Maegaard, J.  Mariani, J.  Odijk, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 4143-4148). European Language Resources Association (ELRA).</apa>
<ieee> B.-A. Brüning, et al., “PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;, N. Calzolari, et al., eds., European Language Resources Association (ELRA), 2012,  pp.4143-4148.</ieee>
<ama>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S. PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In: Calzolari N, Choukri K, Declerck T, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;. European Language Resources Association (ELRA);  2012: 4143-4148.</ama>
<frontiers>Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., and Wachsmuth, S. (2012). “PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;, Calzolari, N., Choukri, K., Declerck, T., Uğur Doğan, M., Maegaard, B., Mariani, J., Odijk, J., and Piperidis, S. eds. (European Language Resources Association (ELRA), 4143-4148.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, B.-A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2012). PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In N. Calzolari, K. Choukri, T. Declerck, M. Uğur Doğan, B. Maegaard, J. Mariani, J. Odijk &amp;amp; S. Piperidis (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 4143-4148). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC), European Language Resources Association (ELRA).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Brüning, B.-A., et al., 2012. PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In N.  Calzolari, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt;.  European Language Resources Association (ELRA), pp. 4143-4148.</harvard1>
<bio1>Brüning B-A, Schnier C, Pitsch K, Wachsmuth S (2012) &lt;br /&gt;PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012). Calzolari N, Choukri K, Declerck T, Uğur Doğan M, Maegaard B, Mariani J, Odijk J, Piperidis S (Eds); European Language Resources Association (ELRA):  4143-4148.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brüning, B. - A., Schnier, C., Pitsch, K., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2012). PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In N.  Calzolari, K.  Choukri, T.  Declerck, M.  Uğur Doğan, B.  Maegaard, J.  Mariani, J.  Odijk, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 4143-4148). European Language Resources Association (ELRA).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B. - A.  Brüning, C.  Schnier, K.  Pitsch, and S.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Calzolari, K. Choukri, T. Declerck, M. Uğur Doğan, B. Maegaard, J. Mariani, J. Odijk, S. Piperidis), European Language Resources Association (Elra), &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 4143-4148.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Brüning, B. - A.; Schnier, C.; Pitsch, K.; Wachsmuth, S. (2012): PAMOCAT: Automatic retrieval of specified postures. In: Nicoletta Calzolari; Khalid Choukri; Thierry Declerck; Mehmet Uğur Doğan; Bente Maegaard; Joseph Mariani; Jan Odijk; Stelios Piperidis (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2012). European Language Resources Association (ELRA).  S. 4143-4148.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2565267</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-04-04T03:45:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>