<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2576303</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Christ</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25339249</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mielebacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sergio</namePart><namePart type="family">Alvarez</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jordi</namePart><namePart type="family">Solé-Casals</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ana</namePart><namePart type="family">Fred</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hugo</namePart><namePart type="family">Gamboa</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BIOSIGNALS_2013_12_CR.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2576303/2653823/BIOSIGNALS_2013_12_CR.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>SciTePress</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25763036</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">11-19</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Christ, P.; Werner, F.; Rückert, U.; Mielebacher, J. (2013): Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In: Sergio Alvarez; Jordi Solé-Casals; Ana Fred; Hugo Gamboa (Hrsg.):  Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies. SciTePress.  S. 11-19.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Christ, P., Werner, F., Rückert, U. &amp;amp; Mielebacher, J. (2013). Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In S. Alvarez, J. Solé-Casals, A. Fred &amp;amp; H. Gamboa (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt; (S. 11-19). SciTePress.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Christ, P., Werner, F., Rückert, U., &amp;amp; Mielebacher, J. (2013). Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In S.  Alvarez, J.  Solé-Casals, A.  Fred, &amp;amp; H.  Gamboa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-19). SciTePress.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Christ, P., Werner, F., Rückert, U., and Mielebacher, J. (2013). “Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor” in &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;, Alvarez, S., Solé-Casals, J., Fred, A., and Gamboa, H. eds. (SciTePress), 11-19.</frontiers>
<mla>Christ, Peter, Werner, F., Rückert, Ulrich, and Mielebacher, J. “Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor”. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sergio Alvarez, Jordi Solé-Casals, Ana Fred, and Hugo Gamboa. SciTePress, 2013. 11-19.</mla>
<default>Christ P, Werner F, Rückert U, Mielebacher J (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies. Alvarez S, Solé-Casals J, Fred A, Gamboa H (Eds);  SciTePress:  11-19.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Christ, F.  Werner, U.  Rückert, and J.  Mielebacher, in &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Alvarez, J. Solé-Casals, A. Fred, H. Gamboa), Scitepress, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 11-19.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Christ P, Werner F, Rückert U, Mielebacher J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies. Alvarez S, Solé-Casals J, Fred A, Gamboa H (Eds); SciTePress:  11-19.</bio1>
<harvard1>Christ, P., et al., 2013. Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In S.  Alvarez, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;.  SciTePress, pp. 11-19.</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Christ, et al., “Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor”, &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;, S. Alvarez, et al., eds., SciTePress, 2013,  pp.11-19.</ieee>
<ama>Christ P, Werner F, Rückert U, Mielebacher J. Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In: Alvarez S, Solé-Casals J, Fred A, Gamboa H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;. SciTePress;  2013: 11-19.</ama>
<apa>Christ, P., Werner, F., Rückert, U., &amp;amp; Mielebacher, J. (2013). Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In S.  Alvarez, J.  Solé-Casals, A.  Fred, &amp;amp; H.  Gamboa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 11-19). SciTePress.</apa>
<lncs> Christ, P., Werner, F., Rückert, U., Mielebacher, J.: Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor. In: Alvarez, S., Solé-Casals, J., Fred, A., and Gamboa, H. (eds.) Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies. p. 11-19. SciTePress (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Christ, Peter, Werner, F., Rückert, Ulrich, and Mielebacher, J. 2013. “Athlete Identification using Acceleration and Electrocardiographic Measurements Recorded with a Wireless Body Sensor”. In &lt;em&gt;Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Bio-Inspired Systems and Signal Processing, Int. Joint Conf. on Biomedical Engineering Systems and Technologies&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sergio Alvarez, Jordi Solé-Casals, Ana Fred, and Hugo Gamboa, 11-19. SciTePress.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2576303</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-04-19T12:56:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>