<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2578967</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Basak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bilecen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6023853</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688781</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper discusses the importance of social network analysis (SNA) in investigating informal social protection across borders. Social network analysis is used to identify relationships among actors such as individuals, organizations, departments within organizations, and countries. One of the major strengths of SNA in the study of social protection is that it allows for the systematic analysis of relations at multiple levels and for easy visualization. When combined with qualitative interviews, SNA has the potential to provide a complete picture of interpersonal relations. The article illustrates how the combined use of methods produces distinctive data on protection strategies and their meanings. It considers the main features of network analysis in the investigation of social protection, while also giving special attention to cross-border social structures. Because of its relationship-based nature, social protection is chosen as a "strategic research site" (Merton 1963) for this methodological approach.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0019_Bilecen.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2578967/2578968/SFB_882_WP_0019_Bilecen.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cross-border studies</topic><topic>social network analysis (SNA)</topic><topic>migration</topic><topic>ROSCA</topic><topic>transnationality</topic><topic>informal social protection</topic><topic>egocentric network analysis</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25789673</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19</number></detail><extent unit="pages">34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Bilecen, &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bilecen B (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 19.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, B. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, Basak. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 19. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bilecen, B.: Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 19. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Bilecen B. &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 19. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2013.</ama>
<default>Bilecen B (2013)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 19.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Bilecen, Basak. &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 19.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bilecen, B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 19). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bilecen, B. (2013). Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 19, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Bilecen, B. (2013): Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<apa>Bilecen, B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 19). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<harvard1>Bilecen, B., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.19, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Bilecen, &lt;em&gt;Analyzing Informal Social Protection Across Borders: Synthesizing Social Network Analysis with Qualitative Interviews&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 19,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2578967</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-05-07T08:57:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>