<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2584766</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25994765</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2190-5576</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ad</namePart><namePart type="family">van Berlo</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kasper</namePart><namePart type="family">Hallenborg</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Juan M. Corchado</namePart><namePart type="family">Rodriguez</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dante I.</namePart><namePart type="family">Tapia</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paulo</namePart><namePart type="family">Novais</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015530</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4th International Symposium on Ambient Intelligence (ISAmI 2013)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We introduce a method for detecting whether two users are engaged in focused interaction using a windowed correlation measure on their acoustic signals, assuming that a continued exchange of verbal turns contributes to anticorrelation of
acoustic activity. We tested our method with manually annotated transitions between focused and unfocused interaction stemming from experiments on AR-based coop-
eration within a research project on alignment in communication. The results show that a high degree and extended duration of speech activity anticorrelation reliably indicates focused interaction, and might thus be a valuable asset for situation-aware technical systems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="id16_neumann_hermann.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2584766/2638083/id16_neumann_hermann.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Salamanca, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>multiscale analysis</topic><topic>data mining</topic><topic>correlation</topic><topic>speech activity</topic><topic>collaboration</topic><topic>situation awareness</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2194-5357</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-25847661</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-00566-9_10</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>219</number></detail><extent unit="pages">71-78</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Neumann A, Hermann T (2013) &lt;br /&gt;A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications. van Berlo A, Hallenborg K, Rodriguez JMC, Tapia DI, Novais P (Eds); Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, 219. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing:  71-78.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Neumann, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. van Berlo, K. Hallenborg, J.M.C. Rodriguez, D.I. Tapia, P. Novais), Springer International Publishing, Switzerland, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 71-78.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, A. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support (Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing). In A. van Berlo, K. Hallenborg, J.M.C. Rodriguez, D.I. Tapia &amp;amp; P. Novais (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (S. 71-78). Gehalten auf der 4th International Symposium on Ambient Intelligence (ISAmI 2013), Switzerland: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-00566-9_10.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, Alexander, and Hermann, Thomas. 2013. “A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support”. In &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ad van Berlo, Kasper Hallenborg, Juan M. Corchado Rodriguez, Dante I. Tapia, and Paulo Novais, 219:71-78. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Neumann, A., Hermann, T.: A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In: van Berlo, A., Hallenborg, K., Rodriguez, J.M.C., Tapia, D.I., and Novais, P. (eds.) Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing. 219, p. 71-78. Springer International Publishing, Switzerland (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Neumann A, Hermann T. A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In: van Berlo A, Hallenborg K, Rodriguez JMC, Tapia DI, Novais P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing. Vol 219. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing;  2013: 71-78.</ama>
<default>Neumann A, Hermann T (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications. van Berlo A, Hallenborg K, Rodriguez JMC, Tapia DI, Novais P (Eds);  Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, 219.  Switzerland: Springer International Publishing:  71-78.</default>
<wels>Neumann, A.; Hermann, T. (2013): A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In: Ad van Berlo; Kasper Hallenborg; Juan M. Corchado Rodriguez; Dante I. Tapia; Paulo Novais (Hrsg.):  Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing. (Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, 219).  S. 71-78.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In A.  van Berlo, K.  Hallenborg, J. M. C.  Rodriguez, D. I.  Tapia, &amp;amp; P.  Novais (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing: Vol. 219&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-78). Switzerland: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-00566-9_10&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Neumann, Alexander, and Hermann, Thomas. “A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support”. &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ad van Berlo, Kasper Hallenborg, Juan M. Corchado Rodriguez, Dante I. Tapia, and Paulo Novais. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing, 2013.Vol. 219. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing. 71-78.</mla>
<frontiers>Neumann, A., and Hermann, T. (2013). “A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support” in &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, van Berlo, A., Hallenborg, K., Rodriguez, J. M. C., Tapia, D. I., and Novais, P. eds. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol. 219, (Switzerland: Springer International Publishing), 71-78.</frontiers>
<apa>Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In A.  van Berlo, K.  Hallenborg, J. M. C.  Rodriguez, D. I.  Tapia, &amp;amp; P.  Novais (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing: Vol. 219&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-78). Switzerland: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-00566-9_10</apa>
<ieee> A. Neumann and T. Hermann, “A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support”, &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;, A. van Berlo, et al., eds., Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol. 219,  Switzerland: Springer International Publishing, 2013,  pp.71-78.</ieee>
<harvard1>Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2013. A Verbal Interaction Measure Using Acoustic Signal Correlation for Dyadic Cooperation Support. In A.  van Berlo, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Ambient Intelligence - Software and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing. no.219  Switzerland: Springer International Publishing, pp. 71-78.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2584766</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-06-04T08:20:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>