<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2603476</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">37260489</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rudolph</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Nikos</namePart><namePart type="family">Mastorakis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Antonella</namePart><namePart type="family">Cecchi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="cimmacs06.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2603476/2624524/cimmacs06.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26034764</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">234-239</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klinger, Roman, and Rudolph, Günter. 2006. “Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Nikos Mastorakis and Antonella Cecchi, 234-239. Venice, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Klinger, R., Rudolph, G.: Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In: Mastorakis, N. and Cecchi, A. (eds.) Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06). p. 234-239. Venice, Italy (2006).</lncs>
<default>Klinger R, Rudolph G (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06). Mastorakis N, Cecchi A (Eds);  Venice, Italy:  234-239.</default>
<mla>Klinger, Roman, and Rudolph, Günter. “Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Nikos Mastorakis and Antonella Cecchi. Venice, Italy, 2006. 234-239.</mla>
<wels>Klinger, R.; Rudolph, G. (2006): Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In: Nikos Mastorakis; Antonella Cecchi (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06). Venice, Italy.  S. 234-239.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Klinger, and G.  Rudolph, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Mastorakis, A. Cecchi), Venice, Italy, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 234-239.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Klinger, R., &amp;amp; Rudolph, G., 2006. Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In N.  Mastorakis &amp;amp; A.  Cecchi, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;.  Venice, Italy, pp. 234-239.</harvard1>
<bio1>Klinger R, Rudolph G (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06). Mastorakis N, Cecchi A (Eds); Venice, Italy:  234-239.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klinger, R., &amp;amp; Rudolph, G. (2006). Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In N.  Mastorakis &amp;amp; A.  Cecchi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 234-239). Venice, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klinger, R. &amp;amp; Rudolph, G. (2006). Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In N. Mastorakis &amp;amp; A. Cecchi (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 234-239). Venice, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Klinger, R., and Rudolph, G. (2006). “Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;, Mastorakis, N., and Cecchi, A. eds. (Venice, Italy), 234-239.</frontiers>
<ama>Klinger R, Rudolph G. Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In: Mastorakis N, Cecchi A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;. Venice, Italy;  2006: 234-239.</ama>
<ieee> R. Klinger and G. Rudolph, “Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt;, N. Mastorakis and A. Cecchi, eds.,  Venice, Italy: 2006,  pp.234-239.</ieee>
<apa>Klinger, R., &amp;amp; Rudolph, G. (2006). Evolutionary Composition of Music with Learned Melody Evaluation. In N.  Mastorakis &amp;amp; A.  Cecchi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Int. Conference on COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, MAN-MACHINE SYSTEMS and CYBERNETICS (CIMMACS '06)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 234-239). Venice, Italy.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2603476</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-06-14T11:24:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-15T12:47:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>