<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2603021</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 8, 1984, Sydney (N.S.W.)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wachsmuth_children_mathematical_knowledge.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2603021/2603023/wachsmuth_children_mathematical_knowledge.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1984</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Sydney (Australia)</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26030212</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">251-257</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, International Group For The Psychology Of Mathematics Education, Sydney, &lt;strong&gt;1984&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 251-257.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (1984) &lt;br /&gt;An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.  Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education:  251-257.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1984). An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 251-257). Gehalten auf der International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 8, 1984, Sydney (N.S.W.), Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1984. “An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, 251-257. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. p. 251-257. International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, Sydney (1984).</lncs>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education;  1984: 251-257.</ama>
<default>Wachsmuth I (1984)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education:  251-257.</default>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 1984. 251-257.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1984). An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, 251-257. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (1984). “An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education), 251-257.</frontiers>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (1984): An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. In: Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.  S. 251-257.</wels>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (1984). An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, 251-257. Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education.</apa>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 1984. An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;.  Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, pp. 251-257.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “An analysis into structures and mechanisms of 5th grade children's mathematical knowledge”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;,  Sydney: International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education, 1984,  pp.251-257.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2603021</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-06-12T08:20:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-15T12:44:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>