<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2605193</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix Gregor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eikmeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19753357</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1623-172X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Antje</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rademacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Angelika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanreich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Magdalena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hennig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jaenicke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5774668</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Irena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32999125</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wibberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19653681</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakrzewski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">12631096</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21937</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4723-2960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klocke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlüter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55545</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4830-310X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

In recent years biogas plants in Germany have been supposed to be involved in amplification and dissemination of pathogenic bacteria causing severe infections in humans and animals. In particular, biogas plants are discussed to contribute to the spreading of Escherichia coli infections in humans or chronic botulism in cattle caused by Clostridium botulinum. Metagenome datasets of microbial communities from an agricultural biogas plant as well as from anaerobic lab-scale digesters operating at different temperatures and conditions were analyzed for the presence of putative pathogenic bacteria and virulence determinants by various bioinformatic approaches.

Results

All datasets featured a low abundance of reads that were taxonomically assigned to the genus Escherichia or further selected genera comprising pathogenic species. Higher numbers of reads were taxonomically assigned to the genus Clostridium. However, only very few sequences were predicted to originate from pathogenic clostridial species. Moreover, mapping of metagenome reads to complete genome sequences of selected pathogenic bacteria revealed that not the pathogenic species itself, but only species that are more or less related to pathogenic ones are present in the fermentation samples analyzed. Likewise, known virulence determinants could hardly be detected. Only a marginal number of reads showed similarity to sequences described in the Microbial Virulence Database MvirDB such as those encoding protein toxins, virulence proteins or antibiotic resistance determinants.

Conclusions

Findings of this first study of metagenomic sequence reads of biogas producing microbial communities suggest that the risk of dissemination of pathogenic bacteria by application of digestates from biogas fermentations as fertilizers is low, because obtained results do not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms in the samples analyzed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1754-6834-6-49.schluter.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2605193/2610683/1754-6834-6-49.schluter.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biotechnology for Biofuels</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1754-6834</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23557021</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000318409700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26051930</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1754-6834-6-49</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> F.G. Eikmeyer, et al., “Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 2013, : 49.</ieee>
<harvard1>Eikmeyer, F.G., et al., 2013. Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, 6(1): 49.</harvard1>
<ama>Eikmeyer FG, Rademacher A, Hanreich A, et al. Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;6(1): 49.</ama>
<apa>Eikmeyer, F. G., Rademacher, A., Hanreich, A., Hennig, M., Jaenicke, S., Maus, I., Wibberg, D., et al. (2013). Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 49. doi:10.1186/1754-6834-6-49</apa>
<lncs> Eikmeyer, F.G., Rademacher, A., Hanreich, A., Hennig, M., Jaenicke, S., Maus, I., Wibberg, D., Zakrzewski, M., Pühler, A., Klocke, M., Schlüter, A.: Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. Biotechnology for Biofuels. 6, : 49 (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Rademacher, Antje, Hanreich, Angelika, Hennig, Magdalena, Jaenicke, Sebastian, Maus, Irena, Wibberg, Daniel, et al. 2013. “Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 6 (1): 49.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Eikmeyer, F. G.; Rademacher, A.; Hanreich, A.; Hennig, M.; Jaenicke, S.; Maus, I.; Wibberg, D.; Zakrzewski, M.; Pühler, A.; Klocke, M.; Schlüter, A. (2013): Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,6:(1):49</wels>
<mla>Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Rademacher, Antje, Hanreich, Angelika, Hennig, Magdalena, Jaenicke, Sebastian, Maus, Irena, Wibberg, Daniel, Zakrzewski, Martha, Pühler, Alfred, Klocke, Michael, and Schlüter, Andreas. “Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 6.1 (2013): 49.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eikmeyer, F. G., Rademacher, A., Hanreich, A., Hennig, M., Jaenicke, S., Maus, I., Wibberg, D., et al. (2013). Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 49. doi:10.1186/1754-6834-6-49&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Eikmeyer, F. G., Rademacher, A., Hanreich, A., Hennig, M., Jaenicke, S., Maus, I., Wibberg, D., Zakrzewski, M., Pühler, A., Klocke, M., et al. (2013). Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 6:49.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eikmeyer, F.G., Rademacher, A., Hanreich, A., Hennig, M., Jaenicke, S., Maus, I., Wibberg, D., Zakrzewski, M., Pühler, A., Klocke, M. &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2013). Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1): 49. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1754-6834-6-49.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Eikmeyer FG, Rademacher A, Hanreich A, Hennig M, Jaenicke S, Maus I, Wibberg D, Zakrzewski M, Pühler A, Klocke M, Schlüter A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 6(1): 49.</default>
<bio1>Eikmeyer FG, Rademacher A, Hanreich A, Hennig M, Jaenicke S, Maus I, Wibberg D, Zakrzewski M, Pühler A, Klocke M, Schlüter A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms.&lt;br /&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels 6(1): 49.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. G.  Eikmeyer, A.  Rademacher, A.  Hanreich, M.  Hennig, S.  Jaenicke, I.  Maus, D.  Wibberg, M.  Zakrzewski, A.  Pühler, M.  Klocke, et al., “Detailed analysis of metagenome datasets obtained from biogas-producing microbial communities residing in biogas reactors does not indicate the presence of putative pathogenic microorganisms”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, : 49.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2605193</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-06-24T13:12:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>