<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2606425</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Muhle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7238469</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5141-5498</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Arno</namePart><namePart type="family">Bammé</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Günter</namePart><namePart type="family">Getzinger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Berger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656064</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Yearbook 2013 Muhle(1).pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2606425/2903093/Yearbook 2013 Muhle(1).pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Profil Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26064253</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">193-210</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Muhle, F.: Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In: Bammé, A., Getzinger, G., and Berger, T. (eds.) Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society. p. 193-210. Profil Verlag, München, Wien (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Muhle, Florian. 2015. “Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research”. In &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Arno Bammé, Günter Getzinger, and Thomas Berger, 193-210. München, Wien: Profil Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Muhle, Florian. “Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research”. &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Arno Bammé, Günter Getzinger, and Thomas Berger. München, Wien: Profil Verlag, 2015. 193-210.</mla>
<default>Muhle F (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society. Bammé A, Getzinger G, Berger T (Eds);  München, Wien: Profil Verlag:  193-210.</default>
<ama>Muhle F. Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In: Bammé A, Getzinger G, Berger T, eds. &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;. München, Wien: Profil Verlag;  2015: 193-210.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Muhle, F. (2015). Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In A. Bammé, G. Getzinger &amp;amp; T. Berger (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt; (S. 193-210). München, Wien: Profil Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Muhle, F. (2015). “Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research” in &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;, Bammé, A., Getzinger, G., and Berger, T. eds. (München, Wien: Profil Verlag), 193-210.</frontiers>
<apa>Muhle, F. (2015). Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In A.  Bammé, G.  Getzinger, &amp;amp; T.  Berger (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-210). München, Wien: Profil Verlag.</apa>
<ieee> F. Muhle, “Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research”, &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;, A. Bammé, G. Getzinger, and T. Berger, eds.,  München, Wien: Profil Verlag, 2015,  pp.193-210.</ieee>
<wels>Muhle, F. (2015): Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In: Arno Bammé; Günter Getzinger; Thomas Berger (Hrsg.):  Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society. München, Wien: Profil Verlag.  S. 193-210.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Muhle, F. (2015). Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In A.  Bammé, G.  Getzinger, &amp;amp; T.  Berger (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-210). München, Wien: Profil Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Muhle F (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society. Bammé A, Getzinger G, Berger T (Eds); München, Wien: Profil Verlag:  193-210.</bio1>
<harvard1>Muhle, F., 2015. Encounters at the borders of the social world. Theoretical and methodological considerations on a new type of sociological research. In A.  Bammé, G.  Getzinger, &amp;amp; T.  Berger, eds. &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;.  München, Wien: Profil Verlag, pp. 193-210.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Muhle, in &lt;em&gt;Yearbook 2013 of the Institute for Advanced Studies on Science, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Bammé, G. Getzinger, T. Berger), Profil Verlag, München, Wien, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 193-210.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2606425</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-06-26T07:42:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>