<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2608835</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart><namePart type="family">Mandl</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alan</namePart><namePart type="family">Lesgold</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This chapter describes an approach to modeling the domain-specific knowledge of mathematics learners in a predicate-logic formalism suited for computer implementation. Two hypotheses are central to this approach. First, a person's cognitive behavior is a knowledge-based process that evolves from relatively simple component processes of an inferential nature. The complexity of a person's observed behavior in a domain depends on the knowledge base: how many facts and rules he or she has and how these facts and rules are organized. Second, a person's behavior in a task situation is generally not supported by the total body of his or her long-term knowledge. Rather, it is assumed that knowledge must be activated to be used in a given situation and that the accessibility of particular knowledge depends on contextual cues in the situation. The degree to which particular knowledge is contextually bound with respect to a set of specific situations is called situation specificity.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Modeling_KB_ML.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2608835/2644489/Modeling_KB_ML.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1988</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-387-96616-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26088351</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">63-79</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (1988). “Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge” in &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Mandl, H., and Lesgold, A. eds. (New York: Springer), 63-79.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1988). Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In H. Mandl &amp;amp; A. Lesgold (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 63-79). New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In: Mandl H, Lesgold A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Springer;  1988: 63-79.</ama>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge”, &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;, H. Mandl and A. Lesgold, eds.,  New York: Springer, 1988,  pp.63-79.</ieee>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (1988). Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In H.  Mandl &amp;amp; A.  Lesgold (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-79). New York: Springer.</apa>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (1988): Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In: Heinz Mandl; Alan Lesgold (Hrsg.):  Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems. New York: Springer.  S. 63-79.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Mandl, A. Lesgold), Springer, New York, &lt;strong&gt;1988&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 63-79.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (1988) &lt;br /&gt;Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems. Mandl H, Lesgold A (Eds); New York: Springer:  63-79.</bio1>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 1988. Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In H.  Mandl &amp;amp; A.  Lesgold, eds. &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: Springer, pp. 63-79.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1988). Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In H.  Mandl &amp;amp; A.  Lesgold (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-79). New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1988. “Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge”. In &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Heinz Mandl and Alan Lesgold, 63-79. New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge. In: Mandl, H. and Lesgold, A. (eds.) Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems. p. 63-79. Springer, New York (1988).</lncs>
<default>Wachsmuth I (1988)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems. Mandl H, Lesgold A (Eds);  New York: Springer:  63-79.</default>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Modeling the knowledge base of mathematics learners: Situation-specific and situation-nonspecific knowledge”. &lt;em&gt;Learning Issues for Intelligent Tutoring Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Heinz Mandl and Alan Lesgold. New York: Springer, 1988. 63-79.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2608835</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-09T10:27:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>