<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2608469</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The concept of intelligence in AI</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Holk</namePart><namePart type="family">Cruse</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jeffrey</namePart><namePart type="family">Dean</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Helge</namePart><namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wachsmuth_zifpaper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2608469/2621101/wachsmuth_zifpaper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-7923-6670-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26084697</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">43-55</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Wachsmuth I (2000)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic. Cruse H, Dean J, Ritter H (Eds);  Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers:  43-55.</default>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “The concept of intelligence in AI”. &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Holk Cruse, Jeffrey Dean, and Helge Ritter. Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers, 2000. 43-55.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2000. “The concept of intelligence in AI”. In &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Holk Cruse, Jeffrey Dean, and Helge Ritter, 43-55. Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: The concept of intelligence in AI. In: Cruse, H., Dean, J., and Ritter, H. (eds.) Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic. p. 43-55. Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands (2000).</lncs>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “The concept of intelligence in AI”, &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;, H. Cruse, J. Dean, and H. Ritter, eds.,  Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers, 2000,  pp.43-55.</ieee>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (2000). The concept of intelligence in AI. In H.  Cruse, J.  Dean, &amp;amp; H.  Ritter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 43-55). Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2000). The concept of intelligence in AI. In H. Cruse, J. Dean &amp;amp; H. Ritter (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt; (S. 43-55). Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (2000). “The concept of intelligence in AI” in &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;, Cruse, H., Dean, J., and Ritter, H. eds. (Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers), 43-55.</frontiers>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. The concept of intelligence in AI. In: Cruse H, Dean J, Ritter H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;. Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers;  2000: 43-55.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Cruse, J. Dean, H. Ritter), Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands, &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 43-55.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 2000. The concept of intelligence in AI. In H.  Cruse, J.  Dean, &amp;amp; H.  Ritter, eds. &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt;.  Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers, pp. 43-55.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (2000) &lt;br /&gt;The concept of intelligence in AI. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic. Cruse H, Dean J, Ritter H (Eds); Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers:  43-55.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2000). The concept of intelligence in AI. In H.  Cruse, J.  Dean, &amp;amp; H.  Ritter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 43-55). Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (2000): The concept of intelligence in AI. In: Holk Cruse; Jeffrey Dean; Helge Ritter (Hrsg.):  Prerational Intelligence: Adaptive Behavior and Intelligent Systems without Symbols and Logic. Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.  S. 43-55.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2608469</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-08T11:41:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>