<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2609938</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart><namePart type="family">Reichardt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Levi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">John-Jules C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Meyer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conj. with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The integration of emotion and cognition in cognitive architectures for embodied agents is a problem of increasing importance. In this paper, we describe how two separate modules for these tasks, as we employ them in our virtual human Max, can give rise to secondary emotions such as frustration and relief. The BDI-based cognitive module is responsible for appraisal as well as reappraisal of elicited emotions that our conversational agent Max becomes aware of. The emotion dynamics simulation system is driven by the valence information of every emotion and assures a general consistency of the simulated emotions over time by dynamically providing an awareness likelihood for every emotion.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="becker_wachsmuth_ki2006.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2609938/2634868/becker_wachsmuth_ki2006.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bremen, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-88722-664-X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26099382</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">31-34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Becker C, Wachsmuth I (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC (Eds); 31-34.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Becker, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Reichardt, P. Levi, J.-J.C. Meyer), &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 31-34.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Becker C, Wachsmuth I (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC (Eds);   31-34.</default>
<mla>Becker, Christian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dirk Reichardt, Paul Levi, and John-Jules C. Meyer. 2006. 31-34.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-34).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Becker, C., and Wachsmuth, I. (2006). “Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, Reichardt, D., Levi, P., and Meyer, J. - J. C. eds. 31-34.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In D. Reichardt, P. Levi &amp;amp; J.-J.C. Meyer (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (S. 31-34). Gehalten auf der First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conj. with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Becker, C.; Wachsmuth, I. (2006): Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In: Dirk Reichardt; Paul Levi; John-Jules C. Meyer (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen.  S. 31-34.</wels>
<lncs> Becker, C., Wachsmuth, I.: Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In: Reichardt, D., Levi, P., and Meyer, J.-J.C. (eds.) Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. p. 31-34. (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, Christian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2006. “Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dirk Reichardt, Paul Levi, and John-Jules C. Meyer, 31-34.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-34).</apa>
<ama>Becker C, Wachsmuth I. Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In: Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. 2006: 31-34.</ama>
<ieee> C. Becker and I. Wachsmuth, “Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, D. Reichardt, P. Levi, and J.-J.C. Meyer, eds., 2006,  pp.31-34.</ieee>
<harvard1>Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2006. Modeling primary and secondary emotions for a believable communication agent. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 31-34.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2609938</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-11T14:12:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>