<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610779</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Studying situated communication with an embodied agent</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="pb594-wachsmuth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610779/2621275/pb594-wachsmuth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26107791</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">44</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (2005): Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. In: Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Stresa, Italy.  S. 44.</wels>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Studying situated communication with an embodied agent”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Stresa, Italy, 2005. 44.</mla>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (2005). “Studying situated communication with an embodied agent” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (Stresa, Italy), 44.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, 44. Stresa, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Wachsmuth I (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Stresa, Italy:  44.</default>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 2005. Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;.  Stresa, Italy, pp. 44.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “Studying situated communication with an embodied agent”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;,  Stresa, Italy: 2005,  pp.44.</ieee>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, 44. Stresa, Italy.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (S. 44). Stresa, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, Stresa, Italy, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 44.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society.  Stresa, Italy:  44.</bio1>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Stresa, Italy;  2005: 44.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2005. “Studying situated communication with an embodied agent”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, 44. Stresa, Italy.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: Studying situated communication with an embodied agent. Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. p. 44. Stresa, Italy (2005).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610779</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-19T09:32:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>