<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610763</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc Erich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Latoschik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8937325</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Biermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart><namePart type="family">Butz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Brian</namePart><namePart type="family">Fisher</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Antonio</namePart><namePart type="family">Krüger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart><namePart type="family">Olivier</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>5th International Symposium on Smart Graphics</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This article describes the integration of knowledge based techniques into simulative Virtual Reality (VR) applications. The approach is motivated using multimodal Virtual Construction as an example domain. An abstract Knowledge Representation Layer (KRL) is proposed which is expressive enough to define all necessary data for diverse simulation tasks and which additionally provides a base formalism for the integration of Artificial Intelligence (AI) representations. The KRL supports two different implementation methods. The first method uses XSLT processing to transform the external KRL format into the representation formats of the diverse target systems. The second method implements the KRL using a functionally extendable semantic network. The semantic net library is tailored for real time simulation systems where it interconnects the required simulation modules and establishes access to the knowledge representations inside the simulation loop. The KRL promotes a novel object model for simulated objects called Semantic Entities which provides a uniform access to the KRL and which allows extensive system modularization. The KRL approach is demonstrated in two simulation areas. First, a generalized scene graph representation is presented which introduces an abstract definition and implementation of geometric node interrelations. It supports scene and application structures which can not be expressed using common scene hierarchies or field route concepts. Second, the KRL’s expressiveness is demonstrated in the design of multimodal interactions. Here, the KRL defines the knowledge particularly required during the semantic analysis of multimodal user utterances.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kitl.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610763/2674895/kitl.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Frauenwörth Cloister, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Smart Graphics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-28179-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26107631</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/11536482_3</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">25-39</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Latoschik, M. E., Biermann, P., and Wachsmuth, I. (2005). “Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments” in &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;, Butz, A., Fisher, B., Krüger, A., and Olivier, P. eds. LNCS 3638 (Berlin: Springer), 25-39.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, M.E., Biermann, P. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments (LNCS 3638). In A. Butz, B. Fisher, A. Krüger &amp;amp; P. Olivier (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 25-39). Gehalten auf der 5th International Symposium on Smart Graphics, Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/11536482_3.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Latoschik ME, Biermann P, Wachsmuth I. Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In: Butz A, Fisher B, Krüger A, Olivier P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;. LNCS 3638. Berlin: Springer;  2005: 25-39.</ama>
<ieee> M.E. Latoschik, P. Biermann, and I. Wachsmuth, “Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments”, &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;, A. Butz, et al., eds., LNCS 3638,  Berlin: Springer, 2005,  pp.25-39.</ieee>
<apa>Latoschik, M. E., Biermann, P., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In A.  Butz, B.  Fisher, A.  Krüger, &amp;amp; P.  Olivier (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNCS 3638&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 25-39). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/11536482_3</apa>
<wels>Latoschik, M. E.; Biermann, P.; Wachsmuth, I. (2005): Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In: Andreas Butz; Brian Fisher; Antonio Krüger; Patrick Olivier (Hrsg.):  Smart Graphics. Berlin: Springer. (LNCS 3638, ).  S. 25-39.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M. E.  Latoschik, P.  Biermann, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Butz, B. Fisher, A. Krüger, P. Olivier), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 25-39.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Latoschik ME, Biermann P, Wachsmuth I (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Smart Graphics. Butz A, Fisher B, Krüger A, Olivier P (Eds); LNCS 3638,  Berlin: Springer:  25-39.</bio1>
<harvard1>Latoschik, M.E., Biermann, P., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2005. Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In A.  Butz, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;. LNCS 3638.  Berlin: Springer, pp. 25-39.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, M. E., Biermann, P., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2005). Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In A.  Butz, B.  Fisher, A.  Krüger, &amp;amp; P.  Olivier (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNCS 3638&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 25-39). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/11536482_3&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, Marc Erich, Biermann, Peter, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2005. “Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments”. In &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Andreas Butz, Brian Fisher, Antonio Krüger, and Patrick Olivier, 25-39. LNCS 3638. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Latoschik, M.E., Biermann, P., Wachsmuth, I.: Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments. In: Butz, A., Fisher, B., Krüger, A., and Olivier, P. (eds.) Smart Graphics. LNCS 3638. p. 25-39. Springer, Berlin (2005).</lncs>
<default>Latoschik ME, Biermann P, Wachsmuth I (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Smart Graphics. Butz A, Fisher B, Krüger A, Olivier P (Eds);  LNCS 3638.  Berlin: Springer:  25-39.</default>
<mla>Latoschik, Marc Erich, Biermann, Peter, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Knowledge in the loop: Semantics representation for multimodal simulative environments”. &lt;em&gt;Smart Graphics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Andreas Butz, Brian Fisher, Antonio Krüger, and Patrick Olivier. Berlin: Springer, 2005. LNCS 3638. 25-39.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610763</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-19T08:57:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>