<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610732</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manuela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Macedonia</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Aylett</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">B.</namePart><namePart type="family">Krenn</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pelachaud</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Shimodaira</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>13th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">An important and often laborious task in foreign language acquisi- tion is vocabulary learning. Research has repeatedly demonstrated that perform- ing iconic gestures together with novel words has a beneficial effect on learn- ing performance. Can these findings be transferred onto virtual agents applied in gesture-supported vocabulary training? We present a study investigating whether iconic gestures performed by a virtual agent and imitated by learners have an impact on verbal memory for words in a foreign language. In a within-subject design we compared participants’ memory performance achieved with the help of a virtual agent and those achieved with the help of a human trainer regarding both short-term learning effects and long-term decay effects. The overall results demonstrate improved memory scores when participants learned with a virtual agent. Especially high performers could profit from gesture-supported training with a virtual agent.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="iva2013_vt_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610732/2628750/iva2013_vt_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Edinburgh, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Intelligent Virtual Agents</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-40414-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26107322</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">139-148</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bergmann K, Macedonia M (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence.  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  139-148.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Macedonia, M. (2013). A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In R.  Aylett, B.  Krenn, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; H.  Shimodaira (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 139-148). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, and Macedonia, Manuela. “A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance”. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, and H. Shimodaira. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2013. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 139-148.</mla>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., and Macedonia, M. (2013). “A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance” in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Aylett, R., Krenn, B., Pelachaud, C., and Shimodaira, H. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer), 139-148.</frontiers>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Macedonia, M. (2013): A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In: R. Aylett; B. Krenn; C. Pelachaud; H. Shimodaira (Hrsg.):  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, ).  S. 139-148.</wels>
<apa>Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Macedonia, M. (2013). A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In R.  Aylett, B.  Krenn, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; H.  Shimodaira (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 139-148). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.</apa>
<ieee> K. Bergmann and M. Macedonia, “A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance”, &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, R. Aylett, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence,  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2013,  pp.139-148.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., &amp;amp; Macedonia, M., 2013. A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In R.  Aylett, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence.  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 139-148.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Macedonia M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence,  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  139-148.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, and M.  Macedonia, in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, H. Shimodaira), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 139-148.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K. &amp;amp; Macedonia, M. (2013). A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud &amp;amp; H. Shimodaira (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (S. 139-148). Gehalten auf der 13th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents, Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Macedonia, M.: A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In: Aylett, R., Krenn, B., Pelachaud, C., and Shimodaira, H. (eds.) Intelligent Virtual Agents. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. p. 139-148. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, and Macedonia, Manuela. 2013. “A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance”. In &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, ed. R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, and H. Shimodaira, 139-148. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Bergmann K, Macedonia M. A Virtual Agent as Vocabulary Trainer: Iconic Gestures Help to Improve Learners’ Memory Performance. In: Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer;  2013: 139-148.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610732</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-18T13:43:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>