<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610083</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart><namePart type="family">Reichardt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Levi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">John-Jules C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Meyer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conj. with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="becker_wachsmuth_demo.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610083/2634988/becker_wachsmuth_demo.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bremen, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1865-6374</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26100830</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">65</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Becker C, Wachsmuth I. Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In: Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. 2006: 65.</ama>
<lncs> Becker, C., Wachsmuth, I.: Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In: Reichardt, D., Levi, P., and Meyer, J.-J.C. (eds.) Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. p. 65. (2006).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, Christian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2006. “Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Dirk Reichardt, Paul Levi, and John-Jules C. Meyer, 65.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In D. Reichardt, P. Levi &amp;amp; J.-J.C. Meyer (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (S. 65). Gehalten auf der First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conj. with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Becker, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Reichardt, P. Levi, J.-J.C. Meyer), &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 65.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Becker C, Wachsmuth I (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC (Eds); 65.</bio1>
<harvard1>Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2006. Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 65.</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Becker and I. Wachsmuth, “Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, D. Reichardt, P. Levi, and J.-J.C. Meyer, eds., 2006,  pp.65.</ieee>
<apa>Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (p. 65).</apa>
<wels>Becker, C.; Wachsmuth, I. (2006): Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In: Dirk Reichardt; Paul Levi; John-Jules C. Meyer (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen.  S. 65.</wels>
<frontiers>Becker, C., and Wachsmuth, I. (2006). “Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;, Reichardt, D., Levi, P., and Meyer, J. - J. C. eds. 65.</frontiers>
<mla>Becker, Christian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Dirk Reichardt, Paul Levi, and John-Jules C. Meyer. 2006. 65.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Becker, C., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2006). Playing the cards game SkipBo against an emotional Max. In D.  Reichardt, P.  Levi, &amp;amp; J. - J. C.  Meyer (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen&lt;/em&gt; (p. 65).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Becker C, Wachsmuth I (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Emotion and Computing in conjunction with the 29th Annual German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI2006), Bremen. Reichardt D, Levi P, Meyer J-JC (Eds);   65.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610083</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-12T10:11:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>