<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610719</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kirsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182997</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kahl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">30411756</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8468-2808</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Aylett</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">B.</namePart><namePart type="family">Krenn</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">C.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pelachaud</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Shimodaira</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015129</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>13th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper addresses the semantic coordination of speech and gesture, a major prerequisite when endowing virtual agents with convincing multimodal behavior. Previous research has focused on build- ing rule- or data-based models speci c for a particular language, culture or individual speaker, but without considering the underlying cognitive processes. We present a exible cognitive model in which both linguistic as well as cognitive constraints are considered in order to simulate natu- ral semantic coordination across speech and gesture. An implementation of this model is presented and rst simulation results, compatible with empirical data from the literature are reported.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="iva2013_b1_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610719/2628716/iva2013_b1_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Edinburgh, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Intelligent Virtual Agents</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-40414-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26107199</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">203-216</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://youtu.be/uQL0nnRu6c8</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Bergmann, K.; Kahl, S.; Kopp, S. (2013): Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In: R. Aylett; B. Krenn; C. Pelachaud; H. Shimodaira (Hrsg.):  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, ).  S. 203-216.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bergmann, S.  Kahl, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, H. Shimodaira), Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 203-216.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bergmann K, Kahl S, Kopp S (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence,  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  203-216.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2013). Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In R.  Aylett, B.  Krenn, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; H.  Shimodaira (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 203-216). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bergmann, K., Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2013. Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In R.  Aylett, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence.  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 203-216.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Bergmann, K., Kahl, S., and Kopp, S. (2013). “Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints” in &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Aylett, R., Krenn, B., Pelachaud, C., and Shimodaira, H. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer), 203-216.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, K., Kahl, S. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2013). Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud &amp;amp; H. Shimodaira (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (S. 203-216). Gehalten auf der 13th International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents, Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bergmann K, Kahl S, Kopp S. Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In: Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H, eds. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer;  2013: 203-216.</ama>
<ieee> K. Bergmann, S. Kahl, and S. Kopp, “Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints”, &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, R. Aylett, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence,  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2013,  pp.203-216.</ieee>
<apa>Bergmann, K., Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2013). Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In R.  Aylett, B.  Krenn, C.  Pelachaud, &amp;amp; H.  Shimodaira (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 203-216). Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Kirsten, Kahl, Sebastian, and Kopp, Stefan. 2013. “Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints”. In &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;, ed. R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, and H. Shimodaira, 203-216. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bergmann, K., Kahl, S., Kopp, S.: Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints. In: Aylett, R., Krenn, B., Pelachaud, C., and Shimodaira, H. (eds.) Intelligent Virtual Agents. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. p. 203-216. Springer, Berlin/Heidelberg (2013).</lncs>
<default>Bergmann K, Kahl S, Kopp S (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Intelligent Virtual Agents. Aylett R, Krenn B, Pelachaud C, Shimodaira H (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence.  Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer:  203-216.</default>
<mla>Bergmann, Kirsten, Kahl, Sebastian, and Kopp, Stefan. “Modeling the semantic coordination of speech and gesture under cognitive and linguistic constraints”. &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Virtual Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. R. Aylett, B. Krenn, C. Pelachaud, and H. Shimodaira. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer, 2013. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 203-216.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610719</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-18T13:34:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>