<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2610958</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21923</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schilling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">172354</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0849-483X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685507</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">An artificial neural network called reaCog is described which is based on a decentralized, reactive and embodied architecture developed to control non-trivial hexapod walking in an unpredictable environment (Walknet) while using insect-like navigation (Navinet). In reaCog, these basic networks are extended in such a way that the complete system, reaCog, adopts the capability of inventing new behaviors and – via internal simulation – of planning ahead. This cognitive expansion enables the reactive system to be enriched with additional procedures. Here, we focus on the question to what extent properties of phenomena to be characterized on a different level of description as for example consciousness can be found in this minimally cognitive system. Adopting a monist view, we argue that the phenomenal aspect of mental phenomena can be neglected when discussing the function of such a system. Under this condition, reaCog is discussed to be equipped with properties as are bottom-up and top-down attention, intentions, volition, and some aspects of Access Consciousness. These properties have not been explicitly implemented but emerge from the cooperation between the elements of the network. The aspects of Access Consciousness found in reaCog concern the above mentioned ability to plan ahead and to invent and guide (new) actions. Furthermore, global accessibility of memory elements, another aspect characterizing Access Consciousness is realized by this network. reaCog allows for both reactive/automatic control and (access-) conscious control of behavior. We discuss examples for interactions between both the reactive domain and the conscious domain. Metacognition or Reflexive Consciousness is not a property of reaCog. Possible expansions are discussed to allow for further properties of Access Consciousness, verbal report on internal states, and for Metacognition. In summary, we argue that already simple networks allow for properties of consciousness if leaving the phenomenal aspect aside.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpsyg-04-00324.schilling.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2610958/2610964/fpsyg-04-00324.schilling.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23785343</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000331044100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26109586</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00324</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">324</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Cruse, H., &amp;amp; Schilling, M., 2013. How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 4, p 324.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Cruse and M. Schilling, “How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 4, 2013,  pp. 324.</ieee>
<apa>Cruse, H., &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2013). How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 324. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00324</apa>
<wels>Cruse, H.; Schilling, M. (2013): How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,4: 324.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cruse, H., &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2013). How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 324. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00324&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Cruse, Holk, and Schilling, Malte. “How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 4 (2013): 324.</mla>
<frontiers>Cruse, H., and Schilling, M. (2013). How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 4, 324.</frontiers>
<default>Cruse H, Schilling M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 4: 324.</default>
<ama>Cruse H, Schilling M. How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;4:324.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cruse, Holk, and Schilling, Malte. 2013. “How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 4: 324.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cruse, H., Schilling, M.: How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. Frontiers in Psychology. 4, 324 (2013).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cruse, H. &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2013). How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 324. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00324.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Cruse, and M.  Schilling, “How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 324.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cruse H, Schilling M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;How and to what end may consciousness contribute to action? Attributing properties of consciousness to an embodied, minimally cognitive artificial neural network.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Psychology 4: 324.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2610958</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-22T13:26:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>