<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611765</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>(Full Paper: KI-NRW Report 95-01)</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lenzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yong</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Leonie</namePart><namePart type="family">Dreschler-Fischer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Simone</namePart><namePart type="family">Pribbenow</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>19. Deutsche Jahrestagung für Künstliche Intelligenz</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes an application of a multiagent system for interaction with a virtual environment carried out in the VIENA project. The VIENA project has the following goals: enable an intelligent communication with a virtual environment, develop a multiagent system as a mediator in humancomputer interaction, and explore its usefulness for interactive design and exploration. Instead of using the mouse and menus to manipulate scene details in a virtual environment we communicate with the system by way of natural language. Our aim is to keep the user (designer) free from technical considerations such as planning of geometric details, etc. Taking special responsibilities in mediating verbal instructions, the VIENA agents cooperate with each other and with the user to offer a goal scene meeting the user's wants. We explain the VIENA multiagent system, give an example application in virtual design, and discuss the specific advantages we found in using agent techniques for building an intelligent interface.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="viena_ki95.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611765/2647782/viena_ki95.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26117655</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">335-337</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In L.  Dreschler-Fischer &amp;amp; S.  Pribbenow (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 335-337). Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I., and Cao, Y. (1995). “VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment” in &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;, Dreschler-Fischer, L., and Pribbenow, S. eds. (Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.), 335-337.</frontiers>
<mla>Lenzmann, Britta, Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Cao, Yong. “VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment”. &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Leonie Dreschler-Fischer and Simone Pribbenow. Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V., 1995. 335-337.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I. &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In L. Dreschler-Fischer &amp;amp; S. Pribbenow (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt; (S. 335-337). Gehalten auf der 19. Deutsche Jahrestagung für Künstliche Intelligenz, Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Lenzmann, B.; Wachsmuth, I.; Cao, Y. (1995): VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In: Leonie Dreschler-Fischer; Simone Pribbenow (Hrsg.):  KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos. Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.  S. 335-337.</wels>
<bio1>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I, Cao Y (1995) &lt;br /&gt;VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos. Dreschler-Fischer L, Pribbenow S (Eds); Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.:  335-337.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Lenzmann, I.  Wachsmuth, and Y.  Cao, in &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: L. Dreschler-Fischer, S. Pribbenow), Gesellschaft Für Informatik E.v., Bonn, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 335-337.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I, Cao Y (1995)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos. Dreschler-Fischer L, Pribbenow S (Eds);  Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.:  335-337.</default>
<ama>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I, Cao Y. VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In: Dreschler-Fischer L, Pribbenow S, eds. &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;. Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.;  1995: 335-337.</ama>
<ieee> B. Lenzmann, I. Wachsmuth, and Y. Cao, “VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment”, &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;, L. Dreschler-Fischer and S. Pribbenow, eds.,  Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V., 1995,  pp.335-337.</ieee>
<harvard1>Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Cao, Y., 1995. VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In L.  Dreschler-Fischer &amp;amp; S.  Pribbenow, eds. &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;.  Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V., pp. 335-337.</harvard1>
<lncs> Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I., Cao, Y.: VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In: Dreschler-Fischer, L. and Pribbenow, S. (eds.) KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos. p. 335-337. Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V., Bonn (1995).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, Britta, Wachsmuth, Ipke, and Cao, Yong. 1995. “VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment”. In &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Leonie Dreschler-Fischer and Simone Pribbenow, 335-337. Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I., &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: An intelligent interface for a virtual environment. In L.  Dreschler-Fischer &amp;amp; S.  Pribbenow (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KI-95 Activities: Workshops, Posters, Demos&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 335-337). Bonn: Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611765</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-29T07:46:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>