<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611480</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes the knowledge processing in the CODY Virtual Constructor, an operational system enabling the interactive assembly of complex aggregates in a virtual environment. Two forms of reasoners are used: a geometric reasoner that infers spatial properties of scene objects and a conceptual reasoner that keeps track of the evolving aggregate’s assembly structure. The combination of the two reasoners enables the system both to simulate assembly processes in the virtual environment and to understand natural language instructions. By maximizing the mutual exchange of information between the reasoners, additional knowledge can be inferred that not only improves understanding of language instructions but also increases efficiency of inferencing.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="AAAI98.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611480/2643937/AAAI98.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-57735-049-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26114807</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">22-27</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jung, B. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments (Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt; (S. 22-27).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Jung B, Wachsmuth I (1998) &lt;br /&gt;Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning.  Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04),  22-27.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Jung, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 22-27.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Jung B, Wachsmuth I. Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04). 1998: 22-27.</ama>
<lncs> Jung, B., Wachsmuth, I.: Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04). p. 22-27. (1998).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jung, Bernhard, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1998. “Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, 22-27. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Jung, B.; Wachsmuth, I. (1998): Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. In: Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning. (Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04), ).  S. 22-27.</wels>
<frontiers>Jung, B., and Wachsmuth, I. (1998). “Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt; Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04) 22-27.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04), 22-27.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Jung, Bernhard, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;. 1998. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04). 22-27.</mla>
<default>Jung B, Wachsmuth I (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04).   22-27.</default>
<ieee> B. Jung and I. Wachsmuth, “Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04), 1998,  pp.22-27.</ieee>
<harvard1>Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1998. Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;. Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04). pp. 22-27.</harvard1>
<apa>Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Integration of geometric and conceptual reasoning for interacting with virtual environments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings AAAI'98 Spring-Symposium on Multimodal Reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, Papers from the AAAI Spring Symposium (Technical Report SS-98-04), 22-27.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611480</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-25T13:48:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>