<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611493</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc Erich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Latoschik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8937325</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart><namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Martin</namePart><namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Gesture Workshop GW'97</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Developing state of the art multimedia applications nowadays calls for the use of sophisticated visualisation and immersion techniques, commonly referenced as Virtual Reality. While Virtual Reality meanwhile reaches good results both in image quality and in fast user feedback using parallel computation techniques, the methods for interacting with these systems need to be improved. In this paper we introduce a multimedia application that uses a gesture-driven interface and, secondly, the architecture for an expandable gesture recognition system. After different gesture types for interaction in a virtual environment are discussed with respect to a required functionality, the implementation of a specific gesture detection module for distant pointing recognition is described, and the whole system design is tested for its task adequacy.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="exploiting_distant_pointing_gestures.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611493/2674836/exploiting_distant_pointing_gestures.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-64424-5</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26114930</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BFb0052999</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">185-196</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Latoschik, M.E., Wachsmuth, I.: Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In: Wachsmuth, I. and Fröhlich, M. (eds.) Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction. LNAI 1371. p. 185-196. Springer, Berlin (1998).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, Marc Erich, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1998. “Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Martin Fröhlich, 185-196. LNAI 1371. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I. Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In: Wachsmuth I, Fröhlich M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI 1371. Berlin: Springer;  1998: 185-196.</ama>
<bio1>Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I (1998) &lt;br /&gt;Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction. Wachsmuth I, Fröhlich M (Eds); LNAI 1371,  Berlin: Springer:  185-196.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M. E.  Latoschik, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Wachsmuth, M. Fröhlich), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 185-196.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, M.E. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment (LNAI 1371). In I. Wachsmuth &amp;amp; M. Fröhlich (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 185-196). Gehalten auf der International Gesture Workshop GW'97, Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/BFb0052999.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Latoschik, M. E., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; M.  Fröhlich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI 1371&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 185-196). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/BFb0052999</apa>
<ieee> M.E. Latoschik and I. Wachsmuth, “Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, I. Wachsmuth and M. Fröhlich, eds., LNAI 1371,  Berlin: Springer, 1998,  pp.185-196.</ieee>
<harvard1>Latoschik, M.E., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1998. Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; M.  Fröhlich, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI 1371.  Berlin: Springer, pp. 185-196.</harvard1>
<default>Latoschik ME, Wachsmuth I (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction. Wachsmuth I, Fröhlich M (Eds);  LNAI 1371.  Berlin: Springer:  185-196.</default>
<mla>Latoschik, Marc Erich, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ipke Wachsmuth and Martin Fröhlich. Berlin: Springer, 1998. LNAI 1371. 185-196.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Latoschik, M. E., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1998). Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In I.  Wachsmuth &amp;amp; M.  Fröhlich (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI 1371&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 185-196). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/BFb0052999&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Latoschik, M. E., and Wachsmuth, I. (1998). “Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Wachsmuth, I., and Fröhlich, M. eds. LNAI 1371 (Berlin: Springer), 185-196.</frontiers>
<wels>Latoschik, M. E.; Wachsmuth, I. (1998): Exploiting distant pointing gestures for object selection in a virtual environment. In: Ipke Wachsmuth; Martin Fröhlich (Hrsg.):  Gesture and Sign Language in Human-Computer Interaction. Berlin: Springer. (LNAI 1371, ).  S. 185-196.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611493</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-25T14:10:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>