<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611840</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lenzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yong</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Victor</namePart><namePart type="family">Lesser</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ICMAS 1995</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="icmas95poster.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611840/2634737/icmas95poster.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>AAAI Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">San Francisco, CA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-262-62102-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26118403</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">465</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke, Lenzmann, Britta, and Cao, Yong. “VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster)”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Victor Lesser. Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press, 1995. 465.</mla>
<default>Wachsmuth I, Lenzmann B, Cao Y (1995)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems. Lesser V (Ed);  Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press:  465.</default>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B., Cao, Y.: VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In: Lesser, V. (ed.) Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems. p. 465. AAAI Press, Menlo Park, Cal. USA (1995).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke, Lenzmann, Britta, and Cao, Yong. 1995. “VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster)”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Victor Lesser, 465. Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Cao, Y., 1995. VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In V.  Lesser, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press, pp. 465.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In V.  Lesser (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (p. 465). Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I, Lenzmann B, Cao Y (1995) &lt;br /&gt;VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems. Lesser V (Ed); Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press:  465.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, B.  Lenzmann, and Y.  Cao, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: V. Lesser), Aaai Press, Menlo Park, Cal. USA, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 465.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I.; Lenzmann, B.; Cao, Y. (1995): VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In: Victor Lesser (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems. Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press.  S. 465.</wels>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In V.  Lesser (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (p. 465). Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press.</apa>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, B. Lenzmann, and Y. Cao, “VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster)”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, V. Lesser, ed.,  Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press, 1995,  pp.465.</ieee>
<ama>Wachsmuth I, Lenzmann B, Cao Y. VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In: Lesser V, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press;  1995: 465.</ama>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B., and Cao, Y. (1995). “VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster)” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Lesser, V. ed. (Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press), 465.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I., Lenzmann, B. &amp;amp; Cao, Y. (1995). VIENA: A multiagent interface to a virtual environment (Poster). In V. Lesser (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First International Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 465). Gehalten auf der ICMAS 1995, Menlo Park, Cal. USA: AAAI Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611840</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-29T09:58:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>