<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611333</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Annelies</namePart><namePart type="family">Braffort</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rachid</namePart><namePart type="family">Gherbi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sylvie</namePart><namePart type="family">Gibet</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">James</namePart><namePart type="family">Richardson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart><namePart type="family">Teil</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Gesture Workshop (GW '99)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Led by the fundamental role that rhythms apparently play in speech and gestural communication among humans, this study was undertaken to substantiate a biologically motivated model for synchronizing speech and gesture input in human computer interaction. Our approach presents a novel method which conceptualizes a multimodal user interface on the basis of timed agent systems. We use multiple agents for the purpose of polling presemantic information from different sensory channels (speech and hand gestures) and integrating them to multimodal data structures that can be processed by an application system which is again based on agent systems. This article motivates and presents technical work which exploits rhythmic patterns in the development; of biologically and cognitively motivated mediator systems between humans and machines.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="gw99ipke.final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611333/2621106/gw99ipke.final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Gif-sur-Yvette, France</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-540-66935-7</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000165605500025</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26113338</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/3-540-46616-9_25</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">277-289</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 1999. Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In A.  Braffort, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI 1739.  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 277-289.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech”, &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, A. Braffort, et al., eds., LNAI 1739,  Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1999,  pp.277-289.</ieee>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In: Braffort A, Gherbi R, Gibet S, Richardson J, Teil D, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. LNAI 1739. Berlin: Springer-Verlag;  1999: 277-289.</ama>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (1999). Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In A.  Braffort, R.  Gherbi, S.  Gibet, J.  Richardson, &amp;amp; D.  Teil (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI 1739&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-289). Berlin: Springer-Verlag. doi:10.1007/3-540-46616-9_25</apa>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In: Braffort, A., Gherbi, R., Gibet, S., Richardson, J., and Teil, D. (eds.) Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop. LNAI 1739. p. 277-289. Springer-Verlag, Berlin (1999).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1999. “Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech”. In &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Annelies Braffort, Rachid Gherbi, Sylvie Gibet, James Richardson, and Daniel Teil, 277-289. LNAI 1739. Berlin: Springer-Verlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (1999): Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In: Annelies Braffort; Rachid Gherbi; Sylvie Gibet; James Richardson; Daniel Teil (Hrsg.):  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop. Berlin: Springer-Verlag. (LNAI 1739, ).  S. 277-289.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1999). Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech (LNAI 1739). In A. Braffort, R. Gherbi, S. Gibet, J. Richardson &amp;amp; D. Teil (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (S. 277-289). Gehalten auf der International Gesture Workshop (GW '99), Berlin: Springer-Verlag. doi:10.1007/3-540-46616-9_25.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (1999). “Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech” in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Braffort, A., Gherbi, R., Gibet, S., Richardson, J., and Teil, D. eds. LNAI 1739 (Berlin: Springer-Verlag), 277-289.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1999). Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. In A.  Braffort, R.  Gherbi, S.  Gibet, J.  Richardson, &amp;amp; D.  Teil (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;LNAI 1739&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 277-289). Berlin: Springer-Verlag. doi:10.1007/3-540-46616-9_25&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech”. &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Annelies Braffort, Rachid Gherbi, Sylvie Gibet, James Richardson, and Daniel Teil. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1999. LNAI 1739. 277-289.</mla>
<default>Wachsmuth I (1999)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop. Braffort A, Gherbi R, Gibet S, Richardson J, Teil D (Eds);  LNAI 1739.  Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  277-289.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Braffort, R. Gherbi, S. Gibet, J. Richardson, D. Teil), Springer-Verlag, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 277-289.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (1999) &lt;br /&gt;Communicative rhythm in gesture and speech. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gesture-Based Communication in Human-Computer Interaction - Proceedings International Gesture Workshop. Braffort A, Gherbi R, Gibet S, Richardson J, Teil D (Eds); LNAI 1739,  Berlin: Springer-Verlag:  277-289.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611333</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-24T14:50:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>