<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611594</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrés</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cardona</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11880841</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26686880</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Over the last two decades, the concepts of ‘social mechanism’ and ‘mechanistic explanation’ have increasingly found their way into both theoretical and empirical work in sociology. This paper contributes to the already extensive literature on the subject by offering, from a sociologist’s perspective, a critical appraisal of the direction the debate has taken. It is argued that in developing a mechanistic agenda in sociology, the basic tenets of a mechanistic approach—generative causality and a commitment to causal explanation that effectively deepen our understanding of phenomena—have been displaced by individual programmatic priorities serving particular theoretical and methodological preferences. To raise awareness of this tendency and bring needed clarity to the debate on social mechanisms, a plea is made to distinguish programmatic conveniences from general claims on causation and causal explanation. Only then will a philosophically informed, broad-based, and inclusive dialog on the necessity and potential advantages of a mechanistic approach enriched by contributions from all corners of the discipline become possible.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0023_Cardona.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611594/2611595/SFB_882_WP_0023_Cardona.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>causal explanation</topic><topic>causation</topic><topic>Social mechanisms</topic><topic>mechanistic explanations</topic><topic>analytical sociology</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26115941</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>23</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Cardona, &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Cardona, A., 2013. &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.23, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<bio1>Cardona A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 23.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cardona, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 23). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Cardona, A. (2013): The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<ieee> A. Cardona, &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 23,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Cardona, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 23). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cardona, A. (2013). &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Cardona, A. (2013). The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 23, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Cardona A. &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 23. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2013.</ama>
<default>Cardona A (2013)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 23.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Cardona, Andrés. &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 23.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cardona, Andrés. 2013. &lt;em&gt;The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 23. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cardona, A.: The Programmatic Bias in the Discussion on Social Mechanisms in Sociology. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 23. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611594</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-26T13:50:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>