<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611059</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Leßmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14820</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kranstedt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>3rd International Joint Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2004</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Max is a human-size conversational agent that employs synthetic speech, gesture, gaze, and facial display to act in cooperative construction tasks taking place in immersive
virtual reality. In the mixed-initiative dialogs involved in
our research scenario, turn-taking abilities and dialog competences play a crucial role for Max to appear as a convincing multimodal communication partner. The way how they rely on Max’s perception of the user and, in special, how turn-taking signals are handled in the agent’s cognitive architecture is the focus of this paper.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PaperAAMAS_Lessmann_Kranstedt_Wachsmuth_2004.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611059/2634806/PaperAAMAS_Lessmann_Kranstedt_Wachsmuth_2004.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">New York, NY, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26110590</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">57-64</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Leßmann N, Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action. New York: IEEE Computer Society:  57-64.</default>
<mla>Leßmann, Nadine, Kranstedt, Alfred, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;. New York: IEEE Computer Society, 2004. 57-64.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Leßmann, Nadine, Kranstedt, Alfred, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2004. “Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, 57-64. New York: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A., Wachsmuth, I.: Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action. p. 57-64. IEEE Computer Society, New York (2004).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Leßmann, A.  Kranstedt, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee Computer Society, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 57-64.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Leßmann N, Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action.  New York: IEEE Computer Society:  57-64.</bio1>
<harvard1>Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2004. Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: IEEE Computer Society, pp. 57-64.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, 57-64. New York: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Leßmann, N.; Kranstedt, A.; Wachsmuth, I. (2004): Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. In: Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action. New York: IEEE Computer Society.  S. 57-64.</wels>
<ieee> N. Leßmann, A. Kranstedt, and I. Wachsmuth, “Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;,  New York: IEEE Computer Society, 2004,  pp.57-64.</ieee>
<apa>Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;, 57-64. New York: IEEE Computer Society.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (S. 57-64). Gehalten auf der 3rd International Joint Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2004, New York: IEEE Computer Society.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Leßmann, N., Kranstedt, A., and Wachsmuth, I. (2004). “Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt; (New York: IEEE Computer Society), 57-64.</frontiers>
<ama>Leßmann N, Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I. Towards a cognitively motivated processing of turn-taking signals for the embodied conversational agent Max. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings Workshop Embodied Conversational Agents: Balanced Perception and Action&lt;/em&gt;. New York: IEEE Computer Society;  2004: 57-64.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611059</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-23T11:24:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>