<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611049</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kranstedt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anja</namePart><namePart type="family">Belz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Roger</namePart><namePart type="family">Evans</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Piwek</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10066</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation, INLG 2004</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This poster describes ongoing work concerning the generation of multimodal utterances, animated and visualized with the anthropomorphic agent Max. Max is a conversational agent that collaborates in cooperative construction tasks taking place in immersive virtual reality, realized in a three-side CAVE- like installation. Max is able to produce synchronized output involving synthetic speech, facial display, and gesture from descriptions of their surface form [Kopp and Wachsmuth, 2004]. Focusing on deixis here it is shown how the influence of situational characteristics in face-to-face conversation can be accounted for in the automatic generation of such descriptions in multimodal dialogue.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="KW_deixis2004.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611049/2649402/KW_deixis2004.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Brighton</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Brockenhurst, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9783540223405</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26110498</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">20-23</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation. Belz A, Evans R, Piwek P (Eds);  Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01.  Brighton UK: University of Brighton:  20-23.</default>
<mla>Kranstedt, Alfred, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue”. &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Anja Belz, Roger Evans, and Paul Piwek. Brighton UK: University of Brighton, 2004. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01. 20-23.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kranstedt, Alfred, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2004. “Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue”. In &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Anja Belz, Roger Evans, and Paul Piwek, 20-23. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01. Brighton UK: University of Brighton.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kranstedt, A., Wachsmuth, I.: Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In: Belz, A., Evans, R., and Piwek, P. (eds.) Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01. p. 20-23. University of Brighton, Brighton UK (2004).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Kranstedt, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Belz, R. Evans, P. Piwek), University Of Brighton, Brighton UK, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 20-23.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation. Belz A, Evans R, Piwek P (Eds); Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01,  Brighton UK: University of Brighton:  20-23.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2004. Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In A.  Belz, R.  Evans, &amp;amp; P.  Piwek, eds. &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01.  Brighton UK: University of Brighton, pp. 20-23.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In A.  Belz, R.  Evans, &amp;amp; P.  Piwek (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 20-23). Brighton UK: University of Brighton.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kranstedt, A.; Wachsmuth, I. (2004): Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In: Anja Belz; Roger Evans; Paul Piwek (Hrsg.):  Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation. Brighton UK: University of Brighton. (Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01, ).  S. 20-23.</wels>
<ieee> A. Kranstedt and I. Wachsmuth, “Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue”, &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;, A. Belz, R. Evans, and P. Piwek, eds., Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01,  Brighton UK: University of Brighton, 2004,  pp.20-23.</ieee>
<apa>Kranstedt, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In A.  Belz, R.  Evans, &amp;amp; P.  Piwek (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 20-23). Brighton UK: University of Brighton.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kranstedt, A. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2004). Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue (Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01). In A. Belz, R. Evans &amp;amp; P. Piwek (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt; (S. 20-23). Gehalten auf der Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation, INLG 2004, Brighton UK: University of Brighton.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kranstedt, A., and Wachsmuth, I. (2004). “Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue” in &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;, Belz, A., Evans, R., and Piwek, P. eds. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01 (Brighton UK: University of Brighton), 20-23.</frontiers>
<ama>Kranstedt A, Wachsmuth I. Situated generation of multimodal deixis in task-oriented dialogue. In: Belz A, Evans R, Piwek P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Extended abstracts of posters presented at the Third International Conference on Natural Language Generation&lt;/em&gt;. Technical Report No. ITRI-04-01. Brighton UK: University of Brighton;  2004: 20-23.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611049</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-23T11:14:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>