<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611152</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Voss</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Julie A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Jacko</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Constantine</namePart><namePart type="family">Stephanidis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10066</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>10th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We describe an implemented system that anticipates user instructions in a collaborative construction task in virtual reality. The functionality of the system is embodied by an anthropomorphic interface agent and enables the usage of functional names for pieces of an uncompleted target aggregate in natural language instructions. Based on an internal model of the construction state and salience ratings for aggregate parts, an anticipatory system behaviour is achieved that tolerates imprecise user instructions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PaperHCII2003final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611152/2658670/PaperHCII2003final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Crete, Greece</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8058-4930-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26111521</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1283-1287</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Voss, I., Wachsmuth, I.: Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In: Jacko, J.A. and Stephanidis, C. (eds.) Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I). p. 1283-1287. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, London (2003).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Voss, Ian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2003. “Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant”. In &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Julie A. Jacko and Constantine Stephanidis, 1283-1287. London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Voss, Ian, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant”. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Julie A. Jacko and Constantine Stephanidis. London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 2003. 1283-1287.</mla>
<default>Voss I, Wachsmuth I (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I). Jacko JA, Stephanidis C (Eds);  London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates:  1283-1287.</default>
<ama>Voss I, Wachsmuth I. Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In: Jacko JA, Stephanidis C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;. London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates;  2003: 1283-1287.</ama>
<frontiers>Voss, I., and Wachsmuth, I. (2003). “Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant” in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;, Jacko, J. A., and Stephanidis, C. eds. (London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates), 1283-1287.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Voss, I. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2003). Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In J.A. Jacko &amp;amp; C. Stephanidis (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1283-1287). Gehalten auf der 10th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction, London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Voss, I., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2003). Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In J. A.  Jacko &amp;amp; C.  Stephanidis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1283-1287). London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.</apa>
<ieee> I. Voss and I. Wachsmuth, “Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant”, &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;, J.A. Jacko and C. Stephanidis, eds.,  London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 2003,  pp.1283-1287.</ieee>
<wels>Voss, I.; Wachsmuth, I. (2003): Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In: Julie A. Jacko; Constantine Stephanidis (Hrsg.):  Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I). London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.  S. 1283-1287.</wels>
<bio1>Voss I, Wachsmuth I (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I). Jacko JA, Stephanidis C (Eds); London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates:  1283-1287.</bio1>
<harvard1>Voss, I., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2003. Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In J. A.  Jacko &amp;amp; C.  Stephanidis, eds. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt;.  London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, pp. 1283-1287.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Voss, I., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2003). Anticipation in a VR-based anthropomorphic construction assistant. In J. A.  Jacko &amp;amp; C.  Stephanidis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1283-1287). London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Voss, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction, Theory and Practice (Part I)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.A. Jacko, C. Stephanidis), Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, London, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1283-1287.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611152</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-23T15:10:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>