<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611602</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammerschmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41913684</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tünnermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177449</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paweł</namePart><namePart type="family">Strumiłło</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michał</namePart><namePart type="family">Bujacz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Monika</namePart><namePart type="family">Popielata</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013)</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>The Cognitive Service Robotics Apartment as Ambient Host (CSRA, LSP-01)</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">Although most of us strive to develop a sustainable and less resource-intensive behavior, this unfortunately is a difficult task, because often we are unaware of relevant information, or our focus of attention lies elsewhere.
Based on this observation, we present a new approach for an unobtrusive and affective ambient auditory information display to become and stay aware of water and energy consumption while taking a shower. 
Using the interaction sound of waterdrops falling onto the bathtub as a carrier for information, our system supports users to be in touch with resource-related variables.
We explore the usage of an affective dimension as an additional layer of information and introduce our 4/5-factor approach to adapt the auditory display's output so that it supports a slow but steady adjustment of the personal showering habit over time.
We present and discuss several alternative sound and interaction designs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HammerschmidtTuennermannHermann-ISF-ICAD2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611602/2611603/HammerschmidtTuennermannHermann-ISF-ICAD2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Lodz University of Technology Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Lodz, Poland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-83-7283-546-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26116029</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">57-64</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2691580</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/HH2013-ISF</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Hammerschmidt, Jan, Tünnermann, Rene, and Hermann, Thomas. “InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower”. &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata. Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, 2013. 57-64.</mla>
<default>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds);  Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press:  57-64.</default>
<lncs> Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., Hermann, T.: InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In: Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. (eds.) ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. p. 57-64. Lodz University of Technology Press, Łódź, Poland (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, Jan, Tünnermann, Rene, and Hermann, Thomas. 2013. “InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower”. In &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata, 57-64. Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T (2013) &lt;br /&gt;InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds); Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press:  57-64.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2013. InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata, eds. &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;.  Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, pp. 57-64.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 57-64). Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hammerschmidt, R.  Tünnermann, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, M. Popielata), Lodz University Of Technology Press, Łódź, Poland, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 57-64.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hammerschmidt, J.; Tünnermann, R.; Hermann, T. (2013): InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In: Paweł Strumiłło; Michał Bujacz; Monika Popielata (Hrsg.):  ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display. Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.  S. 57-64.</wels>
<apa>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 57-64). Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.</apa>
<ieee> J. Hammerschmidt, R. Tünnermann, and T. Hermann, “InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower”, &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, and M. Popielata, eds.,  Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, 2013,  pp.57-64.</ieee>
<ama>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T. InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In: Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M, eds. &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;. Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press;  2013: 57-64.</ama>
<frontiers>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., and Hermann, T. (2013). “InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower” in &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt;, Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. eds. (Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press), 57-64.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). InfoDrops: Sonification for Enhanced Awareness of Resource Consumption in the Shower. In P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz &amp;amp; M. Popielata (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;ICAD 2013 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Auditory Display&lt;/em&gt; (S. 57-64). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013), Łódź, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611602</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-26T16:03:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:52:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>