<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611748</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lenzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems IJCAI-95</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes an approach to user adaptation realized in a multiagent interface system for interaction with a virtual environment. Single agents of the interface system adapt to users’ individual preferences by learning from direct feedback. The core idea is that agents that were succesful in meeting the user’s expectations are given credit while unsuccesful agents are “discredited.” Communicating credit values, agents organize themselves so that the overall behavior of the interface agency gradually adapts to the individual user as the session is proceeding.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijcai95paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611748/2634747/ijcai95paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Quebec, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26117488</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">43-46</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, Britta, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1995. “A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment”. In &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 43-46.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lenzmann, B., Wachsmuth, I.: A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems. p. 43-46. (1995).</lncs>
<ama>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I. A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. In:  &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. 1995: 43-46.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Lenzmann, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 43-46.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I (1995) &lt;br /&gt;A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems.  43-46.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 43-46). Gehalten auf der Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems IJCAI-95.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 43-46.</apa>
<harvard1>Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1995. A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. In &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 43-46.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Lenzmann and I. Wachsmuth, “A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment”, &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 1995,  pp.43-46.</ieee>
<default>Lenzmann B, Wachsmuth I (1995)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems.  43-46.</default>
<mla>Lenzmann, Britta, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment”. &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;. 1995. 43-46.</mla>
<frontiers>Lenzmann, B., and Wachsmuth, I. (1995). “A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment” in &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt; 43-46.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lenzmann, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. &lt;em&gt;Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 43-46.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Lenzmann, B.; Wachsmuth, I. (1995): A user-adaptive interface agency for interaction with a virtual environment. In: Working Notes IJCAI-95 Workshop on Adaptation and Learning in Multiagent Systems.  S. 43-46.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611748</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-29T07:33:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>