<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2611579</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yong</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10066</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The video demonstrates research accomplishments in interactive design and assembly with 3D computer graphics environments. Agent techniques and dynamic knowledge representations are used to process qualitative verbal instructions to quantitative scene changes. A key idea is to exploit situated ‘perceptive’ information by inspecting the computer graphics scene models.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijcai95videotrack.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2611579/2637310/ijcai95videotrack.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Montreal, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26115799</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">2061-2062</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cao, Y., Jung, B. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt; (S. 2061-2062). Gehalten auf der Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>Y.  Cao, B.  Jung, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 2061-2062.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cao Y, Jung B, Wachsmuth I (1995) &lt;br /&gt;Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95.  2061-2062.</bio1>
<ama>Cao Y, Jung B, Wachsmuth I. Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;. 1995: 2061-2062.</ama>
<lncs> Cao, Y., Jung, B., Wachsmuth, I.: Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95. p. 2061-2062. (1995).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cao, Yong, Jung, Bernhard, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1995. “Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;, 2061-2062.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Cao, Y.; Jung, B.; Wachsmuth, I. (1995): Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. In: Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95.  S. 2061-2062.</wels>
<mla>Cao, Yong, Jung, Bernhard, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;. 1995. 2061-2062.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cao, Y., Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;, 2061-2062.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Cao, Y., Jung, B., and Wachsmuth, I. (1995). “Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt; 2061-2062.</frontiers>
<default>Cao Y, Jung B, Wachsmuth I (1995)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95.  2061-2062.</default>
<harvard1>Cao, Y., Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1995. Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 2061-2062.</harvard1>
<ieee> Y. Cao, B. Jung, and I. Wachsmuth, “Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;, 1995,  pp.2061-2062.</ieee>
<apa>Cao, Y., Jung, B., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1995). Situated verbal interaction in virtual design and assembly, IJCAI-95 Videotape Program. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-95&lt;/em&gt;, 2061-2062.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2611579</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-26T11:24:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>