<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2612053</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Grigoris</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Antoniou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart><namePart type="family">Brezillon</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Vadim</namePart><namePart type="family">Stefanuk</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>East-West Conference on Artificial Intelligence, EWAIC-93</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Evolving out of theoretic and practical work, this paper presents the motivation and basic ideas for the construction and use of modular knowledge bases. The approach bears upon earlier work by the two authors done separately from each other. We introduce a model which attempts to merge two previous approaches while maintaining their benefits: Modules for logical knowledge bases, and ordered by generality domains. Central aims are reusability, restriction of memory search, and management of inconsistent (competing) knowledge within one knowledge base. We explain the model by motivational examples and discuss the formal semantics of structured, modular knowledge bases for knowledge representations that are based on logic programming.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="EWAIC-93.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2612053/2678332/EWAIC-93.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Moscow, Russia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>modules</topic><topic>knowledge representation in the large</topic><topic>knowledge sharing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26120539</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">73-77</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2609616</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Antoniou, G., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1993). Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In P.  Brezillon &amp;amp; V.  Stefanuk (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 73-77). Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia.</apa>
<ieee> G. Antoniou and I. Wachsmuth, “Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;, P. Brezillon and V. Stefanuk, eds.,  Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia, 1993,  pp.73-77.</ieee>
<ama>Antoniou G, Wachsmuth I. Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In: Brezillon P, Stefanuk V, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;. Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia;  1993: 73-77.</ama>
<frontiers>Antoniou, G., and Wachsmuth, I. (1993). “Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;, Brezillon, P., and Stefanuk, V. eds. (Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia), 73-77.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Antoniou, G. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1993). Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In P. Brezillon &amp;amp; V. Stefanuk (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt; (S. 73-77). Gehalten auf der East-West Conference on Artificial Intelligence, EWAIC-93, Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Antoniou, G., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1993). Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In P.  Brezillon &amp;amp; V.  Stefanuk (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 73-77). Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Antoniou G, Wachsmuth I (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice. Brezillon P, Stefanuk V (Eds); Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia:  73-77.</bio1>
<harvard1>Antoniou, G., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1993. Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In P.  Brezillon &amp;amp; V.  Stefanuk, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;.  Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia, pp. 73-77.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Antoniou, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Brezillon, V. Stefanuk), Association For Artificial Intelligence Of Russia, Moscow, Russia, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 73-77.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Antoniou, G.; Wachsmuth, I. (1993): Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In: Patrick Brezillon; Vadim Stefanuk (Hrsg.):  Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice. Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia.  S. 73-77.</wels>
<mla>Antoniou, Grigoris, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Patrick Brezillon and Vadim Stefanuk. Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia, 1993. 73-77.</mla>
<default>Antoniou G, Wachsmuth I (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice. Brezillon P, Stefanuk V (Eds);  Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia:  73-77.</default>
<lncs> Antoniou, G., Wachsmuth, I.: Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model. In: Brezillon, P. and Stefanuk, V. (eds.) Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice. p. 73-77. Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia, Moscow, Russia (1993).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Antoniou, Grigoris, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1993. “Structuring and modules for knowledge bases: Motivation for a new model”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings East--West Conference on Artificial Intelligence. From theory to practice&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Patrick Brezillon and Vadim Stefanuk, 73-77. Moscow, Russia: Association for Artificial Intelligence of Russia.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2612053</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-07-29T14:44:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>