<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2613929</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Optimal Constructions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vogel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191188</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9333-0652</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Geraldine</namePart><namePart type="family">Legendre</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Putnam</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Henriette</namePart><namePart type="family">de Swart</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Erin</namePart><namePart type="family">Zaroukian</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015092</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper deals with a well-known
problem in the discussion of argument linking, the flexibility that we find
with particular verbs, and the constraints governing the integration of verbs
with so-called argument structure constructions. We will show that traditional
approaches as well as construction grammar need additional machinery to deal
with variable argument linking. I will present an optimisation approach to
variable argument linking that uses construction grammar as format for
morphosyntax.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="otconstructions.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2613929/2613967/otconstructions.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Optimality Theory</topic><topic>Argument Structure</topic><topic>Construction Grammar</topic><topic>Syntax</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9780198757115</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26139297</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/acprof:oso/9780198757115.003.0003</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">55-77</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Vogel, R., 2016. Optimal Constructions. In G.  Legendre, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics.  Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. 55-77.</harvard1>
<ieee> R. Vogel, “Optimal Constructions”, &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;, G. Legendre, et al., eds., Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics,  Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2016,  pp.55-77.</ieee>
<ama>Vogel R. Optimal Constructions. In: Legendre G, Putnam M, de Swart H, Zaroukian E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics. Oxford: Oxford University Press;  2016: 55-77.</ama>
<apa>Vogel, R. (2016). Optimal Constructions. In G.  Legendre, M.  Putnam, H.  de Swart, &amp;amp; E.  Zaroukian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 55-77). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780198757115.003.0003</apa>
<lncs> Vogel, R.: Optimal Constructions. In: Legendre, G., Putnam, M., de Swart, H., and Zaroukian, E. (eds.) Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics. p. 55-77. Oxford University Press, Oxford (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vogel, Ralf. 2016. “Optimal Constructions”. In &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Geraldine Legendre, Michael Putnam, Henriette de Swart, and Erin Zaroukian, 55-77. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Vogel, R. (2016): Optimal Constructions. In: Geraldine Legendre; Michael Putnam; Henriette de Swart; Erin Zaroukian (Hrsg.):  Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization. Oxford: Oxford University Press. (Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics, ).  S. 55-77.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vogel, R. (2016). Optimal Constructions (Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics). In G. Legendre, M. Putnam, H. de Swart &amp;amp; E. Zaroukian (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt; (S. 55-77). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780198757115.003.0003.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vogel, R. (2016). Optimal Constructions. In G.  Legendre, M.  Putnam, H.  de Swart, &amp;amp; E.  Zaroukian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 55-77). Oxford: Oxford University Press. doi:10.1093/acprof:oso/9780198757115.003.0003&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Vogel, R. (2016). “Optimal Constructions” in &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;, Legendre, G., Putnam, M., de Swart, H., and Zaroukian, E. eds. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics (Oxford: Oxford University Press), 55-77.</frontiers>
<mla>Vogel, Ralf. “Optimal Constructions”. &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Geraldine Legendre, Michael Putnam, Henriette de Swart, and Erin Zaroukian. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2016. Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics. 55-77.</mla>
<default>Vogel R (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization. Legendre G, Putnam M, de Swart H, Zaroukian E (Eds);  Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics.  Oxford: Oxford University Press:  55-77.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Vogel, in &lt;em&gt;Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G. Legendre, M. Putnam, H. de Swart, E. Zaroukian), Oxford University Press, Oxford, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 55-77.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Vogel R (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Optimal Constructions. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Optimality- theoretic syntax, semantics, and pragmatics: From uni- to bidirectional optimization. Legendre G, Putnam M, de Swart H, Zaroukian E (Eds); Oxford Studies in Theoretical Linguistics,  Oxford: Oxford University Press:  55-77.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2613929</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-08-04T15:04:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-02-26T09:49:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>