<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2614106</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus-Rainer</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rollinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rudi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Studer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We present a brief description of the knowledge representation language L-LILOG. In particular, the concept of reference objects is introduced as a central means to build semantic representations for textual information. We describe how to construct internal representations as directed acyclic graphs and how to realize operations on reference objects to be performed in the process of constructing and utilizing semantic representations for natural language texts.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="rollinger_studer_wachsmuth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2614106/2641006/rollinger_studer_wachsmuth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IBM Almaden Research Lab.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1987</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">San Jose, CA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>L-LILOG</topic><topic>knowledge representation</topic><topic>text understanding</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26141066</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Rollinger, C. - R., Studer, R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1987). The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt; San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.</apa>
<ieee> C.-R. Rollinger, R. Studer, and I. Wachsmuth, “The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;,  San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab., 1987.</ieee>
<ama>Rollinger C-R, Studer R, Wachsmuth I. The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.;  1987.</ama>
<frontiers>Rollinger, C. - R., Studer, R., and Wachsmuth, I. (1987). “The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt; (San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rollinger, C.-R., Studer, R. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1987). The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Rollinger C-R, Studer R, Wachsmuth I (1987) &lt;br /&gt;The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems.  San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rollinger, C. - R., Studer, R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1987). The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt; San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Rollinger, C.-R., Studer, R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1987. The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;.  San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>C. - R.  Rollinger, R.  Studer, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Ibm Almaden Research Lab., San Jose, &lt;strong&gt;1987&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Rollinger, C. - R.; Studer, R.; Wachsmuth, I. (1987): The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. In: Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.</wels>
<mla>Rollinger, Claus-Rainer, Studer, Rudi, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab., 1987.</mla>
<default>Rollinger C-R, Studer R, Wachsmuth I (1987)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.</default>
<lncs> Rollinger, C.-R., Studer, R., Wachsmuth, I.: The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG. Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems.  IBM Almaden Research Lab., San Jose (1987).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rollinger, Claus-Rainer, Studer, Rudi, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1987. “The concept of reference objects in the representation of natural language information in L-LILOG”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ITL Conference on Expert Systems&lt;/em&gt;. San Jose: IBM Almaden Research Lab.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2614106</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-08-05T10:24:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>