<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2614568</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25994765</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2190-5576</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paweł</namePart><namePart type="family">Strumiłło</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michał</namePart><namePart type="family">Bujacz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Monika</namePart><namePart type="family">Popielata</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015530</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper introduces a novel sonification-based interaction support for cooperating users in an Augmented Reality setting. When using head-mounted AR displays, the field of view is limited which causes users to miss important activities such as object interactions or deictic references of their interaction partner to (re-)establish joint attention. We introduce an interactive sonification which makes object manipulations of both interaction partners mutually transparent by sounds that convey information about the kind of activity, and which can optionally even identify the object itself. In this paper we focus on the sonification method, interaction design and sound design, and we furthermore render the sonification both from sensor data (e.g. object tracking) and manual annotations. As a spin-off of our approach we propose this method further for the enhancement of interaction observation, data analysis, and multimodal annotation in interactional linguistics and conversation analysis.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="neumann_hermann.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2614568/2638090/neumann_hermann.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Lodz, Poland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-83-7283-546-48</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26145682</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">49-55</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Neumann A, Hermann T. Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In: Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;. The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD);  2013: 49-55.</ama>
<ieee> A. Neumann and T. Hermann, “Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, and M. Popielata, eds., The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), 2013,  pp.49-55.</ieee>
<harvard1>Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2013. Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;.  The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), pp. 49-55.</harvard1>
<lncs> Neumann, A., Hermann, T.: Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In: Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. (eds.) Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. p. 49-55. The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD) (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, Alexander, and Hermann, Thomas. 2013. “Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata, 49-55. The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 49-55). The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</apa>
<mla>Neumann, Alexander, and Hermann, Thomas. “Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata. The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), 2013. 49-55.</mla>
<frontiers>Neumann, A., and Hermann, T. (2013). “Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. eds. (The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), 49-55.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, A., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 49-55). The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Neumann, A. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz &amp;amp; M. Popielata (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (S. 49-55). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013), The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Neumann, A.; Hermann, T. (2013): Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. In: Paweł Strumiłło; Michał Bujacz; Monika Popielata (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).  S. 49-55.</wels>
<bio1>Neumann A, Hermann T (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Interactive Sonification of Collaborative AR-based Planning Tasks for Enhancing Joint Attention. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds); The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD):  49-55.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Neumann, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, M. Popielata), The International Community For Auditory Display (Icad), &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 49-55.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Neumann A, Hermann T (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds);  The International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD):  49-55.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2614568</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-08-08T15:00:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>