<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2617309</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nikolas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hemion</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8412063</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Joublin</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rohlfing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147957</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44326656</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="hemion_etal_2012_wcci_ijcnn.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2617309/2664272/hemion_etal_2012_wcci_ijcnn.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9781467314909</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26173093</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/IJCNN.2012.6252487</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hemion, N.; Joublin, F.; Rohlfing, K. (2012): Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In: IEEE Computational Intelligence Society; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Hrsg.):  The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). Brisbane, Australia: IEEE.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hemion, N., Joublin, F., &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2012). Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In IEEE Computational Intelligence Society &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt; Brisbane, Australia: IEEE. doi:10.1109/IJCNN.2012.6252487&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hemion, N., Joublin, F., and Rohlfing, K. (2012). “Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies” in &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE Computational Intelligence Society, and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers eds. (Brisbane, Australia: IEEE).</frontiers>
<mla>Hemion, Nikolas, Joublin, Frank, and Rohlfing, Katharina. “Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies”. &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. IEEE Computational Intelligence Society and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Brisbane, Australia: IEEE, 2012.</mla>
<default>Hemion N, Joublin F, Rohlfing K (2012)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). IEEE Computational Intelligence Society, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds);  Brisbane, Australia: IEEE.</default>
<harvard1>Hemion, N., Joublin, F., &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K., 2012. Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In IEEE Computational Intelligence Society &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds. &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;.  Brisbane, Australia: IEEE.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Hemion, F. Joublin, and K. Rohlfing, “Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies”, &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE Computational Intelligence Society and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds.,  Brisbane, Australia: IEEE, 2012.</ieee>
<apa>Hemion, N., Joublin, F., &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2012). Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In IEEE Computational Intelligence Society &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt; Brisbane, Australia: IEEE. doi:10.1109/IJCNN.2012.6252487</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hemion, N., Joublin, F. &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2012). Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In IEEE Computational Intelligence Society &amp;amp; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;. Brisbane, Australia: IEEE. doi:10.1109/IJCNN.2012.6252487.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Hemion, F.  Joublin, and K.  Rohlfing, in &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: IEEE Computational Intelligence Society, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers), Ieee, Brisbane, Australia, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hemion N, Joublin F, Rohlfing K (2012) &lt;br /&gt;Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). IEEE Computational Intelligence Society, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (Eds); Brisbane, Australia: IEEE.</bio1>
<ama>Hemion N, Joublin F, Rohlfing K. Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In: IEEE Computational Intelligence Society, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, eds. &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;. Brisbane, Australia: IEEE;  2012.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hemion, Nikolas, Joublin, Frank, and Rohlfing, Katharina. 2012. “Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies”. In &lt;em&gt;The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. IEEE Computational Intelligence Society and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Brisbane, Australia: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hemion, N., Joublin, F., Rohlfing, K.: Integration of sensorimotor mappings by making use of redundancies. In: IEEE Computational Intelligence Society and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (eds.) The 2012 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN).  IEEE, Brisbane, Australia (2012).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2617309</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-09-06T13:03:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>