<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2623746</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michaela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zwissler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Inga</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schalinski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ruf-Leuschner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maggie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kißler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27325660</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33695</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">People with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) often suffer from memory disturbances. In particular, previous studies suggest that PTSD patients perform atypically on tests of directed forgetting, which may be mediated by an altered emotional appraisal of the presented material. Also, a special role of dissociative symptoms in traumatized individuals’ memory performance has been suggested. Here, we investigate these issues in traumatized immigrants in Germany. In an item-method directed forgetting task, pictures were presented individually, each followed by an instruction to either remember or forget it. Later, recognition memory was tested for all pictures, regardless of initial instruction. Overall, the PTSD group’s discrimination accuracy was lower than the control group’s, as PTSD participants produced fewer hits and more false alarms, but the groups did not differ in directed forgetting itself. Moreover, the more negatively participants evaluated the stimuli, the less they were able to discriminate old from new items. Participants with higher dissociation scores were particularly poor at recognizing to-be-forgotten items. Results confirm PTSD patients’ general discrimination deficits, but provide no evidence for a distinct directed forgetting pattern in PTSD. Furthermore, data indicate that, in general, more negatively perceived items are discriminated with less accuracy than more positively appraised ones. Results are discussed in the larger context of emotion and stress-related modulations of episodic memory, with particular focus on the role of dissociative symptoms.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fnbeh_kissler.07-00094.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2623746/2623761/fnbeh_kissler.07-00094.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1662-5153</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1662-5153</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23966914</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000322813500001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26237465</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2013.00094</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">94</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Baumann, M., Zwissler, B., Schalinski, I., Ruf-Leuschner, M., Schauer, M., Kißler, J.: Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience. 7, 94 (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baumann, Michaela, Zwissler, Bastian, Schalinski, Inga, Ruf-Leuschner, Martina, Schauer, Maggie, and Kißler, Johanna. 2013. “Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 7: 94.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Baumann M, Zwissler B, Schalinski I, Ruf-Leuschner M, Schauer M, Kißler J. Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;7:94.</ama>
<bio1>Baumann M, Zwissler B, Schalinski I, Ruf-Leuschner M, Schauer M, Kißler J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience 7: 94.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Baumann, B.  Zwissler, I.  Schalinski, M.  Ruf-Leuschner, M.  Schauer, and J.  Kißler, “Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 94.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baumann, M., Zwissler, B., Schalinski, I., Ruf-Leuschner, M., Schauer, M. &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2013). Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 94. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fnbeh.2013.00094.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Baumann, M., Zwissler, B., Schalinski, I., Ruf-Leuschner, M., Schauer, M., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2013). Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 94. doi:10.3389/fnbeh.2013.00094</apa>
<ieee> M. Baumann, et al., “Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2013,  pp. 94.</ieee>
<harvard1>Baumann, M., et al., 2013. Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 7, p 94.</harvard1>
<default>Baumann M, Zwissler B, Schalinski I, Ruf-Leuschner M, Schauer M, Kißler J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 7: 94.</default>
<frontiers>Baumann, M., Zwissler, B., Schalinski, I., Ruf-Leuschner, M., Schauer, M., and Kißler, J. (2013). Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 7, 94.</frontiers>
<mla>Baumann, Michaela, Zwissler, Bastian, Schalinski, Inga, Ruf-Leuschner, Martina, Schauer, Maggie, and Kißler, Johanna. “Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 7 (2013): 94.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Baumann, M., Zwissler, B., Schalinski, I., Ruf-Leuschner, M., Schauer, M., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2013). Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 94. doi:10.3389/fnbeh.2013.00094&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Baumann, M.; Zwissler, B.; Schalinski, I.; Ruf-Leuschner, M.; Schauer, M.; Kißler, J. (2013): Directed Forgetting in Post-Traumatic-Stress-Disorder: A Study of Refugee Immigrants in Germany &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,7: 94.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2623746</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-09-20T12:01:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>