<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2624391</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Plaß</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">24353790</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patsy Yuen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thuan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jahn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">52383182</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Poh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lai</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Chit</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

To complement available information on mortality in a population Standard Expected Years of Life Lost (SEYLL), an indicator of premature mortality, is increasingly used to calculate the mortality-associated disease burden. SEYLL consider the age at death and therefore allow a more accurate view on mortality patterns as compared to routinely used measures (e.g. death counts). This study provides a comprehensive assessment of disease and injury SEYLL for Hong Kong in 2010.
Methods

To estimate the SEYLL, life-expectancy at birth was set according to the 2004 Global Burden of Disease study at 82.5 and 80 years for females and males, respectively. Cause of death data for 2010 were corrected for misclassification of cardiovascular and cancer causes. In addition to the baseline estimates, scenario analyses were performed using alternative assumptions on life-expectancy (Hong Kong standard life-expectancy), time-discounting and age-weighting. To estimate a trend of premature mortality a time-series analysis from 2001 to 2010 was conducted.
Results

In 2010 524,706.5 years were lost due to premature death in Hong Kong with 58.3% of the SEYLL attributable to male deaths. The three overall leading single causes of SEYLL were “trachea, bronchus and lung cancers”, “ischaemic heart disease” and “lower respiratory infections” together accounting for about 29% of the overall SEYLL. Further, self-inflicted injuries (5.6%; ranked 5) and liver cancer (4.9%; ranked 7) were identified as important causes not adequately captured by classical mortality measures. Scenario analyses highlighted that by using a 3% time-discount rate and non-uniform age-weights the SEYLL dropped by 51.6%. Using Hong Kong’s standard life-expectancy values resulted in an overall increase of SEYLL by 10.8% as compared to the baseline SEYLL. Time-series analysis indicates an overall increase of SEYLL by 6.4%. In particular, group I (communicable, maternal, perinatal and nutritional) conditions showed highest increases with SEYLL-rates per 100,000 in 2010 being 1.4 times higher than 2001.
Conclusions

The study stresses the mortality impact of diseases and injuries that occur in earlier stages of life and thus presents the SEYLL measure as a more sensitive indicator compared to classical mortality indicators. SEYLL provide useful additional information and supplement available death statistics.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1471-2458-13-863.plass.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2624391/2624402/1471-2458-13-863.plass.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24044523</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000324728300001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26243916</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-13-863</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Plaß, D., Chau, P. Y., Thach, T., Jahn, H. J., Lai, P., Wong, C., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2013). Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 863. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-13-863</apa>
<ieee> D. Plaß, et al., “Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 13, 2013, : 863.</ieee>
<ama>Plaß D, Chau PY, Thach T, et al. Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;13(1): 863.</ama>
<frontiers>Plaß, D., Chau, P. Y., Thach, T., Jahn, H. J., Lai, P., Wong, C., and Krämer, A. (2013). Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 13:863.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Plaß, D., Chau, P.Y., Thach, T., Jahn, H.J., Lai, P., Wong, C. &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2013). Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1): 863. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-13-863.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Plaß, D., Chau, P. Y., Thach, T., Jahn, H. J., Lai, P., Wong, C., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2013). Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 863. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-13-863&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Plaß, D., et al., 2013. Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 13(1): 863.</harvard1>
<bio1>Plaß D, Chau PY, Thach T, Jahn HJ, Lai P, Wong C, Krämer A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Public Health 13(1): 863.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Plaß, P. Y.  Chau, T.  Thach, H. J.  Jahn, P.  Lai, C.  Wong, and A.  Krämer, “Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, : 863.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Plaß, D.; Chau, P. Y.; Thach, T.; Jahn, H. J.; Lai, P.; Wong, C.; Krämer, A. (2013): Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,13:(1):863</wels>
<mla>Plaß, Dietrich, Chau, Patsy Yuen, Thach, Thuan, Jahn, Heiko J., Lai, Poh, Wong, Chit, and Krämer, Alexander. “Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 13.1 (2013): 863.</mla>
<default>Plaß D, Chau PY, Thach T, Jahn HJ, Lai P, Wong C, Krämer A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 13(1): 863.</default>
<lncs> Plaß, D., Chau, P.Y., Thach, T., Jahn, H.J., Lai, P., Wong, C., Krämer, A.: Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost. BMC Public Health. 13, : 863 (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Plaß, Dietrich, Chau, Patsy Yuen, Thach, Thuan, Jahn, Heiko J., Lai, Poh, Wong, Chit, and Krämer, Alexander. 2013. “Quantifying the burden of disease due to premature mortality in Hong Kong using standard expected years of life lost”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 13 (1): 863.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2624391</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-09-26T13:04:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>