<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2625161</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5107215</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Randall</namePart><namePart type="family">Shumaker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In order to make a step further towards understanding the impact of multi-modal stimuli in Virtual Reality we conducted a user study with 80 participants performing tasks in a virtual pit environment. Participants were divided into four groups, each presented a different combination of multi-sensory stimuli. Those included real-time 3D graphics, audio stimuli (ambient, static and event sounds), and haptics consisting of wind and tactile feedback when touching objects. A presence questionnaire was used to evaluate subjectively reported presence on the one hand, and on the other physiological sensors were used to measure heart rate and skin conductance as an objective measure. Results strongly indicate that an increase of modalities does not automatically result in an increase of presence.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="_CameraReady_Froehlich_Wachmuth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2625161/2625184/_CameraReady_Froehlich_Wachmuth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>user study</topic><topic>multi-modal feedback</topic><topic>virtual reality</topic><topic>presence</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-39404-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26251616</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-39405-8_19</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">159-168</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Fröhlich, J., Wachsmuth, I.: The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In: Shumaker, R. (ed.) Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8021, p. 159-168. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, Heidelberg (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, Julia, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2013. “The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds”. In &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Randall Shumaker, 8021:159-168. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Fröhlich, Julia, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds”. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Randall Shumaker. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2013.Vol. 8021. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 159-168.</mla>
<default>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Shumaker R (Ed);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8021.  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  159-168.</default>
<ama>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I. The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In: Shumaker R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8021. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg;  2013: 159-168.</ama>
<frontiers>Fröhlich, J., and Wachsmuth, I. (2013). “The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds” in &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, Shumaker, R. ed. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8021, (Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg), 159-168.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, J. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In R. Shumaker (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (S. 159-168). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39405-8_19.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In R.  Shumaker (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-168). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39405-8_19</apa>
<ieee> J. Fröhlich and I. Wachsmuth, “The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds”, &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, R. Shumaker, ed., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8021,  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2013,  pp.159-168.</ieee>
<wels>Fröhlich, J.; Wachsmuth, I. (2013): The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In: Randall Shumaker (Hrsg.):  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8021).  S. 159-168.</wels>
<harvard1>Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2013. The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In R.  Shumaker, ed. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8021  Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, pp. 159-168.</harvard1>
<bio1>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I (2013) &lt;br /&gt;The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Shumaker R (Ed); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8021. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg:  159-168.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). The visual, the auditory and the haptic – A user study on combining modalities in virtual worlds. In R.  Shumaker (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-168). Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-39405-8_19&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Fröhlich, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Shumaker), Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 159-168.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2625161</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-09-30T12:02:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>