<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2631853</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Adrian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hille</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36067050</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schupp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31683510</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5273-643X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26686880</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Despite numerous studies on skill development,we know little about the causal effects of music training on cognitive and non-cognitive skills. This study examines how long-term music training during childhood and youth affects the development of cognitive skills, school grades, personality,time use and ambition using representative data from the German Socio-Economic
Panel (SOEP). Our findings suggest that adolescents with music training have better cognitive skills and school grades and are more conscientious, open and ambitious. These effects do not differ by socio-economic status. Music improves cognitive and non-cognitive skills more than
twice as much as sports, theater or dance. In order to address the non-random selection into music training, we take into account detailed information on parents, which may determine both the decision to pursue music lessons and educational outcomes: socio-economic background,
personality, involvement with the child’s school, and taste for the arts. In addition, we control for the predicted probability to give up music before age 17 as well as the adolescent’s secondary school type. We provide evidence that our results are robust to both reverse causality and the existence of partly treated individuals in the control group.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0024_Hille_Schupp.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2631853/2631861/SFB_882_WP_0024_Hille_Schupp.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cognitive and non-cognitive skills</topic><topic>Music</topic><topic>educational achievement</topic><topic>SOEP</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26318530</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>24</number></detail><extent unit="pages">41</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Hille and J. Schupp, &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 24,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hille, A., &amp;amp; Schupp, J., 2013. &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.24, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa>Hille, A., &amp;amp; Schupp, J. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 24). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<wels>Hille, A.; Schupp, J. (2013): How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<mla>Hille, Adrian, and Schupp, Jürgen. &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2013. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 24.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hille, A., &amp;amp; Schupp, J. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 24). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hille, A., and Schupp, J. (2013). How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 24, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<default>Hille A, Schupp J (2013)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 24.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<ama>Hille A, Schupp J. &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 24. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2013.</ama>
<lncs> Hille, A., Schupp, J.: How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 24. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hille, Adrian, and Schupp, Jürgen. 2013. &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 24. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hille, A. &amp;amp; Schupp, J. (2013). &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Hille A, Schupp J (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 24.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Hille, and J.  Schupp, &lt;em&gt;How Learning a Musical Instrument Affects the Development of Skills&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2631853</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-10-22T11:34:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>