<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2634909</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Axel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Drechsler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Geller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Freund</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmeller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Künzel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rupp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27637395</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Adeline</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Loyau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathieu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Denoël</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emilio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Valbuena-Ureña</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steinfartz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">164260</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The development of microsatellite loci has become more efficient using next-generation sequencing (NGS) approaches, and many studies imply that the amount of applicable loci is large. However, few studies have sought to quantify the number of loci that are retained for use out of the thousands of sequence reads initially obtained. We analyzed the success rate of microsatellite loci development for three amphibian species using a 454 NGS approach on tetra-nucleotide motif-enriched species-specific libraries. The number of sequence reads obtained differed strongly between species and ranged from 19,562 for Triturus cristatus to 55,626 for Lissotriton helveticus, with 52,075 reads obtained for Calotriton asper. PHOBOS was used to identify sequences with tetra-nucleotide repeat motifs with a minimum repeat number of ten and high quality primer binding sites. Of 107 sequences for T. cristatus, 316 for C. asper and 319 for L. helveticus, we tested the amplification success, polymorphism, and degree of heterozygosity for 41 primer combinations each for C. asper and T. cristatus, and 22 for L. helveticus. We found 11 polymorphic loci for T. cristatus, 20 loci for C. asper, and 15 loci for L. helveticus. Extrapolated, the number of potentially amplifiable loci (PALs) resulted in estimated species-specific success rates of 0.15% (T. cristatus), 0.30% (C. asper), and 0.39% (L. helveticus). Compared with representative Illumina NGS approaches, our applied 454-sequencing approach on specifically enriched sublibraries proved to be quite competitive in terms of success rates and number of finally applicable loci.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ece3764.steinfartz.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2634909/2634921/ece3764.steinfartz.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ecology and Evolution</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2045-7758</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24198952</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000325486000024</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26349099</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/ece3.764</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>11</number></detail><extent unit="pages">3947-3957</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2665099</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drechsler, Axel, Geller, Daniel, Freund, Katharina, Schmeller, Dirk S., Künzel, Sven, Rupp, Oliver, Loyau, Adeline, Denoël, Mathieu, Valbuena-Ureña, Emilio, and Steinfartz, Sebastian. 2013. “What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 3 (11): 3947-3957.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Drechsler, A., Geller, D., Freund, K., Schmeller, D.S., Künzel, S., Rupp, O., Loyau, A., Denoël, M., Valbuena-Ureña, E., Steinfartz, S.: What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. Ecology and Evolution. 3, 3947-3957 (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Drechsler A, Geller D, Freund K, et al. What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;3(11):3947-3957.</ama>
<bio1>Drechsler A, Geller D, Freund K, Schmeller DS, Künzel S, Rupp O, Loyau A, Denoël M, Valbuena-Ureña E, Steinfartz S (2013) &lt;br /&gt;What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches.&lt;br /&gt;Ecology and Evolution 3(11): 3947-3957.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Drechsler, D.  Geller, K.  Freund, D. S.  Schmeller, S.  Künzel, O.  Rupp, A.  Loyau, M.  Denoël, E.  Valbuena-Ureña, and S.  Steinfartz, “What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 3947-3957.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drechsler, A., Geller, D., Freund, K., Schmeller, D.S., Künzel, S., Rupp, O., Loyau, A., Denoël, M., Valbuena-Ureña, E. &amp;amp; Steinfartz, S. (2013). What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(11), 3947-3957. Wiley-Blackwell. doi:10.1002/ece3.764.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Drechsler, A., Geller, D., Freund, K., Schmeller, D. S., Künzel, S., Rupp, O., Loyau, A., et al. (2013). What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(11), 3947-3957. doi:10.1002/ece3.764</apa>
<ieee> A. Drechsler, et al., “What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 3, 2013,  pp. 3947-3957.</ieee>
<harvard1>Drechsler, A., et al., 2013. What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, 3(11), p 3947-3957.</harvard1>
<default>Drechsler A, Geller D, Freund K, Schmeller DS, Künzel S, Rupp O, Loyau A, Denoël M, Valbuena-Ureña E, Steinfartz S (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 3(11): 3947-3957.</default>
<wels>Drechsler, A.; Geller, D.; Freund, K.; Schmeller, D. S.; Künzel, S.; Rupp, O.; Loyau, A.; Denoël, M.; Valbuena-Ureña, E.; Steinfartz, S. (2013): What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,3:(11): 3947-3957.</wels>
<frontiers>Drechsler, A., Geller, D., Freund, K., Schmeller, D. S., Künzel, S., Rupp, O., Loyau, A., Denoël, M., Valbuena-Ureña, E., and Steinfartz, S. (2013). What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 3, 3947-3957.</frontiers>
<mla>Drechsler, Axel, Geller, Daniel, Freund, Katharina, Schmeller, Dirk S., Künzel, Sven, Rupp, Oliver, Loyau, Adeline, Denoël, Mathieu, Valbuena-Ureña, Emilio, and Steinfartz, Sebastian. “What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 3.11 (2013): 3947-3957.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Drechsler, A., Geller, D., Freund, K., Schmeller, D. S., Künzel, S., Rupp, O., Loyau, A., et al. (2013). What remains from a 454 run: estimation of success rates of microsatellite loci development in selected newt species (Calotriton asper, Lissotriton helveticus, and Triturus cristatus) and comparison with Illumina-based approaches. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(11), 3947-3957. doi:10.1002/ece3.764&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2634909</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-11-18T13:20:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>