<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2634578</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Breuing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8052178</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Joaquim</namePart><namePart type="family">Filipe</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ana</namePart><namePart type="family">Fred</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">During dialog, humans are able to track ongoing topics, to detect topical shifts, to refer to topics via labels, and to decide on the appropriateness of potential dialog topics. As a result, they interactionally produce coherent sequences of spoken utterances assigning a thematic structure to the whole conversation. Accordingly, an artificial agent that is intended to engage in natural and sophisticated human-agent dialogs should be endowed with similar conversational abilities. This paper presents how to enable topically coherent conversations between humans and interactive systems by emulating humanlike topic awareness in the virtual agent Max. Therefore, we firstly realized automatic topic detection and tracking on the basis of contextual knowledge provided by Wikipedia and secondly adapted the agent’s conversational behavior by means of the gained topic information. As a result, we contribute to improve human-agent dialogs by enabling topical talk between human and artificial interlocutors. This paper is a revised and extended version of A. Breuing and I. Wachsmuth. Let’s talk topically with artificial agents! providing agents with humanlike topic awareness in everyday dialog situations. In Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Agents and Artificial Intelligence (ICAART), pages 62–71, 2012.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BreuingWachsmuth_Springer2012.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2634578/2634597/BreuingWachsmuth_Springer2012.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>automatic topic awareness</topic><topic>embodied conversational agents</topic><topic>human- agent interaction</topic><topic>topic detection and tracking</topic><topic>Wikipedia</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-642-36906-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26345785</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-36907-0_26</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>358</number></detail><extent unit="pages">392-406</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Breuing, A.; Wachsmuth, I. (2013): Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In: Joaquim Filipe; Ana Fred (Hrsg.):  Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers. Berlin: Springer. (Communications in Computer and Information Science, 358).  S. 392-406.</wels>
<harvard1>Breuing, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2013. Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In J.  Filipe &amp;amp; A.  Fred, eds. &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Communications in Computer and Information Science. no.358  Berlin: Springer, pp. 392-406.</harvard1>
<bio1>Breuing A, Wachsmuth I (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers. Filipe J, Fred A (Eds); Communications in Computer and Information Science, 358. Berlin: Springer:  392-406.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Breuing, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In J.  Filipe &amp;amp; A.  Fred (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Communications in Computer and Information Science: Vol. 358&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 392-406). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-36907-0_26&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Breuing, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Filipe, A. Fred), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 392-406.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Breuing A, Wachsmuth I. Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In: Filipe J, Fred A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Communications in Computer and Information Science. Vol 358. Berlin: Springer;  2013: 392-406.</ama>
<frontiers>Breuing, A., and Wachsmuth, I. (2013). “Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent” in &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Filipe, J., and Fred, A. eds. Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol. 358, (Berlin: Springer), 392-406.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Breuing, A. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent (Communications in Computer and Information Science). In J. Filipe &amp;amp; A. Fred (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 392-406). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-36907-0_26.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Breuing, A., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2013). Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In J.  Filipe &amp;amp; A.  Fred (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Communications in Computer and Information Science: Vol. 358&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 392-406). Berlin: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-36907-0_26</apa>
<ieee> A. Breuing and I. Wachsmuth, “Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent”, &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, J. Filipe and A. Fred, eds., Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol. 358,  Berlin: Springer, 2013,  pp.392-406.</ieee>
<lncs> Breuing, A., Wachsmuth, I.: Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent. In: Filipe, J. and Fred, A. (eds.) Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers. Communications in Computer and Information Science. 358, p. 392-406. Springer, Berlin (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Breuing, Alexa, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2013. “Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent”. In &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Joaquim Filipe and Ana Fred, 358:392-406. Communications in Computer and Information Science. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Breuing, Alexa, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Talking topically to artificial dialog partners: Emulating humanlike topic awareness in a virtual agent”. &lt;em&gt;Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Joaquim Filipe and Ana Fred. Berlin: Springer, 2013.Vol. 358. Communications in Computer and Information Science. 392-406.</mla>
<default>Breuing A, Wachsmuth I (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Agents and Artificial Intelligence: 4th International Conference, ICAART 2012, Vilamoura, Portugal, February 6-8, 2012. Revised Selected Papers. Filipe J, Fred A (Eds);  Communications in Computer and Information Science, 358.  Berlin: Springer:  392-406.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2634578</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-11-14T22:49:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>