<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2644087</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manuela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfinder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16213569</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Abstract: There is evidence for social inequalities in the health status of children with prenatal alcohol exposure (PAE). This study aimed to describe social inequalities in low birth weight (LBW) in children/adolescents with PAE and to examine the contribution of anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors to the explanation of social inequalities. A total of 2,159 participants with parental self-reported moderate to regular PAE (enrolled in the cross-sectional German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Children and Adolescents) were examined. At similar levels of PAE, the risk of LBW was significantly increased in subjects with a low socioeconomic status (SES) (adjusted odds ratio (OR) 2.78, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.59, 4.86) and middle SES (adjusted OR 2.04, 95% CI 1.28, 3.24). Maternal height, maternal body mass index (BMI) and smoking during pregnancy mediated the association. The mediating effect of maternal height was 12.5% to 33.7%. Maternal BMI explained 7.9% of the socioeconomic difference in LBW between the high and low SES groups in children with PAE. The mediating effect of smoking during pregnancy was 17.3% to 31.5%. Maternal height, maternal BMI and smoking during pregnancy together explained 24.4% to 60.1% of the socioeconomic differences in LBW in children with PAE. A large proportion of the socioeconomic differences in LBW in children with PAE can be attributed to anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijerph-11-00849.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2644087/2657196/ijerph-11-00849.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>pregnancy</topic><topic>alcohol</topic><topic>low birth weight</topic><topic>social inequalities</topic><topic>smoking</topic><topic>maternal height</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24406666</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000331456400046</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26440871</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph110100849</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">849-865</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Pfinder M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 11(1): 849-865.</default>
<mla>Pfinder, Manuela. “Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 11.1 (2014): 849-865.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, Manuela. 2014. “Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 11 (1): 849-865.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pfinder, M.: Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 11, 849-865 (2014).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Pfinder, “Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 849-865.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Pfinder, M., 2014. Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 11(1), p 849-865.</harvard1>
<bio1>Pfinder M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 11(1): 849-865.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M. (2014). Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(1), 849-865. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph110100849" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph110100849&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Pfinder, M. (2014): Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,11:(1): 849-865.</wels>
<ieee> M. Pfinder, “Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2014,  pp. 849-865.</ieee>
<apa>Pfinder, M. (2014). Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(1), 849-865. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph110100849" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph110100849&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M. (2014). Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(1), 849-865. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph110100849.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pfinder, M. (2014). Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 11, 849-865.</frontiers>
<ama>Pfinder M. Anthropometric and health-related behavioral factors in the explanation of social inequalities in low birth weight in children with prenatal alcohol exposure. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;11(1):849-865.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2644087</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-12-25T10:04:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>