<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2647430</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rost</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harshawardhan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ramachandran</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31312636</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nawrot</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Developing neuromorphic computing paradigms that mimic nervous system function is an emerging field of research with high potential for technical applications. In the present study we take inspiration from the cricket auditory system and propose a biologically plausible neural network architecture that can explain how acoustic pattern recognition is achieved in the cricket central brain. Our circuit model combines two key features of neural processing dynamics: Spike Frequency Adaptation (SFA) and synaptic short term plasticity. We developed and extensively tested the model function in software simulations. Furthermore, the feasibility of an analogue VLSI implementation is demonstrated using a multi-neuron chip comprising Integrate-and-Fire (IF) neurons and adaptive synapses.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ecctd13_cricket.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2647430/2654977/ecctd13_cricket.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Dresden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26474304</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ECCTD.2013.6662247</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-4</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rost, T., Ramachandran, H., Nawrot, M.P. &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2013). A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-4). Gehalten auf der European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD), IEEE. doi:10.1109/ECCTD.2013.6662247.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Rost, H.  Ramachandran, M. P.  Nawrot, and E.  Chicca, in &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-4.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Rost T, Ramachandran H, Nawrot MP, Chicca E (2013) &lt;br /&gt;A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD).  IEEE:  1-4.</bio1>
<ama>Rost T, Ramachandran H, Nawrot MP, Chicca E. A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. In:  &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE;  2013: 1-4.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rost, T., Ramachandran, Harshawardhan, Nawrot, M.P., and Chicca, Elisabetta. 2013. “A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis”. In &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-4. IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rost, T., Ramachandran, H., Nawrot, M.P., Chicca, E.: A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. 2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD). p. 1-4. IEEE (2013).</lncs>
<frontiers>Rost, T., Ramachandran, H., Nawrot, M. P., and Chicca, E. (2013). “A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis” in &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt; (IEEE), 1-4.</frontiers>
<mla>Rost, T., Ramachandran, Harshawardhan, Nawrot, M.P., and Chicca, Elisabetta. “A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis”. &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE, 2013. 1-4.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rost, T., Ramachandran, H., Nawrot, M. P., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2013). A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-4. IEEE. doi:10.1109/ECCTD.2013.6662247&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Rost, T.; Ramachandran, H.; Nawrot, M. P.; Chicca, E. (2013): A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. In: 2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD). IEEE.  S. 1-4.</wels>
<default>Rost T, Ramachandran H, Nawrot MP, Chicca E (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD). IEEE:  1-4.</default>
<harvard1>Rost, T., et al., 2013. A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. In &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;.  IEEE, pp. 1-4.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Rost, et al., “A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis”, &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE, 2013,  pp.1-4.</ieee>
<apa>Rost, T., Ramachandran, H., Nawrot, M. P., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2013). A neuromorphic approach to auditory pattern recognition in cricket phonotaxis. &lt;em&gt;2013 European Conference on Circuit Theory and Design (ECCTD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-4. IEEE. doi:10.1109/ECCTD.2013.6662247</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2647430</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-01-11T23:54:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>