<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2654523</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norberto</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Degara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nagel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paweł</namePart><namePart type="family">Strumiłło</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michał</namePart><namePart type="family">Bujacz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Monika</namePart><namePart type="family">Popielata</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">After 18 ICAD conferences, Auditory Display has become a mature research community. However, a robust evaluation and scientific comparison of sonification methods is often neglected by auditory display researchers. In the last ICAD 2012 conference, only one paper out of 53 makes a statistical comparison of several sonification methods and still no comparison with other state-of-the-art algorithms is provided. In this paper, we review profitable standards in other communities and transfer them to derive recommendations and best practices for auditory display research. We describe SonEX (Sonification Evaluation eXchange), a community-based framework for the formal evaluation of sonification methods. The goals, challenges and architecture of this evaluation platform are discussed. In addition, a simple example of a task definition according to the guidelines of SonEX is also introduced. This paper aims at starting a vivid discussion towards the establishment of thorough scientific methodologies for auditory display research and the definition of standardized sonification tasks.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="DegaraNagelHermann2013-SAE-ICAD2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2654523/2654587/DegaraNagelHermann2013-SAE-ICAD2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Lodz University of Technology Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Lodz, Poland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>auditory display</topic><topic>sonification</topic><topic>reproducible</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-83-7283-546-48</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26545237</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">167-174</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Degara, N., Nagel, F., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 167-174). Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.</apa>
<ieee> N. Degara, F. Nagel, and T. Hermann, “SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, and M. Popielata, eds.,  Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, 2013,  pp.167-174.</ieee>
<ama>Degara N, Nagel F, Hermann T. SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In: Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;. Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press;  2013: 167-174.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Degara, N., Nagel, F. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz &amp;amp; M. Popielata (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (S. 167-174). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2013), Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Degara, N., Nagel, F., and Hermann, T. (2013). “SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. eds. (Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press), 167-174.</frontiers>
<bio1>Degara N, Nagel F, Hermann T (2013) &lt;br /&gt;SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds); Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press:  167-174.</bio1>
<harvard1>Degara, N., Nagel, F., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2013. SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;.  Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, pp. 167-174.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Degara, N., Nagel, F., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2013). SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In P.  Strumiłło, M.  Bujacz, &amp;amp; M.  Popielata (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 167-174). Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Degara, F.  Nagel, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Strumiłło, M. Bujacz, M. Popielata), Lodz University Of Technology Press, Lodz, Poland, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 167-174.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Degara, N.; Nagel, F.; Hermann, T. (2013): SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In: Paweł Strumiłło; Michał Bujacz; Monika Popielata (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.  S. 167-174.</wels>
<mla>Degara, Norberto, Nagel, Frederik, and Hermann, Thomas. “SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata. Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press, 2013. 167-174.</mla>
<default>Degara N, Nagel F, Hermann T (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. Strumiłło P, Bujacz M, Popielata M (Eds);  Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press:  167-174.</default>
<lncs> Degara, N., Nagel, F., Hermann, T.: SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification. In: Strumiłło, P., Bujacz, M., and Popielata, M. (eds.) Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays. p. 167-174. Lodz University of Technology Press, Lodz, Poland (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Degara, Norberto, Nagel, Frederik, and Hermann, Thomas. 2013. “SONEX: An Evaluation Exchange Framework for Reproducible Sonification”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Auditory Displays&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Paweł Strumiłło, Michał Bujacz, and Monika Popielata, 167-174. Lodz, Poland: Lodz University of Technology Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2654523</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-02-06T10:21:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>