<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2661294</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rose</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Damm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8289361</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">152704</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knuf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wutzler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes G</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liese</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hagen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krüger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wahn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tom</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schaberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schwehm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas F</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kochmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eichner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21335</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Routine annual influenza vaccination is primarily recommended for all persons aged 60 and above and for people with underlying chronic conditions in Germany. Other countries have already adopted additional childhood influenza immunisation programmes. The objective of this study is to determine the potential epidemiological impact of implementing paediatric influenza vaccination using intranasally administered live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany.
Methods

A deterministic age-structured model is used to simulate the population-level impact of different vaccination strategies on the transmission dynamics of seasonal influenza in Germany. In our base-case analysis, we estimate the effects of adding a LAIV-based immunisation programme targeting children 2 to 17 years of age to the existing influenza vaccination policy. The data used in the model is based on published evidence complemented by expert opinion.
Results

In our model, additional vaccination of children 2 to 17 years of age with LAIV leads to the prevention of 23.9 million influenza infections and nearly 16 million symptomatic influenza cases within 10 years. This reduction in burden of disease is not restricted to children. About one third of all adult cases can indirectly be prevented by LAIV immunisation of children.
Conclusions

Our results demonstrate that vaccinating children 2–17 years of age is likely associated with a significant reduction in the burden of paediatric influenza. Furthermore, annual routine childhood vaccination against seasonal influenza is expected to decrease the incidence of influenza among adults and older people due to indirect effects of herd protection. In summary, our model provides data supporting the introduction of a paediatric influenza immunisation programme in Germany.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1471-2334-14-40.Damm.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2661294/2661314/1471-2334-14-40.Damm.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Live-attenuated influenza vaccine</topic><topic>Transmission model</topic><topic>Germany</topic><topic>Children</topic><topic>Vaccination</topic><topic>Influenza</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Infectious Diseases</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2334</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24450996</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000331203900002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26612946</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-14-40</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rose, M.A., Damm, O., Greiner, W., Knuf, M., Wutzler, P., Liese, J.G., Krüger, H., Wahn, U., Schaberg, T., Schwehm, M., Kochmann, T.F. &amp;amp; Eichner, M. (2014). The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1): 40. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/1471-2334-14-40.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Rose MA, Damm O, Greiner W, Knuf M, Wutzler P, Liese JG, Krüger H, Wahn U, Schaberg T, Schwehm M, Kochmann TF, Eichner M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases 14(1): 40.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M. A.  Rose, O.  Damm, W.  Greiner, M.  Knuf, P.  Wutzler, J. G.  Liese, H.  Krüger, U.  Wahn, T.  Schaberg, M.  Schwehm, et al., “The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;, : 40.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Rose MA, Damm O, Greiner W, et al. The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;14(1): 40.</ama>
<lncs> Rose, M.A., Damm, O., Greiner, W., Knuf, M., Wutzler, P., Liese, J.G., Krüger, H., Wahn, U., Schaberg, T., Schwehm, M., Kochmann, T.F., Eichner, M.: The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. BMC Infectious Diseases. 14, : 40 (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rose, Markus A, Damm, Oliver, Greiner, Wolfgang, Knuf, Markus, Wutzler, Peter, Liese, Johannes G, Krüger, Hagen, et al. 2014. “The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt; 14 (1): 40.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Rose, M. A.; Damm, O.; Greiner, W.; Knuf, M.; Wutzler, P.; Liese, J. G.; Krüger, H.; Wahn, U.; Schaberg, T.; Schwehm, M.; Kochmann, T. F.; Eichner, M. (2014): The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;,14:(1):40</wels>
<mla>Rose, Markus A, Damm, Oliver, Greiner, Wolfgang, Knuf, Markus, Wutzler, Peter, Liese, Johannes G, Krüger, Hagen, Wahn, Ulrich, Schaberg, Tom, Schwehm, Markus, Kochmann, Thomas F, and Eichner, Martin. “The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt; 14.1 (2014): 40.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rose, M. A., Damm, O., Greiner, W., Knuf, M., Wutzler, P., Liese, J. G., Krüger, H., et al. (2014). The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 40. doi:10.1186/1471-2334-14-40&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Rose, M. A., Damm, O., Greiner, W., Knuf, M., Wutzler, P., Liese, J. G., Krüger, H., Wahn, U., Schaberg, T., Schwehm, M., et al. (2014). The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt; 14:40.</frontiers>
<default>Rose MA, Damm O, Greiner W, Knuf M, Wutzler P, Liese JG, Krüger H, Wahn U, Schaberg T, Schwehm M, Kochmann TF, et al. (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt; 14(1): 40.</default>
<ieee> M.A. Rose, et al., “The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 14, 2014, : 40.</ieee>
<harvard1>Rose, M.A., et al., 2014. The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;, 14(1): 40.</harvard1>
<apa>Rose, M. A., Damm, O., Greiner, W., Knuf, M., Wutzler, P., Liese, J. G., Krüger, H., et al. (2014). The epidemiological impact of childhood influenza vaccination using live-attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV) in Germany: predictions of a simulation study. &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 40. doi:10.1186/1471-2334-14-40</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2661294</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-03-04T09:29:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>