<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2662343</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hofstätter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karl</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kerstin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hasse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker-Asano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marco</namePart><namePart type="family">Costa</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefano</namePart><namePart type="family">Tampellini</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="hofstaetter_etal.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2662343/2662807/hofstaetter_etal.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bologna, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26623438</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">137-138</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hofstätter, A.; Grammer, K.; Hasse, K.; Becker-Asano, C. W.; Wachsmuth, I. (2008): How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In: Marco Costa; Stefano Tampellini (Hrsg.):  XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts.  S. 137-138.</wels>
<bio1>Hofstätter A, Grammer K, Hasse K, Becker-Asano CW, Wachsmuth I (2008) &lt;br /&gt;How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. &lt;br /&gt;In:  XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts. Costa M, Tampellini S (Eds); 137-138.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hofstätter, A., et al., 2008. How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In M.  Costa &amp;amp; S.  Tampellini, eds. &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 137-138.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofstätter, A., Grammer, K., Hasse, K., Becker-Asano, C. W., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2008). How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In M.  Costa &amp;amp; S.  Tampellini (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 137-138).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Hofstätter, K.  Grammer, K.  Hasse, C. W.  Becker-Asano, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Costa, S. Tampellini), &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 137-138.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hofstätter A, Grammer K, Hasse K, Becker-Asano CW, Wachsmuth I. How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In: Costa M, Tampellini S, eds. &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;. 2008: 137-138.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofstätter, A., Grammer, K., Hasse, K., Becker-Asano, C.W. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2008). How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In M. Costa &amp;amp; S. Tampellini (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt; (S. 137-138). Gehalten auf der XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hofstätter, A., Grammer, K., Hasse, K., Becker-Asano, C. W., and Wachsmuth, I. (2008). “How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar” in &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;, Costa, M., and Tampellini, S. eds. 137-138.</frontiers>
<apa>Hofstätter, A., Grammer, K., Hasse, K., Becker-Asano, C. W., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2008). How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In M.  Costa &amp;amp; S.  Tampellini (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 137-138).</apa>
<ieee> A. Hofstätter, et al., “How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar”, &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;, M. Costa and S. Tampellini, eds., 2008,  pp.137-138.</ieee>
<lncs> Hofstätter, A., Grammer, K., Hasse, K., Becker-Asano, C.W., Wachsmuth, I.: How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar. In: Costa, M. and Tampellini, S. (eds.) XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts. p. 137-138. (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofstätter, Andrea, Grammer, Karl, Hasse, Kerstin, Becker-Asano, Christian W., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2008. “How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar”. In &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Marco Costa and Stefano Tampellini, 137-138.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hofstätter, Andrea, Grammer, Karl, Hasse, Kerstin, Becker-Asano, Christian W., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “How Emma learned to smile and frown. The implementation of the facial action coding system in an avatar”. &lt;em&gt;XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Marco Costa and Stefano Tampellini. 2008. 137-138.</mla>
<default>Hofstätter A, Grammer K, Hasse K, Becker-Asano CW, Wachsmuth I (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  XIX Biennial Conference of the International Society for Human Ethology: Abstracts. Costa M, Tampellini S (Eds);   137-138.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2662343</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-03-07T14:08:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>