<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2663059</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Spyridon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kousidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31490072</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Casey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kennington</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23347505</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2862170</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Dialogue in Motion</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Holding non-co-located conversations while driving is dangerous (Horrey and Wickens, 2006; Strayer et al., 2006), much more so than conversations with physically present, “situated” interlocutors (Drews et al., 2004). In-car dialogue systems typically resemble non-co-located conversations more, and share their negative impact (Strayer et al., 2013). We implemented and tested a simple strategy for making in-car dialogue systems aware of the driving situation, by giving them the capability to interrupt themselves when a dangerous situation is detected, and resume when over. We show that this improves both driving performance and recall of system-presented information, compared to a non-adaptive strategy.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kousidis-etal-2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2663059/2673183/Kousidis-etal-2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Gothenburg, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26630595</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3115/v1/W14-0212</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">68-72</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Kousidis, S., Kennington, C., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., Schlangen, D.: Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion. p. 68-72. Gothenburg, Sweden (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, Spyridon, Kennington, Casey, Baumann, Timo, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Schlangen, David. 2014. “Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;, 68-72. Gothenburg, Sweden.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kousidis, Spyridon, Kennington, Casey, Baumann, Timo, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Schlangen, David. “Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;. Gothenburg, Sweden, 2014. 68-72.</mla>
<default>Kousidis S, Kennington C, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion. Gothenburg, Sweden:  68-72.</default>
<wels>Kousidis, S.; Kennington, C.; Baumann, T.; Buschmeier, H.; Kopp, S.; Schlangen, D. (2014): Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. In: Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion. Gothenburg, Sweden.  S. 68-72.</wels>
<bio1>Kousidis S, Kennington C, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion.  Gothenburg, Sweden:  68-72.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kousidis, S., et al., 2014. Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;.  Gothenburg, Sweden, pp. 68-72.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S., Kennington, C., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;, 68-72. Gothenburg, Sweden. doi:10.3115/v1/W14-0212&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kousidis, C.  Kennington, T.  Baumann, H.  Buschmeier, S.  Kopp, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;, Gothenburg, Sweden, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 68-72.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kousidis S, Kennington C, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D. Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;. Gothenburg, Sweden;  2014: 68-72.</ama>
<frontiers>Kousidis, S., Kennington, C., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., and Schlangen, D. (2014). “Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt; (Gothenburg, Sweden), 68-72.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S., Kennington, C., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt; (S. 68-72). Gehalten auf der Dialogue in Motion, Gothenburg, Sweden. doi:10.3115/v1/W14-0212.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kousidis, S., Kennington, C., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;, 68-72. Gothenburg, Sweden. doi:10.3115/v1/W14-0212</apa>
<ieee> S. Kousidis, et al., “Situationally Aware In-Car Information Presentation Using Incremental Speech Generation: Safer, and More Effective”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the EACL 2014 Workshop on Dialogue in Motion&lt;/em&gt;,  Gothenburg, Sweden: 2014,  pp.68-72.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2663059</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-03-11T08:55:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>