<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2663500</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rosin</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Ulrike</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Ravens-Sieberer</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background
In spite of WHO/UNICEF programs and subsequent measures to promote breastfeeding, breastfeeding still does not represent the norm for infant feeding on a global scale. 

Objective
A questionnaire for experts in the field of lactation was designed to assess the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion including: The experts’ work situation with respect to contentedness, motivation and acceptance, the progress of breastfeeding promotion and the identification of remaining obstacles to derive practice-based policy recommendations towards a breastfeeding culture.

Methods
Quantitative evaluations based on closed question items included mainly descriptive statistics. Qualitative methods based on open question items categorised mutually exclusive response groups by paraphrasing. 

Results
Lactation consulting is lacking of payment and career opportunities on an international level and needs a firm position in the health care system with reimbursement to the full extent of work. However, lactation consultants describe themselves as mostly contented and idealistically motivated. Societal and political support is poor and research funds are lacking, NCBFs' should gain political weight and take on additional tasks. Health care providers without education in lactation represent a decisive obstacle to breastfeeding. WHO/UNICEF measures remain priority with overdue implementation.

Conclusions
Health policies to protect and promote breastfeeding including legislation, consumer protection and the integration of lactation consulting in the health care systems represent key measures to achieve progress in the implementation of WHO/UNICEF and subsequent programs to re-establish the breastfeeding culture. A basic education of all health-care providers in the lactation field seems indispensable to promote breastfeeding consistently.

Discussion
Breastfeeding support should be prioritized as promotion of a major health resource on a global scale. Facing a global economic and climate crisis it should be an imperative for health policies to re-build the breastfeeding culture with priority to protect our offspring.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation_Stefanie_Rosin.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2663500/2663522/Dissertation_Stefanie_Rosin.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universitätsbibliothek</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>WHO UNICEF</topic><topic>breastfeeding protection and promotion</topic><topic>lactation consultant</topic><topic>society</topic><topic>integrated care</topic><topic>breastfeeding support</topic><topic>expert</topic><topic>International Code for the Marketing of Breastmilk Substitutes</topic><topic>National Breastfeeding Committee</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-26635005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2663500</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">222</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2013-12-09</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Rosin S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Rosin, &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;, Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Rosin S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.</bio1>
<wels>Rosin, S. (2010): Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rosin, S. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.4119/unibi/2663500.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Rosin, S. (2010). Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rosin, S. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.4119/unibi/2663500&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Rosin, Stefanie. &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2010.</mla>
<apa>Rosin, S. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek. doi:10.4119/unibi/2663500</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rosin, Stefanie. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rosin, S.: Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations. Universitätsbibliothek, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
<harvard1>Rosin, S., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Rosin, &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek, 2010.</ieee>
<ama>Rosin S. &lt;em&gt;Assessing the international situation of breastfeeding, lactation consulting and breastfeeding promotion as viewed by international, interdisciplinary experts and resulting recommendations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universitätsbibliothek; 2010.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2663500</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-03-12T13:25:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-08-10T06:42:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>