<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2669786</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raphael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Susewind</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22853575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1022-4748</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Darwis</namePart><namePart type="family">Khudori</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Elikia</namePart><namePart type="family">Mbokolo</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bandung-Chapter-Final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2669786/2900845/Bandung-Chapter-Final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Univ. Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Gujarat</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26697861</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">221-228</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Susewind, R. (2013). “Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India” in &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;, Khudori, D., and Mbokolo, E. eds. (Brawijaya: Univ. Press), 221-228.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Susewind, R. (2013). Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In D. Khudori &amp;amp; E. Mbokolo (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt; (S. 221-228). Brawijaya: Univ. Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Susewind R. Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In: Khudori D, Mbokolo E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;. Brawijaya: Univ. Press;  2013: 221-228.</ama>
<ieee> R. Susewind, “Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India”, &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;, D. Khudori and E. Mbokolo, eds.,  Brawijaya: Univ. Press, 2013,  pp.221-228.</ieee>
<apa>Susewind, R. (2013). Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In D.  Khudori &amp;amp; E.  Mbokolo (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 221-228). Brawijaya: Univ. Press.</apa>
<wels>Susewind, R. (2013): Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In: Darwis Khudori; Elikia Mbokolo (Hrsg.):  Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia. Brawijaya: Univ. Press.  S. 221-228.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Susewind, in &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Khudori, E. Mbokolo), Univ. Press, Brawijaya, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 221-228.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Susewind, R., 2013. Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In D.  Khudori &amp;amp; E.  Mbokolo, eds. &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;.  Brawijaya: Univ. Press, pp. 221-228.</harvard1>
<bio1>Susewind R (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia. Khudori D, Mbokolo E (Eds); Brawijaya: Univ. Press:  221-228.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Susewind, R. (2013). Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In D.  Khudori &amp;amp; E.  Mbokolo (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 221-228). Brawijaya: Univ. Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Susewind, Raphael. 2013. “Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India”. In &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Darwis Khudori and Elikia Mbokolo, 221-228. Brawijaya: Univ. Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Susewind, R.: Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India. In: Khudori, D. and Mbokolo, E. (eds.) Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia. p. 221-228. Univ. Press, Brawijaya (2013).</lncs>
<default>Susewind R (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia. Khudori D, Mbokolo E (Eds);  Brawijaya: Univ. Press:  221-228.</default>
<mla>Susewind, Raphael. “Unity in diversity? Muslim civil society and Muslims in civil society in Gujarat, India”. &lt;em&gt;Religious diversity in a globalised society: Challenges and responses in Africa and Asia&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Darwis Khudori and Elikia Mbokolo. Brawijaya: Univ. Press, 2013. 221-228.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2669786</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-03T13:32:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>