<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2669168</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spitta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41186</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Fevzi</namePart><namePart type="family">Belli</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Farokh</namePart><namePart type="family">Bastani</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Albert</namePart><namePart type="family">Endres</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>IEEE /ISSRE '98</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The knowledge of development and maintenance effort is a necessary precondition for all types of software management, IS-controlling, guidance of quality and effort estimation. Data collecting systems seem to be widely used, but the data is said to be unsafe and firm-specific. This paper presents a concept for the collection of personnel effort and for events (e.g. faults). The revised informal specification of this paper is based on experience with such a system used by 40 developers in five locations for many years. Design and practical use of a system based on that concept allow the collection of statistically valid effort data. This would only be possible if developers are sure to be not supervised by their data, and if they don’t need to decide upon classifications during data-entry time. Examples show applications of the data for project management, quality control and IS resource management reporting from 6« years with overall 170 PYs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="EffortShort_ISSRE98.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2669168/2670158/EffortShort_ISSRE98.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Paderborn</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>IT-Controlling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26691687</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">111-120</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Spitta, T. (1998). Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In F.  Belli, F.  Bastani, &amp;amp; A.  Endres (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 111-120). IEEE.</apa>
<ieee> T. Spitta, “Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments”, &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;, F. Belli, F. Bastani, and A. Endres, eds., IEEE, 1998,  pp.111-120.</ieee>
<ama>Spitta T. Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In: Belli F, Bastani F, Endres A, eds. &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE;  1998: 111-120.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, T. (1998). Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In F. Belli, F. Bastani &amp;amp; A. Endres (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 111-120). Gehalten auf der IEEE /ISSRE '98, IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Spitta, T. (1998). “Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments” in &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;, Belli, F., Bastani, F., and Endres, A. eds. (IEEE), 111-120.</frontiers>
<bio1>Spitta T (1998) &lt;br /&gt;Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE). Belli F, Bastani F, Endres A (Eds); IEEE:  111-120.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, T. (1998). Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In F.  Belli, F.  Bastani, &amp;amp; A.  Endres (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 111-120). IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Spitta, T., 1998. Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In F.  Belli, F.  Bastani, &amp;amp; A.  Endres, eds. &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;.  IEEE, pp. 111-120.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Spitta, in &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: F. Belli, F. Bastani, A. Endres), Ieee, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 111-120.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Spitta, T. (1998): Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In: Fevzi Belli; Farokh Bastani; Albert Endres (Hrsg.):  9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE). IEEE.  S. 111-120.</wels>
<mla>Spitta, Thorsten. “Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments”. &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Fevzi Belli, Farokh Bastani, and Albert Endres. IEEE, 1998. 111-120.</mla>
<default>Spitta T (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE). Belli F, Bastani F, Endres A (Eds);  IEEE:  111-120.</default>
<lncs> Spitta, T.: Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments. In: Belli, F., Bastani, F., and Endres, A. (eds.) 9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE). p. 111-120. IEEE (1998).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, Thorsten. 1998. “Personnel IS-Effort Collection in Industrial Environments”. In &lt;em&gt;9th International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Fevzi Belli, Farokh Bastani, and Albert Endres, 111-120. IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2669168</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-02T11:45:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>