<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2671727</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maria B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chiarolla</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4244291</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4291-6610</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we study a continuous time, optimal stochastic investment problem under limited resources in a market with N firms. The investment processes are subject to a time-dependent stochastic constraint. Rather than using a dynamic programming approach, we exploit the concavity of the profit functional to derive some necessary and sufficient first order conditions for the corresponding Social Planner optimal policy. Our conditions are a stochastic infinite-dimensional generalization of the Kuhn-Tucker Theorem. As a subproduct we obtain an enlightening interpretation of the first order conditions for a single firm in Bank [5].
In the infinite-horizon case, with operating profit functions of Cobb-Douglas type, our method allows the explicit calculation of the optimal policy in terms of the `base capacity'process, i.e. the unique solution of the Bank and El Karoui representation problem [4].</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_463.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2671727/2671728/IMW_working_paper_463.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>base capacity</topic><topic>Lagrange multiplier optional measure</topic><topic>stochastic irreversible investment</topic><topic>the Bank and El KarouiRepresentation Theorem</topic><topic>optimal stopping</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26717275</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>463</number></detail><extent unit="pages">25</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Chiarolla, M. B.; Ferrari, G.; Riedel, F. (2012): Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Chiarolla, M. B., Ferrari, G., and Riedel, F. (2012). Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 463, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Chiarolla, Maria B., Ferrari, Giorgio, and Riedel, Frank. &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 463.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chiarolla, M. B., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 463). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chiarolla, M.B., Ferrari, G. &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2012). &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Chiarolla MB, Ferrari G, Riedel F (2012)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 463.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<bio1>Chiarolla MB, Ferrari G, Riedel F (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 463.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M. B.  Chiarolla, G.  Ferrari, and F.  Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> M.B. Chiarolla, G. Ferrari, and F. Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 463,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012.</ieee>
<harvard1>Chiarolla, M.B., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Riedel, F., 2012. &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.463, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ama>Chiarolla MB, Ferrari G, Riedel F. &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 463. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2012.</ama>
<apa>Chiarolla, M. B., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 463). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<lncs> Chiarolla, M.B., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F.: Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 463. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chiarolla, Maria B., Ferrari, Giorgio, and Riedel, Frank. 2012. &lt;em&gt;Generalized Kuhn–Tucker conditions for N-Firm stochastic irreversible investment under limited resources&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 463. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2671727</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-15T13:16:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>