<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2671737</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dieter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Balkenborg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hofbauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuzmics</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23538564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2732-2838</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper provides an in-depth study of the (most) refined best reply correspondence introduced by Balkenborg, Hofbauer, and Kuzmics (2012). An example demonstrates that this correspondence can be very different from the standard best reply correspondence. In two-player games, however, the refined best reply correspondence of a given game is the same as the best reply correspondence of a slightly modified game. The 
modified game is derived from the original game by reducing the payoff by a small amount for all pure strategies that are weakly inferior. Weakly inferior strategies, for two-player games, are pure strategies that are either weakly dominated or are equivalent to a proper mixture of other pure strategies. Fixed points of the 
refined best reply correspondence are not equivalent to any known Nash equilibrium refinement. A class of simple communication games demonstrates the usefulness and intuitive appeal of the refined best reply correspondence.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_466.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2671737/2671738/IMW_working_paper_466.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>strict and weak dominance</topic><topic>strategic stability</topic><topic>Nash equilibrium refinements</topic><topic>best-response correspondence</topic><topic>persistent equilibria</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26717370</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>466</number></detail><extent unit="pages">21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J., Kuzmics, C.: The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 466. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Balkenborg, Dieter, Hofbauer, Josef, and Kuzmics, Christoph. 2012. &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 466. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Balkenborg D, Hofbauer J, Kuzmics C. &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 466. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2012.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Balkenborg, J.  Hofbauer, and C.  Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Balkenborg D, Hofbauer J, Kuzmics C (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 466.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J. &amp;amp; Kuzmics, C. (2012). &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J., &amp;amp; Kuzmics, C. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 466). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<harvard1>Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J., &amp;amp; Kuzmics, C., 2012. &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.466, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Balkenborg, J. Hofbauer, and C. Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 466,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012.</ieee>
<default>Balkenborg D, Hofbauer J, Kuzmics C (2012)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 466.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J., &amp;amp; Kuzmics, C. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 466). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Balkenborg, Dieter, Hofbauer, Josef, and Kuzmics, Christoph. &lt;em&gt;The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 466.</mla>
<frontiers>Balkenborg, D., Hofbauer, J., and Kuzmics, C. (2012). The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 466, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Balkenborg, D.; Hofbauer, J.; Kuzmics, C. (2012): The refined best-response correspondence in normal form games. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2671737</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-15T13:48:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>