<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2671761</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Niko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Noeske</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We analyze indirect evolutionary two-player games to identify the dynamic emergence
of (strong) reciprocity in a large number of economic settings. The underlying evolutionary
environment allows for an arbitrary initial population state provided that
every degree of the compact space of reciprocity is adherent to at least one individual
of the corresponding continuum population. The basic results, which essentially
maintain the evolutionary viability of reciprocity, are, in several directions, context
dependent, and minimum valid for the wide class of evolutionary dynamics which
hold for regularity and payoff-monotonicity. The evolutionary solution concept which
is applied to elevate the explanatory power of emerging Nash equilibria is dominance
solvability, in this case, for continuous strategy spaces. An asymmetric aspect comes
into play since the actions of the evolutionary players are not only determined by the
current state of reciprocity but also by their inherent, context-free preferences towards
others which differ among one another devoid of being endogenized in the time span
of the dynamic process at hand.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_446.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2671761/2900051/IMW_working_paper_446.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Reciprocity</topic><topic>Evolutionary Game Theory</topic><topic>Dominance Solvability</topic><topic>Asymmetric Game Setting</topic><topic>Payoff-monotonic Dynamics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26717616</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>446</number></detail><extent unit="pages">31</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Noeske, N., 2011. &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.446, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Noeske, &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 446,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011.</ieee>
<apa>Noeske, N. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 446). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<wels>Noeske, N. (2011): A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<mla>Noeske, Niko. &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 446.</mla>
<frontiers>Noeske, N. (2011). A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 446, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Noeske, N. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 446). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Noeske N (2011)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 446.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ama>Noeske N. &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 446. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2011.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Noeske, Niko. 2011. &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 446. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Noeske, N.: A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 446. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Noeske, N. (2011). &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Noeske, &lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Noeske N (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A dynamic model of reciprocity with asymmetric equilibrium payoffs&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 446.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2671761</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-15T14:19:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>