<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2673554</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptive distance measures for sequential data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bassam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mokbel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18880650</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paaßen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49941564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3899-2450</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michel</namePart><namePart type="family">Verleysen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Recent extensions of learning vector quantization (LVQ) to general (dis-)similarity data have paved the way towards LVQ classifiers for possibly discrete, structured objects such as sequences addressed by classical alignment. In this contribution, we propose a metric learning scheme based on this framework which allows for autonomous learning of the underlying scoring matrix according to a given discriminative task. Besides facilitating the often crucial and problematic choice of the scoring matrix in applications, this extension offers an increased interpretability of the results by pointing out structural invariances for the given task.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MokbelEtAl2014-ESANN2014-AdaptiveAlignmentGLVQ.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2673554/2712748/MokbelEtAl2014-ESANN2014-AdaptiveAlignmentGLVQ.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>i6doc.com</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bruges, Belgium</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>learning vector quantization</topic><topic>sequence alignment</topic><topic>dissimilarity data</topic><topic>metric adaptation</topic><topic>metric learning</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">9782874190957</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26735541</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">265-270</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, Bassam, Paaßen, Benjamin, and Hammer, Barbara. 2014. “Adaptive distance measures for sequential data”. In &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michel Verleysen, 265-270. Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B., Hammer, B.: Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In: Verleysen, M. (ed.) ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. p. 265-270. i6doc.com, Bruges, Belgium (2014).</lncs>
<default>Mokbel B, Paaßen B, Hammer B (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed);  Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com:  265-270.</default>
<mla>Mokbel, Bassam, Paaßen, Benjamin, and Hammer, Barbara. “Adaptive distance measures for sequential data”. &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michel Verleysen. Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com, 2014. 265-270.</mla>
<wels>Mokbel, B.; Paaßen, B.; Hammer, B. (2014): Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In: Michel Verleysen (Hrsg.):  ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com.  S. 265-270.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Mokbel, B.  Paaßen, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Verleysen), I6Doc.com, Bruges, Belgium, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 265-270.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2014). Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 265-270). Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Mokbel B, Paaßen B, Hammer B (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed); Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com:  265-270.</bio1>
<harvard1>Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2014. Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In M.  Verleysen, ed. &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;.  Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com, pp. 265-270.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B., and Hammer, B. (2014). “Adaptive distance measures for sequential data” in &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, Verleysen, M. ed. (Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com), 265-270.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2014). Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In M. Verleysen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (S. 265-270). Gehalten auf der European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN), Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Mokbel B, Paaßen B, Hammer B. Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In: Verleysen M, ed. &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com;  2014: 265-270.</ama>
<ieee> B. Mokbel, B. Paaßen, and B. Hammer, “Adaptive distance measures for sequential data”, &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, M. Verleysen, ed.,  Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com, 2014,  pp.265-270.</ieee>
<apa>Mokbel, B., Paaßen, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2014). Adaptive distance measures for sequential data. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;ESANN, 22nd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 265-270). Bruges, Belgium: i6doc.com.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2673554</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-28T08:16:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>