<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2674096</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moehlmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18044938</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Agnieszka</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rusinowska</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emily</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tanimura</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We develop a modification of the connections model by Jackson and Wolinsky (1996)that takes into account negative externalities arising from the connectivity of direct and indirect neighbors, thus combining aspects of the connections model and the co-author model. We consider
a general functional form for agents’ utility that incorporates both the effects of distance and of
neighbors’ degree. Consequently, we introduce a framework that can be seen as a degree-distancebased
connections model with both negative and positive externalities. Our analysis shows how the introduction of negative externalities modifies certain results about stability and efficiency compared to the original connections model. In particular, we see the emergence of new stable structures, such as a star with links between peripheral nodes. We also identify structures, for
example, certain disconnected networks, that are efficient in our model but which could not be efficient in the original connections model. While our results are proved for the general utility function, some of them are illustrated by using a specific functional form of the degree-distancebased utility.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_479.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2674096/2901850/IMW_working_paper_479.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>efficiency</topic><topic>pairwise stability</topic><topic>positive externalities</topic><topic>negative externalities</topic><topic>distance</topic><topic>degree</topic><topic>connections model</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26740969</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>479</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Moehlmeier, A.  Rusinowska, and E.  Tanimura, &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A., &amp;amp; Tanimura, E. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 479). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A., &amp;amp; Tanimura, E., 2013. &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.479, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Moehlmeier P, Rusinowska A, Tanimura E (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 479.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<wels>Moehlmeier, P.; Rusinowska, A.; Tanimura, E. (2013): A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<ieee> P. Moehlmeier, A. Rusinowska, and E. Tanimura, &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 479,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<default>Moehlmeier P, Rusinowska A, Tanimura E (2013)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 479.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Moehlmeier, Philipp, Rusinowska, Agnieszka, and Tanimura, Emily. &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2013. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 479.</mla>
<apa>Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A., &amp;amp; Tanimura, E. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 479). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A., and Tanimura, E. (2013). A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 479, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A. &amp;amp; Tanimura, E. (2013). &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Moehlmeier, Philipp, Rusinowska, Agnieszka, and Tanimura, Emily. 2013. &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 479. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Moehlmeier P, Rusinowska A, Tanimura E. &lt;em&gt;A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 479. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2013.</ama>
<lncs> Moehlmeier, P., Rusinowska, A., Tanimura, E.: A degree-distance-based connections model with negative and positive externalities. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 479. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2674096</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-30T09:26:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>