<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2674626</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fröhlich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5107215</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Randall</namePart><namePart type="family">Shumaker</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In order to make a significant step towards more realistic virtual experiences, we created a multi-sensory stimuli display for a CAVE-like environment. It comprises graphics, sound, tactile feedback, wind and warmth. In the present report we discuss the possibilities and constraints tied to such an enhancement. To use a multi-modal display in a proper way, many considerations have to be taken into account. This includes safety requirements, hardware devices and software integration. For each stimulus different possibilities are reviewed with regard to their assets and drawbacks. Eventually the resulting setup realized in our lab is described – to our knowledge one of the most comprehensive systems. Technical evaluations as well as user studies accompanied the development and gave hints with respect to necessities and chances.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="_Pre-Print_HCII2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2674626/2683934/_Pre-Print_HCII2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing Switzerland</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Virtual Reality</topic><topic>Wind</topic><topic>Warmth</topic><topic>Presence</topic><topic>Multi-Sensory Stimuli</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-07457-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26746261</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-07458-0_5</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8525</number></detail><extent unit="pages">44-54</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Fröhlich, J., Wachsmuth, I.: Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In: Shumaker, R. (ed.) Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8525, p. 44-54. Springer International Publishing Switzerland, Cham (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, Julia, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2014. “Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report”. In &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Randall Shumaker, 8525:44-54. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Fröhlich, Julia, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report”. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Randall Shumaker. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, 2014.Vol. 8525. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 44-54.</mla>
<default>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Shumaker R (Ed);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8525.  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland:  44-54.</default>
<ama>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I. Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In: Shumaker R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8525. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland;  2014: 44-54.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, J. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In R. Shumaker (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (S. 44-54). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07458-0_5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Fröhlich, J., and Wachsmuth, I. (2014). “Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report” in &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, Shumaker, R. ed. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8525, (Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland), 44-54.</frontiers>
<apa>Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In R.  Shumaker (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8525&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 44-54). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07458-0_5</apa>
<ieee> J. Fröhlich and I. Wachsmuth, “Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report”, &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;, R. Shumaker, ed., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8525,  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, 2014,  pp.44-54.</ieee>
<wels>Fröhlich, J.; Wachsmuth, I. (2014): Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In: Randall Shumaker (Hrsg.):  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8525).  S. 44-54.</wels>
<bio1>Fröhlich J, Wachsmuth I (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments. Shumaker R (Ed); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8525. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland:  44-54.</bio1>
<harvard1>Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2014. Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In R.  Shumaker, ed. &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8525  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, pp. 44-54.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fröhlich, J., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Combining multi-sensory stimuli in virtual worlds - a progress report. In R.  Shumaker (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8525&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 44-54). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07458-0_5&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Fröhlich, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Virtual Augmented and Mixed Reality. Designing and Developing Augmented and Virtual Environments&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Shumaker), Springer International Publishing Switzerland, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 44-54.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2674626</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-05-02T09:39:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>