<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2674034</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we derive a new handy integral equation for the free boundary of infinite time horizon, continuous time, stochastic, irreversible investment problems with uncertainty modeled as a one-dimensional, regular diffusion X0;x. The new integral equation allows to explicitly find the free boundary b(.) in some so far unsolved cases, as when X0;x is a three-dimensional Bessel process or a CEV process. Our result follows from purely probabilistic
arguments. Indeed, we first show that b(X0;x(t)) = l*(t), with l*(t) unique optional solution of a representation problem in the spirit of Bank-El Karoui [4]; then, thanks to such identification and the fact that l* uniquely solves a backward stochastic equation, we find the integral problem for the free boundary.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_471.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2674034/2674035/IMW_working_paper_471.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>free boundary</topic><topic>irreversible investment</topic><topic>integral equation</topic><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>Bank and El Karoui's Representation Theorem</topic><topic>one-dimensional diusion</topic><topic>optimal stopping</topic><topic>base capacity.</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26740341</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>471</number></detail><extent unit="pages">20</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, Giorgio. 2012. &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 471. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ferrari, G.: On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 471. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2012).</lncs>
<default>Ferrari G (2012)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 471.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Ferrari, Giorgio. &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 471.</mla>
<frontiers>Ferrari, G. (2012). On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 471, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G. (2012). &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ferrari G. &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 471. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2012.</ama>
<ieee> G. Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 471,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2012.</ieee>
<apa>Ferrari, G. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 471). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<wels>Ferrari, G. (2012): On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G. (2012).  &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 471). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Ferrari, G., 2012. &lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.471, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ferrari G (2012) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On an integral equation for the free boundary of stochastic, irreversible investment problems&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 471.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2674034</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-04-29T12:08:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>