<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2675338</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böhm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">80680</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Claas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17867857</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper analyzes the implications of right-to-manage wage bargaining between a producers' syndicate and a workers' union representing finite numbers of identical members in a monetary macroconomic model of the AS-AD type with government activity. At given prices and price expectations, nominal wages are set according to a Nash bargaining agreement. Producers then choose labor demand and commodity supply to maximize profits at given output prices. The commodity market clears in a competitive fashion. Unique temporary equilibria are shown to exist for each level of relative power of the union. These equilibria may exhibit under- or overemployment, depending on the level of union power.
The paper presents a complete comparative-statics analysis of the temporary equilibrium, in particular of the role of union power on employment, wages, and income distribution, including a variety of different qualitative features compared to the situation under efficient bargaining. These differences arise primarily from a supply-side effect of union power under the right-to-manage approach as compared to a demand-side effect under efficient bargaining.
In addition, the dynamic evolution under perfect foresight is monotonic with two co-existing balanced steady states, one of which is stable under certain conditions. These
properties are qualitatively identical to those under efficient bargaining or under perfect competition.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_502.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2675338/2901869/IMW_working_paper_502.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Collective Bargaining</topic><topic>Nash Bargaining</topic><topic>Union Power</topic><topic>Aggregate Supply-Aggregate Demand</topic><topic>Government Deficits</topic><topic>Perfect Foresight</topic><topic>Dynamics</topic><topic>Stability</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26753389</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>502</number></detail><extent unit="pages">35</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Claas, O. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 502). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Böhm, Volker, and Claas, Oliver. &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 502.</mla>
<frontiers>Böhm, V., and Claas, O. (2014). Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 502, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Böhm, V.; Claas, O. (2014): Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Böhm V, Claas O (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 502.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Claas, O., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.502, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> V. Böhm and O. Claas, &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 502,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Böhm, V., &amp;amp; Claas, O. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 502). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, V. &amp;amp; Claas, O. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Böhm, and O.  Claas, &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Böhm V, Claas O (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 502.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Böhm V, Claas O. &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 502. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böhm, Volker, and Claas, Oliver. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 502. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Böhm, V., Claas, O.: Wage Bargaining, Employment, and Union Power: The Right-to-Manage Approach. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 502. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2675338</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-05-08T13:41:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>