<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2675066</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stefanini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Chiara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bartolozzi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giacomo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Indiveri</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Several analog and digital brain-inspired electronic systems have been recently proposed as dedicated solutions for fast simulations of spiking neural networks. While these architectures are useful for exploring the computational properties of large-scale models of the nervous system, the challenge of building low-power compact physical artifacts that can behave intelligently in the real world and exhibit cognitive abilities still remains open. In this paper, we propose a set of neuromorphic engineering solutions to address this challenge. In particular, we review neuromorphic circuits for emulating neural and synaptic dynamics in real time and discuss the role of biophysically realistic temporal dynamics in hardware neural processing architectures; we review the challenges of realizing spike-based plasticity mechanisms in real physical systems and present examples of analog electronic circuits that implement them; we describe the computational properties of recurrent neural networks and show how neuromorphic winner-take-all circuits can implement working-memory and decision-making mechanisms. We validate the neuromorphic approach proposed with experimental results obtained from our own circuits and systems, and argue how the circuits and networks presented in this work represent a useful set of components for efficiently and elegantly implementing neuromorphic cognition.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1403.6428v1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2675066/2675068/1403.6428v1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Chicca_etal14b.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2675066/2934808/Chicca_etal14b.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess"/>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Cognitive systemslearning systemsneuromorphic engineeringreal-time neuromorphic systemsspike-timing-dependent plasticity (STDP)spiking neural network architecturesubthreshold analog circuitsvery large-scale integration (VLSI)winner-take-all (WTA)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the IEEE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0018-9219</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1558-2256</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000344481800008</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26750665</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2014.2313954</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>102</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>9</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1367-1388</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Chicca E, Stefanini F, Bartolozzi C, Indiveri G (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the IEEE. Proceedings of the IEEE, 102(9).  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  1367-1388.</default>
<mla>Chicca, Elisabetta, Stefanini, Fabio, Bartolozzi, Chiara, and Indiveri, Giacomo. “Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2014.Vol. 102. Proceedings of the IEEE. 1367-1388.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chicca, Elisabetta, Stefanini, Fabio, Bartolozzi, Chiara, and Indiveri, Giacomo. 2014. “Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;, 102:1367-1388. Proceedings of the IEEE. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C., Indiveri, G.: Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. Proceedings of the IEEE. Proceedings of the IEEE. 102, p. 1367-1388. IEEE, Piscataway, NJ (2014).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Chicca, F.  Stefanini, C.  Bartolozzi, and G.  Indiveri, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Piscataway, NJ, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1367-1388.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2014). Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the IEEE, &lt;em&gt;102&lt;/em&gt;, 1367-1388. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/JPROC.2014.2313954&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Chicca E, Stefanini F, Bartolozzi C, Indiveri G (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the IEEE.  Proceedings of the IEEE, 102. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  1367-1388.</bio1>
<harvard1>Chicca, E., et al., 2014. Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of the IEEE. no.102  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, pp. 1367-1388.</harvard1>
<wels>Chicca, E.; Stefanini, F.; Bartolozzi, C.; Indiveri, G. (2014): Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. In: Proceedings of the IEEE. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. (Proceedings of the IEEE, 102).  S. 1367-1388.</wels>
<ieee> E. Chicca, et al., “Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the IEEE, vol. 102,  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2014,  pp.1367-1388.</ieee>
<apa>Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C., &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2014). Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the IEEE, &lt;em&gt;102&lt;/em&gt;, 1367-1388. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/JPROC.2014.2313954</apa>
<frontiers>Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C., and Indiveri, G. (2014). “Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of the IEEE, vol. 102, (Piscataway, NJ: IEEE), 1367-1388.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C. &amp;amp; Indiveri, G. (2014). Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems (Proceedings of the IEEE). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1367-1388). Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/JPROC.2014.2313954.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Chicca E, Stefanini F, Bartolozzi C, Indiveri G. Neuromorphic Electronic Circuits for Building Autonomous Cognitive Systems. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the IEEE&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of the IEEE. Vol 102. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE;  2014: 1367-1388.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2675066</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-05-06T11:33:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-25T07:52:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>