<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2675090</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ullrich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11741747</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roland</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kern</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22116</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7258-9956</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Egelhaaf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">156194</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9336-4270</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684834</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The responses of visual interneurons of flies involved in the processing of motion information do not only depend on the velocity, but also on other stimulus parameters, such as the contrast and the spatial frequency content of the stimulus pattern. These dependencies have been known for long, but it is still an open question how they affect the neurons’ performance in extracting information about the structure of the environment under the specific dynamical conditions of natural flight. Free-flight of blowflies is characterized by sequences of phases of translational movements lasting for just 30–100 ms interspersed with even shorter and extremely rapid saccade-like rotational shifts in flight and gaze direction. Previous studies already analyzed how nearby objects, leading to relative motion on the retina with respect to a more distant background, influenced the response of a class of fly motion sensitive visual interneurons, the horizontal system (HS) cells. In the present study, we focused on objects that differed from their background by discontinuities either in their brightness contrast or in their spatial frequency content. We found strong object-induced effects on the membrane potential even during the short intersaccadic intervals, if the background contrast was small and the object contrast sufficiently high. The object evoked similar response increments provided that it contained higher spatial frequencies than the background, but not under reversed conditions. This asymmetry in the response behavior is partly a consequence of the depolarization level induced by the background. Thus, our results suggest that, under the specific dynamical conditions of natural flight, i.e., on a very short timescale, the responses of HS cells represent object information depending on the polarity of the difference between object and background contrast and spatial frequency content.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fnint-08-00034.ullrich.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2675090/2675095/fnint-08-00034.ullrich.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1662-5145</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1662-5145</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24808836</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26750901</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fnint.2014.00034</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><extent unit="pages">34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Ullrich, R.  Kern, and M.  Egelhaaf, “Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 34.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ullrich T, Kern R, Egelhaaf M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience 8: 34.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ullrich, T., Kern, R., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (2014). Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 34. doi:10.3389/fnint.2014.00034&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Ullrich, T., Kern, R., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M., 2014. Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 8, p 34.</harvard1>
<wels>Ullrich, T.; Kern, R.; Egelhaaf, M. (2014): Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,8: 34.</wels>
<ieee> T. Ullrich, R. Kern, and M. Egelhaaf, “Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2014,  pp. 34.</ieee>
<apa>Ullrich, T., Kern, R., &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (2014). Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 34. doi:10.3389/fnint.2014.00034</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ullrich, T., Kern, R. &amp;amp; Egelhaaf, M. (2014). Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 34. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fnint.2014.00034.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Ullrich, T., Kern, R., and Egelhaaf, M. (2014). Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 8, 34.</frontiers>
<ama>Ullrich T, Kern R, Egelhaaf M. Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;8:34.</ama>
<default>Ullrich T, Kern R, Egelhaaf M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 8: 34.</default>
<mla>Ullrich, Thomas, Kern, Roland, and Egelhaaf, Martin. “Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 8 (2014): 34.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ullrich, Thomas, Kern, Roland, and Egelhaaf, Martin. 2014. “Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 8: 34.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ullrich, T., Kern, R., Egelhaaf, M.: Texture-defined objects influence responses of blowfly motion-sensitive neurons under natural dynamical conditions. Frontiers in Integrative Neuroscience. 8, 34 (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2675090</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-05-06T13:18:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:25:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>