<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2675336</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuzmics</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23538564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2732-2838</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Motivated by trying to better understand the norms that govern pedestrian traffic, I study symmetric two-player coordination games with independent private values. The strategies of "always pass on the left" and "always pass on the right" are always equilibria of this game. Some such games, however, also have other (pure strategy)equilibria with a positive likelihood of mis-coordination. Perhaps surprisingly, in some such games, these Pareto-inefficient equilibria, with a positive likelihood of mis-coordination, are the only evolutionarily stable equilibria of the game.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_501.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2675336/2901868/IMW_working_paper_501.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>evolutionary stability</topic><topic>best-response dynamics</topic><topic>CSS</topic><topic>incomplete information</topic><topic>continuously stable strategy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26753365</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>501</number></detail><extent unit="pages">17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, C. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kuzmics C (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 501.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Kuzmics C. &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 501. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, Christoph. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 501. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kuzmics, C.: Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 501. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<mla>Kuzmics, Christoph. &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 501.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 501). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kuzmics, C. (2014). Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 501, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Kuzmics, C. (2014): Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Kuzmics C (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 501.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Kuzmics, C., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.501, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 501,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Kuzmics, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Coordination with independent private values: why pedestrians sometimes bump into each other&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 501). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2675336</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-05-08T13:34:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>