<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2678800</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Magdalena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kröber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23918556</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wibberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19653681</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rita</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grosch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix Gregor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eikmeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19753357</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1623-172X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bart</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Verwaaijen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41577028</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soumitra P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chowdhury</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21937</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4723-2960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlüter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55545</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4830-310X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Application of the plant associated bacterium Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on lettuce (Lactuca sativa) confirmed its capability to promote plant growth and health by reducing disease severity (DS) caused by the phytopathogenic fungus Rhizoctonia solani. Therefore this strain is commercially applied as an eco-friendly plant protective agent. It is able to produce cyclic lipopeptides (CLP) and polyketides featuring antifungal and antibacterial properties. Production of these secondary metabolites led to the question of a possible impact of strain FZB42 on the composition of microbial rhizosphere communities after its application. Rating of DS and lettuce growth during a field trial confirmed the positive impact of strain FZB42 on the health of the host plant. To verify B. amyloliquefaciens as an environmentally compatible plant protective agent, its effect on the indigenous rhizosphere community was analyzed by metagenome sequencing. Rhizosphere microbial communities of lettuce treated with B. amyloliquefaciens FZB42 and non-treated plants were profiled by high-throughput metagenome sequencing of whole community DNA. Fragment recruitments of metagenome sequence reads on the genome sequence of B. amyloliquefaciens FZB42 proved the presence of the strain in the rhizosphere over 5 weeks of the field trial. Comparison of taxonomic community profiles only revealed marginal changes after application of strain FZB42. The orders Burkholderiales, Actinomycetales and Rhizobiales were most abundant in all samples. Depending on plant age a general shift within the composition of the microbial communities that was independent of the application of strain FZB42 was observed. In addition to the taxonomic profiling, functional analysis of annotated sequences revealed no major differences between samples regarding application of the inoculant strain.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fmicb-05-00252.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2678800/2678820/fmicb-05-00252.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>taxonomic profiling</topic><topic>fragment recruitment</topic><topic>B. amyloliquefaciens FZB42</topic><topic>rhizosphere</topic><topic>lettuce</topic><topic>metagenome sequencing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Microbiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-302x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-302X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24904564</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000336663500002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26788009</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2014.00252</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Kröber, M., et al., 2014. Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, 5: 252.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Kröber, et al., “Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 5, 2014, : 252.</ieee>
<apa>Kröber, M., Wibberg, D., Grosch, R., Eikmeyer, F. G., Verwaaijen, B., Chowdhury, S. P., Hartmann, A., et al. (2014). Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 252. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2014.00252</apa>
<mla>Kröber, Magdalena, Wibberg, Daniel, Grosch, Rita, Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Verwaaijen, Bart, Chowdhury, Soumitra P., Hartmann, Anton, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. “Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 5 (2014): 252.</mla>
<frontiers>Kröber, M., Wibberg, D., Grosch, R., Eikmeyer, F. G., Verwaaijen, B., Chowdhury, S. P., Hartmann, A., Pühler, A., and Schlüter, A. (2014). Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 5:252.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kröber, M., Wibberg, D., Grosch, R., Eikmeyer, F. G., Verwaaijen, B., Chowdhury, S. P., Hartmann, A., et al. (2014). Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 252. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2014.00252&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kröber, M.; Wibberg, D.; Grosch, R.; Eikmeyer, F. G.; Verwaaijen, B.; Chowdhury, S. P.; Hartmann, A.; Pühler, A.; Schlüter, A. (2014): Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,5:252</wels>
<default>Kröber M, Wibberg D, Grosch R, Eikmeyer FG, Verwaaijen B, Chowdhury SP, Hartmann A, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 5: 252.</default>
<ama>Kröber M, Wibberg D, Grosch R, et al. Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;5: 252.</ama>
<lncs> Kröber, M., Wibberg, D., Grosch, R., Eikmeyer, F.G., Verwaaijen, B., Chowdhury, S.P., Hartmann, A., Pühler, A., Schlüter, A.: Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. Frontiers in Microbiology. 5, : 252 (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kröber, Magdalena, Wibberg, Daniel, Grosch, Rita, Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Verwaaijen, Bart, Chowdhury, Soumitra P., Hartmann, Anton, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. 2014. “Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 5: 252.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kröber, M., Wibberg, D., Grosch, R., Eikmeyer, F.G., Verwaaijen, B., Chowdhury, S.P., Hartmann, A., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2014). Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;: 252. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2014.00252.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Kröber, D.  Wibberg, R.  Grosch, F. G.  Eikmeyer, B.  Verwaaijen, S. P.  Chowdhury, A.  Hartmann, A.  Pühler, and A.  Schlüter, “Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, : 252.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kröber M, Wibberg D, Grosch R, Eikmeyer FG, Verwaaijen B, Chowdhury SP, Hartmann A, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Effect of the strain Bacillus amyloliquefaciens FZB42 on the microbial community in the rhizosphere of lettuce under field conditions analyzed by whole metagenome sequencing.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology 5: 252.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2678800</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-05T14:03:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>