<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2678631</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Campus Management Systems as Administrative Software Systems</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spitta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41186</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grechenig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Henning</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brune</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10185</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marco</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Carolla</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Strobl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="ger">Ein von der Politik ausgelöster Bruch in den deutsprachigen Ländern – der sog. Bologna Prozess –
löste eine große Nachfrage nach neuen Informationssystemen aus, die die akademischen Prozesse
Lehre und Forschung unterstützen konnten. Die Software ist in der notwendigen Qualität am Markt
nicht verfügbar. Einige Systeme sind große Pilotprojekte in Universitäten, die die Rolle von Pionieren
spielen. Weil die Universitäten – im Gegensatz zu Wirtschaftsunternehmen – wenig Erfahrung
mit solchen Projekten und dem Systembetrieb haben, erscheint es hilfreich, die wesentlichen
Eigenschaften organisatorischer Informationssysteme grundsätzlich zu betrachten. Nach
Lehmanns Definition vor 35 Jahren über Embedded Software haben wir es mit sehr komplexen und
großen Systemen zu tun, die in eine Organisation als Umwelt eingebettet sind. Die Komplexität
dieser Systeme liegt in der Datenbasis, die von den Benutzern erzeugt und gepflegt wird. Wir
diskutieren aus der Sicht dieser originären Daten, welche Funktionen zum Kern eines Campus-
Management Systems (CaMS) gehören und welche nicht. Z. B. gehören E-Learning und Bibliothek
nicht dazu, benötigen allerdings sichere und effiziente Schnittstellen. Weil CaMS groß und
teuer sind, sollten sie evolutionär in die Organisation implementiert werden.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Caused by a politically initiated break in German speaking European countries – the so-called Bologna
Process – we observe a huge demand for new information systems supporting the academic
processes of teaching and research. The software qualitatively demanded is not available on the
market. Some systems are large projects of pilot-systems in pioneer universities. Because universities
– in contrast to enterprises – have little experience in implementing and operating such systems,
it seems to be worth while to examine the essentials of organizational information systems basically.
After Lehman's definition of embedded systems 35 years ago, we look at very complex systems,
embedded into large organizations. The complexity of such system's software stems from its
database, created and maintained by the the organization's users. We argue, from our basic view at
original data, which functions are part of the core of a campus management system (CaMS) and
which are not. E. g. E-learning or library do not belong to this core, but need secure and efficient
interfaces to it. Because CaMS are large and expensive they should be implemented into an organization
evolutionary.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_06_2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2678631/2915489/wpaper_06_2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Campus-Management</topic><topic>Administrative Software</topic><topic>Konzeptuelles Datenmodell</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26786313</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2678631</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>06-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> T. Spitta, et al., &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management, vol. 06-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Spitta, T., Grechenig, T., Brune, H., Carolla, M., &amp;amp; Strobl, S. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management, 06-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2678631</apa>
<frontiers>Spitta, T., Grechenig, T., Brune, H., Carolla, M., and Strobl, S. (2014). Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management&lt;/em&gt;, 06-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, T., Grechenig, T., Brune, H., Carolla, M. &amp;amp; Strobl, S. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2678631.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Spitta T, Grechenig T, Brune H, Carolla M, Strobl S. &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management. Vol 06-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Spitta, T.  Grechenig, H.  Brune, M.  Carolla, and S.  Strobl, &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Spitta, T., et al., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management, no.06-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Spitta T, Grechenig T, Brune H, Carolla M, Strobl S (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management; 06-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, T., Grechenig, T., Brune, H., Carolla, M., &amp;amp; Strobl, S. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management, 06-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2678631&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Spitta, T.; Grechenig, T.; Brune, H.; Carolla, M.; Strobl, S. (2014): Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Spitta T, Grechenig T, Brune H, Carolla M, Strobl S (2014)  Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management; 06-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Spitta, Thorsten, Grechenig, Thomas, Brune, Henning, Carolla, Marco, and Strobl, Stefan. &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management. 06-2014.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Spitta, Thorsten, Grechenig, Thomas, Brune, Henning, Carolla, Marco, and Strobl, Stefan. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 06-2014. Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Spitta, T., Grechenig, T., Brune, H., Carolla, M., Strobl, S.: Campus-Management Systeme als Administrative Systeme. Working Papers in Economics &amp;amp; Management, 06-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2678631</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-04T14:32:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>