<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2680318</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Björn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Andernach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49877273</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schunck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17575160</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688499</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Factorial surveys are a common method for studying social norms, attitudes, and hypothetical decision situations in the social sciences. Although they are usually applied in interview settings which allow for a visual representation of the factorial survey, they are also regularly used in computer assisted telephone interviews (CATI). However, we know little about the applicability of a factorial survey in an interview mode that does not allow for a visual presentation of the factorial survey. This paper investigates potential problems that may arise in implementing a factorial survey in a CATI by investigating how respondents of different age and educational backgrounds deal with factorial surveys of different degrees of complexity. To asses potential problems we rely on respondents’ self-reported response difficulties, a measure of response latency, and response consistency. We do not find that older respondents are experiencing or reporting more difficulties in processing the factorial survey. Respondents with higher levels education appear to produce more consistent responses.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0028_Andernach_Schunck.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2680318/2680322/SFB_882_WP_0028_Andernach_Schunck.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>age</topic><topic>response consistency</topic><topic>education</topic><topic>response latency</topic><topic>telephone interviews</topic><topic>vignettes</topic><topic>factorial survey</topic><topic>CATI</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26803182</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>28</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Andernach B, Schunck R (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 28.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Andernach, B., &amp;amp; Schunck, R. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 28). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Andernach, Björn, and Schunck, Reinhard. &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 28.</mla>
<frontiers>Andernach, B., and Schunck, R. (2014). Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 28, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Andernach, B.; Schunck, R. (2014): Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<apa>Andernach, B., &amp;amp; Schunck, R. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 28). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<harvard1>Andernach, B., &amp;amp; Schunck, R., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.28, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Andernach and R. Schunck, &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 28,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Andernach, and R.  Schunck, &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Andernach B, Schunck R (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 28.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Andernach, B. &amp;amp; Schunck, R. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Andernach, Björn, and Schunck, Reinhard. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 28. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Andernach, B., Schunck, R.: Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 28. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<ama>Andernach B, Schunck R. &lt;em&gt;Investigating the feasibility of a factorial survey in a CATI&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 28. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2680318</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-13T09:20:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>