<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2682029</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Caterina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rohde</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9424262</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Faist</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The au-pair migration programme was originally founded to support the exchange of cultures by arranging a one year sojourn of foreign young people in a local host family. Although recent publications assume that au-pair immigration is misused on the one hand by local households as employing low-wage domestic workers and on the other hand by au-pairs as a "springboard" to permanent settlement only very few migration research on this phenomenon has been carried out as of yet. Taking Russian au-pairs in Germany as an example, this research project explores the fundamental characteristics of the au-pair stay as a specific form of female migration. Based on the theoretical approach of transnationalisation, the au-pairs' act of migrating in order to fulfil life plans will be interpreted as a process of transnationalizing biographies. By employing methods of qualitative research the following research question will be raised on a micro level of analysis: What is the meaning and impact of au-pair migration in the life of young Russian women? Attention is paid to how statuspassages - the entry into work and partnership - execute in a biography of an au-pair migrant and how statuspassages relate to settlement in the host country, return to the home country, or above that foster the creation of transnational social spaces. Furthermore the involvement of macro level structures (especially immigration and employment regulations) and meso level structures (especially formal and informal networks and organizations) and their manifestations in individual biographies will be revealed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation-Rohde-Caterina-Au-pair-Migration.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2682029/2682032/Dissertation-Rohde-Caterina-Au-pair-Migration.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-26820293</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">215</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2013-05-02</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Rohde C. &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2013.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rohde, Caterina. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rohde, C.: Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rohde, C. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Rohde C (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Rohde, &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> C. Rohde, &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Rohde, C., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<apa>Rohde, C. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<wels>Rohde, C. (2013): Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<mla>Rohde, Caterina. &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2013.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rohde, C. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Rohde, C. (2013). Au-pair Migration: geographische und soziale Mobilität junger Frauen zwischen Russland und Deutschland. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<default>Rohde C (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2682029</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-23T12:44:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>