<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2683760</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paaßen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49941564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3899-2450</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stöckel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">80194247</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raphael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dickfelder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan Philip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Göpfert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27345942</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1982-9399</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nicole</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brazda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tarek</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kirchhoffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">37260489</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Diana</namePart><namePart type="family">Maynard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marieke</namePart><namePart type="family">Erp van</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Brian</namePart><namePart type="family">Davis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Preclinical research in the field of central nervous system trauma advances at a fast pace, currently yielding over 8,000 new publications per year, at an exponentially growing rate. This amount of published information by far exceeds the capacity of individual scientists to read and understand the relevant literature. So far, no clinical trial has led to therapeutic approaches which achieve functional recovery in human patients.
In this paper, we describe a first prototype of an ontology-based information extraction system that
automatically extracts relevant preclinical knowledge about spinal cord injury treatments from natural language text by recognizing participating entity classes and linking them to each other. The evaluation on an independent test corpus of manually annotated full text articles shows a macro-average F1 measure of 0.74 with precision 0.68 and recall 0.81 on the task of identifying entities participating in relations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paassen2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2683760/2683774/paassen2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>spinal cord injury</topic><topic>information extraction</topic><topic>ontologies</topic><topic>preclinical experiments</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26837609</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">25-32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Paaßen, B., Stöckel, A., Dickfelder, R., Göpfert, J.P., Brazda, N., Kirchhoffer, T., Müller, H.W., Klinger, R., Hartung, M., Cimiano, P.: Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In: Maynard, D., Erp van, M., and Davis, B. (eds.) Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING). p. 25-32. Dublin, Ireland (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, Benjamin, Stöckel, Andreas, Dickfelder, Raphael, Göpfert, Jan Philip, Brazda, Nicole, Kirchhoffer, Tarek, Müller, Hans Werner, Klinger, Roman, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2014. “Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments”. In &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Diana Maynard, Marieke Erp van, and Brian Davis, 25-32. Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Paaßen, Benjamin, Stöckel, Andreas, Dickfelder, Raphael, Göpfert, Jan Philip, Brazda, Nicole, Kirchhoffer, Tarek, Müller, Hans Werner, Klinger, Roman, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments”. &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Diana Maynard, Marieke Erp van, and Brian Davis. Dublin, Ireland, 2014. 25-32.</mla>
<default>Paaßen B, Stöckel A, Dickfelder R, Göpfert JP, Brazda N, Kirchhoffer T, Müller HW, Klinger R, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING). Maynard D, Erp van M, Davis B (Eds);  Dublin, Ireland:  25-32.</default>
<wels>Paaßen, B.; Stöckel, A.; Dickfelder, R.; Göpfert, J. P.; Brazda, N.; Kirchhoffer, T.; Müller, H. W.; Klinger, R.; Hartung, M.; Cimiano, P. (2014): Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In: Diana Maynard; Marieke Erp van; Brian Davis (Hrsg.):  Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING). Dublin, Ireland.  S. 25-32.</wels>
<bio1>Paaßen B, Stöckel A, Dickfelder R, Göpfert JP, Brazda N, Kirchhoffer T, Müller HW, Klinger R, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING). Maynard D, Erp van M, Davis B (Eds); Dublin, Ireland:  25-32.</bio1>
<harvard1>Paaßen, B., et al., 2014. Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In D.  Maynard, M.  Erp van, &amp;amp; B.  Davis, eds. &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;.  Dublin, Ireland, pp. 25-32.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Stöckel, A., Dickfelder, R., Göpfert, J. P., Brazda, N., Kirchhoffer, T., Müller, H. W., et al. (2014). Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In D.  Maynard, M.  Erp van, &amp;amp; B.  Davis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 25-32). Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Paaßen, A.  Stöckel, R.  Dickfelder, J. P.  Göpfert, N.  Brazda, T.  Kirchhoffer, H. W.  Müller, R.  Klinger, M.  Hartung, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Maynard, M. Erp van, B. Davis), Dublin, Ireland, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 25-32.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Paaßen B, Stöckel A, Dickfelder R, et al. Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In: Maynard D, Erp van M, Davis B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;. Dublin, Ireland;  2014: 25-32.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Stöckel, A., Dickfelder, R., Göpfert, J.P., Brazda, N., Kirchhoffer, T., Müller, H.W., Klinger, R., Hartung, M. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2014). Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In D. Maynard, M. Erp van &amp;amp; B. Davis (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 25-32). Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Paaßen, B., Stöckel, A., Dickfelder, R., Göpfert, J. P., Brazda, N., Kirchhoffer, T., Müller, H. W., Klinger, R., Hartung, M., and Cimiano, P. (2014). “Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments” in &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;, Maynard, D., Erp van, M., and Davis, B. eds. (Dublin, Ireland), 25-32.</frontiers>
<apa>Paaßen, B., Stöckel, A., Dickfelder, R., Göpfert, J. P., Brazda, N., Kirchhoffer, T., Müller, H. W., et al. (2014). Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments. In D.  Maynard, M.  Erp van, &amp;amp; B.  Davis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 25-32). Dublin, Ireland.</apa>
<ieee> B. Paaßen, et al., “Ontology-based Extraction of Structured Information from Publications on Preclinical Experiments for Spinal Cord Injury Treatments”, &lt;em&gt;Third Workshop on Semantic Web and Information Extraction (SWAIE). The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)&lt;/em&gt;, D. Maynard, M. Erp van, and B. Davis, eds.,  Dublin, Ireland: 2014,  pp.25-32.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2683760</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-07-03T09:46:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>