<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2683410</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nikita</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mattar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191149</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Masaaki</namePart><namePart type="family">Kurosu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Agents that are able to build relationships with the people they are interacting with are envisioned to be more successful in long-term interactions. Small talk about impersonal topics has been found an adequate tool in human-agent interactions for manipulation of such relationships. We suspect that an agent and the interaction with it will be evaluated even more positively when the agent talks about personal information it remembers about its interlocutor from previous encounters. In this paper a model of person memory that provides virtual agents with information needed in social conversations is presented. An interaction study demonstrates the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations and validates the performance of our model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2014_mattar_wachsmuth_lets_get_personal_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2683410/2708036/2014_mattar_wachsmuth_lets_get_personal_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>conversational agents</topic><topic>intelligent virtual agents</topic><topic>human-agent interaction</topic><topic>person memory</topic><topic>social conversations</topic><topic>interaction study</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-07229-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26834106</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-07230-2_43</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8511</number></detail><extent unit="pages">450-461</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Mattar, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Kurosu), Springer, Berlin [u.a.], &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 450-461.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Mattar, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 2014. Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In M.  Kurosu, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8511  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, pp. 450-461.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mattar, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In M.  Kurosu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8511&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 450-461). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07230-2_43&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Mattar N, Wachsmuth I (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques. Kurosu M (Ed); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8511. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer:  450-461.</bio1>
<wels>Mattar, N.; Wachsmuth, I. (2014): Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In: Masaaki Kurosu (Hrsg.):  Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8511).  S. 450-461.</wels>
<ieee> N. Mattar and I. Wachsmuth, “Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations”, &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;, M. Kurosu, ed., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8511,  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, 2014,  pp.450-461.</ieee>
<apa>Mattar, N., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In M.  Kurosu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8511&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 450-461). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07230-2_43</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mattar, N. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (2014). Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In M. Kurosu (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt; (S. 450-461). Berlin [u.a.]: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-07230-2_43.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Mattar, N., and Wachsmuth, I. (2014). “Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations” in &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;, Kurosu, M. ed. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8511, (Berlin [u.a.]: Springer), 450-461.</frontiers>
<ama>Mattar N, Wachsmuth I. Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In: Kurosu M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8511. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer;  2014: 450-461.</ama>
<default>Mattar N, Wachsmuth I (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques. Kurosu M (Ed);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8511.  Berlin [u.a.]: Springer:  450-461.</default>
<mla>Mattar, Nikita, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations”. &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Masaaki Kurosu. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer, 2014.Vol. 8511. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 450-461.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mattar, Nikita, and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2014. “Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations”. In &lt;em&gt;Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Masaaki Kurosu, 8511:450-461. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Mattar, N., Wachsmuth, I.: Let’s get personal: Assessing the impact of personal information in human-agent conversations. In: Kurosu, M. (ed.) Human-Computer Interaction. Advanced Interaction Modalities and Techniques. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8511, p. 450-461. Springer, Berlin [u.a.] (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2683410</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-30T11:54:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>