<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2684167</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harshawardhan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ramachandran</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31312636</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Syed Ahmed</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aamir</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabetta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chicca</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26461080</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5518-8990</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26824835</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present real-time neuromorphic VLSI circuits
that implement the synaptic dynamics of Short Term Plasticity
(STP). STP supports useful signal processing computational
primitives such as change detection and gain control. Compact
circuits implementing these mechanisms play a key role in
providing neuromorphic VLSI systems with autonomous adaptation
capabilities. We propose two different, flexible, short-term
adaptation CMOS circuits for controlling the efficacy of synapses
in response to incoming spikes. These circuits can be configured
to either implement short-term depression or facilitation, with
independent control over the adaptation and recovery rates.
Our results demonstrate the dynamic properties of the</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="iscas14_STD.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2684167/2684170/iscas14_STD.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ramachandran_etal14.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2684167/2934809/Ramachandran_etal14.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess"/>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Melbourne, Australia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26841675</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ISCAS.2014.6865271</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">858-861</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Ramachandran, H., Weber, S., Aamir, S. A., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2014). Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;, 858-861. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2014.6865271</apa>
<ieee> H. Ramachandran, et al., “Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control”, &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;,  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2014,  pp.858-861.</ieee>
<ama>Ramachandran H, Weber S, Aamir SA, Chicca E. Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. In:  &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE;  2014: 858-861.</ama>
<frontiers>Ramachandran, H., Weber, S., Aamir, S. A., and Chicca, E. (2014). “Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control” in &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt; (Piscataway, NJ: IEEE), 858-861.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ramachandran, H., Weber, S., Aamir, S.A. &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2014). Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 858-861). Gehalten auf der International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS), Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2014.6865271.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ramachandran, H., Weber, S., Aamir, S. A., &amp;amp; Chicca, E. (2014). Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;, 858-861. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISCAS.2014.6865271&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Ramachandran, H., et al., 2014. Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. In &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, pp. 858-861.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ramachandran H, Weber S, Aamir SA, Chicca E (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS).  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  858-861.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Ramachandran, S.  Weber, S. A.  Aamir, and E.  Chicca, in &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Piscataway, NJ, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 858-861.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Ramachandran, H.; Weber, S.; Aamir, S. A.; Chicca, E. (2014): Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. In: 2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS). Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.  S. 858-861.</wels>
<mla>Ramachandran, Harshawardhan, Weber, Stefan, Aamir, Syed Ahmed, and Chicca, Elisabetta. “Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control”. &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2014. 858-861.</mla>
<default>Ramachandran H, Weber S, Aamir SA, Chicca E (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS). Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  858-861.</default>
<lncs> Ramachandran, H., Weber, S., Aamir, S.A., Chicca, E.: Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control. 2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS). p. 858-861. IEEE, Piscataway, NJ (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ramachandran, Harshawardhan, Weber, Stefan, Aamir, Syed Ahmed, and Chicca, Elisabetta. 2014. “Neuromorphic Circuits for Short-Term Plasticity with Recovery Control”. In &lt;em&gt;2014 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)&lt;/em&gt;, 858-861. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2684167</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-07-04T14:54:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-25T07:54:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>