<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2685091</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wienke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20991629</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4517-5368</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nordmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18384284</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Davide</namePart><namePart type="family">Brugali</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jan F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Broenink</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Torsten</namePart><namePart type="family">Kroeger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bruce A.</namePart><namePart type="family">MacDonald</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Research on robot systems either integrating a large number of capabilities in a single architecture or displaying outstanding perfor- mance in a single domain achieved considerable progress over the last years. Results are typically validated through experimental evaluation or demonstrated live, e.g., at robotics competitions. While common robot hardware, simulation and programming platforms yield an improved ba- sis, many of the described experiments still cannot be reproduced easily by interested researchers to confirm the reported findings. We consider this a critical challenge for experimental robotics. Hence, we address this problem with a novel process which facilitates the reproduction of robotics experiments. We identify major obstacles to experiment repli- cation and introduce an integrated approach that allows (i) aggregation and discovery of required research artifacts, (ii) automated software build and deployment, as well as (iii) experiment description, repeatable exe- cution and evaluation. We explain the usage of the introduced process along an exemplary robotics experiment and discuss our approach in the context of current ecosystems for robot programming and simulation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="simpar-2014-citk-preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2685091/2702035/simpar-2014-citk-preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bergamo, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Continuous Integration</topic><topic>Semantic Web</topic><topic>Software Deployment</topic><topic>ExperimentalRobotics</topic><topic>Development Process</topic><topic>SoftwareEngineering</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title> SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-11899-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26850912</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-11900-7_34</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8810</number></detail><extent unit="pages">400-411</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Lier, F., Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wachsmuth, S., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2014). The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In D.  Brugali, J. F.  Broenink, T.  Kroeger, &amp;amp; B. A.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science : Vol. 8810&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 400-411). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11900-7_34</apa>
<harvard1>Lier, F., et al., 2014. The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In D.  Brugali, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science . no.8810  Cham: Springer, pp. 400-411.</harvard1>
<ieee> F. Lier, et al., “The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments”, &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, D. Brugali, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science , vol. 8810,  Cham: Springer, 2014,  pp.400-411.</ieee>
<default>Lier F, Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wachsmuth S, Wrede S (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:   SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald BA (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science , 8810.  Cham: Springer:  400-411.</default>
<wels>Lier, F.; Wienke, J.; Nordmann, A.; Wachsmuth, S.; Wrede, S. (2014): The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In: Davide Brugali; Jan F. Broenink; Torsten Kroeger; Bruce A. MacDonald (Hrsg.):   SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Cham: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science , 8810).  S. 400-411.</wels>
<frontiers>Lier, F., Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wachsmuth, S., and Wrede, S. (2014). “The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments” in &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, Brugali, D., Broenink, J. F., Kroeger, T., and MacDonald, B. A. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science , vol. 8810, (Cham: Springer), 400-411.</frontiers>
<mla>Lier, Florian, Wienke, Johannes, Nordmann, Arne, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Sebastian. “The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments”. &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Davide Brugali, Jan F. Broenink, Torsten Kroeger, and Bruce A. MacDonald. Cham: Springer, 2014.Vol. 8810. Lecture Notes in Computer Science . 400-411.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wachsmuth, S., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2014). The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In D.  Brugali, J. F.  Broenink, T.  Kroeger, &amp;amp; B. A.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science : Vol. 8810&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 400-411). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11900-7_34&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, Florian, Wienke, Johannes, Nordmann, Arne, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2014. “The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments”. In &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Davide Brugali, Jan F. Broenink, Torsten Kroeger, and Bruce A. MacDonald, 8810:400-411. Lecture Notes in Computer Science . Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lier, F., Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wachsmuth, S., Wrede, S.: The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In: Brugali, D., Broenink, J.F., Kroeger, T., and MacDonald, B.A. (eds.)  SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Lecture Notes in Computer Science . 8810, p. 400-411. Springer, Cham (2014).</lncs>
<ama>Lier F, Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wachsmuth S, Wrede S. The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. In: Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald BA, eds. &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science . Vol 8810. Cham: Springer;  2014: 400-411.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Lier, J.  Wienke, A.  Nordmann, S.  Wachsmuth, and S.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Brugali, J.F. Broenink, T. Kroeger, B.A. MacDonald), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 400-411.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lier F, Wienke J, Nordmann A, Wachsmuth S, Wrede S (2014) &lt;br /&gt;The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments. &lt;br /&gt;In:   SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald BA (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science , 8810. Cham: Springer:  400-411.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Wienke, J., Nordmann, A., Wachsmuth, S. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2014). The Cognitive Interaction Toolkit – Improving Reproducibility of Robotic Systems Experiments (Lecture Notes in Computer Science ). In D. Brugali, J.F. Broenink, T. Kroeger &amp;amp; B.A. MacDonald (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt; SIMPAR: International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt; (S. 400-411). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR), Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11900-7_34.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2685091</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-07-12T14:46:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-25T13:59:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>