<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2685966</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Casey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kennington</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60447866</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Spyridon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kousidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31490072</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23347505</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>AutomotiveUI 2014: 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">It is established that driver distraction is the result of sharing cognitive resources between the primary task (driving) and any other secondary task. In the case of holding conversations, a human passenger who is aware of the driving conditions can choose to interrupt his speech in situations potentially requiring more attention from the driver, but in-car information systems typically do not exhibit such sensitivity. We have designed and tested such a system in a driving simulation environment. Unlike other systems, our system delivers infor- mation via speech (calendar entries with scheduled meetings) but is able to react to signals from the environment to interrupt when the driver needs to be fully attentive to the driving task and subsequently resume its delivery. Distraction is measured by a secondary short-term memory task. In both tasks, drivers perform significantly worse when the system does not adapt its speech, while they perform equally well to control conditions (no concurrent task) when the system intelligently interrupts and resumes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kennington-etal-2014-AutoUI.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2685966/2699128/Kennington-etal-2014-AutoUI.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Seattle, Washington, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26859667</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1145/2667317.2667332</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">7:1-7:7</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, Casey, Kousidis, Spyridon, Baumann, Timo, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Schlangen, David. 2014. “Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation”. In &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 7:1-7:7. Seattle, Washington, USA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kennington, C., Kousidis, S., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., Schlangen, D.: Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications. p. 7:1-7:7. Seattle, Washington, USA (2014).</lncs>
<default>Kennington C, Kousidis S, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications. Seattle, Washington, USA:  7:1-7:7.</default>
<mla>Kennington, Casey, Kousidis, Spyridon, Baumann, Timo, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Kopp, Stefan, and Schlangen, David. “Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation”. &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Seattle, Washington, USA, 2014. 7:1-7:7.</mla>
<wels>Kennington, C.; Kousidis, S.; Baumann, T.; Buschmeier, H.; Kopp, S.; Schlangen, D. (2014): Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. In: AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications. Seattle, Washington, USA.  S. 7:1-7:7.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kennington, S.  Kousidis, T.  Baumann, H.  Buschmeier, S.  Kopp, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;, Seattle, Washington, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 7:1-7:7.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kennington C, Kousidis S, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications.  Seattle, Washington, USA:  7:1-7:7.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kennington, C., et al., 2014. Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. In &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;.  Seattle, Washington, USA, pp. 7:1-7:7.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, C., Kousidis, S., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 7:1-7:7. Seattle, Washington, USA. doi:10.1145/2667317.2667332&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kennington, C., Kousidis, S., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., and Schlangen, D. (2014). “Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation” in &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt; (Seattle, Washington, USA), 7:1-7:7.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, C., Kousidis, S., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt; (S. 7:1-7:7). Gehalten auf der AutomotiveUI 2014: 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications, Seattle, Washington, USA. doi:10.1145/2667317.2667332.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kennington C, Kousidis S, Baumann T, Buschmeier H, Kopp S, Schlangen D. Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. In:  &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;. Seattle, Washington, USA;  2014: 7:1-7:7.</ama>
<ieee> C. Kennington, et al., “Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation”, &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;,  Seattle, Washington, USA: 2014,  pp.7:1-7:7.</ieee>
<apa>Kennington, C., Kousidis, S., Baumann, T., Buschmeier, H., Kopp, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2014). Better Driving and Recall When In-car Information Presentation Uses Situationally-Aware Incremental Speech Output Generation. &lt;em&gt;AutomotiveUI 2014: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 7:1-7:7. Seattle, Washington, USA. doi:10.1145/2667317.2667332</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2685966</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-07-22T15:25:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>