<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2685211</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Séverin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lemaignan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanheide</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45581</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Karg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harmish</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Khambhaita</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kunze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lütkebohle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">153332</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Grégoire</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Milliez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Davide</namePart><namePart type="family">Brugali</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jan F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Broenink</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Torsten</namePart><namePart type="family">Kroeger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Bruce</namePart><namePart type="family">MacDonald</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Simulation in robotics is often a love-hate relationship: while simulators do save us a lot of time and effort compared to regular deployment of complex software architectures on complex hardware, simulators are also known to evade many (if not most) of the real issues that robots need to manage when they enter the real world. Because humans are the paragon of dynamic, unpredictable, complex, real world entities, simulation of human-robot interactions may look condemn to fail, or, in the best case, to be mostly useless. This collective article reports on five independent applications of the MORSE simulator in the field of human-robot interaction: It appears that simulation is already useful, if not essential, to successfully carry out research in the field of HRI, and sometimes in scenarios we do not anticipate.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="morse-simpar-2014-preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2685211/2702024/morse-simpar-2014-preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bergamo, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-11899-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26852118</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8810</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Lemaignan S, Hanheide M, Karg M, et al. Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In: Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI). Vol 8810. Cham: Springer International Publishing;  2014.</ama>
<frontiers>Lemaignan, S., Hanheide, M., Karg, M., Khambhaita, H., Kunze, L., Lier, F., Lütkebohle, I., and Milliez, G. (2014). “Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator” in &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Brugali, D., Broenink, J. F., Kroeger, T., and MacDonald, B. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI), vol. 8810, (Cham: Springer International Publishing).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lemaignan, S., Hanheide, M., Karg, M., Khambhaita, H., Kunze, L., Lier, F., Lütkebohle, I. &amp;amp; Milliez, G. (2014). Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI). In D. Brugali, J.F. Broenink, T. Kroeger &amp;amp; B. MacDonald (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR), Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Lemaignan, S., Hanheide, M., Karg, M., Khambhaita, H., Kunze, L., Lier, F., Lütkebohle, I., et al. (2014). Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In D.  Brugali, J. F.  Broenink, T.  Kroeger, &amp;amp; B.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI): Vol. 8810&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Cham: Springer International Publishing.</apa>
<ieee> S. Lemaignan, et al., “Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator”, &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, D. Brugali, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI), vol. 8810,  Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2014.</ieee>
<wels>Lemaignan, S.; Hanheide, M.; Karg, M.; Khambhaita, H.; Kunze, L.; Lier, F.; Lütkebohle, I.; Milliez, G. (2014): Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In: Davide Brugali; Jan F. Broenink; Torsten Kroeger; Bruce MacDonald (Hrsg.):  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings. Cham: Springer International Publishing. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI), 8810).</wels>
<harvard1>Lemaignan, S., et al., 2014. Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In D.  Brugali, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI). no.8810  Cham: Springer International Publishing.</harvard1>
<bio1>Lemaignan S, Hanheide M, Karg M, Khambhaita H, Kunze L, Lier F, Lütkebohle I, Milliez G (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings. Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald B (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI), 8810. Cham: Springer International Publishing.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lemaignan, S., Hanheide, M., Karg, M., Khambhaita, H., Kunze, L., Lier, F., Lütkebohle, I., et al. (2014). Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In D.  Brugali, J. F.  Broenink, T.  Kroeger, &amp;amp; B.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI): Vol. 8810&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Lemaignan, M.  Hanheide, M.  Karg, H.  Khambhaita, L.  Kunze, F.  Lier, I.  Lütkebohle, and G.  Milliez, in &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D. Brugali, J.F. Broenink, T. Kroeger, B. MacDonald), Springer International Publishing, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Lemaignan, S., Hanheide, M., Karg, M., Khambhaita, H., Kunze, L., Lier, F., Lütkebohle, I., Milliez, G.: Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator. In: Brugali, D., Broenink, J.F., Kroeger, T., and MacDonald, B. (eds.) Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI). 8810,  Springer International Publishing, Cham (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lemaignan, Séverin, Hanheide, Marc, Karg, Michael, Khambhaita, Harmish, Kunze, Lars, Lier, Florian, Lütkebohle, Ingo, and Milliez, Grégoire. 2014. “Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator”. In &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Davide Brugali, Jan F. Broenink, Torsten Kroeger, and Bruce MacDonald. Vol. 8810. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI). Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Lemaignan, Séverin, Hanheide, Marc, Karg, Michael, Khambhaita, Harmish, Kunze, Lars, Lier, Florian, Lütkebohle, Ingo, and Milliez, Grégoire. “Simulation and HRI Recent Perspectives with the MORSE Simulator”. &lt;em&gt;Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Davide Brugali, Jan F. Broenink, Torsten Kroeger, and Bruce MacDonald. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2014.Vol. 8810. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI).</mla>
<default>Lemaignan S, Hanheide M, Karg M, Khambhaita H, Kunze L, Lier F, Lütkebohle I, Milliez G (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots. 4th International Conference, proceedings. Brugali D, Broenink JF, Kroeger T, MacDonald B (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNAI), 8810.  Cham: Springer International Publishing.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2685211</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-07-14T09:46:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>