<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2691510</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11239417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8090-6886</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">307642090</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The study investigates justice evaluations of earnings for male and female employees and links them to the actual inequality people are embedded in. Previous studies in non-reflexive sociological justice research found mixed results. Some studies report a just gender pay gap favoring
men; others do not find this gap. This study provides an explanation for these mixed results by combining sociological justice research and status construction theory. Three factorial survey studies were carried
out consisting of descriptions of employees with varying characteristics including gender. One study was conducted with social sciences students and two with population samples of German inhabitants. Results show that social sciences students revealed no gender gap in their ratings.
In the population surveys, both men and women, showed a rating behavior favoring male employees. The findings indicate that actual inequalities between men and women influence the existence, sign, and size of a just gender pay gap.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0029_Sauer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2691510/2691526/SFB_882_WP_0029_Sauer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>factorial survey</topic><topic>status beliefs</topic><topic>gender inequalities</topic><topic>just gender pay gap</topic><topic>Justice evaluations</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26915103</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>29</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Sauer, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 29). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<ieee> C. Sauer, &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 29,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<ama>Sauer C. &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 29. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, C. (2014). &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Sauer, C. (2014). A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 29, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<bio1>Sauer C (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 29.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 29). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Sauer, C., 2014. &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.29, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Sauer, &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Sauer, C. (2014): A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<mla>Sauer, Carsten. &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 29.</mla>
<default>Sauer C (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 29.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<lncs> Sauer, C.: A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 29. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sauer, Carsten. 2014. &lt;em&gt;A just gender pay gap? Three factorial survey studies on justice evaluations of earnings for male an female employees&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 29. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2691510</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-08-21T08:44:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-28T07:46:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>