<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2695855</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cesarini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bodo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ungerechts</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191073</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tony</namePart><namePart type="family">Stockmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Oussama</namePart><namePart type="family">Metatla</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Doon</namePart><namePart type="family">MacDonald</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper introduces a novel hardware and software system to measure, process, and sonify the instantaneous hydrodynamic pressure at any surface of the human body during sports swimming. In particular, we use four sensors attached to the palmar and dorsal side of the hands to calculate the net pressure difference of piezo probes, corresponding to the net energy transferred to water due to hand actions. The information corresponds to the ‘feel-for-water’ which is critical to improve the effectiveness of swimming. With our system the information is conveyed, using audio, by interactive sonifications using in-ear headphones, allowing a stereo spatialized sound representation of the interaction of both hands and water. For the first time, we hereby demonstrate in-water-experience of swimming actions using sonification. We focus on the system setup and present two parameter-mapping sonification designs that represent differently derived information and illustrate the system performance with interaction videos.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="CesariniHermannUngerechts2014-ART-ICAD2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2695855/2695856/CesariniHermannUngerechts2014-ART-ICAD2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">New York</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Biofeedback</topic><topic>Sonification</topic><topic>Swimming</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26958555</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/CHU2014-ART/</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> D. Cesarini, T. Hermann, and B. Ungerechts, “A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;, T. Stockmann, O. Metatla, and D. MacDonald, eds., Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance,  New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), 2014.</ieee>
<harvard1>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B., 2014. A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In T.  Stockmann, O.  Metatla, &amp;amp; D.  MacDonald, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;. Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance.  New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</harvard1>
<apa>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In T.  Stockmann, O.  Metatla, &amp;amp; D.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt; New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</apa>
<wels>Cesarini, D.; Hermann, T.; Ungerechts, B. (2014): A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In: Tony Stockmann; Oussama Metatla; Doon MacDonald (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014). New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD). (Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance, ).</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In T.  Stockmann, O.  Metatla, &amp;amp; D.  MacDonald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt; New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Cesarini, Daniel, Hermann, Thomas, and Ungerechts, Bodo. “A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Tony Stockmann, Oussama Metatla, and Doon MacDonald. New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), 2014. Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance.</mla>
<frontiers>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., and Ungerechts, B. (2014). “A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;, Stockmann, T., Metatla, O., and MacDonald, D. eds. Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance (New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</frontiers>
<default>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014). Stockmann T, Metatla O, MacDonald D (Eds);  Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance.  New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</default>
<ama>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B. A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In: Stockmann T, Metatla O, MacDonald D, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;. Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance. New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD);  2014.</ama>
<lncs> Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., Ungerechts, B.: A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. In: Stockmann, T., Metatla, O., and MacDonald, D. (eds.) Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014). Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance.  International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD), New York, NY, USA (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, Daniel, Hermann, Thomas, and Ungerechts, Bodo. 2014. “A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Tony Stockmann, Oussama Metatla, and Doon MacDonald. Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance. New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming (Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance). In T. Stockmann, O. Metatla &amp;amp; D. MacDonald (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014), New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B (2014) &lt;br /&gt;A Real-time Auditory Biofeedback System for Sports Swimming. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014). Stockmann T, Metatla O, MacDonald D (Eds); Workshop on Sonification for Sports and Performance,  New York, NY, USA: International Community for Auditory Display (ICAD).</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Cesarini, T.  Hermann, and B.  Ungerechts, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Auditory Display (ICAD 2014)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Stockmann, O. Metatla, D. MacDonald), International Community For Auditory Display (Icad), New York, NY, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2695855</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-09-22T10:32:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>