<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2696059</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kühl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4312658</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Boris</namePart><namePart type="family">Holzer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Fatima</namePart><namePart type="family">Kastner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart><namePart type="family">Werron</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kühl,_Stefan,_2015,_The_Diffusion_of_Organizations._The_Role_of_Foreign_Aid.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2696059/2917540/Kühl,_Stefan,_2015,_The_Diffusion_of_Organizations._The_Role_of_Foreign_Aid.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Routledge</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-138-77690-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26960597</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>131</number></detail><extent unit="pages">258-278</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, Stefan. 2015. “The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid”. In &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Boris Holzer, Fatima Kastner, and Tobias Werron, 131:258-278. Routledge advances in sociology. New York/London: Routledge.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kühl, S.: The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In: Holzer, B., Kastner, F., and Werron, T. (eds.) From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives. Routledge advances in sociology. 131, p. 258-278. Routledge, New York/London (2015).</lncs>
<ama>Kühl S. The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In: Holzer B, Kastner F, Werron T, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge advances in sociology. Vol 131. New York/London: Routledge;  2015: 258-278.</ama>
<bio1>Kühl S (2015) &lt;br /&gt;The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives. Holzer B, Kastner F, Werron T (Eds); Routledge advances in sociology, 131. New York/London: Routledge:  258-278.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kühl, in &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Holzer, F. Kastner, T. Werron), Routledge, New York/London, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 258-278.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (2015). The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid (Routledge advances in sociology). In B. Holzer, F. Kastner &amp;amp; T. Werron (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (S. 258-278). New York/London: Routledge.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kühl, S. (2015). The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In B.  Holzer, F.  Kastner, &amp;amp; T.  Werron (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Routledge advances in sociology: Vol. 131&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 258-278). New York/London: Routledge.</apa>
<ieee> S. Kühl, “The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid”, &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, B. Holzer, F. Kastner, and T. Werron, eds., Routledge advances in sociology, vol. 131,  New York/London: Routledge, 2015,  pp.258-278.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kühl, S., 2015. The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In B.  Holzer, F.  Kastner, &amp;amp; T.  Werron, eds. &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge advances in sociology. no.131  New York/London: Routledge, pp. 258-278.</harvard1>
<default>Kühl S (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives. Holzer B, Kastner F, Werron T (Eds);  Routledge advances in sociology, 131.  New York/London: Routledge:  258-278.</default>
<frontiers>Kühl, S. (2015). “The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid” in &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Holzer, B., Kastner, F., and Werron, T. eds. Routledge advances in sociology, vol. 131, (New York/London: Routledge), 258-278.</frontiers>
<mla>Kühl, Stefan. “The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid”. &lt;em&gt;From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Boris Holzer, Fatima Kastner, and Tobias Werron. New York/London: Routledge, 2015.Vol. 131. Routledge advances in sociology. 258-278.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (2015). The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In B.  Holzer, F.  Kastner, &amp;amp; T.  Werron (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Routledge advances in sociology: Vol. 131&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 258-278). New York/London: Routledge.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kühl, S. (2015): The Diffusion of Organizations: The Role of Foreign Aid. In: Boris Holzer; Fatima Kastner; Tobias Werron (Hrsg.):  From Globalization to World Society. Neo-Institutional and Systems-Theoretical Perspectives. New York/London: Routledge. (Routledge advances in sociology, 131).  S. 258-278.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2696059</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-09-23T07:58:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>