<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2697195</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cesarini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bodo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ungerechts</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191073</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sandra</namePart><namePart type="family">Pauletto</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Howard</namePart><namePart type="family">Cambridge</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Radek</namePart><namePart type="family">Rudnicki</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10027</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We introduce a novel setting for the measurement, real-time processing and interactive acoustic representation (sonification) of changing hydrodynamic pressure induced by the hand-water-interaction, causing momentum changes and in reaction to that propulsion. The sound is presented in real-time both to the swimmer, via in-ear waterproof headphones, and to the coach. 
We used our setting in a first empirical test concerning the symmetry of induced effects of hand-water-interaction during breaststroke swimming. The swimmers were asked to attend to the sounds and in case they perceive asymmetry, they should try to adapt their interaction, interactively in combination with the actual motion and body perception. Afterwards, swimmers were asked to judge the usability of the system. As a result, the functional sounds were ranked to be helpful to change hand-water-interaction.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SoniHED_14_System_swim_evaluated_Final_CesaD_BUng.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2697195/2697196/SoniHED_14_System_swim_evaluated_Final_CesaD_BUng.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">York / GB</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26971954</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">22-27</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., Ungerechts, B.: An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In: Pauletto, S., Cambridge, H., and Rudnicki, R. (eds.) Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings. p. 22-27. (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, Daniel, Hermann, Thomas, and Ungerechts, Bodo. 2014. “An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users”. In &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sandra Pauletto, Howard Cambridge, and Radek Rudnicki, 22-27.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Cesarini, Daniel, Hermann, Thomas, and Ungerechts, Bodo. “An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users”. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sandra Pauletto, Howard Cambridge, and Radek Rudnicki. 2014. 22-27.</mla>
<default>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings. Pauletto S, Cambridge H, Rudnicki R (Eds);   22-27.</default>
<wels>Cesarini, D.; Hermann, T.; Ungerechts, B. (2014): An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In: Sandra Pauletto; Howard Cambridge; Radek Rudnicki (Hrsg.):  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings.  S. 22-27.</wels>
<bio1>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B (2014) &lt;br /&gt;An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings. Pauletto S, Cambridge H, Rudnicki R (Eds); 22-27.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In S.  Pauletto, H.  Cambridge, &amp;amp; R.  Rudnicki (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 22-27).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B., 2014. An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In S.  Pauletto, H.  Cambridge, &amp;amp; R.  Rudnicki, eds. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 22-27.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Cesarini, T.  Hermann, and B.  Ungerechts, in &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Pauletto, H. Cambridge, R. Rudnicki), &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 22-27.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Cesarini D, Hermann T, Ungerechts B. An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In: Pauletto S, Cambridge H, Rudnicki R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. 2014: 22-27.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In S. Pauletto, H. Cambridge &amp;amp; R. Rudnicki (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 22-27). Gehalten auf der Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., and Ungerechts, B. (2014). “An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users” in &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Pauletto, S., Cambridge, H., and Rudnicki, R. eds. 22-27.</frontiers>
<apa>Cesarini, D., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Ungerechts, B. (2014). An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users. In S.  Pauletto, H.  Cambridge, &amp;amp; R.  Rudnicki (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 22-27).</apa>
<ieee> D. Cesarini, T. Hermann, and B. Ungerechts, “An Interactive Sonification System for Swimming Evaluated by Users”, &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data - York 2014. Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, S. Pauletto, H. Cambridge, and R. Rudnicki, eds., 2014,  pp.22-27.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2697195</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-09-28T08:31:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>