<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2698961</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karolina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barglowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29706264</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688781</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Recently, social inequalities at the intersection of migration and care became a highly debated topic. This article contributes to existing literature on social inequalities in migration and care by going beyond debates about ‘care drains’ and ‘care chains’. I argue that distinct features of social inequalities in transnational social spaces are overlooked when not taking into account the ‘symbolic’ dimension of care, work and migration. I investigate ways and processes of task division within transnational families, who are involved in caring for and about each oth-er within and across borders, from the lens of social classifications, understood as systems of knowledge and perceptions which are generated in and guide social interactions. 20 inter-views with migrants from Poland in Germany and 10 interviews with their significant others in Poland reveal that in transnational spaces, classifications are guided by structures of (at least) two countries, which may interrelate, producing new classifications and also reproduc-ing older ones. I show how meanings of work and care are affected by migration, causing inequalities in access to resources and life chances alongside heterogeneities, such as ethnici-ty, gender and generation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0032_Barglowski.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2698961/2698975/SFB_882_WP_0032_Barglowski.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Care</topic><topic>Social Inequalities</topic><topic>Transnationality</topic><topic>Bourdieu</topic><topic>Intersectionality</topic><topic>Social Classifications</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26989613</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>32</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Barglowski, K.: Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 32. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barglowski, Karolina. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 32. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Barglowski K. &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 32. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Barglowski, &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Barglowski K (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 32.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barglowski, K. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Barglowski, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 32). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<harvard1>Barglowski, K., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.32, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> K. Barglowski, &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 32,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<default>Barglowski K (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 32.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barglowski, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 32). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Barglowski, Karolina. &lt;em&gt;Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 32.</mla>
<frontiers>Barglowski, K. (2014). Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 32, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Barglowski, K. (2014): Social classifications and inequalities: Ideologies of mobility, care and work in transnational families. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2698961</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-10-09T09:23:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>