<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2699085</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Holtgräwe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">162199</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1062-4576</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rosleff Sörensen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">152156</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Prisca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Viehöver</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">159120</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jessica</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">12602885</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Borchardt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kraft</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Himmelbauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weisshaar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">86212</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7635-3473</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2684836</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Molecular markers are a highly valuable tool for creating genetic maps. Like in many other crops, sugar beet (Beta vulgaris L.) breeding is increasingly supported by the application of such genetic markers. Single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) based markers have a high potential for automated analysis and high-throughput genotyping. We developed a bioinformatics workflow that uses Sanger and 2nd-generation sequence data for detection, evaluation and verification of new transcript-associated SNPs from sugar beet. RNAseq data from one parent of an established mapping population were produced by 454-FLX sequencing and compared to Sanger ESTs derived from the other parent. The workflow established for SNP detection considers the quality values of both types of reads, provides polymorphic alignments as well as selection criteria for reliable SNP detection and allows painless generation of new genetic markers within genes. We obtained a total of 14,323 genic SNPs and InDels. According to empirically optimised settings for the quality parameters, we classified these SNPs into four usability categories. Validation of a subset of the in silico detected SNPs by genotyping the mapping population indicated a high success rate of the SNP detection. Finally, a total of 307 new markers were integrated with existing data into a new genetic map of sugar beet which offers improved resolution and the integration of terminal markers.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.Weisshaar.0110113.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2699085/2699314/journal.pone.Weisshaar.0110113.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLoS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25302600</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000343730400112</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26990857</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0110113</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>10</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Holtgräwe D, Rosleff Sörensen T, Viehöver P, et al. Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;9(10): e110113.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Holtgräwe, D., Rosleff Sörensen, T., Viehöver, P., Schneider, J., Schulz, B., Borchardt, D., Kraft, T., Himmelbauer, H. &amp;amp; Weisshaar, B. (2014). Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(10): e110113. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0110113.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Holtgräwe, D., Rosleff Sörensen, T., Viehöver, P., Schneider, J., Schulz, B., Borchardt, D., Kraft, T., Himmelbauer, H., and Weisshaar, B. (2014). Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 9:e110113.</frontiers>
<apa>Holtgräwe, D., Rosleff Sörensen, T., Viehöver, P., Schneider, J., Schulz, B., Borchardt, D., Kraft, T., et al. (2014). Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(10), e110113. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0110113</apa>
<ieee> D. Holtgräwe, et al., “Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris)”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2014, : e110113.</ieee>
<wels>Holtgräwe, D.; Rosleff Sörensen, T.; Viehöver, P.; Schneider, J.; Schulz, B.; Borchardt, D.; Kraft, T.; Himmelbauer, H.; Weisshaar, B. (2014): Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris) &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,9:(10):e110113</wels>
<bio1>Holtgräwe D, Rosleff Sörensen T, Viehöver P, Schneider J, Schulz B, Borchardt D, Kraft T, Himmelbauer H, Weisshaar B (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris).&lt;br /&gt;PLoS ONE 9(10): e110113.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Holtgräwe, D., Rosleff Sörensen, T., Viehöver, P., Schneider, J., Schulz, B., Borchardt, D., Kraft, T., et al. (2014). Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(10), e110113. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0110113&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Holtgräwe, D., et al., 2014. Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 9(10): e110113.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Holtgräwe, T.  Rosleff Sörensen, P.  Viehöver, J.  Schneider, B.  Schulz, D.  Borchardt, T.  Kraft, H.  Himmelbauer, and B.  Weisshaar, “Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris)”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, : e110113.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Holtgräwe, D., Rosleff Sörensen, T., Viehöver, P., Schneider, J., Schulz, B., Borchardt, D., Kraft, T., Himmelbauer, H., Weisshaar, B.: Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris). PLoS ONE. 9, : e110113 (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Holtgräwe, Daniela, Rosleff Sörensen, Thomas, Viehöver, Prisca, Schneider, Jessica, Schulz, Britta, Borchardt, Dietrich, Kraft, Thomas, Himmelbauer, Heinz, and Weisshaar, Bernd. 2014. “Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris)”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 9 (10): e110113.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Holtgräwe, Daniela, Rosleff Sörensen, Thomas, Viehöver, Prisca, Schneider, Jessica, Schulz, Britta, Borchardt, Dietrich, Kraft, Thomas, Himmelbauer, Heinz, and Weisshaar, Bernd. “Reliable In Silico Identification of Sequence Polymorphisms and Their Application for Extending the Genetic Map of Sugar Beet (Beta vulgaris)”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 9.10 (2014): e110113.</mla>
<default>Holtgräwe D, Rosleff Sörensen T, Viehöver P, Schneider J, Schulz B, Borchardt D, Kraft T, Himmelbauer H, Weisshaar B (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 9(10): e110113.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2699085</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-10-11T09:49:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>