<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2699049</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hale</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Utar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42546710</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Using the dismantling of trade quotas on Chinese textile and clothing products in conjunction
with China's accession to the WTO and an employer-employee matched data-set for the period
1999 to 2010, workers' adjustments to intensified low-wage competition is analyzed. Utilizing
within-industry heterogeneity in workers' exposure to this trade shock, results reveal negative
and significant impact of the low-wage import shock on workers' future earnings and employment
trajectories. The abolishment of quotas leads to higher likelihood of unemployment and shorter
future tenure for workers. While most workers employed by firms exposed to low-wage competition
are influenced negatively to a similar extent at the exposed employer, the degree of adjustment to
the initial shock varies greatly across different types of workers. In particular less-educated, older
and those who had elementary occupations or occupations that require industry-specific training
at the exposed firms had the worst adjustment experience. The results suggest that adjustment
costs are very important and heterogeneous across different types of workers and highlight the
need for targeting specific groups in assistance and adjustment schemes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_12_2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2699049/2915527/wpaper_12_2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-26990494</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2699049</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">59</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Utar H (2014)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Utar, Hale. &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 12-2014.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, Hale. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12-2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Utar, H.: Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Utar, &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Utar H (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Utar, H., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.12-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, H. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2699049&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Utar, H. (2014): Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<ieee> H. Utar, &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 12-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Utar, H. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2699049</apa>
<frontiers>Utar, H. (2014). Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 12-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, H. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2699049.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Utar H. &lt;em&gt;Workers beneath the Floodgates: The Impact of removing trade quotas for China on Danish workers&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 12-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2699049</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-10-10T11:02:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>