<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2700866</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abendroth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27919701</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Silvia Maja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Melzer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27029279</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jacobebbinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">28973911</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabienne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlechter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688499</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_TechnicalReport_12_B3.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2700866/2700870/SFB_882_TechnicalReport_12_B3.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-985X</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27008660</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Abendroth, A., et al., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Technical Report Series, no.12, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Abendroth, et al., &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Technical Report Series, vol. 12,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<ama>Abendroth A, Melzer SM, Jacobebbinghaus P, Schlechter F. &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Technical Report Series. Vol 12. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<apa>Abendroth, A., Melzer, S. M., Jacobebbinghaus, P., &amp;amp; Schlechter, F. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Technical Report Series, 12). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, Anja, Melzer, Silvia Maja, Jacobebbinghaus, Peter, and Schlechter, Fabienne. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12. SFB 882 Technical Report Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Abendroth, A., Melzer, S.M., Jacobebbinghaus, P., Schlechter, F.: Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”. SFB 882 Technical Report Series, 12. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<wels>Abendroth, A.; Melzer, S. M.; Jacobebbinghaus, P.; Schlechter, F. (2014): Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A., Melzer, S.M., Jacobebbinghaus, P. &amp;amp; Schlechter, F. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Technical Report Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Abendroth, A., Melzer, S. M., Jacobebbinghaus, P., and Schlechter, F. (2014). Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Technical Report Series&lt;/em&gt;, 12, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<mla>Abendroth, Anja, Melzer, Silvia Maja, Jacobebbinghaus, Peter, and Schlechter, Fabienne. &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Technical Report Series. 12.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A., Melzer, S. M., Jacobebbinghaus, P., &amp;amp; Schlechter, F. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Technical Report Series, 12). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Abendroth A, Melzer SM, Jacobebbinghaus P, Schlechter F (2014)  SFB 882 Technical Report Series; 12.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Abendroth, S. M.  Melzer, P.  Jacobebbinghaus, and F.  Schlechter, &lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Abendroth A, Melzer SM, Jacobebbinghaus P, Schlechter F (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodological Report Employee and Partner Surveys of the Linked Employer- Employee Panel (LEEP-B3) in Project B3 “Interactions Between Capabilities in Work and Private Life: A Study of Employees in Different Work Organizations”&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Technical Report Series; 12.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2700866</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-10-24T13:48:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>