<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2700436</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Strongly Incremental Repair Detection</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hough</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">48164400</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthew</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Purver</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>EMNLP</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present STIR (STrongly Incremental Repair detection), a system that detects speech repairs and edit terms on transcripts incrementally with minimal latency. STIR uses information-theoretic measures from n-gram models as its principal decision features in a pipeline of classifiers detecting the different stages of repairs. Results on the Switchboard disfluency tagged corpus show utterance-final accuracy on a par with state-of-the-art incremental repair detection methods, but with better incremental accuracy, faster time-to-detection and less computational overhead. We evaluate its performance using incremental metrics and propose new repair processing evaluation standards.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HoughPurver14EMNLP.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2700436/2700437/HoughPurver14EMNLP.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACL</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Doha, Qatar</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27004369</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">78-89</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hough, J., Purver, M.: Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). p. 78-89. ACL, Doha, Qatar (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, Julian, and Purver, Matthew. 2014. “Strongly Incremental Repair Detection”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;, 78-89. Doha, Qatar: ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hough, Julian, and Purver, Matthew. “Strongly Incremental Repair Detection”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;. Doha, Qatar: ACL, 2014. 78-89.</mla>
<default>Hough J, Purver M (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). Doha, Qatar: ACL:  78-89.</default>
<ama>Hough J, Purver M. Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;. Doha, Qatar: ACL;  2014: 78-89.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J. &amp;amp; Purver, M. (2014). Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 78-89). Gehalten auf der EMNLP, Doha, Qatar: ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hough, J., and Purver, M. (2014). “Strongly Incremental Repair Detection” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt; (Doha, Qatar: ACL), 78-89.</frontiers>
<apa>Hough, J., &amp;amp; Purver, M. (2014). Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;, 78-89. Doha, Qatar: ACL.</apa>
<ieee> J. Hough and M. Purver, “Strongly Incremental Repair Detection”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;,  Doha, Qatar: ACL, 2014,  pp.78-89.</ieee>
<wels>Hough, J.; Purver, M. (2014): Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. In: Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). Doha, Qatar: ACL.  S. 78-89.</wels>
<harvard1>Hough, J., &amp;amp; Purver, M., 2014. Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;.  Doha, Qatar: ACL, pp. 78-89.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J., &amp;amp; Purver, M. (2014). Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;, 78-89. Doha, Qatar: ACL.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hough J, Purver M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Strongly Incremental Repair Detection. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP).  Doha, Qatar: ACL:  78-89.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hough, and M.  Purver, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)&lt;/em&gt;, Acl, Doha, Qatar, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 78-89.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2700436</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-10-22T09:22:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>