<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2703288</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammerschmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41913684</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tünnermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177449</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Pauletto</namePart><namePart type="family">Sandra</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Cambridge</namePart><namePart type="family">Howard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rudnicki</namePart><namePart type="family">Radek</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>SoniHED – Conference on Sonification of Health and Environmental Data</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In order to support drivers in adopting a more fuel efficient driving style, there currently exists a range of fuel economy displays, providing drivers feedback on instantaneous and long-term fuel consumption. While these displays rely almost completely on visual components for conveying relevant information, we argue that there are significant benefits in using auditory interfaces for providing feedback while driving.
We review existing literature and discuss various design strategies for auditory displays that are applicable for supporting a fuel-efficient driving style. Exploring one of these design strategies, we furthermore introduce several prototypical sonification designs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HammerschmidtTuennermannHermann-ETA-SoniHED2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2703288/2703290/HammerschmidtTuennermannHermann-ETA-SoniHED2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">York, England</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sonification</topic><topic>Feedback</topic><topic>Eco-Driving</topic><topic>Auditory Display</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Sonification of Health and Environmental Data</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27032883</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">51-56</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://www.techfak.uni-bielefeld.de/ags/ami/publications/HTH2014-ETA/</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> J. Hammerschmidt, R. Tünnermann, and T. Hermann, “EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style”, &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;, P. Sandra, C. Howard, and R. Radek, eds.,  York, England: 2014,  pp.51-56.</ieee>
<apa>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In P.  Sandra, C.  Howard, &amp;amp; R.  Radek (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 51-56). York, England.</apa>
<frontiers>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., and Hermann, T. (2014). “EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style” in &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;, Sandra, P., Howard, C., and Radek, R. eds. (York, England), 51-56.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In P. Sandra, C. Howard &amp;amp; R. Radek (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt; (S. 51-56). Gehalten auf der SoniHED – Conference on Sonification of Health and Environmental Data, York, England.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T. EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In: Sandra P, Howard C, Radek R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;. York, England;  2014: 51-56.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hammerschmidt, R.  Tünnermann, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Sandra, C. Howard, R. Radek), York, England, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 51-56.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T (2014) &lt;br /&gt;EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data. Sandra P, Howard C, Radek R (Eds); York, England:  51-56.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2014). EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In P.  Sandra, C.  Howard, &amp;amp; R.  Radek (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 51-56). York, England.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2014. EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In P.  Sandra, C.  Howard, &amp;amp; R.  Radek, eds. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;.  York, England, pp. 51-56.</harvard1>
<wels>Hammerschmidt, J.; Tünnermann, R.; Hermann, T. (2014): EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In: Pauletto Sandra; Cambridge Howard; Rudnicki Radek (Hrsg.):  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data. York, England.  S. 51-56.</wels>
<default>Hammerschmidt J, Tünnermann R, Hermann T (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Sonification of Health and Environmental Data. Sandra P, Howard C, Radek R (Eds);  York, England:  51-56.</default>
<mla>Hammerschmidt, Jan, Tünnermann, Rene, and Hermann, Thomas. “EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style”. &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Pauletto Sandra, Cambridge Howard, and Rudnicki Radek. York, England, 2014. 51-56.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hammerschmidt, Jan, Tünnermann, Rene, and Hermann, Thomas. 2014. “EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style”. In &lt;em&gt;Sonification of Health and Environmental Data&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Pauletto Sandra, Cambridge Howard, and Rudnicki Radek, 51-56. York, England.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hammerschmidt, J., Tünnermann, R., Hermann, T.: EcoSonic: Towards an Auditory Display Supporting a Fuel-Efficient Driving Style. In: Sandra, P., Howard, C., and Radek, R. (eds.) Sonification of Health and Environmental Data. p. 51-56. York, England (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2703288</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-11-08T14:39:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>