<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2704233</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10822979</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Roel</namePart><namePart type="family">Willems</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="knoeferle_chapter_cognitiveneuroscience.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2704233/2704234/knoeferle_chapter_cognitiveneuroscience.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27042338</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">77-100</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Knoeferle P (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use. Willems R (Ed);  Cambridge University Press:  77-100.</default>
<bio1>Knoeferle P (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use. Willems R (Ed); Cambridge University Press:  77-100.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Knoeferle, in &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: R. Willems), Cambridge University Press, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 77-100.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Knoeferle, P. (2015): Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In: Roel Willems (Hrsg.):  Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use. Cambridge University Press.  S. 77-100.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knoeferle, P. (2015). Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In R.  Willems (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-100). Cambridge University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Knoeferle, Pia. “Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials”. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Roel Willems. Cambridge University Press, 2015. 77-100.</mla>
<frontiers>Knoeferle, P. (2015). “Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials” in &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;, Willems, R. ed. (Cambridge University Press), 77-100.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knoeferle, P. (2015). Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In R. Willems (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt; (S. 77-100). Cambridge University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Knoeferle, P. (2015). Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In R.  Willems (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-100). Cambridge University Press.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knoeferle, Pia. 2015. “Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials”. In &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Roel Willems, 77-100. Cambridge University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Knoeferle, P.: Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In: Willems, R. (ed.) Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use. p. 77-100. Cambridge University Press (2015).</lncs>
<ieee> P. Knoeferle, “Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials”, &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;, R. Willems, ed., Cambridge University Press, 2015,  pp.77-100.</ieee>
<harvard1>Knoeferle, P., 2015. Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In R.  Willems, ed. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;.  Cambridge University Press, pp. 77-100.</harvard1>
<ama>Knoeferle P. Language comprehension in rich non-linguistic contexts: combining eye tracking and event-related brain potentials. In: Willems R, ed. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience of Natural Language Use&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge University Press;  2015: 77-100.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2704233</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-11-14T07:07:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>