<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2705235</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Loth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26988863</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3580-8099</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Colin J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Davis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Although research has established the phonologicalsyllable as a processing unit in speech production (e.g., Levelt &amp; Wheeldon, 1994), its role in recognition is somewhat controversial. There was no clear syllabic effect in speech perception in English (e.g., Cutler, Mehler, Norris, &amp; Segui, 1986), and also no clear-cut effects in visual word recognition in English (Macizo &amp; van Petten, 2006). However, inhibitory effects of syllable frequency have been reported in German visual word recognition (Conrad, Stenneken, &amp; Jacobs, 2006). In this poster we examine the latter effects more closely, and conclude that they find their basis in morphological processing rather than in syllabification processes. This criticism is applicable to (virtually) all items in German syllable frequency research (Hutzler, Conrad, &amp; Jacobs, 2005; Conrad &amp; Jacobs, 2004; Conrad, Stenneken, &amp; Jacobs, 2006). We report a new experiment that shows no effect of first syllable frequency in a lexical decision task in German. These data challenge the claim that syllabic units affect visual word recognition.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="EPS2009_syllable_frequency.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2705235/2705241/EPS2009_syllable_frequency.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Experimental Psychology Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">London, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Visual word recognition</topic><topic>lexical decision</topic><topic>orthographic syllable</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27052356</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Loth S, Davis CJ (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</default>
<mla>Loth, Sebastian, and Davis, Colin J. “Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.”. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK, London, UK: Experimental Psychology Society, 2009.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Loth, Sebastian, and Davis, Colin J. 2009. “Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.”. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK . London, UK: Experimental Psychology Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Loth, S., Davis, C.J.: Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK (2009).</lncs>
<ieee> S. Loth and C.J. Davis, “Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.”, Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK,  London, UK: Experimental Psychology Society, 2009.</ieee>
<apa>Loth, S., &amp;amp; Davis, C. J. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</apa>
<frontiers>Loth, S., and Davis, C. J. (2009).“Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.”. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Loth, S. &amp;amp; Davis, C.J. (2009). Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. Gehalten auf der Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK: Experimental Psychology Society.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Loth S, Davis CJ. Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Loth, and C. J.  Davis, Experimental Psychology Society, London, UK, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Loth, S., &amp;amp; Davis, C. J. (2009). &lt;em&gt;Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed.&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Loth, S., &amp;amp; Davis, C.J., 2009. Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</harvard1>
<bio1>Loth S, Davis CJ (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Experimental Psychology Society - London Meeting, London, UK.</bio1>
<wels>Loth, S.; Davis, C. J. (2009): Do syllables matter in visual word recognition? – German evidence extended and reviewed. London, UK: Experimental Psychology Society.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2705235</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-11-20T16:53:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>