<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2706344</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Irla</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34792979</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Armin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neshat</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23984104</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Trygve</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brautaset</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42238</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9722-4435</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070724</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 is a thermophilic, facultative ribulose monophosphate (RuMP) cycle methylotroph. Together with its ability to produce high yields of amino acids, the relevance of this microorganism as a promising candidate for biotechnological applications is evident. The B. methanolicus MGA3 genome consists of a 3,337,035 nucleotides (nt) circular chromosome, the 19,174 nt plasmid pBM19 and the 68,999 nt plasmid pBM69. 3,218 protein-coding regions were annotated on the chromosome, 22 on pBM19 and 82 on pBM69. In the present study, the RNA-seq approach was used to comprehensively investigate the transcriptome of B. methanolicus MGA3 in order to improve the genome annotation, identify novel transcripts, analyze conserved sequence motifs involved in gene expression and reveal operon structures. For this aim, two different cDNA library preparation methods were applied: one which allows characterization of the whole transcriptome and another which includes enrichment of primary transcript 5′-ends.
Results

Analysis of the primary transcriptome data enabled the detection of 2,167 putative transcription start sites (TSSs) which were categorized into 1,642 TSSs located in the upstream region (5′-UTR) of known protein-coding genes and 525 TSSs of novel antisense, intragenic, or intergenic transcripts. Firstly, 14 wrongly annotated translation start sites (TLSs) were corrected based on primary transcriptome data. Further investigation of the identified 5′-UTRs resulted in the detailed characterization of their length distribution and the detection of 75 hitherto unknown cis-regulatory RNA elements. Moreover, the exact TSSs positions were utilized to define conserved sequence motifs for translation start sites, ribosome binding sites and promoters in B. methanolicus MGA3. Based on the whole transcriptome data set, novel transcripts, operon structures and mRNA abundances were determined. The analysis of the operon structures revealed that almost half of the genes are transcribed monocistronically (940), whereas 1,164 genes are organized in 381 operons. Several of the genes related to methylotrophy had highly abundant transcripts.
Conclusion

The extensive insights into the transcriptional landscape of B. methanolicus MGA3, gained in this study, represent a valuable foundation for further comparative quantitative transcriptome analyses and possibly also for the development of molecular biology tools which at present are very limited for this organism.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wendisch.s12864-015-1239-4.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2706344/2722399/wendisch.s12864-015-1239-4.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Transcript abundances</topic><topic>Regulatory RNA</topic><topic>Operon structures</topic><topic>Conserved sequence motifs</topic><topic>Transcriptome analysis</topic><topic>RNA-sequencing</topic><topic>Bacillus methanolicus</topic><topic>Methylotrophy</topic><topic>Transcriptional start sites</topic><topic>Ribosome binding sites</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Genomics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2164</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25758049</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000350161900001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27063443</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12864-015-1239-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Irla M, Neshat A, Brautaset T, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Wendisch VF. Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;16(1): 73.</ama>
<lncs> Irla, M., Neshat, A., Brautaset, T., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., Wendisch, V.F.: Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. BMC Genomics. 16, : 73 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, Marta, Neshat, Armin, Brautaset, Trygve, Rückert, Christian, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Wendisch, Volker F. 2015. “Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 16 (1): 73.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, M., Neshat, A., Brautaset, T., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J. &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F. (2015). Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1): 73. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/s12864-015-1239-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Irla M, Neshat A, Brautaset T, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Wendisch VF (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 16(1): 73.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Irla, A.  Neshat, T.  Brautaset, C.  Rückert, J.  Kalinowski, and V. F.  Wendisch, “Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, : 73.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> M. Irla, et al., “Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2015, : 73.</ieee>
<harvard1>Irla, M., et al., 2015. Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, 16(1): 73.</harvard1>
<apa>Irla, M., Neshat, A., Brautaset, T., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2015). Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 73. doi:10.1186/s12864-015-1239-4</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, M., Neshat, A., Brautaset, T., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2015). Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 73. doi:10.1186/s12864-015-1239-4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Irla, Marta, Neshat, Armin, Brautaset, Trygve, Rückert, Christian, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Wendisch, Volker F. “Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 16.1 (2015): 73.</mla>
<frontiers>Irla, M., Neshat, A., Brautaset, T., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., and Wendisch, V. F. (2015). Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 16:73.</frontiers>
<wels>Irla, M.; Neshat, A.; Brautaset, T.; Rückert, C.; Kalinowski, J.; Wendisch, V. F. (2015): Transcriptome analysis of thermophilic methylotrophic Bacillus methanolicus MGA3 using RNA-sequencing provides detailed insights into its previously uncharted transcriptional landscape &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,16:(1):73</wels>
<default>Irla M, Neshat A, Brautaset T, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Wendisch VF (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 16(1): 73.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2706344</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-11-28T14:44:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>