<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2706921</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:820</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Popular Drama, the Literary Field and Intertextuality – Robert W. Buchanan's Adaptations for the Victorian Theatre</title>
</titleInfo>




<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sigrid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Handel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This dissertation analyses Robert W. Buchanan’s (1841-1901) theatrical adaptations for the London commercial stage. It uses two theoretical approaches: Intertextual theory for detailed textual analysis and comparison, and Pierre Bourdieu’s (1930-2002) sociology of culture that takes into account social aspects of literature. This includes society’s various influences on the definitions of “literature”, “literary success” and “literary quality”, e.g. the author’s habitus, his reputation and the expectations raised by it, as well as his social and financial position and background. 
After outlining the late Victorian theatrical field, Buchanan’s habitus and his position(s) therein, this thesis offers six in-depth studies of specific adaptations, with a special focus on the author’s motivation, the changes and modifications of the texts, their presentation on stage and their reception. All six plays are unpublished and can be accessed as manuscripts in the Lord Chamberlain’s Plays of the British Library. 
By analysing the textual and social aspects of Buchanan’s adaptations, this dissertation draws a comprehensive picture of London’s theatrical landscape in the late nineteenth century and of a neglected author. Bourdieu’s approach illuminates especially the subtle nuances and omissions that make Buchanan’s plays unique despite their apparent conventionality.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Die vorliegende Dissertation untersucht Robert W. Buchanans (1841-1901) Adaptionen für das kommerzielle Londoner Theater und verbindet dabei zwei gegensätzliche Ansätze: Die Intertextualitätstheorie als Grundlage für detaillierte Textvergleiche und Pierre Bourdieus (1930-2002) kultursoziologische Feldtheorie, die die Untersuchung der gesellschaftlichen Dimension von Literatur ermöglicht. Zu Letzterer gehören vor allem textexterne Einflüsse auf “Literatur”, “literarischen Erfolg” oder auch “literarische Qualität”, z.B. der Habitus eines Autors, sein Ruf und die damit einhergehenden Erwartungen, seine finanzielle und soziale Stellung und Herkunft. 
Die Arbeit gibt einen Überblick über das Londoner Theaterfeld zu Buchanans Zeit, seinen Habitus und die von ihm besetzte(n) Position(en). Es folgen sechs Einzelstudien konkreter Adaptionen, die sich besonders Buchanans Motivation, den vorgenommenen Änderungen, den Darbietungsbedingungen und der Rezeption widmen. Die besprochenen Theaterstücke stammen aus dem Zensurarchiv der British Library in London und sind bisher unveröffentlicht. 
Durch die konsequente Anwendung von Bourdieus historisierendem Ansatz wird ein umfassendes Bild der spätviktorianischen Theaterlandschaft und eines nahezu vergessenen Autors gezeichnet. Der Brückenschlag zwischen textinterner und -externer Analyse beleuchtet gerade die leisen Zwischentöne und Auslassungen in Buchanans Stücken, die diese trotz aller oberflächlichen Konventionalität einzigartig machen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="buchanan_adaptionen.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2706921/2706923/buchanan_adaptionen.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>kommerzielles Theater</topic><topic>Capital</topic><topic>Intertextuality</topic><topic>Literary Field</topic><topic>Sociology of Literature</topic><topic>Sociology of Culture</topic><topic>Victorian Theatre</topic><topic>Popular Theatre</topic><topic>Adaption</topic><topic>Adaptation</topic><topic>Intertextualität</topic><topic>Kapital</topic><topic>Habitus</topic><topic>literarisches Feld</topic><topic>Literatursoziologie</topic><topic>Pierre Bourdieu</topic><topic>Kultursoziologie</topic><topic>Robert Williams Buchanan</topic><topic>populäres Theater</topic><topic>viktorianisches Theater</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-27069215</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">437</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2014-03-31</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Handel, S. (2013): Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<harvard1>Handel, S., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<bio1>Handel S (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Handel, S. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Handel, &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Handel S. &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2013.</ama>
<frontiers>Handel, S. (2013). Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Handel, S. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Handel, S. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> S. Handel, &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2013.</ieee>
<lncs> Handel, S.: Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Handel, Sigrid. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Handel, Sigrid. &lt;em&gt;Populäres Drama, literarisches Feld und Intertextualität – Robert W. Buchanans Adaptionen für das viktorianische Theater&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2013.</mla>
<default>Handel S (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2706921</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-02T14:54:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>