<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2707157</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Walter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32983951</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8589-8715</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15477016</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7306-3262</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Peter</namePart><namePart type="family">Mika</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tania</namePart><namePart type="family">Tudorache</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Abraham</namePart><namePart type="family">Bernstein</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Chris</namePart><namePart type="family">Welty</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Craig</namePart><namePart type="family">Knoblock</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Denny</namePart><namePart type="family">VrandeÄiÄ</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Groth</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Natasha</namePart><namePart type="family">Noy</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Krzysztof</namePart><namePart type="family">Janowicz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Carole</namePart><namePart type="family">Goble</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Many tasks in which a system needs to mediate between natural language expressions and elements of a vocabulary in an ontology or dataset require knowledge about how the elements of the vocabulary (i.e. classes, properties, and individuals) are expressed in natural language. In a multilingual setting, such knowledge is needed for each of the supported languages. In this paper we present M-ATOLL, a framework for automatically inducing ontology lexica in multiple languages on the basis of a multilingual corpus. The framework exploits a set of language-specific dependency patterns which are formalized as SPARQL queries and run over a parsed corpus. We have instantiated the system for two languages: German and English. We evaluate it in terms of precision, recall and F-measure for English and German by comparing an automatically induced lexicon to manually constructed ontology lexica for DBpedia. In particular, we investigate the contribution of each single dependency pattern and perform an analysis of the impact of different parameters.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="87960464-m-atoll-a-framework-for-the-lexicalization-of-ontologies-in-multiple-languages.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2707157/2707173/87960464-m-atoll-a-framework-for-the-lexicalization-of-ontologies-in-multiple-languages.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-11963-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27071571</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-11964-9_30</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8796</number></detail><extent unit="pages">472-486</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> S. Walter, C. Unger, and P. Cimiano, “M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages”, &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;, P. Mika, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8796,  Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2014,  pp.472-486.</ieee>
<apa>Walter, S., Unger, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2014). M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In P.  Mika, T.  Tudorache, A.  Bernstein, C.  Welty, C.  Knoblock, D.  VrandeÄiÄ, P.  Groth, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8796&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 472-486). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11964-9_30</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, S., Unger, C. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2014). M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In P. Mika, T. Tudorache, A. Bernstein, C. Welty, C. Knoblock, D. VrandeÄiÄ, P. Groth, N. Noy, K. Janowicz &amp;amp; C. Goble (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt; (S. 472-486). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11964-9_30.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Walter, S., Unger, C., and Cimiano, P. (2014). “M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages” in &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;, Mika, P., Tudorache, T., Bernstein, A., Welty, C., Knoblock, C., VrandeÄiÄ, D., Groth, P., Noy, N., Janowicz, K., and Goble, C. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 8796, (Cham: Springer International Publishing), 472-486.</frontiers>
<ama>Walter S, Unger C, Cimiano P. M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In: Mika P, Tudorache T, Bernstein A, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 8796. Cham: Springer International Publishing;  2014: 472-486.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Walter, C.  Unger, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Mika, T. Tudorache, A. Bernstein, C. Welty, C. Knoblock, D. VrandeÄiÄ, P. Groth, N. Noy, K. Janowicz, C. Goble, et al.), Springer International Publishing, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 472-486.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Walter, S., Unger, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2014. M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In P.  Mika, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.8796  Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 472-486.</harvard1>
<bio1>Walter S, Unger C, Cimiano P (2014) &lt;br /&gt;M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014. Mika P, Tudorache T, Bernstein A, Welty C, Knoblock C, VrandeÄiÄ D, Groth P, Noy N, Janowicz K, Goble C (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8796. Cham: Springer International Publishing:  472-486.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, S., Unger, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2014). M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In P.  Mika, T.  Tudorache, A.  Bernstein, C.  Welty, C.  Knoblock, D.  VrandeÄiÄ, P.  Groth, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 8796&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 472-486). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-11964-9_30&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Walter, S.; Unger, C.; Cimiano, P. (2014): M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In: Peter Mika; Tania Tudorache; Abraham Bernstein; Chris Welty; Craig Knoblock; Denny VrandeÄiÄ; Paul Groth; Natasha Noy; Krzysztof Janowicz; Carole Goble (Hrsg.):  The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014. Cham: Springer International Publishing. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8796).  S. 472-486.</wels>
<default>Walter S, Unger C, Cimiano P (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014. Mika P, Tudorache T, Bernstein A, Welty C, Knoblock C, VrandeÄiÄ D, Groth P, Noy N, Janowicz K, Goble C (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 8796.  Cham: Springer International Publishing:  472-486.</default>
<mla>Walter, Sebastian, Unger, Christina, and Cimiano, Philipp. “M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages”. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Peter Mika, Tania Tudorache, Abraham Bernstein, Chris Welty, Craig Knoblock, Denny VrandeÄiÄ, Paul Groth, Natasha Noy, Krzysztof Janowicz, and Carole Goble. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2014.Vol. 8796. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 472-486.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Walter, Sebastian, Unger, Christina, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2014. “M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages”. In &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Peter Mika, Tania Tudorache, Abraham Bernstein, Chris Welty, Craig Knoblock, Denny VrandeÄiÄ, Paul Groth, et al., 8796:472-486. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Walter, S., Unger, C., Cimiano, P.: M-ATOLL: A Framework for the Lexicalization of Ontologies in Multiple Languages. In: Mika, P., Tudorache, T., Bernstein, A., Welty, C., Knoblock, C., VrandeÄiÄ, D., Groth, P., Noy, N., Janowicz, K., and Goble, C. (eds.) The Semantic Web – ISWC 2014. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 8796, p. 472-486. Springer International Publishing, Cham (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2707157</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-04T22:14:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>