<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2708593</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.D.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gulewitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Enck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hautzinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Angelika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlarb</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46110571</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33700</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Aim. To investigate the degree of mental strain and chronic stress in a German community sample of students with IBS-like symptoms. Methods and Materials. Following an internet-based survey about stress, this study recruited 176 German university students ( years; 48.3% males) with IBS-like symptoms according to Rome III and 181 students without IBS ( years; 50.3% males) and compared them regarding current mental strain (SCL-90-R) and the extend of chronic stress. Beyond this, IBS subtypes, IBS severity, and health care utilization were assessed. Results. Students fulfilling IBS criteria showed significantly elevated values of mental strain and chronic stress. Nearly 40% of the IBS group (versus 20% of the controls) reached a clinically relevant value on the SCL-90-R global severity scale. IBS subtypes did not differ in terms of mental distress or chronic stress. Somatization, anxiety, and the chronic stressors “work overload,” “social tension,” and “dissatisfaction with job” were most closely connected to IBS symptom severity. Regarding health care utilization, our results show that consulting a physician frequently was not associated significantly with elevated mental strain or chronic stress but with IBS symptom severity. Conclusion. Our data contribute additional evidence to the distinct association between psychological stress and IBS in community samples.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="AS_2013_mental_strain.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2708593/2708594/AS_2013_mental_strain.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Hindawi Publishing Corporation</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gastroenterology Research and Practice</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1687-6121</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1687-630X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23843782</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000321353000001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27085930</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1155/2013/206574</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1-8</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Gulewitsch, M. D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2013). Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2013&lt;/em&gt;, 1-8. doi:10.1155/2013/206574</apa>
<ieee> M.D. Gulewitsch, et al., “Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms”, &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 2013, 2013,  pp. 1-8.</ieee>
<harvard1>Gulewitsch, M.D., et al., 2013. Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, 2013, p 1-8.</harvard1>
<default>Gulewitsch MD, Enck P, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 2013: 1-8.</default>
<wels>Gulewitsch, M. D.; Enck, P.; Hautzinger, M.; Schlarb, A. (2013): Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;,2013: 1-8.</wels>
<frontiers>Gulewitsch, M. D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., and Schlarb, A. (2013). Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 2013, 1-8.</frontiers>
<mla>Gulewitsch, M.D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., and Schlarb, Angelika. “Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms”. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 2013 (2013): 1-8.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gulewitsch, M. D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2013). Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2013&lt;/em&gt;, 1-8. doi:10.1155/2013/206574&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gulewitsch, M.D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., and Schlarb, Angelika. 2013. “Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms”. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 2013: 1-8.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gulewitsch, M.D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M., Schlarb, A.: Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. Gastroenterology Research and Practice. 2013, 1-8 (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Gulewitsch MD, Enck P, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A. Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;2013:1-8.</ama>
<bio1>Gulewitsch MD, Enck P, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms.&lt;br /&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice 2013: 1-8.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M. D.  Gulewitsch, P.  Enck, M.  Hautzinger, and A.  Schlarb, “Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms”, &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2013&lt;/em&gt;, 1-8.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gulewitsch, M.D., Enck, P., Hautzinger, M. &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2013). Mental strain and chronic stress among a communit sample of university students with irritable bowel syndrome symptoms. &lt;em&gt;Gastroenterology Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2013&lt;/em&gt;, 1-8. Hindawi Publishing Corporation. doi:10.1155/2013/206574.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2708593</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-10T08:47:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>