<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2708841</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:100</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reconstituting Phenomena</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kronfeldner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8222168</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Uskali</namePart><namePart type="family">Mäki</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ioannis</namePart><namePart type="family">Votsis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stéphanie</namePart><namePart type="family">Ruphy</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Gerhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Schurz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10024</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In the face of causal complexity, scientists reconstitute phenomena in order to arrive at a more simplified and partial picture that ignores most of the “bigger picture.” This paper will distinguish between two modes of reconstituting phenomena: one moving down to a level of greater decomposition (toward organizational parts of the original phenomenon), and one moving up to a level of greater abstraction (toward different differences regarding the phenomenon). The first aim of the paper is to illustrate that phenomena are moving targets, i.e., they are not fixed once and for all, but are adapted, if necessary, on the basis of the preferred perspective adopted for pragmatic reasons. The second aim is to analyze in detail the second mode of reconstituting phenomena. This includes an exposition of the kind of pragmatic-pluralistic picture resulting from the fact that phenomena are reconstituted by a move up to a level of greater abstraction.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kronfeldner_Reconstituting-phenomena_rev-fin_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2708841/2916289/Kronfeldner_Reconstituting-phenomena_rev-fin_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>pluralism</topic><topic>pragmatism</topic><topic>autonomy of disciplines</topic><topic>abstraction</topic><topic>causal selection</topic><topic>reconstituting phenomena</topic><topic>causal complexity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-23014-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27088417</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-23015-3_13</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">169-182</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Kronfeldner, M. (2015). “Reconstituting Phenomena” in &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;, Mäki, U., Votsis, I., Ruphy, S., and Schurz, G. eds. European Studies in Philosophy of Science, vol. 1, (Cham: Springer International Publishing), 169-182.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kronfeldner, M. (2015). Reconstituting Phenomena (European Studies in Philosophy of Science). In U. Mäki, I. Votsis, S. Ruphy &amp;amp; G. Schurz (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt; (S. 169-182). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-23015-3_13.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kronfeldner M. Reconstituting Phenomena. In: Mäki U, Votsis I, Ruphy S, Schurz G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;. European Studies in Philosophy of Science. Vol 1. Cham: Springer International Publishing;  2015: 169-182.</ama>
<ieee> M. Kronfeldner, “Reconstituting Phenomena”, &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;, U. Mäki, et al., eds., European Studies in Philosophy of Science, vol. 1,  Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2015,  pp.169-182.</ieee>
<apa>Kronfeldner, M. (2015). Reconstituting Phenomena. In U.  Mäki, I.  Votsis, S.  Ruphy, &amp;amp; G.  Schurz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;European Studies in Philosophy of Science: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 169-182). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-23015-3_13</apa>
<wels>Kronfeldner, M. (2015): Reconstituting Phenomena. In: Uskali Mäki; Ioannis Votsis; Stéphanie Ruphy; Gerhard Schurz (Hrsg.):  Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science. Cham: Springer International Publishing. (European Studies in Philosophy of Science, 1).  S. 169-182.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Kronfeldner, in &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U. Mäki, I. Votsis, S. Ruphy, G. Schurz), Springer International Publishing, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 169-182.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kronfeldner M (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Reconstituting Phenomena. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science. Mäki U, Votsis I, Ruphy S, Schurz G (Eds); European Studies in Philosophy of Science, 1. Cham: Springer International Publishing:  169-182.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kronfeldner, M. (2015). Reconstituting Phenomena. In U.  Mäki, I.  Votsis, S.  Ruphy, &amp;amp; G.  Schurz (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;European Studies in Philosophy of Science: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 169-182). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-23015-3_13&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kronfeldner, M., 2015. Reconstituting Phenomena. In U.  Mäki, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;. European Studies in Philosophy of Science. no.1  Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 169-182.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kronfeldner, Maria. 2015. “Reconstituting Phenomena”. In &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Uskali Mäki, Ioannis Votsis, Stéphanie Ruphy, and Gerhard Schurz, 1:169-182. European Studies in Philosophy of Science. Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kronfeldner, M.: Reconstituting Phenomena. In: Mäki, U., Votsis, I., Ruphy, S., and Schurz, G. (eds.) Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science. European Studies in Philosophy of Science. 1, p. 169-182. Springer International Publishing, Cham (2015).</lncs>
<default>Kronfeldner M (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science. Mäki U, Votsis I, Ruphy S, Schurz G (Eds);  European Studies in Philosophy of Science, 1.  Cham: Springer International Publishing:  169-182.</default>
<mla>Kronfeldner, Maria. “Reconstituting Phenomena”. &lt;em&gt;Recent Developments in the Philosophy of Science&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Uskali Mäki, Ioannis Votsis, Stéphanie Ruphy, and Gerhard Schurz. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2015.Vol. 1. European Studies in Philosophy of Science. 169-182.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2708841</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-11T07:53:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>