<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2709114</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6471004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8865-7466</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neugart</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688232</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">42173282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Regions within the European Union differ substantially not only with respect to per capita GDP, but also with respect to income inequality within the regions. This paper studies the effects of different types of technology-oriented cohesion policies, aiming at the reduction
of regional differences, on the convergence of regions and the dynamics of income inequality within regions. In particular, policies are analyzed using a two-region agent-based macroeconomic model – theEurace@Unibi model – where firms in the lagging region receive subsidies
for investment in physical capital. It is demonstrated that the short-, medium- and long-term effects of the policies on per-capita output and between as well as within regional inequality differ substantially
depending on how successful the policy is in incentivizing
firms to choose best available capital vintages and on how flexible labor markets are in the targeted region.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0034_Dawid_Harting_Neugart.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2709114/2709129/SFB_882_WP_0034_Dawid_Harting_Neugart.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Eurace@Unibi model</topic><topic>cohesion policies</topic><topic>inequality</topic><topic>technology adoption</topic><topic>agent-based modelling</topic><topic>etace_agent_based_modelling</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27091148</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>34</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 34. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Harting, P., Neugart, M.: Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 34. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, Michael. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 34. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P. &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, P.  Harting, and M.  Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 34.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.34, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Dawid, P. Harting, and M. Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 34,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 34). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 34). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, Michael. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 34.</mla>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., Harting, P., and Neugart, M. (2014). Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 34, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Harting, P.; Neugart, M. (2014): Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<default>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 34.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2709114</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-12T09:18:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>