<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2709151</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Caroline</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fehl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Freistein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030473</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688975</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In the field of International Relations, some extent of disciplinary agreement exists that inequalities matter to global political outcomes. Yet, it is striking that the very term “inequality” does not occupy a central position in the vocabulary of IR theorists and a shared conceptual framework to compare different dimensions of inequality is so far missing. Similarly, for research about social inequalities, the dimension of global relations has not played a major role, so far. Ideas to formulate a theory of global inequality have been proposed , yet not systematically explored. The paper argues in favour of broadening inequality research to the realm of the global. The main focus of the paper is on (in)equality in institutional orders, proposing that international organisations and institutions can alleviate but also perpetuate and deepen inequalities among state and/or non-state actors. Which processes within organised forums contribute to the production or mitigation of inequalities and thus function as mechanisms is a further key question of the paper.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0037_Fehl_Freistein.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2709151/2709152/SFB_882_WP_0037_Fehl_Freistein.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>international Political Sociology</topic><topic>institutional mechanisms</topic><topic>inequalities</topic><topic>Global Order</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27091510</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>37</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Fehl, C., Freistein, K.: Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 37. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fehl, Caroline, and Freistein, Katja. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 37. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Fehl, Caroline, and Freistein, Katja. &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 37.</mla>
<default>Fehl C, Freistein K (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 37.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<wels>Fehl, C.; Freistein, K. (2014): Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<harvard1>Fehl, C., &amp;amp; Freistein, K., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.37, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fehl, C., &amp;amp; Freistein, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 37). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Fehl C, Freistein K (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 37.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Fehl, and K.  Freistein, &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Fehl C, Freistein K. &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 37. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<frontiers>Fehl, C., and Freistein, K. (2014). Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 37, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fehl, C. &amp;amp; Freistein, K. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Fehl, C., &amp;amp; Freistein, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 37). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<ieee> C. Fehl and K. Freistein, &lt;em&gt;Institutional Mechanisms of Global Inequality Reproduction&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 37,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2709151</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-12T10:47:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>