<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2709155</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Freistein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030473</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688975</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">With reference to a global (democratic) imaginary, the paper studies how the issue of inequalities is discussed in empirical global and international inequality debates. While the established social inequality literature assumes a positive relationship between national democracy and equality, this relation cannot easily be transferred to the global realm. That makes a study about global inequality interesting for the idea of a global democratic imaginary. In order to show how (or if at all) questions of democracy have entered inequality analyses the paper explores the ideas put forward in experts’ accounts and global development programmes. The concepts raised there include definitions of what constitutes inequalities, the specifics of a global context, the strategies envisioned to overcome inequalities and, at least implicitly, the normative framework that allows for a definition of inequality as a relevant object of international politics.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0038_Freistein.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2709155/2709156/SFB_882_WP_0038_Freistein.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Social inequalities</topic><topic>social imaginary</topic><topic>global debates</topic><topic>democracy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27091559</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>38</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Freistein, K., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.38, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> K. Freistein, &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 38,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Freistein, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 38). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<mla>Freistein, Katja. &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 38.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Freistein, K. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 38). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Freistein, K. (2014). Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality? &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 38, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<wels>Freistein, K. (2014): Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<default>Freistein K (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 38.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<ama>Freistein K. &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 38. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Freistein, Katja. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 38. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Freistein, K.: Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality? SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 38. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Freistein, K. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Freistein, &lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Freistein K (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are there any Global Imaginaries of Equality and Democracy in Discussions about Inequality?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 38.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2709155</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-12T10:55:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>