<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2709139</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liebig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9195366</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9977-6874</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Meike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">May</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11754045</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11239417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8090-6886</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simone</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26709954</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Valet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17913718</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">307642090</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper asks how two structural conditions of an interview situation – the presence of the interviewer and the use of incentives – influence the preferences towards inequality. According to goal-framing theory and the findings of empirical justice research, different goal frames are activated in different types of relationships, producing different distributional preferences: A normative goal frame results in a stronger preference for equality in cooperative situations whereas a gain frame favors inequality in competitive situations. We assume the former type of relationship to be established by the presence of an interviewer, and the latter type to be established by incentivizing. Two experimental studies test our hypotheses. The results suggest that generating a collaborative relationship through interviewer presence and cooperation priming leads to a preference for equality in comparison to a neutral, competitive, or exchange situation using competitive priming techniques. The use of incentives generates a clear preference for inequality.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0035_Liebig_May_Sauer_Schneider_Valet.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2709139/2709140/SFB_882_WP_0035_Liebig_May_Sauer_Schneider_Valet.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>priming techniques</topic><topic>survey methodology</topic><topic>incentives</topic><topic>interviewer presence</topic><topic>inequality preferences</topic><topic>justice attitudes</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27091398</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>35</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2759734</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, Stefan, May, Meike, Sauer, Carsten, Schneider, Simone, and Valet, Peter. 2014. &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 35. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Liebig, S., May, M., Sauer, C., Schneider, S., Valet, P.: How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 35. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<default>Liebig S, May M, Sauer C, Schneider S, Valet P (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 35.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Liebig, Stefan, May, Meike, Sauer, Carsten, Schneider, Simone, and Valet, Peter. &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 35.</mla>
<wels>Liebig, S.; May, M.; Sauer, C.; Schneider, S.; Valet, P. (2014): How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Liebig, M.  May, C.  Sauer, S.  Schneider, and P.  Valet, &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, S., May, M., Sauer, C., Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 35). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Liebig S, May M, Sauer C, Schneider S, Valet P (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 35.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Liebig, S., et al., 2014. &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.35, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, S., May, M., Sauer, C., Schneider, S. &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2014). &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Liebig, S., May, M., Sauer, C., Schneider, S., and Valet, P. (2014). How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 35, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Liebig S, May M, Sauer C, Schneider S, Valet P. &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 35. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<ieee> S. Liebig, et al., &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 35,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Liebig, S., May, M., Sauer, C., Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;How Much Inequality of Earnings do People Perceive as Just?: the Effect of Interviewer Presence on Inequality Preferences&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 35). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2709139</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-12-12T10:22:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-28T07:42:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>