<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2712431</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abendroth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27919701</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pausch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030162</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böhm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">190849</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688499</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This article studies the relevance of the workplace and family context as well as the experience of conflicts between the work and family domain for fathers’ preference to reduce working hours to care for their children. Previous research was not able to disentangle whether the preference to reduce working hours is related to fathers’ caring involvement or to other reasons. Integrating insights from work-family research and arguments on the relevance of the social context for preference formation we formulate need-based and opportunity-based arguments. Findings on data from the German study "Employment Relationships as Social Exchange" (beata), indicate that the experience of a work-family conflict as well as time-based workplace demands increase the likelihood of fathers’ to hold the preference to reduce working hours, supporting need-based arguments. Our findings further call attention to the importance of the family-friendliness of the organisational culture for fathers’ opportunity to develop the preference to reduce working hours to be more involved in caring tasks.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0041_Abendroth_Pausch_Bohm.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2712431/2712432/SFB_882_WP_0041_Abendroth_Pausch_Bohm.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>work context</topic><topic>family context</topic><topic>preferences</topic><topic>fathers</topic><topic>working hours</topic><topic>demands and resources</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27124314</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>41</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Abendroth, A., Pausch, S., &amp;amp; Böhm, S., 2014. &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.41, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Abendroth, S. Pausch, and S. Böhm, &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 41,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014.</ieee>
<ama>Abendroth A, Pausch S, Böhm S. &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 41. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2014.</ama>
<apa>Abendroth, A., Pausch, S., &amp;amp; Böhm, S. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 41). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, Anja, Pausch, Stephanie, and Böhm, Sebastian. 2014. &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 41. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Abendroth, A., Pausch, S., Böhm, S.: German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 41. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<wels>Abendroth, A.; Pausch, S.; Böhm, S. (2014): German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A., Pausch, S. &amp;amp; Böhm, S. (2014). &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Abendroth, A., Pausch, S., and Böhm, S. (2014). German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 41, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A., Pausch, S., &amp;amp; Böhm, S. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 41). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Abendroth, Anja, Pausch, Stephanie, and Böhm, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2014. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 41.</mla>
<default>Abendroth A, Pausch S, Böhm S (2014)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 41.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Abendroth, S.  Pausch, and S.  Böhm, &lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Abendroth A, Pausch S, Böhm S (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;German fathers and their preference to reduce working hours to care for their children&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 41.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2712431</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-15T12:42:33Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>