<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2712496</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liebig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9195366</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9977-6874</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11239417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8090-6886</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Friedhoff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">24274401</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This article provides an overview of how factorial surveys have been used in justice research in the past. It addresses the question of why this method is particularly useful to survey attitudes toward justice. This question is discussed with reference to five problems of empirical justice research. For each of these problems, findings are presented from recent justice research that has used the factorial survey method, with a focus on assessing the allocation and distribution of goods (earnings/income, transfer payments, pensions) and burdens (taxes). The paper concludes with a discussion of future developments and possible applications in this research field.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0047_Liebig_Sauer_Friedhoff.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2712496/2712497/SFB_882_WP_0047_Liebig_Sauer_Friedhoff.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27124963</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>47</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2786499</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, Stefan, Sauer, Carsten, and Friedhoff, Stefan. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 47. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Liebig, S., Sauer, C., Friedhoff, S.: Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 47. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<default>Liebig S, Sauer C, Friedhoff S (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 47.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Liebig, Stefan, Sauer, Carsten, and Friedhoff, Stefan. &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 47.</mla>
<wels>Liebig, S.; Sauer, C.; Friedhoff, S. (2015): Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Liebig, C.  Sauer, and S.  Friedhoff, &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Friedhoff, S. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 47). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Liebig S, Sauer C, Friedhoff S (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 47.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Liebig, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Friedhoff, S., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.47, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Liebig, S., Sauer, C. &amp;amp; Friedhoff, S. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Liebig, S., Sauer, C., and Friedhoff, S. (2015). Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 47, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Liebig S, Sauer C, Friedhoff S. &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 47. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
<ieee> S. Liebig, C. Sauer, and S. Friedhoff, &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 47,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Liebig, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Friedhoff, S. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Using factorial surveys to study justice perceptions: five methodological problems of attitudinal justice research&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 47). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2712496</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-15T13:52:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-28T05:21:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>