<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2714583</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bax</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holger</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bekel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gunther</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heidemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Okyay</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaynak</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Joint International Conference ICANN/ICONIP 2003</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present a cognitively motivated vision architecture for the evaluation of pointing gestures. The system views a scene of several structured objects and a pointing human hand. A neural classifier gives an estimation of the pointing direction, then the object correspondence is established using a sub-symbolic representation of both the scene and the pointing direction. The system achieves high robustness because the result (the indicated location) does not primarily depend on the accuracy of the pointing direction classification. Instead, the scene is analysed for low level saliency features to restrict the set of all possible pointing locations to a subset of highly likely locations. This transformation of the "continuous" to a "discrete" pointing problem simultaneously facilitates an auditory feedback whenever the object reference changes, which leads to a significantly improved human-machine interaction.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bax_bekel_heidemann_ICANN03.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2714583/2719832/bax_bekel_heidemann_ICANN03.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Istanbul, Turkey</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-540-40408-2</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000185378100051</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27145831</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2712</number></detail><extent unit="pages">425-432</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, I., Bekel, H. &amp;amp; Heidemann, G. (2003). Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback (Lecture notes in computer science). In O. Kaynak (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 425-432). Gehalten auf der Joint International Conference ICANN/ICONIP 2003, Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Bax, H.  Bekel, and G.  Heidemann, in &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: O. Kaynak), Springer, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 425-432.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bax I, Bekel H, Heidemann G (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings. Kaynak O (Ed); Lecture notes in computer science, 2712. Berlin: Springer:  425-432.</bio1>
<ama>Bax I, Bekel H, Heidemann G. Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In: Kaynak O, ed. &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. Vol 2712. Berlin: Springer;  2003: 425-432.</ama>
<lncs> Bax, I., Bekel, H., Heidemann, G.: Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In: Kaynak, O. (ed.) Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings. Lecture notes in computer science. 2712, p. 425-432. Springer, Berlin (2003).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, Ingo, Bekel, Holger, and Heidemann, Gunther. 2003. “Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback”. In &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Okyay Kaynak, 2712:425-432. Lecture notes in computer science. Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, I., Bekel, H., &amp;amp; Heidemann, G. (2003). Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In O.  Kaynak (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 2712&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 425-432). Berlin: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bax, Ingo, Bekel, Holger, and Heidemann, Gunther. “Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback”. &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Okyay Kaynak. Berlin: Springer, 2003.Vol. 2712. Lecture notes in computer science. 425-432.</mla>
<frontiers>Bax, I., Bekel, H., and Heidemann, G. (2003). “Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback” in &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Kaynak, O. ed. Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 2712, (Berlin: Springer), 425-432.</frontiers>
<wels>Bax, I.; Bekel, H.; Heidemann, G. (2003): Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In: Okyay Kaynak (Hrsg.):  Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings. Berlin: Springer. (Lecture notes in computer science, 2712).  S. 425-432.</wels>
<default>Bax I, Bekel H, Heidemann G (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings. Kaynak O (Ed);  Lecture notes in computer science, 2712.  Berlin: Springer:  425-432.</default>
<harvard1>Bax, I., Bekel, H., &amp;amp; Heidemann, G., 2003. Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In O.  Kaynak, ed. &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture notes in computer science. no.2712  Berlin: Springer, pp. 425-432.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Bax, H. Bekel, and G. Heidemann, “Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback”, &lt;em&gt;Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, O. Kaynak, ed., Lecture notes in computer science, vol. 2712,  Berlin: Springer, 2003,  pp.425-432.</ieee>
<apa>Bax, I., Bekel, H., &amp;amp; Heidemann, G. (2003). Recognition of Gestural Object Reference with Auditory Feedback. In O.  Kaynak (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture notes in computer science: Vol. 2712&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial neural networks and neural information processing. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 425-432). Berlin: Springer.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2714583</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-23T09:32:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>