<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2714227</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bax</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gunther</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heidemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Harold H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Szu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BaxEtAl-2005-SPIE.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2714227/2719836/BaxEtAl-2005-SPIE.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>SPIE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Orlando, Florida</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8194-5803-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27142270</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5818</number></detail><extent unit="pages">144-152</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Bax, I., Heidemann, G., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In H. H.  Szu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering: Vol. 5818&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 144-152). Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE.</apa>
<ieee> I. Bax, G. Heidemann, and H. Ritter, “A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks”, &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;, H.H. Szu, ed., Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering, vol. 5818,  Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE, 2005,  pp.144-152.</ieee>
<ama>Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H. A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In: Szu HH, ed. &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering. Vol 5818. Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE;  2005: 144-152.</ama>
<frontiers>Bax, I., Heidemann, G., and Ritter, H. (2005). “A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks” in &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;, Szu, H. H. ed. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering, vol. 5818, (Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE), 144-152.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, I., Heidemann, G. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks (Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering). In H.H. Szu (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt; (S. 144-152). Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Bax, I., Heidemann, G., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2005. A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In H. H.  Szu, ed. &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering. no.5818  Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE, pp. 144-152.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H (2005) &lt;br /&gt;A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III. Szu HH (Ed); Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering, 5818. Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE:  144-152.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, I., Heidemann, G., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2005). A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In H. H.  Szu (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering: Vol. 5818&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 144-152). Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Bax, G.  Heidemann, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: H.H. Szu), Spie, Bellingham, Wash., &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 144-152.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Bax, I.; Heidemann, G.; Ritter, H. (2005): A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In: Harold H. Szu (Hrsg.):  Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III. Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE. (Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering, 5818).  S. 144-152.</wels>
<mla>Bax, Ingo, Heidemann, Gunther, and Ritter, Helge. “A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks”. &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Harold H. Szu. Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE, 2005.Vol. 5818. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering. 144-152.</mla>
<default>Bax I, Heidemann G, Ritter H (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III. Szu HH (Ed);  Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering, 5818.  Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE:  144-152.</default>
<lncs> Bax, I., Heidemann, G., Ritter, H.: A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks. In: Szu, H.H. (ed.) Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering. 5818, p. 144-152. SPIE, Bellingham, Wash. (2005).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bax, Ingo, Heidemann, Gunther, and Ritter, Helge. 2005. “A Hierarchical Feed-forward Network for Object Detection Tasks”. In &lt;em&gt;Independent component analyses, wavelets, unsupervised smart sensors, and neural networks III&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Harold H. Szu, 5818:144-152. Proceedings. SPIE, International Society for Optical Engineering. Bellingham, Wash.: SPIE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2714227</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-23T09:32:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>