<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2716728</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kluth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">54885831</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zoe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Falomir</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">I.</namePart><namePart type="family">Sanz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">L.</namePart><namePart type="family">Museros</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J. A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Ortega</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015562</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper the description of 3D indoor scenes in natural language is studied from the point of view of intrinsic and relative location of the objects. An approach has been developed for this purpose which uses a XBox 360 Kinect in combination with ROS and PCL to obtain 3D-data from the scene. Object features are computed on these 3D-data, which are used to generate a SVM-model which classifies the different objects in the scene. After detecting the objects in the scene, their orientation is obtained and qualitative spatial relations between the objects are computed to generate a natural-language description of the scene.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="jarca2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2716728/2716734/jarca2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Proceedings from the University of Seville</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Natural Language</topic><topic>indoor scene decsription</topic><topic>XBox Kinect</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-84-616-7622-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27167285</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Falomir, Z. (2013). Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In I.  Sanz, L.  Museros, &amp;amp; J. A.  Ortega (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt; Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kluth, Thomas, and Falomir, Zoe. “Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language”. &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. I. Sanz, L. Museros, and J. A. Ortega. Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville, 2013.</mla>
<frontiers>Kluth, T., and Falomir, Z. (2013). “Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language” in &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;, Sanz, I., Museros, L., and Ortega, J. A. eds. (Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville).</frontiers>
<wels>Kluth, T.; Falomir, Z. (2013): Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In: I. Sanz; L. Museros; J. A. Ortega (Hrsg.):  XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental. Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.</wels>
<default>Kluth T, Falomir Z (2013)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental. Sanz I, Museros L, Ortega JA (Eds);  Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.</default>
<ieee> T. Kluth and Z. Falomir, “Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language”, &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;, I. Sanz, L. Museros, and J.A. Ortega, eds.,  Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Falomir, Z., 2013. Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In I.  Sanz, L.  Museros, &amp;amp; J. A.  Ortega, eds. &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;.  Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.</harvard1>
<apa>Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Falomir, Z. (2013). Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In I.  Sanz, L.  Museros, &amp;amp; J. A.  Ortega (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt; Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T. &amp;amp; Falomir, Z. (2013). Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In I. Sanz, L. Museros &amp;amp; J.A. Ortega (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;. Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kluth T, Falomir Z (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. &lt;br /&gt;In:  XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental. Sanz I, Museros L, Ortega JA (Eds); Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Kluth, and Z.  Falomir, in &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Sanz, L. Museros, J.A. Ortega), Proceedings From The University Of Seville, Murcia, Spain, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kluth T, Falomir Z. Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In: Sanz I, Museros L, Ortega JA, eds. &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;. Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville;  2013.</ama>
<lncs> Kluth, T., Falomir, Z.: Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language. In: Sanz, I., Museros, L., and Ortega, J.A. (eds.) XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental.  Proceedings from the University of Seville, Murcia, Spain (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, Thomas, and Falomir, Zoe. 2013. “Studying the Role of Location in 3D Scene Description using Natural Language”. In &lt;em&gt;XV Jornadas de la Asociación de Razonamiento Cualitativo y Aplicaciones (JARCA '13). Sistemas Cualitativos y sus Aplicaciones en Diagnosis, Robótica e Inteligencia Ambiental&lt;/em&gt;, ed. I. Sanz, L. Museros, and J. A. Ortega. Murcia, Spain: Proceedings from the University of Seville.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2716728</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-28T12:49:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>