<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2716937</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sonja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kruphölter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11239417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8090-6886</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Valet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17913718</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">307642090</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Gender differences in justice evaluations of earnings are of considerable interest since the late 1970s, especially against the backdrop that women usually earn less than men but widely perceive their earnings as being more just. Newer research specifically draws attention to contextual influences in order to explain this seeming paradox. The idea of this paper is to first identify three parameters that are crucial for justice evaluations: comparison processes, status beliefs and occupational segregation. We assume that the segregation of the labor market in male and female dominated occupations influences justice evaluations of men and women. Hypotheses are tested using data from the German Socio-Economic Panel Study (SOEP) of years 2009-2013. Results indicate that women working in female dominated occupations evaluate their earnings as being less unjust than women in male-dominated occupations. Men in female-dominated occupations do not show differences in their justice evaluations compared to men in other occupations. The implications of these findings are discussed in the light of the literature on gender segregation, social comparisons, status beliefs and distributive justice.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0045_Krupholter_Sauer_Valet.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2716937/2716938/SFB_882_WP_0045_Krupholter_Sauer_Valet.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27169377</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>45</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kruphölter S, Sauer C, Valet P (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 45.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Kruphölter, Sonja, Sauer, Carsten, and Valet, Peter. &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 45.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kruphölter, Sonja, Sauer, Carsten, and Valet, Peter. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 45. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C., Valet, P.: Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 45. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kruphölter, C.  Sauer, and P.  Valet, &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Valet, P., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.45, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<bio1>Kruphölter S, Sauer C, Valet P (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 45.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 45). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kruphölter, S.; Sauer, C.; Valet, P. (2015): Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<ieee> S. Kruphölter, C. Sauer, and P. Valet, &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 45,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C., &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 45). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<frontiers>Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C., and Valet, P. (2015). Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 45, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kruphölter, S., Sauer, C. &amp;amp; Valet, P. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kruphölter S, Sauer C, Valet P. &lt;em&gt;Occupational gender segregation and gender differences in justice evaluations&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 45. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2716937</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-01-30T08:04:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-28T07:58:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>