<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2717405</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Loes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van Dam</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23351012</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0590-9347</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc O.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ernst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23350875</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685448</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>The Hand Embodied</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">Humans can learn and store multiple visuomotor mappings (dual-adaptation) when feedback for each is provided alternately. Moreover, learned context cues associated with each mapping can be used to switch between the stored mappings. However, little is known about the associative learning between cue and required visuomotor mapping, and how learning generalises to novel but similar conditions. To investigate these questions, participants performed a rapid target-pointing task while we manipulated the offset between visual feedback and movement end-points. The visual feedback was presented with horizontal offsets of different amounts, dependent on the targets shape. Participants thus needed to use different visuomotor mappings between target location and required motor response depending on the target shape in order to “hit” it. The target shapes were taken from a continuous set of shapes, morphed between spiky and circular shapes. After training we tested participants performance, without feedback, on different target shapes that had not been learned previously. We compared two hypotheses. First, we hypothesised that participants could (explicitly) extract the linear relationship between target shape and visuomotor mapping and generalise accordingly. Second, using previous findings of visuomotor learning, we developed a (implicit) Bayesian learning model that predicts generalisation that is more consistent with categorisation (i.e. use one mapping or the other). The experimental results show that, although learning the associations requires explicit awareness of the cues’ role, participants apply the mapping corresponding to the trained shape that is most similar to the current one, consistent with the Bayesian learning model. Furthermore, the Bayesian learning model predicts that learning should slow down with increased numbers of training pairs, which was confirmed by the present results. In short, we found a good correspondence be- tween the Bayesian learning model and the empirical results indicating that this model poses a possible mechanism for simultaneously learning multiple visuomotor mappings.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pcbi.1004172.vandam.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2717405/2735212/journal.pcbi.1004172.vandam.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Bayes Theorem</topic><topic>Learning</topic><topic>Kalman Filter</topic><topic>Generalisation</topic><topic>Visuomotor behaviour</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLoS Computational Biology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1553-734X</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1553-7358</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25815787</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000352195700050</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27174059</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004172</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>van Dam, L., &amp;amp; Ernst, M. O. (2015). Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3), e1004172. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004172</apa>
<harvard1>van Dam, L., &amp;amp; Ernst, M.O., 2015. Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 11(3): e1004172.</harvard1>
<ieee> L. van Dam and M.O. Ernst, “Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2015, : e1004172.</ieee>
<default>van Dam L, Ernst MO (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt; 11(3): e1004172.</default>
<mla>van Dam, Loes, and Ernst, Marc O. “Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt; 11.3 (2015): e1004172.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Dam, L., &amp;amp; Ernst, M. O. (2015). Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3), e1004172. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004172&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>van Dam, L., and Ernst, M. O. (2015). Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt; 11:e1004172.</frontiers>
<wels>van Dam, L.; Ernst, M. O. (2015): Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;,11:(3):e1004172</wels>
<lncs> van Dam, L., Ernst, M.O.: Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. PLoS Computational Biology. 11, : e1004172 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Dam, Loes, and Ernst, Marc O. 2015. “Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt; 11 (3): e1004172.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>van Dam L, Ernst MO. Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;11(3): e1004172.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  van Dam, and M. O.  Ernst, “Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, : e1004172.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>van Dam L, Ernst MO (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information.&lt;br /&gt;PLoS Computational Biology 11(3): e1004172.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Dam, L. &amp;amp; Ernst, M.O. (2015). Mapping Shape to Visuomotor Mapping: Learning and Generalisation of Sensorimotor Behaviour Based on Contextual Information. &lt;em&gt;PLoS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3): e1004172. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004172.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2717405</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-02-04T11:47:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:54:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>