<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2718036</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:796</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cesarini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bodo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ungerechts</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191073</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10027</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>10th IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS2015)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Auditory biofeedback systems in the field of sports are increasingly adopted to provide an online guidance to the people performing actions. This paper concentrates on swimming and on producing auditory feedback intended to enhance the perception of the interaction between a swimmer’s body and the surrounding water masses while swimming. The information is related to the concept of ‘feel-for-water’, that is a key factor to produce an effective propulsion, through a correct perception of the boundary effects of body and water. The presented system is composed of pressure sensors, plastic tubes ending between the swimmer’s hand fingers on the dorsal and palmar side, a microcontroller reading the sensors and sending data to a PC for further processing producing the auditory feedback through interactive sonification. We focus on the system setup and present a simple parameter-mapping sonification design as an example, along with possible extensions of the system and other sonification designs. Finally, we present video and audio examples of the system.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="CesariniUH2015-SIT.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2718036/2906262/CesariniUH2015-SIT.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Zadar, Croatia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4799-6116-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27180367</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2718039</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 10th IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS2015), Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Cesarini, B.  Ungerechts, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Piscataway, NJ, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cesarini D, Ungerechts B, Hermann T (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.</bio1>
<ama>Cesarini D, Ungerechts B, Hermann T. Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. In:  &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE;  2015.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, Daniel, Ungerechts, Bodo, and Hermann, Thomas. 2015. “Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system”. In &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B., Hermann, T.: Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. 2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings.  IEEE, Piscataway, NJ (2015).</lncs>
<wels>Cesarini, D.; Ungerechts, B.; Hermann, T. (2015): Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. In: 2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.</wels>
<mla>Cesarini, Daniel, Ungerechts, Bodo, and Hermann, Thomas. “Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system”. &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2015.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B., and Hermann, T. (2015). “Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system” in &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Piscataway, NJ: IEEE).</frontiers>
<default>Cesarini D, Ungerechts B, Hermann T (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.</default>
<harvard1>Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B., &amp;amp; Hermann, T., 2015. Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. In &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Cesarini, B. Ungerechts, and T. Hermann, “Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system”, &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;,  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Cesarini, D., Ungerechts, B., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Swimmers in the Loop: sensing moving water masses for an auditive biofeedback system. &lt;em&gt;2015 IEEE  Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS) Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2718036</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-02-09T14:41:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>