<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2722310</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Spyridon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kousidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31490072</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="KousidisSchlangen2015SSSTurnTaking.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2722310/2733331/KousidisSchlangen2015SSSTurnTaking.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27223109</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">36-43</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Kousidis, S., Schlangen, D.: The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction. p. 36-43. Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A. (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, Spyridon, and Schlangen, David. 2015. “The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 36-43. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kousidis, Spyridon, and Schlangen, David. “The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, 2015. 36-43.</mla>
<default>Kousidis S, Schlangen D (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence:  36-43.</default>
<wels>Kousidis, S.; Schlangen, D. (2015): The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. In: Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.  S. 36-43.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 36-43. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Kousidis S, Schlangen D (2015) &lt;br /&gt;The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction.  Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence:  36-43.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kousidis, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2015. The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;.  Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, pp. 36-43.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kousidis, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Association For The Advancement Of Artificial Intelligence, Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A., &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 36-43.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kousidis S, Schlangen D. The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence;  2015: 36-43.</ama>
<frontiers>Kousidis, S., and Schlangen, D. (2015). “The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence), 36-43.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kousidis, S. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 36-43). Gehalten auf der AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction, Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kousidis, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 36-43. Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.</apa>
<ieee> S. Kousidis and D. Schlangen, “The Power of a Glance: Evaluating Embodiment and Turn-Tracking Strategies of an Active Robotic Overhearer”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of AAAI Spring Symposium on Turn-taking and Coordination in Human-Machine Interaction&lt;/em&gt;,  Palo Alto, CA, U.S.A.: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, 2015,  pp.36-43.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2722310</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-05T12:47:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>