<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2722382</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:572</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yvonne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stolze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36203221</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakrzewski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Irena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32999125</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix Gregor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eikmeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19753357</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1623-172X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jaenicke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5774668</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nils</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rottmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Clemens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Siebner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21937</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4723-2960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlüter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55545</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4830-310X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441927</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Decomposition of biomass for biogas production can be practiced under wet and dry fermentation conditions. In contrast to the dry fermentation technology, wet fermentation is characterized by a high liquid content and a relatively low total solid content. In this study, the composition and functional potential of a biogas-producing microbial community in an agricultural biogas reactor operating under wet fermentation conditions was analyzed by a metagenomic approach applying 454-pyrosequencing. The obtained metagenomic dataset and corresponding 16S rRNA gene amplicon sequences were compared to the previously sequenced comparable metagenome from a dry fermentation process, meeting explicitly identical boundary conditions regarding sample and community DNA preparation, sequencing technology, processing of sequence reads and data analyses by bioinformatics tools.
Results

High-throughput metagenome sequencing of community DNA from the wet fermentation process applying the pyrosequencing approach resulted in 1,532,780 reads, with an average read length of 397 bp, accounting for approximately 594 million bases of sequence information in total. Taxonomic comparison of the communities from wet and dry fermentation revealed similar microbial profiles with Bacteria being the predominant superkingdom, while the superkingdom Archaea was less abundant. In both biogas plants, the bacterial phyla Firmicutes, Bacteroidetes, Spirochaetes and Proteobacteria were identified with descending frequencies. Within the archaeal superkingdom, the phylum Euryarchaeota was most abundant with the dominant class Methanomicrobia. Functional profiles of the communities revealed that environmental gene tags representing methanogenesis enzymes were present in both biogas plants in comparable frequencies. 16S rRNA gene amplicon high-throughput sequencing disclosed differences in the sub-communities comprising methanogenic Archaea between both processes. Fragment recruitments of metagenomic reads to the reference genome of the archaeon Methanoculleus bourgensis MS2T revealed that dominant methanogens within the dry fermentation process were highly related to the reference.
Conclusions

Although process parameters, substrates and technology differ between the wet and dry biogas fermentations analyzed in this study, community profiles are very similar at least at higher taxonomic ranks, illustrating that core community taxa perform key functions in biomass decomposition and methane synthesis. Regarding methanogenesis, Archaea highly related to the type strain M. bourgensis MS2T dominate the dry fermentation process, suggesting the adaptation of members belonging to this species to specific fermentation process parameters.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schluter.s13068-014-0193-8.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2722382/2722393/Schluter.s13068-014-0193-8.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Biogas</topic><topic>Dry fermentation</topic><topic>Wet fermentation</topic><topic>Microbial communities</topic><topic>Methanogenesis</topic><topic>Metagenomics</topic><topic>16S rRNA</topic><topic>Methanoculleus bourgensis</topic><topic>Fragment recruitment</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biotechnology for Biofuels</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1754-6834</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1754-6834</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25688290</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000349714100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27223829</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13068-014-0193-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2915826</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stolze, Yvonne, Zakrzewski, Martha, Maus, Irena, Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Jaenicke, Sebastian, Rottmann, Nils, Siebner, Clemens, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. 2015. “Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 8 (1): 14.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Stolze, Y., Zakrzewski, M., Maus, I., Eikmeyer, F.G., Jaenicke, S., Rottmann, N., Siebner, C., Pühler, A., Schlüter, A.: Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. Biotechnology for Biofuels. 8, : 14 (2015).</lncs>
<default>Stolze Y, Zakrzewski M, Maus I, Eikmeyer FG, Jaenicke S, Rottmann N, Siebner C, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 8(1): 14.</default>
<mla>Stolze, Yvonne, Zakrzewski, Martha, Maus, Irena, Eikmeyer, Felix Gregor, Jaenicke, Sebastian, Rottmann, Nils, Siebner, Clemens, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. “Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 8.1 (2015): 14.</mla>
<frontiers>Stolze, Y., Zakrzewski, M., Maus, I., Eikmeyer, F. G., Jaenicke, S., Rottmann, N., Siebner, C., Pühler, A., and Schlüter, A. (2015). Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 8:14.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stolze, Y., Zakrzewski, M., Maus, I., Eikmeyer, F.G., Jaenicke, S., Rottmann, N., Siebner, C., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2015). Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 14. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13068-014-0193-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Stolze Y, Zakrzewski M, Maus I, et al. Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;8(1): 14.</ama>
<ieee> Y. Stolze, et al., “Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2015, : 14.</ieee>
<apa>Stolze, Y., Zakrzewski, M., Maus, I., Eikmeyer, F. G., Jaenicke, S., Rottmann, N., Siebner, C., et al. (2015). Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 14. doi:10.1186/s13068-014-0193-8</apa>
<wels>Stolze, Y.; Zakrzewski, M.; Maus, I.; Eikmeyer, F. G.; Jaenicke, S.; Rottmann, N.; Siebner, C.; Pühler, A.; Schlüter, A. (2015): Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,8:(1):14</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>Y.  Stolze, M.  Zakrzewski, I.  Maus, F. G.  Eikmeyer, S.  Jaenicke, N.  Rottmann, C.  Siebner, A.  Pühler, and A.  Schlüter, “Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, : 14.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Stolze Y, Zakrzewski M, Maus I, Eikmeyer FG, Jaenicke S, Rottmann N, Siebner C, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions.&lt;br /&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels 8(1): 14.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stolze, Y., Zakrzewski, M., Maus, I., Eikmeyer, F. G., Jaenicke, S., Rottmann, N., Siebner, C., et al. (2015). Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 14. doi:10.1186/s13068-014-0193-8&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Stolze, Y., et al., 2015. Comparative metagenomics of biogas-producing microbial communities from production-scale biogas plants operating under wet or dry fermentation conditions. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1): 14.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2722382</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-06T06:51:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>