<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2723919</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:550</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Berkemeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Shiraiwa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Poeschl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koop</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">104033</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7571-3684</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17980</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Organic aerosol particles play a key role in climate by serving as nuclei for clouds and precipitation. Their sources and composition are highly variable, and their phase state ranges from liquid to solid under atmospheric conditions, affecting the pathway of activation to cloud droplets and ice crystals. Due to slow diffusion of water in the particle phase, organic particles may deviate in phase and morphology from their thermodynamic equilibrium state, hampering the prediction of their influence on cloud formation. We overcome this problem by combining a novel semi-empirical method for estimation of water diffusivity with a kinetic flux model that explicitly treats water diffusion. We estimate timescales for particle deliquescence as well as various ice nucleation pathways for a wide variety of organic substances, including secondary organic aerosol (SOA) from the oxidation of isoprene, alpha-pinene, naphthalene, and dodecane. The simulations show that, in typical atmospheric updrafts, glassy states and solid/liquid core-shell morphologies can persist for long enough that heterogeneous ice nucleation in the deposition and immersion mode can dominate over homogeneous ice nucleation. Such competition depends strongly on ambient temperature and relative humidity as well as humidification rate and particle size. Due to differences in glass transition temperature, hygroscopicity and atomic O/C ratio of the different SOA, naphthalene SOA particles have the highest potential to act as heterogeneous ice nuclei. Our findings demonstrate that kinetic limitations of water diffusion into organic aerosol particles are likely to be encountered under atmospheric conditions and can strongly affect ice nucleation pathways. For the incorporation of ice nucleation by organic aerosol particles into atmospheric models, our results demonstrate a demand for model formalisms that account for the effects of molecular diffusion and not only describe ice nucleation onsets as a function of temperature and relative humidity but also include updraft velocity, particle size and composition.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Berkemeier et al._Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics_2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2723919/2908342/Berkemeier et al._Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics_2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Copernicus Gesellschaft Mbh</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1680-7316</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000348536700009</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27239191</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.5194/acp-14-12513-2014</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>22</number></detail><extent unit="pages">12513-12531</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U. &amp;amp; Koop, T. (2014). Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(22), 12513-12531. Copernicus Gesellschaft Mbh. doi:10.5194/acp-14-12513-2014.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Berkemeier, M.  Shiraiwa, U.  Poeschl, and T.  Koop, “Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles”, &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;, 12513-12531.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Berkemeier T, Shiraiwa M, Poeschl U, Koop T (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles.&lt;br /&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics 14(22): 12513-12531.</bio1>
<ama>Berkemeier T, Shiraiwa M, Poeschl U, Koop T. Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;14(22):12513-12531.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., and Koop, Thomas. 2014. “Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles”. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 14 (22): 12513-12531.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., Koop, T.: Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 14, 12513-12531 (2014).</lncs>
<frontiers>Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., and Koop, T. (2014). Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 14, 12513-12531.</frontiers>
<mla>Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., and Koop, Thomas. “Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles”. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 14.22 (2014): 12513-12531.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., &amp;amp; Koop, T. (2014). Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(22), 12513-12531. doi:10.5194/acp-14-12513-2014&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Berkemeier, T.; Shiraiwa, M.; Poeschl, U.; Koop, T. (2014): Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;,14:(22): 12513-12531.</wels>
<default>Berkemeier T, Shiraiwa M, Poeschl U, Koop T (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt; 14(22): 12513-12531.</default>
<harvard1>Berkemeier, T., et al., 2014. Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, 14(22), p 12513-12531.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Berkemeier, et al., “Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles”, &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 14, 2014,  pp. 12513-12531.</ieee>
<apa>Berkemeier, T., Shiraiwa, M., Poeschl, U., &amp;amp; Koop, T. (2014). Competition between water uptake and ice nucleation by glassy organic aerosol particles. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(22), 12513-12531. doi:10.5194/acp-14-12513-2014</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2723919</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-17T06:50:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>