<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2724423</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Conte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marco</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Scarsini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oktay</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sürücü</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701960</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We experimentally explore the effects of time pressure on decision making. Under different time allowance conditions, subjects are presented with a queueing
situation and asked to join one of two queues that differ in length, server speed, and entry fee. The results can be grouped under two main categories. The first one concerns the factors driving customers' decisions in a queueing system. Only a proportion of subjects behave rationally and use the relevant information efficiently. The rest of the subjects seem to adopt a rule of thumb that ignores the
information on server speed and follows the shorter queue. The second category is related to the effects of time pressure on decision performance. A significant
proportion of the population is not affected by time limitations and shows a consistent behavior throughout the treatments. On the other hand, the majority of
subjects' performance is impaired by time limitations. More importantly, this impairment is not due to the stringency of the limitation but mainly due to the
fact that being exposed to a time limitation, even to a loose one, brings along stress and panic, and causes subjects to use time inefficiently.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_538.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2724423/2724426/IMW_working_paper_538.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Time pressure</topic><topic>queues with entry fee</topic><topic>join the shortest queue</topic><topic>experimentation</topic><topic>decision times</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27244237</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>538</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Conte, Anna, Scarsini, Marco, and Sürücü, Oktay. &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 538.</mla>
<default>Conte A, Scarsini M, Sürücü O (2015)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 538.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<lncs> Conte, A., Scarsini, M., Sürücü, O.: Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 538. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Conte, Anna, Scarsini, Marco, and Sürücü, Oktay. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 538. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Conte, A., Scarsini, M., &amp;amp; Sürücü, O. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 538). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Conte, A., Scarsini, M., &amp;amp; Sürücü, O., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.538, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Conte A, Scarsini M, Sürücü O (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 538.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Conte, M.  Scarsini, and O.  Sürücü, &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Conte, A.; Scarsini, M.; Sürücü, O. (2015): Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa>Conte, A., Scarsini, M., &amp;amp; Sürücü, O. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 538). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> A. Conte, M. Scarsini, and O. Sürücü, &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 538,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<ama>Conte A, Scarsini M, Sürücü O. &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 538. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2015.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Conte, A., Scarsini, M. &amp;amp; Sürücü, O. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Conte, A., Scarsini, M., and Sürücü, O. (2015). Does time pressure impair performance? An experiment on queueing behavior. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 538, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2724423</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-19T09:30:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>