<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2724156</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paaßen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49941564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3899-2450</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bassam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mokbel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18880650</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michel</namePart><namePart type="family">Verleysen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Today's learning supporting systems for programming mostly rely on pre-coded feedback provision, such that their applicability is restricted to modelled tasks. In this contribution, we investigate the suitability of machine learning techniques to automate this process by means of a presentationm of similar solution strategies from a set of stored examples.
To this end we apply structure metric learning methods in local and global alignment which can be used to compare Java programs.
We demonstrate that automatically adapted metrics better identify the underlying programming strategy as compared to their default counterparts in a benchmark example from programming.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paassen_mokbel_hammer_adaptive_structure_metrics.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2724156/2752725/paassen_mokbel_hammer_adaptive_structure_metrics.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bruges, Belgium</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>intelligent tutoring systems</topic><topic>metric learning</topic><topic>sequence alignment</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn"> 	 978-2-87587-014-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27241567</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">307-312</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2900684</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B., and Hammer, B. (2015). “Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, Verleysen, M. ed. 307-312.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2015). Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In M. Verleysen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (S. 307-312). Gehalten auf der ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Paaßen B, Mokbel B, Hammer B. Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In: Verleysen M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. 2015: 307-312.</ama>
<ieee> B. Paaßen, B. Mokbel, and B. Hammer, “Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, M. Verleysen, ed., 2015,  pp.307-312.</ieee>
<apa>Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2015). Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 307-312).</apa>
<wels>Paaßen, B.; Mokbel, B.; Hammer, B. (2015): Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In: Michel Verleysen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning.  S. 307-312.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Paaßen, B.  Mokbel, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Verleysen), &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 307-312.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2015. Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In M.  Verleysen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 307-312.</harvard1>
<bio1>Paaßen B, Mokbel B, Hammer B (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed); 307-312.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2015). Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 307-312).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, Benjamin, Mokbel, Bassam, and Hammer, Barbara. 2015. “Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michel Verleysen, 307-312.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Paaßen, B., Mokbel, B., Hammer, B.: Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming. In: Verleysen, M. (ed.) Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. p. 307-312. (2015).</lncs>
<default>Paaßen B, Mokbel B, Hammer B (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed);   307-312.</default>
<mla>Paaßen, Benjamin, Mokbel, Bassam, and Hammer, Barbara. “Adaptive structure metrics for automated feedback provision in Java programming”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 23rd European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michel Verleysen. 2015. 307-312.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2724156</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-17T12:41:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-21T11:05:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>