<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2724561</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Manuela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfinder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16213569</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The mechanisms involved in the reproduction of educational inequalities are not yet fully understood, and therefore, this study aims to go beyond the scope of postnatal mechanisms. This study examines the role of prenatal exposures in the reproduction of educational differences. It is argued that health behaviors during pregnancy are associated with levels of maternal education and that prenatal exposures affect educational attainment. Thus, prenatal exposures might contribute to our understanding of educational inequalities. Using data from the German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Children and Adolescents (N=5,670), evidence is found that the risk of lower educational attainment is increased in offspring exposed to tobacco, or to both alcohol and tobacco, during pregnancy. Additionally, prenatal exposures mediate the effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s school attainment. These results emphasize the need to include prenatal exposures when conducting research on both social origins and educational attainment.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0052_Pfinder.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2724561/2724566/SFB_882_WP_0052_Pfinder.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Reproduction of educational inequalities</topic><topic>prenatal exposures</topic><topic>alcohol</topic><topic>tobacco</topic><topic>maternal health-related behaviors</topic><topic>pregnancy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27245617</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>52</number></detail><extent unit="pages">38</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, Manuela. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 52. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pfinder, M.: Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 52. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<default>Pfinder M (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 52.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Pfinder, Manuela. &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 52.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pfinder, M. (2015). Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 52, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Pfinder M. &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 52. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
<ieee> M. Pfinder, &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 52,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Pfinder, M. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 52). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<wels>Pfinder, M. (2015): Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Pfinder, &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Pfinder M (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 52.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Pfinder, M., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.52, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfinder, M. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Effect of maternal educational level on offspring’s educational attainment: role of prenatal exposures&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 52). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2724561</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-19T13:58:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>