<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2724548</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susanne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Edler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22437447</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jacobebbinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">28973911</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liebig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9195366</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9977-6874</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688572</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this article, we examine the effects of unemployment on reentry wages in Germany. Based on the theories of signaling effects, human capital, and occupational segmentation, we discuss the heterogeneity of reemployment wages among different types of reemployment and among different occupations. The empirical analysis is based on the German social security records of the Linked Employer–Employee Data from IAB (LIAB). Our results indicate that the wage effects of unemployment vary considerably across occupations. First, occupations characterized by higher rates of participation in further education showed stronger negative effects of unemployment on reentry wages. This finding indicates that occupations that involve less technological change are associated with a slower depreciation of specific human capital. Second, the lost wages after unemployment are higher in occupations with a typically higher rate of unemployment, indicating that an oversupply of employees leads to lower bargaining power on the part of workers. Third, the negative effect of unemployment is reduced if employees are reemployed by a former employer within one year of dismissal. This finding reflects the fact that employers already know the productivity of former employees and can thus retain company-specific human capital.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0051_Edler_Jacobebbinghaus_Liebig.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2724548/2724553/SFB_882_WP_0051_Edler_Jacobebbinghaus_Liebig.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>recall employment</topic><topic>occupational segmentation</topic><topic>unemployment</topic><topic>wage losses</topic><topic>reemployment</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27245481</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>51</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P., &amp;amp; Liebig, S., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.51, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P., &amp;amp; Liebig, S. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 51). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Edler S, Jacobebbinghaus P, Liebig S (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 51.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Edler, P.  Jacobebbinghaus, and S.  Liebig, &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Edler, S.; Jacobebbinghaus, P.; Liebig, S. (2015): Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<apa>Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P., &amp;amp; Liebig, S. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 51). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<ieee> S. Edler, P. Jacobebbinghaus, and S. Liebig, &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 51,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<ama>Edler S, Jacobebbinghaus P, Liebig S. &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 51. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
<frontiers>Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P., and Liebig, S. (2015). Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 51, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P. &amp;amp; Liebig, S. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Edler, Susanne, Jacobebbinghaus, Peter, and Liebig, Stefan. &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 51.</mla>
<default>Edler S, Jacobebbinghaus P, Liebig S (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 51.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<lncs> Edler, S., Jacobebbinghaus, P., Liebig, S.: Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 51. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Edler, Susanne, Jacobebbinghaus, Peter, and Liebig, Stefan. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Effects of unemployment on wages: differences between types of reemployment and types of occupation&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 51. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2724548</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-19T13:49:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>