<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2726548</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33056</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5842-9991</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">G.</namePart><namePart type="family">Carbone</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Gomez-Bravo</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27015523</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The sense of touch allows humans and higher animals to perform coordinated and efficient interactions within their environment. Recently, tactile sensor arrays providing high force, spatial, and temporal resolution became available
for robotics, which allows us to consider new control strategies to exploit this important and valuable sensory channel for grasping and manipulation tasks. Successful
dexterous manipulation strongly depends on tight feedback loops integrating proprioceptive, visual, and tactile feedback. We introduce a framework for tactile servoing
that can realize specific tactile interaction patterns, for example to establish and maintain contact (grasping) or to explore and manipulate objects. We demonstrate and
evaluate the capabilities of the proposed control framework in a series of preliminary experiments employing a 16 × 16 tactile sensor array attached to a Kuka LWR arm as a large fingertip.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="314724_1_En_4_Chapter_OnlinePDF.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2726548/2726549/314724_1_En_4_Chapter_OnlinePDF.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Grasping
Tactile servoing
Online motion planning</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2211-0984</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">9783319147048</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27265480</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-14705-5_4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>29</number></detail><extent unit="pages">522</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Haschke, R. (2015): Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In: G. Carbone; F. Gomez-Bravo (Hrsg.):  Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems. Switzerland: Springer. (Mechanisms and Machine Science, 29).  S. 522.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haschke, R. (2015). Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In G.  Carbone &amp;amp; F.  Gomez-Bravo (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Mechanisms and Machine Science: Vol. 29&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt; (p. 522). Switzerland: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-14705-5_4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Haschke, R. (2015). “Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback” in &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Carbone, G., and Gomez-Bravo, F. eds. Mechanisms and Machine Science, vol. 29, (Switzerland: Springer), 522.</frontiers>
<mla>Haschke, Robert. “Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback”. &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. G. Carbone and F. Gomez-Bravo. Switzerland: Springer, 2015.Vol. 29. Mechanisms and Machine Science. 522.</mla>
<default>Haschke R (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems. Carbone G, Gomez-Bravo F (Eds);  Mechanisms and Machine Science, 29.  Switzerland: Springer:  522.</default>
<harvard1>Haschke, R., 2015. Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In G.  Carbone &amp;amp; F.  Gomez-Bravo, eds. &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanisms and Machine Science. no.29  Switzerland: Springer, pp. 522.</harvard1>
<ieee> R. Haschke, “Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback”, &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;, G. Carbone and F. Gomez-Bravo, eds., Mechanisms and Machine Science, vol. 29,  Switzerland: Springer, 2015,  pp.522.</ieee>
<apa>Haschke, R. (2015). Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In G.  Carbone &amp;amp; F.  Gomez-Bravo (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Mechanisms and Machine Science: Vol. 29&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt; (p. 522). Switzerland: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-14705-5_4</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haschke, R. (2015). Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback (Mechanisms and Machine Science). In G. Carbone &amp;amp; F. Gomez-Bravo (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 522). Switzerland: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-14705-5_4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Haschke, in &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G. Carbone, F. Gomez-Bravo), Springer, Switzerland, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 522.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Haschke R (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems. Carbone G, Gomez-Bravo F (Eds); Mechanisms and Machine Science, 29. Switzerland: Springer:  522.</bio1>
<ama>Haschke R. Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In: Carbone G, Gomez-Bravo F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanisms and Machine Science. Vol 29. Switzerland: Springer;  2015: 522.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haschke, Robert. 2015. “Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback”. In &lt;em&gt;Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. G. Carbone and F. Gomez-Bravo, 29:522. Mechanisms and Machine Science. Switzerland: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Haschke, R.: Grasping and Manipulation of Unknown Objects Based on Visual and Tactile Feedback. In: Carbone, G. and Gomez-Bravo, F. (eds.) Motion and Operation Planning of Robotic Systems. Mechanisms and Machine Science. 29, p. 522. Springer, Switzerland (2015).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2726548</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-26T08:39:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>