<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2727170</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Czerwinski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42986725</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Emily</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Finne</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14402624</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-6736-0022</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kolip</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14955037</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1052-5869</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bucksch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19648218</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21334</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Young people spend half of their days in school, but evidence concerning the influence of school environment on the physical activity (PA) of pupils is still inconsistent. A better understanding of potential correlates of PA on the school-level and their possible interaction with individual aspects is needed to improve the development of more effective interventions.
Methods

We used data from the 2009/10 German Health Behaviour in School-aged Children study (HBSC)-sample (n=5,005 students aged 11–15 years) including self-reported moderate to vigorous intensity PA as well as a variety of biological, demographic and behavioral correlates and matched them with school-level data from the national school principals’ HBSC questionnaire. We analyzed the associations of individual- and school-level correlates with MVPA by gender-specific multi-level regression.
Results

Only a small share of the overall variation in student’s PA was attributable to the school-level. Consequently, the associations of individual-level correlates with PA were stronger than those of the school-level. Our analysis revealed significant associations of individual-level (i.e. age, consumption of softdrinks, overweight) as well as school-level correlates (i.e. the availability of a football ground and a swimming pool) with MVPA. We also observed some gender-specific findings especially for the school level correlates. Cross-level interactions between individual- and school-level were not apparent.
Conclusions

Our findings indicate the usefulness of applying an ecological framework to understand and explain complex health behaviors like PA. As we found gender-specific association it might be important to acknowledge that boys and girls have specific needs to be more physically active. Further research should also take other features/elements of the school environment and neighborhood as well as socio-cognitive correlates into account to advance the field.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="czerwinski.s12889-015-1715-4.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2727170/2735405/czerwinski.s12889-015-1715-4.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Adolescents</topic><topic>(Moderate-to-vigorous) physical activity</topic><topic>School</topic><topic>Correlates</topic><topic>Environment</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25928443</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000353940200001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27271709</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1715-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>15</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Czerwinski, F., Finne, E., Kolip, P. &amp;amp; Bucksch, J. (2015). Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(1): 393. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/s12889-015-1715-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Czerwinski, F., Finne, E., Kolip, P., and Bucksch, J. (2015). Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15:393.</frontiers>
<ama>Czerwinski F, Finne E, Kolip P, Bucksch J. Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;15(1): 393.</ama>
<ieee> F. Czerwinski, et al., “Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 15, 2015, : 393.</ieee>
<apa>Czerwinski, F., Finne, E., Kolip, P., &amp;amp; Bucksch, J. (2015). Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(1), 393. doi:10.1186/s12889-015-1715-4</apa>
<wels>Czerwinski, F.; Finne, E.; Kolip, P.; Bucksch, J. (2015): Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,15:(1):393</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Czerwinski, E.  Finne, P.  Kolip, and J.  Bucksch, “Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;, : 393.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Czerwinski, F., et al., 2015. Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 15(1): 393.</harvard1>
<bio1>Czerwinski F, Finne E, Kolip P, Bucksch J (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Public Health 15(1): 393.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Czerwinski, F., Finne, E., Kolip, P., &amp;amp; Bucksch, J. (2015). Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(1), 393. doi:10.1186/s12889-015-1715-4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Czerwinski, Fabian, Finne, Emily, Kolip, Petra, and Bucksch, Jens. 2015. “Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15 (1): 393.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Czerwinski, F., Finne, E., Kolip, P., Bucksch, J.: Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis. BMC Public Health. 15, : 393 (2015).</lncs>
<default>Czerwinski F, Finne E, Kolip P, Bucksch J (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15(1): 393.</default>
<mla>Czerwinski, Fabian, Finne, Emily, Kolip, Petra, and Bucksch, Jens. “Individual and school level correlates of moderate to vigorous physical activity among school-children in Germany - a multi-level analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15.1 (2015): 393.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2727170</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-03-30T18:32:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>