<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2730606</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:100</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73476</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4786-5189</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Catrin</namePart><namePart type="family">Misselhorn</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">27003888</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10066</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Understanding others’ intentions and representing them as being able to understand intentions are relevant factors in cooperation, as is the ability to represent shared goals and coordinated action plans (joint intentions). To endow artificial systems with cooperative functionality, they need to be enabled to adopt the goals of another individual and act together with the other to achieve these goals. Such systems may be embodied as robotic agents or as humanoid agents projected in virtual reality (“embodied cooperative systems”). A central question is how the processes involved interact and how their interplay can be modeled. For example, inter-agent cooperation relies very much on common ground, i.e. the mutually shared knowledge of the interlocutors. Nonverbal behaviors such as gaze and gestures are important means of coordinating attention between interlocutors (joint attention) in the pursuit of goals. In the context of cooperative settings, the view that humans are users of a certain “tool” has shifted to that of a “partnership” with artificial agents, insofar they can be considered as being able to take initiative as autonomous entities. This chapter will outline these ideas taking the virtual humanoid agent “Max” as an example.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_ECS.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2730606/2908330/Wachsmuth_ECS.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing Switzerland</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>joint intention</topic><topic>artificial agents</topic><topic>intentions</topic><topic>theory of mind</topic><topic>cooperation</topic><topic>joint attention</topic><topic>BDI</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-15514-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27306069</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-15515-9_4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>122</number></detail><extent unit="pages">63-79</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 2015. “Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership”. In &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Catrin Misselhorn, 122:63-79. Philosophical Studies Series. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wachsmuth, I.: Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In: Misselhorn, C. (ed.) Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems. Philosophical Studies Series. 122, p. 63-79. Springer International Publishing Switzerland, Cham (2015).</lncs>
<default>Wachsmuth I (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems. Misselhorn C (Ed);  Philosophical Studies Series, 122.  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland:  63-79.</default>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership”. &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Catrin Misselhorn. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, 2015.Vol. 122. Philosophical Studies Series. 63-79.</mla>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (2015). “Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership” in &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;, Misselhorn, C. ed. Philosophical Studies Series, vol. 122, (Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland), 63-79.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2015). Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership (Philosophical Studies Series). In C. Misselhorn (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt; (S. 63-79). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-15515-9_4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In: Misselhorn C, ed. &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Philosophical Studies Series. Vol 122. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland;  2015: 63-79.</ama>
<ieee> I. Wachsmuth, “Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership”, &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;, C. Misselhorn, ed., Philosophical Studies Series, vol. 122,  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, 2015,  pp.63-79.</ieee>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (2015). Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In C.  Misselhorn (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Studies Series: Vol. 122&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-79). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-15515-9_4</apa>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (2015): Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In: Catrin Misselhorn (Hrsg.):  Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. (Philosophical Studies Series, 122).  S. 63-79.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: C. Misselhorn), Springer International Publishing Switzerland, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 63-79.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 2015. Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In C.  Misselhorn, ed. &lt;em&gt;Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;. Philosophical Studies Series. no.122  Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland, pp. 63-79.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems. Misselhorn C (Ed); Philosophical Studies Series, 122. Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland:  63-79.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (2015). Embodied cooperative systems: From tool to partnership. In C.  Misselhorn (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Studies Series: Vol. 122&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Collective Agency and Cooperation in Natural and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-79). Cham: Springer International Publishing Switzerland. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-15515-9_4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2730606</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-04-16T20:03:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>