<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2732529</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wanja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schindler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32434708</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7054-5431</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brand</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33695</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The Implicit Association Test (IAT) aims to measure participants’ automatic evaluation of an attitude object and is useful especially for the measurement of attitudes related to socially sensitive subjects, e.g. doping in sports. Several studies indicate that IAT scores can be faked on instruction. But fully or semi-instructed research scenarios might not properly reflect what happens in more realistic situations, when participants secretly decide to try faking the test. The present study is the first to investigate IAT faking when there is only an implicit incentive to do so. Sixty-five athletes (22.83 years ± 2.45; 25 women) were randomly assigned to an incentive-to-fake condition or a control condition. Participants in the incentive-to-fake condition were manipulated to believe that athletes with lenient doping attitudes would be referred to a tedious 45-minute anti-doping program. Attitudes were measured with the pictorial doping brief IAT (BIAT) and with the Performance Enhancement Attitude Scale (PEAS). A one-way MANOVA revealed significant differences between conditions after the manipulation in PEAS scores, but not in the doping BIAT. In the light of our hypothesis this suggests that participants successfully faked an exceedingly negative attitude to doping when completing the PEAS, but were unsuccessful in doing so on the reaction time-based test. This study assessed BIAT faking in a setting that aimed to resemble a situation in which participants want to hide their attempts to cheat. The two measures of attitude were differentially affected by the implicit incentive. Our findings provide evidence that the pictorial doping BIAT is relatively robust against spontaneous and naïve faking attempts. (B)IATs might be less prone to faking than implied by previous studies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wolff_et_al.__2015__Implictly_incentiviced_faking_PLOS_journal.pone.0118507.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2732529/2732534/Wolff_et_al.__2015__Implictly_incentiviced_faking_PLOS_journal.pone.0118507.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLoS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">25902142</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000353331500002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27325295</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0118507</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>4</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Wolff, W.; Schindler, S.; Brand, R. (2015): The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,10:(4):e0118507</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Wolff, S.  Schindler, and R.  Brand, “The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : e0118507.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wolff, W., Schindler, S., &amp;amp; Brand, R. (2015). The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4), e0118507. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0118507&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Wolff, W., Schindler, S., &amp;amp; Brand, R., 2015. The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 10(4): e0118507.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wolff W, Schindler S, Brand R (2015) &lt;br /&gt;The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping.&lt;br /&gt;PLoS ONE 10(4): e0118507.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wolff, W., Schindler, S. &amp;amp; Brand, R. (2015). The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4): e0118507. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0118507.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wolff, W., Schindler, S., and Brand, R. (2015). The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10:e0118507.</frontiers>
<ama>Wolff W, Schindler S, Brand R. The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;10(4): e0118507.</ama>
<ieee> W. Wolff, S. Schindler, and R. Brand, “The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2015, : e0118507.</ieee>
<apa>Wolff, W., Schindler, S., &amp;amp; Brand, R. (2015). The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4), e0118507. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0118507</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wolff, Wanja, Schindler, Sebastian, and Brand, Ralf. 2015. “The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10 (4): e0118507.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wolff, W., Schindler, S., Brand, R.: The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping. PLoS ONE. 10, : e0118507 (2015).</lncs>
<default>Wolff W, Schindler S, Brand R (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10(4): e0118507.</default>
<mla>Wolff, Wanja, Schindler, Sebastian, and Brand, Ralf. “The Effect of Implicitly Incentivized Faking on Explicit and Implicit Measures of Doping Attitude: When Athletes Want to Pretend an Even More Negative Attitude to Doping”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10.4 (2015): e0118507.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2732529</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-04-25T12:11:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>