<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2732804</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Casey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kennington</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="KenningtonSchlangen2015ACL.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2732804/2764622/KenningtonSchlangen2015ACL.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Beijing, China</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27328042</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">292-301</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kennington C, Schlangen D (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL). Association for Computational Linguistics:  292-301.</default>
<frontiers>Kennington, C., and Schlangen, D. (2015). “Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt; (Association for Computational Linguistics), 292-301.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 292-301. Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kennington, Casey, and Schlangen, David. “Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics, 2015. 292-301.</mla>
<wels>Kennington, C.; Schlangen, D. (2015): Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. In: Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL). Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 292-301.</wels>
<apa>Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 292-301. Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<ieee> C. Kennington and D. Schlangen, “Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;, Association for Computational Linguistics, 2015,  pp.292-301.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2015. Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;.  Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 292-301.</harvard1>
<bio1>Kennington C, Schlangen D (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL).  Association for Computational Linguistics:  292-301.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kennington, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;, Association For Computational Linguistics, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 292-301.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, C. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2015). Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 292-301). Gehalten auf der Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kennington, Casey, and Schlangen, David. 2015. “Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 292-301. Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kennington, C., Schlangen, D.: Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL). p. 292-301. Association for Computational Linguistics (2015).</lncs>
<ama>Kennington C, Schlangen D. Simple Learning and Compositional Application of Perceptually Grounded Word Meanings for Incremental Reference Resolution. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Conference for the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics;  2015: 292-301.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2732804</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-04-27T09:58:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>