<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2758874</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:796</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bodo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ungerechts</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">191073</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cesarini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vanessa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiebel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart><namePart type="family">Daly</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10027</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Leuven_ears_drivehands_abs_BUng_DCes.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2758874/2766477/Leuven_ears_drivehands_abs_BUng_DCes.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Leuven</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27588745</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">61-61</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Ungerechts, B., Cesarini, D., Wiebel, V., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In D.  Daly (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 61-61). Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences.</apa>
<ieee> B. Ungerechts, et al., “Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation”, &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;, D. Daly, ed.,  Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, 2015,  pp.61-61.</ieee>
<ama>Ungerechts B, Cesarini D, Wiebel V, Hermann T. Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In: Daly D, ed. &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;. Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences;  2015: 61-61.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ungerechts, B., Cesarini, D., Wiebel, V. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In D. Daly (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt; (S. 61-61). Gehalten auf der European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Ungerechts, B., Cesarini, D., Wiebel, V., and Hermann, T. (2015). “Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation” in &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;, Daly, D. ed. (Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences), 61-61.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Ungerechts, B., et al., 2015. Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In D.  Daly, ed. &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;.  Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, pp. 61-61.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ungerechts B, Cesarini D, Wiebel V, Hermann T (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015. Daly D (Ed); Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences:  61-61.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ungerechts, B., Cesarini, D., Wiebel, V., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2015). Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In D.  Daly (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 61-61). Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Ungerechts, D.  Cesarini, V.  Wiebel, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: D. Daly), Kuleuven, Faculty Of Kinesiology And Rehabilitation Sciences, Leuven, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 61-61.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Ungerechts, B.; Cesarini, D.; Wiebel, V.; Hermann, T. (2015): Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In: Daniel Daly (Hrsg.):  Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015. Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences.  S. 61-61.</wels>
<mla>Ungerechts, Bodo, Cesarini, Daniel, Wiebel, Vanessa, and Hermann, Thomas. “Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation”. &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Daniel Daly. Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, 2015. 61-61.</mla>
<default>Ungerechts B, Cesarini D, Wiebel V, Hermann T (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015. Daly D (Ed);  Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences:  61-61.</default>
<lncs> Ungerechts, B., Cesarini, D., Wiebel, V., Hermann, T.: Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation. In: Daly, D. (ed.) Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015. p. 61-61. KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, Leuven (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ungerechts, Bodo, Cesarini, Daniel, Wiebel, Vanessa, and Hermann, Thomas. 2015. “Ears drive hands. Sonification of liquid effects induced by aquatic space activities contributes to cognitive representation”. In &lt;em&gt;Abstracts Book of the Second European Conference on Evidence Based Aquatic Therapy, AQUA-LEUVEN 2015&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Daniel Daly, 61-61. Leuven: KULeuven, Faculty of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2758874</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-06-24T06:34:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>