<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2759297</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pausch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27030162</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mareike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reimann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40670923</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8007-4840</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abendroth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27919701</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Diewald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">124110</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688499</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This study investigates the complex interplay between couples’ work and private life spheres and disentangles how demands and resources affect partners’ satisfaction with their work-life balance. Next to the individual process of spillover of workplace demands and resources to the private life sphere we investigate processes of crossover of one spouse’s demands and resources to the other. We particularly argue that within partnerships an accumulation of individual demands and resources from both partners takes place leading to specifically disadvantaged situations, when it comes to demands, and specifically advantaged situations, when it comes to resources. Furthermore we investigate gender differences in the relevance of spillover, crossover and accumulation for a satisfying work-life balance. We make use of a German Linked Employer-Employee Panel Survey (LEEP-B3), which includes information on 100 work organizations, 6,454 employees, and their partners (2,185). Our results mainly support the spillover of demands and resources from work to private life meaning that workplace demands make integrating work and private life more difficult whereas workplace resources can help reaching a satisfying work-life balance more easily. The results also partly support the hypothesized crossover of demands and resources from one partner to the other. However, there is no such clear-cut picture for the accumulation of demands and resources within partnerships.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0054_Pausch_Reimann_Abendroth_Diewald.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2759297/2759321/SFB_882_WP_0054_Pausch_Reimann_Abendroth_Diewald.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>work-life balance</topic><topic>dual-earner couples</topic><topic>job demands and resources</topic><topic>spillover</topic><topic>crossover</topic><topic>partnerships</topic><topic>cumulative advantages and disadvantages</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27592973</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>54</number></detail><extent unit="pages">39</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Pausch S, Reimann M, Abendroth A, Diewald M (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 54.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<mla>Pausch, Stephanie, Reimann, Mareike, Abendroth, Anja, and Diewald, Martin. &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 54.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pausch, Stephanie, Reimann, Mareike, Abendroth, Anja, and Diewald, Martin. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 54. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pausch, S., Reimann, M., Abendroth, A., Diewald, M.: Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships? SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 54. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Pausch, M.  Reimann, A.  Abendroth, and M.  Diewald, &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Pausch S, Reimann M, Abendroth A, Diewald M (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 54.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Pausch, S., et al., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.54, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pausch, S., Reimann, M., Abendroth, A., &amp;amp; Diewald, M. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 54). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Pausch, S.; Reimann, M.; Abendroth, A.; Diewald, M. (2015): Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<ieee> S. Pausch, et al., &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 54,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Pausch, S., Reimann, M., Abendroth, A., &amp;amp; Diewald, M. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 54). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pausch, S., Reimann, M., Abendroth, A. &amp;amp; Diewald, M. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pausch, S., Reimann, M., Abendroth, A., and Diewald, M. (2015). Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships? &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 54, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<ama>Pausch S, Reimann M, Abendroth A, Diewald M. &lt;em&gt;Work-life balance of dual-earner couples: Do advantages and disadvantages of workplace demands and resources accumulate within partnerships?&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 54. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2759297</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-06-25T12:11:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>