<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2763862</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Spiros</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Georgiladakis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15477016</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7306-3262</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Iosif</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Walter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32983951</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8589-8715</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Euripides</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Petrakis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandros</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Potamianos</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Using different sources of information for grammar induction results in grammars that vary in coverage and precision. Fusing such grammars with a strategy that exploits their strengths while minimizing their weaknesses is expected to produce grammars with superior performance. We focus on the fusion of grammars produced using a knowledge-based approach using lexicalized ontologies and a data-driven approach using semantic similarity clustering. We propose various algorithms for finding the map- ping between the (non-terminal) rules generated by each gram- mar induction algorithm, followed by rule fusion. Three fusion approaches are investigated: early, mid and late fusion. Results show that late fusion provides the best relative F-measure per- formance improvement by 20%.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="InterSpeech14.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2763862/2763870/InterSpeech14.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>spoken dialogue systems</topic><topic>corpus-based grammar induction</topic><topic>ontology-based grammar induction</topic><topic>grammar fusion</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27638625</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Georgiladakis, S., et al., 2014. Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. In &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Georgiladakis, et al., “Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction”, &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Georgiladakis, S., Unger, C., Iosif, E., Walter, S., Cimiano, P., Petrakis, E., &amp;amp; Potamianos, A. (2014). Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<wels>Georgiladakis, S.; Unger, C.; Iosif, E.; Walter, S.; Cimiano, P.; Petrakis, E.; Potamianos, A. (2014): Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. In: Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Georgiladakis, S., Unger, C., Iosif, E., Walter, S., Cimiano, P., Petrakis, E., &amp;amp; Potamianos, A. (2014). Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Georgiladakis, Spiros, Unger, Christina, Iosif, Elias, Walter, Sebastian, Cimiano, Philipp, Petrakis, Euripides, and Potamianos, Alexandros. “Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction”. &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;. 2014.</mla>
<frontiers>Georgiladakis, S., Unger, C., Iosif, E., Walter, S., Cimiano, P., Petrakis, E., and Potamianos, A. (2014). “Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction” in &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<default>Georgiladakis S, Unger C, Iosif E, Walter S, Cimiano P, Petrakis E, Potamianos A (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association.</default>
<ama>Georgiladakis S, Unger C, Iosif E, et al. Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. In:  &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;. 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Georgiladakis, Spiros, Unger, Christina, Iosif, Elias, Walter, Sebastian, Cimiano, Philipp, Petrakis, Euripides, and Potamianos, Alexandros. 2014. “Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction”. In &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Georgiladakis, S., Unger, C., Iosif, E., Walter, S., Cimiano, P., Petrakis, E., Potamianos, A.: Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association.  (2014).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Georgiladakis, S., Unger, C., Iosif, E., Walter, S., Cimiano, P., Petrakis, E. &amp;amp; Potamianos, A. (2014). Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Georgiladakis, C.  Unger, E.  Iosif, S.  Walter, P.  Cimiano, E.  Petrakis, and A.  Potamianos, in &lt;em&gt;Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Georgiladakis S, Unger C, Iosif E, Walter S, Cimiano P, Petrakis E, Potamianos A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Fusion of Knowledge-Based and Data-Driven Approaches to Grammar Induction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Fifteenth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association. .</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2763862</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-07-17T16:53:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>