<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2763174</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Inger M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Janssen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ansgar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gerhardus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gero</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">von Gersdorff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schaller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fueloep</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Scheibler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Conrad</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Baldamus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>














<abstract lang="eng">Background: Chronic kidney disease is an increasing health problem worldwide and in its final stage (stage V) can only be treated by renal replacement therapy, mostly hemodialysis. Hemodialysis has a major influence on the everyday life of patients and many patients report dissatisfaction with treatment. Little is known about which aspects of treatment are considered important by hemodialysis patients. The objective of this study was to rate the relative importance of different outcomes for hemodialysis patients and to analyze whether the relative importance differed among subgroups of patients.
Patients and methods: Within the framework of a yearly questionnaire which is distributed among patients receiving hemodialysis by the largest hemodialysis provider in Germany, we assessed the relative importance of 23 outcomes as rated on a discrete visual analog scale. Descriptive statistics were used to rank the outcomes. Subgroup analyses were performed using Mann–Whitney U or Kruskal–Wallis tests.
Results: Questionnaires of 4,518 hemodialysis patients were included in the analysis. The three most important outcomes were safety of treatment, health-related quality of life, and satisfaction with care. Further important outcomes were hospital stays, accompanying symptoms, hemodialysis duration, and the improvement or preservation of a good emotional state. Age, profession, and education had the strongest influence on relevant differences of preferences for outcomes; no relevant influence of sex or comorbidity was observed.
Conclusion: Outcomes concerning the delivery or provision of care and aspects influencing quality of life are rated by patients to be at least as important as clinical outcomes. Many of the outcomes judged to be important by the patients are not regularly considered in research, evaluation studies, or quality programs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PPA-79559-preferences-of-patients-undergoing-hemodialysis-----results-_062615.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2763174/2778931/PPA-79559-preferences-of-patients-undergoing-hemodialysis-----results-_062615.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Dove Medical Press Ltd.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>preference elicitation</topic><topic>patient-centered outcomes</topic><topic>rating scale</topic><topic>patient-centered research</topic><topic>chronic disease</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Patient Preference and Adherence</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1177-889X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26170634</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000357030000001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27631745</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.2147/PPA.S79559</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2015</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>9</number></detail><extent unit="pages">847-855</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Janssen, I.M., Gerhardus, A., von Gersdorff, G., Schaller, M., Barth, C., Scheibler, F. &amp;amp; Baldamus, C. (2015). Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2015&lt;/em&gt;(9), 847-855. Dove Medical Press Ltd. doi:10.2147/PPA.S79559.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>I. M.  Janssen, A.  Gerhardus, G.  von Gersdorff, M.  Schaller, C.  Barth, F.  Scheibler, and C.  Baldamus, “Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients”, &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2015&lt;/em&gt;, 847-855.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Janssen IM, Gerhardus A, von Gersdorff G, Schaller M, Barth C, Scheibler F, Baldamus C (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients.&lt;br /&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence 2015(9): 847-855.</bio1>
<ama>Janssen IM, Gerhardus A, von Gersdorff G, et al. Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;2015(9):847-855.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Janssen, Inger M., Gerhardus, Ansgar, von Gersdorff, Gero, Schaller, Mathias, Barth, Claudia, Scheibler, Fueloep, and Baldamus, Conrad. 2015. “Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients”. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt; 2015 (9): 847-855.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Janssen, I.M., Gerhardus, A., von Gersdorff, G., Schaller, M., Barth, C., Scheibler, F., Baldamus, C.: Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. Patient Preference and Adherence. 2015, 847-855 (2015).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Janssen, I. M., Gerhardus, A., von Gersdorff, G., Schaller, M., Barth, C., Scheibler, F., &amp;amp; Baldamus, C. (2015). Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2015&lt;/em&gt;(9), 847-855. doi:10.2147/PPA.S79559&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Janssen, I. M., Gerhardus, A., von Gersdorff, G., Schaller, M., Barth, C., Scheibler, F., and Baldamus, C. (2015). Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt; 2015, 847-855.</frontiers>
<mla>Janssen, Inger M., Gerhardus, Ansgar, von Gersdorff, Gero, Schaller, Mathias, Barth, Claudia, Scheibler, Fueloep, and Baldamus, Conrad. “Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients”. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt; 2015.9 (2015): 847-855.</mla>
<wels>Janssen, I. M.; Gerhardus, A.; von Gersdorff, G.; Schaller, M.; Barth, C.; Scheibler, F.; Baldamus, C. (2015): Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;,2015:(9): 847-855.</wels>
<default>Janssen IM, Gerhardus A, von Gersdorff G, Schaller M, Barth C, Scheibler F, Baldamus C (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt; 2015(9): 847-855.</default>
<harvard1>Janssen, I.M., et al., 2015. Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;, 2015(9), p 847-855.</harvard1>
<ieee> I.M. Janssen, et al., “Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients”, &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 2015, 2015,  pp. 847-855.</ieee>
<apa>Janssen, I. M., Gerhardus, A., von Gersdorff, G., Schaller, M., Barth, C., Scheibler, F., &amp;amp; Baldamus, C. (2015). Preferences of patients undergoing hemodialysis - results from a questionnaire-based study with 4,518 patients. &lt;em&gt;Patient Preference and Adherence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2015&lt;/em&gt;(9), 847-855. doi:10.2147/PPA.S79559</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2763174</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-07-14T07:08:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-05-29T09:13:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>