<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2766749</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nalin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harischandra</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27820520</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">André Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krause</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">165785</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dürr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21971</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9239-4964</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685507</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Embodied Motion Intelligence for Cognitive, Autonomous Robots</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">An essential component of autonomous and flexible behaviour in animals is active exploration of the environment, allowing for perception-guided planning and control of actions. An important sensory system involved is active touch. Here, we introduce a general modelling framework of Central Pattern Generators (CPGs) for movement generation in active tactile exploration behaviour. The CPG consists of two network levels: (i) phase-coupled Hopf oscillators for rhythm generation, and (ii) pattern formation networks for capturing the frequency and phase characteristics of individual joint oscillations. The model captured the natural, quasi-rhythmic joint kinematics as observed in coordinated antennal movements of walking stick insects. Moreover, it successfully produced tactile exploration behaviour on a three-dimensional skeletal model of the insect antennal system with physically realistic parameters. The effect of proprioceptor ablations could be simulated by changing the amplitude and offset parameters of the joint oscillators, only. As in the animal, the movement of both antennal joints was coupled with a stable phase difference, despite the quasi-rhythmicity of the joint angle time courses. We found that the phase-lead of the distal scape-pedicel joint relative to the proximal head-scape joint was essential for producing the natural tactile exploration behaviour and, thus, for tactile efficiency. For realistic movement patterns, the phase-lead could vary within a limited range of 10 to 30 degrees only. Tests with artificial movement patterns strongly suggest that this phase sensitivity is not a matter of the frequency composition of the natural movement pattern. Based on our modelling results, we propose that a constant phase difference is coded into the CPG of the antennal motor system and that proprioceptors are acting locally to regulate the joint movement amplitude.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fncom-09-00107.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2766749/2777463/fncom-09-00107.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1662-5188</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26347644</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000360181500001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27667498</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fncom.2015.00107</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Harischandra N, Krause AF, Dürr V. Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;9: 107.</ama>
<ieee> N. Harischandra, A.F. Krause, and V. Dürr, “Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2015, : 107.</ieee>
<harvard1>Harischandra, N., Krause, A.F., &amp;amp; Dürr, V., 2015. Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 9: 107.</harvard1>
<lncs> Harischandra, N., Krause, A.F., Dürr, V.: Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience. 9, : 107 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Harischandra, Nalin, Krause, André Frank, and Dürr, Volker. 2015. “Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 9: 107.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Harischandra, N., Krause, A. F., &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2015). Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 107. doi:10.3389/fncom.2015.00107</apa>
<mla>Harischandra, Nalin, Krause, André Frank, and Dürr, Volker. “Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 9 (2015): 107.</mla>
<frontiers>Harischandra, N., Krause, A. F., and Dürr, V. (2015). Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 9:107.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Harischandra, N., Krause, A. F., &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2015). Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 107. doi:10.3389/fncom.2015.00107&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Harischandra, N., Krause, A.F. &amp;amp; Dürr, V. (2015). Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;: 107. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fncom.2015.00107.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Harischandra, N.; Krause, A. F.; Dürr, V. (2015): Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,9:107</wels>
<bio1>Harischandra N, Krause AF, Dürr V (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience 9: 107.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Harischandra, A. F.  Krause, and V.  Dürr, “Stable phase-shift despite quasi-rhythmic movements: a CPG-driven dynamic model of active tactile exploration in an insect”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, : 107.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Harischandra N, Krause AF, Dürr V (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 9: 107.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2766749</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-08-10T08:41:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:54:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>