<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2768330</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simone</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26709954</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hawal</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Shamon</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688381</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">While it is generally agreed that individuals compare themselves with others when assessing their earnings, little is known about the duality/interaction of contextual and individual forces with regard to justice evaluations. This study combines a proposition of judgment theory, i.e. range-frequency theory, with sociological justice theories and examines, in an organizational setting, whether employees base their justice evaluation of their own earnings on the income distribution they are surrounded by and/or their personal ranking within the income hierarchy. It argues that both the range of incomes in the organization as well as the person’s ranking influence how a person evaluates their income. The empirical analysis is based on 636 full-time and part-time employees in Germany who participated in a factorial survey that was integrated into a larger representative survey study of German employees. Respondents were asked to evaluate their income after they were given information on the incomes of others and their personal position/rank in the income hierarchy. In line with the theoretical reasoning, this paper finds that employees base their justice evaluations on both range and rank. It finds the effects to be equally strong and both effects add to each other in terms of absolute values.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0044_Schneider_Shamon.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2768330/2768334/SFB_882_WP_0044_Schneider_Shamon.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Experiment</topic><topic>Factorial Survey</topic><topic>Social Position</topic><topic>Income Inequality</topic><topic>Income Justice</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27683309</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>44</number></detail><extent unit="pages">35</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Schneider, Simone, and Shamon, Hawal. &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 44.</mla>
<default>Schneider S, Shamon H (2015)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 44.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<lncs> Schneider, S., Shamon, H.: How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 44. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, Simone, and Shamon, Hawal. 2015. &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 44. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Shamon, H. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 44). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<ieee> S. Schneider and H. Shamon, &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 44,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2015.</ieee>
<ama>Schneider S, Shamon H. &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 44. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2015.</ama>
<frontiers>Schneider, S., and Shamon, H. (2015). How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 44, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, S. &amp;amp; Shamon, H. (2015). &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Shamon, H. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 44). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Schneider S, Shamon H (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 44.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<harvard1>Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Shamon, H., 2015. &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.44, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Schneider, and H.  Shamon, &lt;em&gt;How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Schneider, S.; Shamon, H. (2015): How others' earnings influence our justice perceptions: studying the effects of income distribution and social position on reflexive justice evaluations among German employees. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2768330</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-08-14T12:38:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>