<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2768618</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wegrzyn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31315167</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabelle</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruckhaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kißler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27325660</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33695</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Human observers are remarkably proficient at recognizing expressions of emotions and at readily grouping them into distinct categories. When morphing one facial expression into another, the linear changes in low-level features are insufficient to describe the changes in perception, which instead follow an s-shaped function. Important questions are, whether there are single diagnostic regions in the face that drive categorical perception for certain parings of emotion expressions, and how information in those regions interacts when presented together. We report results from two experiments with morphed fear-anger expressions, where (a) half of the face was masked or (b) composite faces made up of different expressions were presented. When isolated upper and lower halves of faces were shown, the eyes were found to be almost as diagnostic as the whole face, with the response function showing a steep category boundary. In contrast, the mouth allowed for a substantially lesser amount of accuracy and responses followed a much flatter psychometric function. When a composite face consisting of mismatched upper and lower halves was used and observers were instructed to exclusively judge either the expression of mouth or eyes, the to-be-ignored part always influenced perception of the target region. In line with experiment 1, the eye region exerted a much stronger influence on mouth judgements than vice versa. Again, categorical perception was significantly more pronounced for upper halves of faces. The present study shows that identification of fear and anger in morphed faces relies heavily on information from the upper half of the face, most likely the eye region. Categorical perception is possible when only the upper face half is present, but compromised when only the lower part is shown. Moreover, observers tend to integrate all available features of a face, even when trying to focus on only one part.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0134790.Wegrzyn.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2768618/2768623/journal.pone.0134790.Wegrzyn.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLoS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26263000</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000359353300042</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27686186</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0134790</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Wegrzyn, Martin, Bruckhaus, Isabelle, and Kißler, Johanna. “Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10.8 (2015): e0134790.</mla>
<default>Wegrzyn M, Bruckhaus I, Kißler J (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10(8): e0134790.</default>
<lncs> Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I., Kißler, J.: Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. PLoS ONE. 10, : e0134790 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wegrzyn, Martin, Bruckhaus, Isabelle, and Kißler, Johanna. 2015. “Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10 (8): e0134790.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2015). Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0134790. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0134790</apa>
<ieee> M. Wegrzyn, I. Bruckhaus, and J. Kißler, “Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2015, : e0134790.</ieee>
<ama>Wegrzyn M, Bruckhaus I, Kißler J. Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;10(8): e0134790.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I. &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2015). Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8): e0134790. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0134790.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I., and Kißler, J. (2015). Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10:e0134790.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I., &amp;amp; Kißler, J., 2015. Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 10(8): e0134790.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wegrzyn M, Bruckhaus I, Kißler J (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces.&lt;br /&gt;PLoS ONE 10(8): e0134790.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wegrzyn, M., Bruckhaus, I., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2015). Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0134790. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0134790&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Wegrzyn, I.  Bruckhaus, and J.  Kißler, “Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : e0134790.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Wegrzyn, M.; Bruckhaus, I.; Kißler, J. (2015): Categorical Perception of Fear and Anger Expressions in Whole, Masked and Composite Faces &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,10:(8):e0134790</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2768618</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-08-17T09:35:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>