<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2769347</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ptatscheck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34405502</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Traunspurger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21944</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685511</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objectives

In this study we investigated the dynamics of meiofaunal and macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes. The abundances and, for the first time, biomasses and secondary production rates of these communities were examined. The experimental set-up consisted of 300 brown plastic cups placed in temperate mixed forests and sampled five times over a period of 16 months to determine the impact of (i) seasonal events, (ii) physicochemical parameters, and (iii) food resources on the tree hole metazoans.
Outcomes

Metazoan organisms, especially the meiofauna (rotifers and nematodes) occupied nearly all of the cups (&gt; 99%) throughout the year. Between 55% and 99% of the metazoan community was represented by rotifers (max. 557,000 individuals 100 cm-2) and nematodes (max. 58,000 individuals 100 cm-2). Diptera taxa, particularly Dasyhelea sp. (max. 256 individuals 100 cm-2) dominated the macrofaunal community. Macrofauna accounted for the majority of the metazoan biomass, with a mean dry weight of 5,800 μg 100 cm-2 and an annual production rate of 20,400 μg C 100 cm-2, whereas for meiofauna mean biomass and annual production were 100 μg 100 cm-2 and 5,300 μg C 100 cm-2, respectively. The macrofaunal taxa tended to show more fluctuating population dynamic while the meiofaunal dynamic was rather low with partly asynchronous development. Seasonality (average temperature and rain intervals) had a significant impact on both meiofauna and macrofauna. Furthermore, bottom-up control (chlorophyll-a and organic carbon), mainly attributable to algae, was a significant factor that shaped the metazoan communities. In contrast, physicochemical water parameters had no evident influence. 23.7% of organism density distribution was explained by redundancy analysis (RDA) indicating a high dynamic and asynchrony of the systems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0133447.Ptatscheck.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2769347/2777462/journal.pone.0133447.Ptatscheck.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLoS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26284811</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000359666100003</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27693472</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0133447</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ptatscheck, C. &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2015). Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8): e0133447. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0133447.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ptatscheck, C., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2015). Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0133447. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0133447&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Ptatscheck, C., and Traunspurger, W. (2015). Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10:e0133447.</frontiers>
<mla>Ptatscheck, Christoph, and Traunspurger, Walter. “Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10.8 (2015): e0133447.</mla>
<wels>Ptatscheck, C.; Traunspurger, W. (2015): Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,10:(8):e0133447</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Ptatscheck, and W.  Traunspurger, “Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : e0133447.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ptatscheck C, Traunspurger W (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources.&lt;br /&gt;PLoS ONE 10(8): e0133447.</bio1>
<default>Ptatscheck C, Traunspurger W (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10(8): e0133447.</default>
<ama>Ptatscheck C, Traunspurger W. Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;10(8): e0133447.</ama>
<harvard1>Ptatscheck, C., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W., 2015. Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 10(8): e0133447.</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Ptatscheck and W. Traunspurger, “Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources”, &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2015, : e0133447.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ptatscheck, Christoph, and Traunspurger, Walter. 2015. “Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources”. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 10 (8): e0133447.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ptatscheck, C., Traunspurger, W.: Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. PLoS ONE. 10, : e0133447 (2015).</lncs>
<apa>Ptatscheck, C., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2015). Meio- and Macrofaunal communities in artificial water-filled tree holes: Effects of seasonality, physical and chemical parameters, and availability of food resources. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0133447. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0133447</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2769347</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-08-21T14:45:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>