<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2775519</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Priesters</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46566808</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schilling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">172354</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0849-483X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christine</namePart><namePart type="family">Howes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Staffan</namePart><namePart type="family">Larsson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>19th SemDial Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue (goDIAL)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PriestersEtAl-SemDial-2015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2775519/2775520/PriestersEtAl-SemDial-2015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Gothenburg</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Gothenburg, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2308-2275</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27755199</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">206-207</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Priesters, Matthias, Schilling, Malte, and Kopp, Stefan. 2015. “Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Christine Howes and Staffan Larsson, 206-207. Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Priesters, M., Schilling, M., Kopp, S.: Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In: Howes, C. and Larsson, S. (eds.) Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue. p. 206-207. University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg (2015).</lncs>
<default>Priesters M, Schilling M, Kopp S (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue. Howes C, Larsson S (Eds);  Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg:  206-207.</default>
<mla>Priesters, Matthias, Schilling, Malte, and Kopp, Stefan. “Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Christine Howes and Staffan Larsson. Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg, 2015. 206-207.</mla>
<wels>Priesters, M.; Schilling, M.; Kopp, S. (2015): Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In: Christine Howes; Staffan Larsson (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue. Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg.  S. 206-207.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Priesters, M.  Schilling, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Howes, S. Larsson), University Of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 206-207.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Priesters, M., Schilling, M., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2015). Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In C.  Howes &amp;amp; S.  Larsson (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 206-207). Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Priesters M, Schilling M, Kopp S (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue. Howes C, Larsson S (Eds); Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg:  206-207.</bio1>
<harvard1>Priesters, M., Schilling, M., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2015. Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In C.  Howes &amp;amp; S.  Larsson, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;.  Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg, pp. 206-207.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Priesters, M., Schilling, M., and Kopp, S. (2015). “Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;, Howes, C., and Larsson, S. eds. (Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg), 206-207.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Priesters, M., Schilling, M. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2015). Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In C. Howes &amp;amp; S. Larsson (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt; (S. 206-207). Gehalten auf der 19th SemDial Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue (goDIAL), Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Priesters M, Schilling M, Kopp S. Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In: Howes C, Larsson S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;. Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg;  2015: 206-207.</ama>
<ieee> M. Priesters, M. Schilling, and S. Kopp, “Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;, C. Howes and S. Larsson, eds.,  Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg, 2015,  pp.206-207.</ieee>
<apa>Priesters, M., Schilling, M., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2015). Towards a layered framework for embodied language processing in situated human-robot interaction. In C.  Howes &amp;amp; S.  Larsson (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 206-207). Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2775519</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-09-16T08:44:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>