<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2783432</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zaharieva</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22426124</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">42173282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper incorporates social networks into a frictional labour market framework. There are two worker types and two occupations. Both occupations are subject to correlated
business cycle fluctuations in labour demand. The equilibrium in this model is characterized by occupational mismatch which is associated with a wage penalty. This paper shows that there exists a unique value of network homophily maximizing the present value of income.
Therefore, there is a gain for risk-neutral workers if their network is diversified between the two occupations. The reason for diversification is that the present value of income is a non-linear function of the network composition. Thus, it is not the desire to reduce the
volatility of income as in standard portfolio theory which is driving the decision of workers. Nevertheless, the optimal diversification level is higher with stronger negative correlation in labour demand between the two occupations, with a lower unemployment benefit and with
a higher probability of recession in the primary occupation. On the other hand, the optimal
diversification level is reduced if there is on-the-job search in the state of mismatch.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="547.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2783432/2783433/547.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Occupational mismatch</topic><topic>social networks</topic><topic>homophily</topic><topic>diversification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27834324</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>547</number></detail><extent unit="pages">33</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, Anna. 2015. &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 547. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Zaharieva, A.: On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 547. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<default>Zaharieva A (2015)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 547.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Zaharieva, Anna. &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 547.</mla>
<frontiers>Zaharieva, A. (2015). On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 547, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, A. (2015). &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Zaharieva A. &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 547. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2015.</ama>
<ieee> A. Zaharieva, &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 547,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Zaharieva, A. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 547). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<wels>Zaharieva, A. (2015): On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Zaharieva, &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Zaharieva, A., 2015. &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.547, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, A. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 547). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Zaharieva A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the Puzzle of Diversification in Social Networks with Occupational Mismatch&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 547.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2783432</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-10-27T10:39:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>