<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2783369</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bassam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mokbel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18880650</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34943216</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0739-612X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart><namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Martinetz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Villmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>New Challenges in Neural Computation</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we investigate in how far nonlinear dimensionality reduction (DR) techniques can be utilized to tackle particular challenges of sensor data from smart home environments. Smart homes often contain a large number of sensors of various types, providing output in real time, which results in a sequence of high-dimensional, heterogeneous data vectors. We propose that DR techniques can provide a truthful low-dimensional representation (i.e. a compression) of this kind of data, together with a corresponding reconstruction (i.e. decompression). This yields an automatic fusion of uncoordinated raw sensor signals, as well as an economical storage format, with a certain robustness against sensor failure. In proof-of-concept experiments, we present first empirical results to test our approach based on real-world data.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="MokbelSchulz2015-NC2-DR_for_smart_homes.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2783369/2783385/MokbelSchulz2015-NC2-DR_for_smart_homes.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Aachen</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>dimensionality reduction</topic><topic>low-dimensional representations</topic><topic>sensor data</topic><topic>smart home</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1865-3960</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27833696</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">41-48</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Mokbel, B., Schulz, A.: Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In: Hammer, B., Martinetz, T., and Villmann, T. (eds.) Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015). Machine Learning Reports. p. 41-48. (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, Bassam, and Schulz, Alexander. 2015. “Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Barbara Hammer, Thomas Martinetz, and Thomas Villmann, 41-48. Machine Learning Reports.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Mokbel, Bassam, and Schulz, Alexander. “Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Barbara Hammer, Thomas Martinetz, and Thomas Villmann. 2015. Machine Learning Reports. 41-48.</mla>
<default>Mokbel B, Schulz A (2015)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015). Hammer B, Martinetz T, Villmann T (Eds);  Machine Learning Reports(3).   41-48.</default>
<ama>Mokbel B, Schulz A. Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In: Hammer B, Martinetz T, Villmann T, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. 2015: 41-48.</ama>
<frontiers>Mokbel, B., and Schulz, A. (2015). “Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;, Hammer, B., Martinetz, T., and Villmann, T. eds. Machine Learning Reports 41-48.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B. &amp;amp; Schulz, A. (2015). Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data (Machine Learning Reports). In B. Hammer, T. Martinetz &amp;amp; T. Villmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 41-48). Gehalten auf der New Challenges in Neural Computation.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Schulz, A. (2015). Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In B.  Hammer, T.  Martinetz, &amp;amp; T.  Villmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Machine Learning Reports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 41-48).</apa>
<ieee> B. Mokbel and A. Schulz, “Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;, B. Hammer, T. Martinetz, and T. Villmann, eds., Machine Learning Reports, 2015,  pp.41-48.</ieee>
<wels>Mokbel, B.; Schulz, A. (2015): Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In: Barbara Hammer; Thomas Martinetz; Thomas Villmann (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015). (Machine Learning Reports, ).  S. 41-48.</wels>
<harvard1>Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Schulz, A., 2015. Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In B.  Hammer, T.  Martinetz, &amp;amp; T.  Villmann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. pp. 41-48.</harvard1>
<bio1>Mokbel B, Schulz A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015). Hammer B, Martinetz T, Villmann T (Eds); Machine Learning Reports,  41-48.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mokbel, B., &amp;amp; Schulz, A. (2015). Towards Dimensionality Reduction for Smart Home Sensor Data. In B.  Hammer, T.  Martinetz, &amp;amp; T.  Villmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Machine Learning Reports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 41-48).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Mokbel, and A.  Schulz, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC² 2015)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Hammer, T. Martinetz, T. Villmann), &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 41-48.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2783369</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-10-26T14:59:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>