<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2788391</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herzberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies collective decision making with regard to convex
risk measures: It addresses the question whether there exist nondictatorial
aggregation functions of convex risk measures satisfying
Arrow-type rationality axioms (weak universality, systematicity, Pareto
principle). Herein, convex risk measures are identified with variational
preferences on account of the Maccheroni-Marinacci-Rustichini (2006)
axiomatisation of variational preference relations and the Föllmer-
Schied (2002, 2004) representation theorem for concave monetary utility
functionals.
We prove a variational analogue of Arrow's impossibility theorem
for finite electorates. For infinite electorates, the possibility of rational
aggregation depends on a uniform continuity condition for the variational
preference profiles; we prove variational analogues of both Campbell's
impossibility theorem and Fishburn's possibility theorem. The proof
methodology is based on a model-theoretic approach to aggregation theory
inspired by Lauwers-Van Liedekerke (1995).
An appendix applies the Dietrich-List (2010) analysis of majority
voting to the problem of variational preference aggregation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_432.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2788391/2788392/IMW_working_paper_432.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>convex risk measure</topic><topic>multiple priorspreferences</topic><topic>variational preferences</topic><topic>abstract aggregation theory</topic><topic>judgment aggregation</topic><topic>Arrow-type preference aggregation</topic><topic>model theory</topic><topic>first-order predicate logic</topic><topic>ultraproduct</topic><topic>ultrafilter</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-27883912</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>432</number></detail><extent unit="pages">22</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Herzberg F (2010)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 432.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Herzberg, Frederik. &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2010. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 432.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, Frederik. 2010. &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 432. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herzberg, F.: Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 432. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2010).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Herzberg, F., 2010. &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.432, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Herzberg F (2010) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 432.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 432). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Herzberg, F. (2010): Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<ieee> F. Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 432,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2010.</ieee>
<apa>Herzberg, F. (2010).  &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 432). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Herzberg, F. (2010). Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 432, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Herzberg F. &lt;em&gt;Social choice of convex risk measures through Arrovian aggregation of variational preferences&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 432. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2010.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2788391</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-03T15:22:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>