<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2788146</id><setSpec>research_data</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:ResearchData</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>research_dataFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>database</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Janet Junqing</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objectives	
University students in general face multiple challenges, which may affect their levels of perceived stress and life satisfaction. Chinese students currently face specific strains due to the One-Child Policy (OCP). The aim of this study was to assess (1) whether the levels of perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction are associated with only-child (OC) status after controlling for demographic, socio-economic and lifestyle-related characteristics and (2) whether these associations differ between Chinese and international students.
Materials and Methods
A cross-sectional health survey based on a standardised questionnaire was conducted among 1,843 (1,543 Chinese, 300 international) students at two Chinese universities in 2010-2011. Cohen’ PSS-14, Stock and Kraemer’s Studying-related life satisfaction scale were used to measure perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction respectively. Multivariable logistic regression analyses were used to examine the associations of OC status by sex with perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction for Chinese students and international students separately.
Results
The Chinese NOC students were more likely from small cities. Multivariable regression models indicated that among the Chinese students, NOCs were more stressed (OR = 1.39, 1.11-1.74) than OCs with higher impact on men (OR = 1.48, 1.08-2.02) than women (OR = 1.26, 0.89-1.77); NOCs were also more dissatisfied (OR = 1.37, 1.09-1.73) than their OC fellows. Among international students, no associations between OC status and perceived stress or studying-related life satisfaction were found. 
Conclusions
To promote equality between OCs and NOCs at Chinese universities, the causes of more stress and less studying-related life satisfaction among NOCs compared to OCs need further exploration.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="University_student_health_in_China.sav">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2788146/2788147/University_student_health_in_China.sav</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-spss-sav</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://opendatacommons.org/licenses/pddl/summary/index.html</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>satisfaction</topic><topic>perceived stress</topic><topic>Student health</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2788146</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, J.J. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2788146.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J. J.  Chu, &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Chu JJ (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<ama>Chu JJ. &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University; 2015.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, Janet Junqing. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Chu, J.J.: Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. Bielefeld University (2015).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, J. J. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2788146&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Chu, Janet Junqing. &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University, 2015.</mla>
<frontiers>Chu, J. J. (2015). Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<wels>Chu, J. J. (2015): Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Chu JJ (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</default>
<harvard1>Chu, J.J., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> J.J. Chu, &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, 2015.</ieee>
<apa>Chu, J. J. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2788146</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2788146</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-02T09:18:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>