<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900327</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Glüer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">30231209</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arnold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lohaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">174992</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33696</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Victimization is associated with negative developmental outcomes in childhood and adolescence. However, previous studies have provided mixed results regarding the association between offline and online victimization and indicators of social, psychological, and somatic well-being. In this study, we investigated 1,890 German children and adolescents (grades 5–10, mean age = 13.9; SD = 2.1) with and without offline or online victimization experiences who participated in a social online network (SNS). Online questionnaires were used to assess previous victimization (offline, online, combined, and without), somatic and psychological symptoms, self-esteem, and social self-concept (social competence, resistance to peer influence, esteem by others). In total, 1,362 (72.1%) children and adolescents reported being a member of at least one SNS, and 377 students (28.8%) reported previous victimization. Most children and adolescents had offline victimization experiences (17.5%), whereas 2.7% reported online victimization, and 8.6% reported combined experiences. Girls reported more online and combined victimization, and boys reported more offline victimization. The type of victimization (offline, online, combined) was associated with increased reports of psychological and somatic symptoms, lower self-esteem and esteem by others, and lower resistance to peer influences. The effects were comparable for the groups with offline and online victimization. They were, however, increased in the combined group in comparison to victims with offline experiences alone.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpubh-03-00274.glueer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900327/2900328/fpubh-03-00274.glueer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2296-2565</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26734598</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000498912900214</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29003278</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2015.00274</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Glüer, M., Lohaus, A.: Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. Frontiers in Public Health. 3, : 274 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Glüer, Michael, and Lohaus, Arnold. 2015. “Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 3: 274.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Glüer, Michael, and Lohaus, Arnold. “Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 3 (2015): 274.</mla>
<default>Glüer M, Lohaus A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 3: 274.</default>
<wels>Glüer, M.; Lohaus, A. (2015): Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,3:274</wels>
<bio1>Glüer M, Lohaus A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Public Health 3: 274.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Glüer, M., &amp;amp; Lohaus, A. (2015). Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 274. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2015.00274&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Glüer, M., &amp;amp; Lohaus, A., 2015. Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 3: 274.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Glüer, and A.  Lohaus, “Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, : 274.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Glüer M, Lohaus A. Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;3: 274.</ama>
<frontiers>Glüer, M., and Lohaus, A. (2015). Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 3:274.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Glüer, M. &amp;amp; Lohaus, A. (2015). Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;: 274. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2015.00274.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Glüer, M., &amp;amp; Lohaus, A. (2015). Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 274. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2015.00274</apa>
<ieee> M. Glüer and A. Lohaus, “Frequency of Victimization Experiences and Well-Being Among Online, Offline, and Combined Victims on Social Online Network Sites of German Children and Adolescents”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 3, 2015, : 274.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900327</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-13T10:35:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>