<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900053</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beißner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26462239</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper establishes, in the setting of Brownian information, a
general equilibrium existence result under a stochastic differential for-
mulation of intertemporal recursive utility. The present class of utility
functionals is generated by a backward stochastic differential equation
and incorporates preference for the local risk of the stochastic utility
process.
The setting contains models in which Knightian uncertainty is repre-
sented in the subjective and objective sense.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_447.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900053/2900054/IMW_working_paper_447.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>BSDE</topic><topic>GSDU</topic><topic>super-gradients</topic><topic>properness</topic><topic>general equilibrium</topic><topic>Knightian uncertainty</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29000533</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>447</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Beißner, P. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics., 447). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> P. Beißner, &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics., vol. 447,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011.</ieee>
<ama>Beißner P. &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 447. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2011.</ama>
<frontiers>Beißner, P. (2011). Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics.&lt;/em&gt;, 447, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beißner, P. (2011). &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Beißner, P., 2011. &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics., no.447, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Beißner P (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics.; 447.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beißner, P. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics., 447). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Beißner, &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Beißner, P. (2011): Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<mla>Beißner, Patrick. &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 447.</mla>
<default>Beißner P (2011)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics.; 447.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<lncs> Beißner, P.: Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics., 447. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Beißner, Patrick. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Existence of Arrow-Debreu Equilibrium with Generalized Stochastic Differential Utility&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 447. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900053</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-11T15:40:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>