<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900168</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cem</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Memili</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ETRA 2016</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Heat maps, or more generally, attention maps or saliency maps are an often used technique to visualize eye-tracking data. With heat maps qualitative information about visual processing can be easily visualized and communicated between experts and laymen. They are thus a versatile tool for many disciplines, in particular for usability engineering, and are often used to get a first overview about recorded eye-tracking data.

Today, heat maps are typically generated for 2D stimuli that have been presented on a computer display. In such cases the mapping of overt visual attention on the stimulus is rather straight forward and the process is well understood. However, when turning towards mobile eye tracking and eye tracking in 3D virtual environments, the case is much more complicated. 

In the first part of the paper, we discuss several challenges that have to be considered in 3D environments, such as changing perspectives, multiple viewers, object occlusions, depth of fixations, or dynamically moving objects. In the second part, we present an approach for the generation of 3D heat maps addressing the above mentioned issues while working in real-time. Our visualizations provide high-quality output for multi-perspective eye-tracking recordings of visual attention in 3D environments.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Pfeiffer_Memili_-_Model-based_Real-Time_Visualization_of_Realistic_Three-Dimensional_Heat_Maps.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900168/2902235/Pfeiffer_Memili_-_Model-based_Real-Time_Visualization_of_Realistic_Three-Dimensional_Heat_Maps.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACM Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Charleston, SC, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Eyetracking</topic><topic>Gaze-based Interaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp; Applications</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4503-4125-7/16/03</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29001685</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1145/2857491.2857541</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">95-102</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://etra2016heatmap.eyemovementresearch.com/</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> T. Pfeiffer and C. Memili, “Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;,  New York, NY, USA: ACM Press, 2016,  pp.95-102.</ieee>
<apa>Pfeiffer, T., &amp;amp; Memili, C. (2016). Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 95-102. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145/2857491.2857541</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T. &amp;amp; Memili, C. (2016). Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt; (S. 95-102). Gehalten auf der ETRA 2016, New York, NY, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145/2857491.2857541.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Pfeiffer, T., and Memili, C. (2016). “Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt; (New York, NY, USA: ACM Press), 95-102.</frontiers>
<ama>Pfeiffer T, Memili C. Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press;  2016: 95-102.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Pfeiffer, and C.  Memili, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;, Acm Press, New York, NY, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 95-102.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Pfeiffer, T., &amp;amp; Memili, C., 2016. Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;.  New York, NY, USA: ACM Press, pp. 95-102.</harvard1>
<bio1>Pfeiffer T, Memili C (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications.  New York, NY, USA: ACM Press:  95-102.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, T., &amp;amp; Memili, C. (2016). Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 95-102. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145/2857491.2857541&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Pfeiffer, T.; Memili, C. (2016): Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. In: Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press.  S. 95-102.</wels>
<default>Pfeiffer T, Memili C (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press:  95-102.</default>
<mla>Pfeiffer, Thies, and Memili, Cem. “Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press, 2016. 95-102.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pfeiffer, Thies, and Memili, Cem. 2016. “Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 95-102. New York, NY, USA: ACM Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pfeiffer, T., Memili, C.: Model-based Real-time Visualization of Realistic Three-Dimensional Heat Maps for Mobile Eye Tracking and Eye Tracking in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the Ninth Biennial ACM Symposium on Eye Tracking Research &amp;amp; Applications. p. 95-102. ACM Press, New York, NY, USA (2016).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900168</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-21T15:00:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>