<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900961</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harry</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haupt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6141079</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Verena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Classical growth convergence regressions fail to account for various sources
of heterogeneity and nonlinearity. While recent contributions are able to address either
the one or the other, we present a simple two-step method to address both issues. Based
on a slightly augmented version of a recently proposed algorithm to identify convergence
clubs, we formulate a flexible nonlinear framework which allows to analyze convergence
effects on both individual and club level, while alleviating potential misclassification in
the club formation process using simultaneous smoothing over the club structure. The
merits of the method are illustrated for data on different aggregational levels.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_455.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900961/2900962/IMW_working_paper_455.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29009614</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>455</number></detail><extent unit="pages">47</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://doi.org/10.1002/jae.2544</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Haupt, H., &amp;amp; Meier, V., 2011. &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.455, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Haupt H, Meier V (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 455.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haupt, H., &amp;amp; Meier, V. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 455). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Haupt, and V.  Meier, &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Haupt, H.; Meier, V. (2011): Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa>Haupt, H., &amp;amp; Meier, V. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 455). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> H. Haupt and V. Meier, &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 455,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011.</ieee>
<ama>Haupt H, Meier V. &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 455. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2011.</ama>
<frontiers>Haupt, H., and Meier, V. (2011). Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 455, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haupt, H. &amp;amp; Meier, V. (2011). &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Haupt, Harry, and Meier, Verena. &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 455.</mla>
<default>Haupt H, Meier V (2011)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 455.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<lncs> Haupt, H., Meier, V.: Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 455. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haupt, Harry, and Meier, Verena. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Dealing with heterogeneity, nonlinearity and club misclassification in growth convergence: A nonparametric two-step approach&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 455. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900961</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-11T14:06:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>