<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900480</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29415012</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jacco J.J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thijssen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we study a two–player investment game with a first mover advantage in continuous time
with stochastic payoffs, driven by a geometric Brownian motion. One of the players is assumed to be
ambiguous with max–min preferences over a strongly rectangular set of priors. We develop a strategy
and equilibrium concept allowing for ambiguity and show that equilibria can be preemptive (a player
invests at a point where investment is Pareto dominated by waiting) or sequential (one player invests as
if she were the exogenously appointed leader). Following the standard literature, the worst–case prior for
the ambiguous player if she is the second mover is obtained by setting the lowest possible trend in the set
of priors. However, if the ambiguous player is the first mover, then the worst–case prior can be given by
either the lowest or the highest trend in the set of priors. This novel result shows that “worst–case prior”
in a setting with geometric Brownian motion and –ambiguity over the drift does not always equate to
“lowest trend”.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_533a.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900480/2900481/IMW_working_paper_533a.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Real Options</topic><topic>Knightian Uncertainty</topic><topic>Worst–Case Prior</topic><topic>Optimal Stopping</topic><topic>Timing Game</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29004800</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>533</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hellmann, T., Thijssen, J.J.J.: Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 533, Januar 2016. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, Tobias, and Thijssen, Jacco J.J. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;. Januar 2016. Vol. 533. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Hellmann T, Thijssen JJJ. &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 533 Januar 2016. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2016.</ama>
<bio1>Hellmann T, Thijssen JJJ (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 533, Januar 2016.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Hellmann, and J. J. J.  Thijssen, &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, T. &amp;amp; Thijssen, J.J.J. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers) (Januar 2016.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Hellmann, T., &amp;amp; Thijssen, J. J. J. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 533) Januar 2016. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> T. Hellmann and J.J.J. Thijssen, &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 533, Januar 2016.,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2016.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hellmann, T., &amp;amp; Thijssen, J.J.J., 2016. &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.533, Januar 2016., Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<default>Hellmann T, Thijssen JJJ (2016)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 533, Januar 2016.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Hellmann, Tobias, and Thijssen, Jacco J.J. &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt;. Januar 2016. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2016. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 533.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hellmann, T., &amp;amp; Thijssen, J. J. J. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 533) Januar 2016. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hellmann, T., and Thijssen, J. J. J. (2016). Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 533, Januar 2016. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Hellmann, T.; Thijssen, J. J. J. (2016): Fear of the market or fear of the competitor? Ambiguity in a real options game. Januar 2016.  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900480</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-19T13:23:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>