<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900049</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herzberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper continues Dietrich and List's [2010] work on propositionalattitude
aggregation theory, which is a generalised unication of the
judgment-aggregation and probabilistic opinion-pooling literatures. We
rst propose an algebraic framework for an analysis of (many-valued)
propositional-attitude aggregation problems. Then we shall show
that systematic propositional-attitude aggregators can be viewed as
homomorphisms in the category of C.C. Chang's [1958] MV-algebras.
Since the 2-element Boolean algebra as well as the real unit interval can be
endowed with an MV-algebra structure, we obtain as natural corollaries
two famous theorems: Arrow's theorem for judgment aggregation as well
as McConway's [1981] characterisation of linear opinion pools.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_445.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900049/2900050/IMW_working_paper_445.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>propositional attitude aggregation</topic><topic>judgment aggregation</topic><topic>linear opinion pooling</topic><topic>Arrow's impossibility theorem</topic><topic>many-valued logic</topic><topic>MV-algebra</topic><topic>homomorphism</topic><topic>Arrow's impossibility theorem</topic><topic>functional equation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29000497</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>445</number></detail><extent unit="pages">13</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, Frederik. 2011. &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 445. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herzberg, F.: An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 445. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<ama>Herzberg F. &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 445. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2011.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Herzberg F (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 445.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2011). &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Herzberg, F. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 445). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<harvard1>Herzberg, F., 2011. &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.445, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> F. Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 445,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011.</ieee>
<default>Herzberg F (2011)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 445.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<wels>Herzberg, F. (2011): An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<mla>Herzberg, Frederik. &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 445.</mla>
<frontiers>Herzberg, F. (2011). An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 445, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;An algebraic approach to general aggregation theory: Propositional-attitude aggregators as MV-homomorphisms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 445). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900049</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-11T15:25:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>