<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900676</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paaßen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49941564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3899-2450</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Göpfert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">70126969</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2517-4907</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michele</namePart><namePart type="family">Verleysen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Time series prediction constitutes a classic topic in machine learning with wide-ranging  applications, but mostly restricted to the domain of vectorial sequence entries. In recent years, time series of structured data (such as sequences, trees or graph structures) have become more and more important, for example in social network analysis or intelligent tutoring systems. 
In this contribution, we propose an extension of time series models to strucured data based on Gaussian processes and structure kernels. We also provide speedup techniques for predictions in linear time, and we evaluate our approach on real data from the domain of intelligent tutoring systems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paassen_goepfert_hammer_2016_gaussian_process_prediction_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900676/2903256/paassen_goepfert_hammer_2016_gaussian_process_prediction_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ciaco - i6doc.com</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bruges</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>structured data</topic><topic>gaussian processes</topic><topic>time series prediction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-2-87587-026-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29006762</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">41--46</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2900666</url>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2900684</url>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2913104</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2016). Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In M. Verleysen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (S. 41--46). Gehalten auf der 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN), Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Paaßen B, Göpfert C, Hammer B (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed); Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com:  41--46.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Paaßen, C.  Göpfert, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Verleysen), Ciaco - I6Doc.com, Louvain-la-Neuve, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 41--46.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Paaßen B, Göpfert C, Hammer B. Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In: Verleysen M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com;  2016: 41--46.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, Benjamin, Göpfert, Christina, and Hammer, Barbara. 2016. “Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michele Verleysen, 41--46. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C., Hammer, B.: Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In: Verleysen, M. (ed.) Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. p. 41--46. Ciaco - i6doc.com, Louvain-la-Neuve (2016).</lncs>
<frontiers>Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C., and Hammer, B. (2016). “Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, Verleysen, M. ed. (Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com), 41--46.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2016). Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 41--46). Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Paaßen, Benjamin, Göpfert, Christina, and Hammer, Barbara. “Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michele Verleysen. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, 2016. 41--46.</mla>
<wels>Paaßen, B.; Göpfert, C.; Hammer, B. (2016): Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In: Michele Verleysen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.  S. 41--46.</wels>
<default>Paaßen B, Göpfert C, Hammer B (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed);  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com:  41--46.</default>
<ieee> B. Paaßen, C. Göpfert, and B. Hammer, “Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, M. Verleysen, ed.,  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, 2016,  pp.41--46.</ieee>
<harvard1>Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2016. Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In M.  Verleysen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;.  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, pp. 41--46.</harvard1>
<apa>Paaßen, B., Göpfert, C., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2016). Gaussian process prediction for time series of structured data. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 41--46). Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900676</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-26T14:30:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-21T11:05:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>