<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900365</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sara Rizvi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jafree</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rubeena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">71732873</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Muhammad</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakria Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">85269868</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fischer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">35453272</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4388-1245</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

There is an absence of formal error tracking systems in public sector hospitals of Pakistan and also a lack of literature concerning error reporting culture in the health care sector. Nurse practitioners have front-line knowledge and rich exposure about both the organizational culture and error sharing in hospital settings. The aim of this paper was to investigate the association between organizational culture and the culture of error reporting, as perceived by nurses.
Methods

The authors used the “Practice Environment Scale-Nurse Work Index Revised” to measure the six dimensions of organizational culture. Seven questions were used from the “Survey to Solicit Information about the Culture of Reporting” to measure error reporting culture in the region. Overall, 309 nurses participated in the survey, including female nurses from all designations such as supervisors, instructors, ward-heads, staff nurses and student nurses. We used SPSS 17.0 to perform a factor analysis. Furthermore, descriptive statistics, mean scores and multivariable logistic regression were used for the analysis.
Results

Three areas were ranked unfavorably by nurse respondents, including: (i) the error reporting culture, (ii) staffing and resource adequacy, and (iii) nurse foundations for quality of care. Multivariable regression results revealed that all six categories of organizational culture, including: (1) nurse manager ability, leadership and support, (2) nurse participation in hospital affairs, (3) nurse participation in governance, (4) nurse foundations of quality care, (5) nurse-coworkers relations, and (6) nurse staffing and resource adequacy, were positively associated with higher odds of error reporting culture. In addition, it was found that married nurses and nurses on permanent contract were more likely to report errors at the workplace.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bmc.hsr.fischer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900365/2900366/bmc.hsr.fischer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Organizational culture Error reporting Pakistan Nurse Public sector</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Health Services Research</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1472-6963</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26728071</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000367506100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29003655</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-1252-y</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jafree, Sara Rizvi, Zakar, Rubeena, Zakria Zakar, Muhammad, and Fischer, Florian. 2016. “Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt; 16 (1): 3.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jafree, S.R., Zakar, R., Zakria Zakar, M., Fischer, F.: Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. BMC Health Services Research. 16, : 3 (2016).</lncs>
<default>Jafree SR, Zakar R, Zakria Zakar M, Fischer F (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt; 16(1): 3.</default>
<mla>Jafree, Sara Rizvi, Zakar, Rubeena, Zakria Zakar, Muhammad, and Fischer, Florian. “Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt; 16.1 (2016): 3.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jafree, S.R., Zakar, R., Zakria Zakar, M. &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2016). Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1): 3. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1186/s12913-015-1252-y.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Jafree, S. R., Zakar, R., Zakria Zakar, M., and Fischer, F. (2016). Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt; 16:3.</frontiers>
<ama>Jafree SR, Zakar R, Zakria Zakar M, Fischer F. Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;16(1): 3.</ama>
<ieee> S.R. Jafree, et al., “Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2016, : 3.</ieee>
<apa>Jafree, S. R., Zakar, R., Zakria Zakar, M., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2016). Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 3. doi:10.1186/s12913-015-1252-y</apa>
<wels>Jafree, S. R.; Zakar, R.; Zakria Zakar, M.; Fischer, F. (2016): Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;,16:(1):3</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S. R.  Jafree, R.  Zakar, M.  Zakria Zakar, and F.  Fischer, “Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, : 3.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Jafree SR, Zakar R, Zakria Zakar M, Fischer F (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Health Services Research 16(1): 3.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jafree, S. R., Zakar, R., Zakria Zakar, M., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2016). Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 3. doi:10.1186/s12913-015-1252-y&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Jafree, S.R., et al., 2016. Nurse perceptions of organizational culture and its association with the culture of error reporting: a case of public sector hospitals in Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;BMC Health Services Research&lt;/em&gt;, 16(1): 3.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900365</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-14T10:41:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>