<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2900947</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>American options with multiple priors in continuous time</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vorbrink</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We investigate American options in a multiple prior setting of continuous
time and determine optimal exercise strategies form the perspective
of an ambiguity averse buyer. The multiple prior setting
relaxes the presumption of a known distribution of the stock price
process and captures the idea of incomplete information of the market
data leading to model uncertainty. Using the theory of (reflected)
backward stochastic differential equations we are able to solve the optimal
stopping problem under multiple priors and identify the particular
worst-case scenario in terms of the worst-case prior. By means of the
analysis of exotic American options we highlight the main difference
to classical single prior models. This is characterized by a resulting
endogenous dynamic structure of the worst-case scenario generated
by model adjustments of the agent due to particular occurring events
that change the agent’s beliefs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_448.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2900947/2900948/IMW_working_paper_448.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Optimal stopping for exotic American options</topic><topic>uncertainty aversion</topic><topic>ultiple priors</topic><topic>robustness</topic><topic>(reflected) BSDEs</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29009476</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>448</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vorbrink, Jörg. 2011. &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 448. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Vorbrink, J.: American options with multiple priors in continuous time. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 448. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2011).</lncs>
<ama>Vorbrink J. &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 448. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2011.</ama>
<bio1>Vorbrink J (2011) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 448.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Vorbrink, &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vorbrink, J. (2011). &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Vorbrink, J. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 448). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> J. Vorbrink, &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 448,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011.</ieee>
<harvard1>Vorbrink, J., 2011. &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.448, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<default>Vorbrink J (2011)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 448.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<wels>Vorbrink, J. (2011): American options with multiple priors in continuous time. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Vorbrink, J. (2011).  &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 448). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Vorbrink, J. (2011). American options with multiple priors in continuous time. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 448, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Vorbrink, Jörg. &lt;em&gt;American options with multiple priors in continuous time&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2011. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 448.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2900947</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-11T10:41:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>