<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901528</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tiziano</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">de Angelis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moriarty</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We show that the equivalence between certain problems of singular stochastic
control (SSC) and related questions of optimal stopping known for convex performance criteria
(see, for example, Karatzas and Shreve (1984)) continues to hold in a non convex problem
provided a related discretionary stopping time is introduced. Our problem is one of storage
and consumption for electricity, a partially storable commodity with both positive and negative
prices in some markets, and has similarities to the finite fuel monotone follower problem. In
particular we consider a non convex infinite time horizon SSC problem whose state consists of an
uncontrolled diffusion representing a real-valued commodity price, and a controlled increasing
bounded process representing an inventory. We analyse the geometry of the action and inaction
regions by characterising the related optimal stopping boundaries.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_508.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901528/2902029/IMW_working_paper_508.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>finite-fuel singular stochastic control</topic><topic>optimal stopping</topic><topic>free-boundary</topic><topic>smooth- fit</topic><topic>Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman equation</topic><topic>irreversible investment</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29015289</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>508</number></detail><extent unit="pages">25</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2766940</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Moriarty, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 508). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;de Angelis, Tiziano, Ferrari, Giorgio, and Moriarty, John. 2014. &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 508. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G., Moriarty, J.: A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 508. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<ieee> T. de Angelis, G. Ferrari, and J. Moriarty, &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 508,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<harvard1>de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Moriarty, J., 2014. &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.508, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ama>de Angelis T, Ferrari G, Moriarty J. &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 508. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<default>de Angelis T, Ferrari G, Moriarty J (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 508.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<bio1>de Angelis T, Ferrari G, Moriarty J (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 508.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  de Angelis, G.  Ferrari, and J.  Moriarty, &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>de Angelis, T.; Ferrari, G.; Moriarty, J. (2014): A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G., and Moriarty, J. (2014). A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 508, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>de Angelis, Tiziano, Ferrari, Giorgio, and Moriarty, John. &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 508.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Moriarty, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 508). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;de Angelis, T., Ferrari, G. &amp;amp; Moriarty, J. (2014). &lt;em&gt;A non convex singular stochastic control problem and its related optimal stopping boundaries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901528</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-14T09:33:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-16T10:47:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>