<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901297</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wibberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19653681</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rupp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blom</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lukas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jelonek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8253486</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Magdalena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kröber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23918556</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bart</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Verwaaijen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41577028</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Goesmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albaum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">181902</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1827-9914</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rita</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grosch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21937</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4723-2960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlüter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55545</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4830-310X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Rhizoctonia solani, a soil-born plant pathogenic basidiomycetous fungus, affects various economically important agricultural and horticultural crops. The draft genome sequence for the R. solani AG1-IB isolate 7/3/14 as well as a corresponding transcriptome dataset (Expressed Sequence Tags-ESTs) were established previously. Development of a specific R. solani AG1-IB gene model based on GMAP transcript mapping within the eukaryotic gene prediction platform AUGUSTUS allowed detection of new genes and provided insights into the gene structure of this fungus. In total, 12,616 genes were recognized in the genome of the AG1-IB isolate. Analysis of predicted genes by means of different bioinformatics tools revealed new genes whose products potentially are involved in degradation of plant cell wall components, melanin formation and synthesis of secondary metabolites. Comparative genome analyses between members of different R. solani anastomosis groups, namely AG1-IA, AG3 and AG8 and the newly annotated R. solani AG1-IB genome were performed within the comparative genomics platform EDGAR. It appeared that only 21 to 28% of all genes encoded in the draft genomes of the different strains were identified as core genes. Based on Average Nucleotide Identity (ANI) and Average Amino-acid Identity (AAI) analyses, considerable sequence differences between isolates representing different anastomosis groups were identified. However, R. solani isolates form a distinct cluster in relation to other fungi of the phylum Basidiomycota. The isolate representing AG1-IB encodes significant more genes featuring predictable functions in secondary metabolite production compared to other completely sequenced R. solani strains. The newly established R. solani AG1-IB 7/3/14 gene layout now provides a reliable basis for post-genomics studies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0144769.schlueter.PDF">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901297/2906007/journal.pone.0144769.schlueter.PDF</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library Science</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Plos One</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26690577</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000367092300015</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29012970</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0144769</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Wibberg, D., Rupp, O., Blom, J., Jelonek, L., Kröber, M., Verwaaijen, B., Goesmann, A., Albaum, S., Grosch, R., Pühler, A., et al. (2015). Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10:e0144769.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wibberg, D., Rupp, O., Blom, J., Jelonek, L., Kröber, M., Verwaaijen, B., Goesmann, A., Albaum, S., Grosch, R., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2015). Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12): e0144769. Public Library Science. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144769.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wibberg D, Rupp O, Blom J, et al. Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;10(12): e0144769.</ama>
<ieee> D. Wibberg, et al., “Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates”, &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2015, : e0144769.</ieee>
<apa>Wibberg, D., Rupp, O., Blom, J., Jelonek, L., Kröber, M., Verwaaijen, B., Goesmann, A., et al. (2015). Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0144769. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144769</apa>
<wels>Wibberg, D.; Rupp, O.; Blom, J.; Jelonek, L.; Kröber, M.; Verwaaijen, B.; Goesmann, A.; Albaum, S.; Grosch, R.; Pühler, A.; Schlüter, A. (2015): Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;,10:(12):e0144769</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Wibberg, O.  Rupp, J.  Blom, L.  Jelonek, M.  Kröber, B.  Verwaaijen, A.  Goesmann, S.  Albaum, R.  Grosch, A.  Pühler, et al., “Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates”, &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : e0144769.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Wibberg, D., et al., 2015. Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, 10(12): e0144769.</harvard1>
<bio1>Wibberg D, Rupp O, Blom J, Jelonek L, Kröber M, Verwaaijen B, Goesmann A, Albaum S, Grosch R, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates.&lt;br /&gt;Plos One 10(12): e0144769.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wibberg, D., Rupp, O., Blom, J., Jelonek, L., Kröber, M., Verwaaijen, B., Goesmann, A., et al. (2015). Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0144769. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144769&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wibberg, Daniel, Rupp, Oliver, Blom, Jochen, Jelonek, Lukas, Kröber, Magdalena, Verwaaijen, Bart, Goesmann, Alexander, et al. 2015. “Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates”. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10 (12): e0144769.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wibberg, D., Rupp, O., Blom, J., Jelonek, L., Kröber, M., Verwaaijen, B., Goesmann, A., Albaum, S., Grosch, R., Pühler, A., Schlüter, A.: Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates. Plos One. 10, : e0144769 (2015).</lncs>
<default>Wibberg D, Rupp O, Blom J, Jelonek L, Kröber M, Verwaaijen B, Goesmann A, Albaum S, Grosch R, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10(12): e0144769.</default>
<mla>Wibberg, Daniel, Rupp, Oliver, Blom, Jochen, Jelonek, Lukas, Kröber, Magdalena, Verwaaijen, Bart, Goesmann, Alexander, Albaum, Stefan, Grosch, Rita, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. “Development of a Rhizoctonia solani AG1-IB Specific Gene Model Enables Comparative Genome Analyses between Phytopathogenic R-solani AG1-IA, AG1-IB, AG3 and AG8 Isolates”. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10.12 (2015): e0144769.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901297</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-03T06:55:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>