<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901671</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staudigl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26057873</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This note contains complementary information to the paper Staudigl and Steg
(2014). We present a martingale characterization of continuation payoff processes in a
class of repeated games with imperfect public monitoring. Our martingale approach
allows us to work out a clear connection between the discrete time and continuous
time payoff processes. A general proof of convergence is the open issue in this literature,
and I strongly belief that the characterization result reported here is the key to
solve this problem.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_526.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901671/2902681/IMW_working_paper_526.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Repeated games</topic><topic>Public Perfect Equilibrium</topic><topic>Martingale Representation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29016713</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>526</number></detail><extent unit="pages">17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Staudigl, M. (2014). &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Staudigl M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 526.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Staudigl, &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Staudigl M. &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 526. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<lncs> Staudigl, M.: On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 526. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Staudigl, Mathias. 2014. &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 526. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Staudigl, M. (2014): On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Staudigl, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 526). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Staudigl, Mathias. &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 526.</mla>
<frontiers>Staudigl, M. (2014). On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 526, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Staudigl M (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 526.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ieee> M. Staudigl, &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 526,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<harvard1>Staudigl, M., 2014. &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.526, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Staudigl, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;On Repeated games with imperfect public monitoring: Characterization of Continuation payoff processes&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 526). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901671</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-16T08:06:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>