<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901488</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">William H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sandholm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staudigl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26057873</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We consider a model of stochastic evolution under general noisy best response
protocols, allowing the probabilities of suboptimal choices to depend on their payoff
consequences. Our analysis focuses on behavior in the small noise double limit: we
first take the noise level in agents’ decisions to zero, and then take the population
size to infinity. We show that in this double limit, escape from and transitions between
equilibria can be described in terms of solutions to continuous optimal control
problems. These are used in turn to characterize the asymptotics of the the stationary
distribution, and so to determine the stochastically stable states. The control problems
are tractable in certain interesting cases, allowing analytical descriptions of the escape
dynamics and long run behavior of the stochastic evolutionary process.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_505.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901488/2901489/IMW_working_paper_505.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29014883</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>505</number></detail><extent unit="pages">43</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://econtheory.org/ojs/index.php/te/article/view/20160279</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Sandholm WH, Staudigl M (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 505.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Sandholm, William H., and Staudigl, Mathias. &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 505.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sandholm, William H., and Staudigl, Mathias. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 505. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Sandholm, W.H., Staudigl, M.: Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 505. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>W. H.  Sandholm, and M.  Staudigl, &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sandholm, W. H., &amp;amp; Staudigl, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 505). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Sandholm, W.H., &amp;amp; Staudigl, M., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.505, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Sandholm WH, Staudigl M (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 505.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<wels>Sandholm, W. H.; Staudigl, M. (2014): Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<ieee> W.H. Sandholm and M. Staudigl, &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 505,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Sandholm, W. H., &amp;amp; Staudigl, M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 505). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Sandholm, W. H., and Staudigl, M. (2014). Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 505, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sandholm, W.H. &amp;amp; Staudigl, M. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Sandholm WH, Staudigl M. &lt;em&gt;Large Deviations and Stochastic Stability in the Small Noise Double Limit, I: Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 505. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901488</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-11T10:44:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>