<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901450</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4244291</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4291-6610</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan-Henrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182054</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study a continuous-time problem of public good contribution under uncertainty
for an economy with a finite number of agents. Each agent aims to maximize his expected
utility allocating his initial wealth over a given time period between private consumption and
repeated but irreversible contributions to increase the stock of some public good. We study the
corresponding social planner problem and the case of strategic interaction between the agents.
These problems are set up as stochastic control problems with both monotone and classical controls
representing the cumulative contribution into the public good and the consumption of the
private good, respectively. We characterize the optimal investment policies by a set of necessary
and sufficient stochastic Kuhn-Tucker conditions, which in turn allow to identify a universal signal
process that triggers the public good investments. Further we show that our model exhibits
a dynamic free rider effect. We explicitly evaluate it in a symmetric Black-Scholes setting with
Cobb-Douglas utilities and we show that uncertainty and irreversibility of public good provisions
need not affect the degree of free-riding.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_485a.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901450/2901451/IMW_working_paper_485a.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>irreversible investment</topic><topic>public good contribution</topic><topic>free-riding</topic><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>first order conditions for optimality</topic><topic>stochastic games</topic><topic>Nash equilibrium</topic><topic>Lévy processes</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29014502</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>485</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G., Riedel, F. &amp;amp; Steg, J.-H. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers) (Version  February 2015.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Ferrari G, Riedel F, Steg J-H (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 485, Version  February 2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Ferrari, F.  Riedel, and J. - H.  Steg, &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Ferrari G, Riedel F, Steg J-H. &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 485 Version  February 2015. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2015.</ama>
<lncs> Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., Steg, J.-H.: Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 485, Version  February 2015. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, Giorgio, Riedel, Frank, and Steg, Jan-Henrik. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Version  February 2015. Vol. 485. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., and Steg, J. - H. (2015). Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 485, Version  February 2015. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Ferrari, Giorgio, Riedel, Frank, and Steg, Jan-Henrik. &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Version  February 2015. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 485.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., &amp;amp; Steg, J. - H. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 485) Version  February 2015. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Ferrari, G.; Riedel, F.; Steg, J. - H. (2015): Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty. Version  February 2015.  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Ferrari G, Riedel F, Steg J-H (2015)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 485, Version  February 2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ieee> G. Ferrari, F. Riedel, and J.-H. Steg, &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 485, Version  February 2015.,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<harvard1>Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., &amp;amp; Steg, J.-H., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.485, Version  February 2015., Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., &amp;amp; Steg, J. - H. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Continuous-Time Public Good Contribution under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 485) Version  February 2015. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901450</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-10T13:05:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>