<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901500</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kluth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">54885831</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michele</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Burigo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16869637</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2068-9936</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015562</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Cognitive models are – due to their computational nature – useful for the development and improvement of artificial cognitive systems. However, if two models perform equally well on the existent data, comparing them directly can permit us to select the more appropriate one. One way of comparing to models is to perform an in-depth analysis of their predictions. In this study, we compared the predictions of two similar cognitive models of spatial language comprehension using the Parameter Space Partitioning (PSP) algorithm proposed by Pitt, Kim, Navarro, and Myung (2006).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kogsys2016.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901500/2901501/kogsys2016.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kogsys2016_talk.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901500/2901757/kogsys2016_talk.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bochum</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Spatial Language</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29015009</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2918231</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> T. Kluth, M. Burigo, and P. Knoeferle, “Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension”, Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum, 2016.</ieee>
<apa>Kluth, T., Burigo, M., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T., Burigo, M. &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2016). Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension. Gehalten auf der 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kluth, T., Burigo, M., and Knoeferle, P. (2016).“Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension”. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</frontiers>
<ama>Kluth T, Burigo M, Knoeferle P. Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Kluth, M.  Burigo, and P.  Knoeferle, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kluth T, Burigo M, Knoeferle P (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T., Burigo, M., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kluth, T., Burigo, M., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P., 2016. Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</harvard1>
<wels>Kluth, T.; Burigo, M.; Knoeferle, P. (2016): Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension.</wels>
<default>Kluth T, Burigo M, Knoeferle P (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum.</default>
<mla>Kluth, Thomas, Burigo, Michele, and Knoeferle, Pia. “Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension”. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum, 2016.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, Thomas, Burigo, Michele, and Knoeferle, Pia. 2016. “Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension”. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kluth, T., Burigo, M., Knoeferle, P.: Investigating the Parameter Space of Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Comprehension. Presented at the 5. Interdisziplinärer Workshop Kognitive Systeme: Mensch, Teams, Systeme und Automaten. Verstehen, Beschreiben und Gestalten Kognitiver (Technischer) Systeme, Bochum (2016).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901500</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-11T12:03:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-23T09:01:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>