<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901685</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Paavo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Salminen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We derive a new equation for the optimal investment boundary of a general
irreversible investment problem under exponential Lévy uncertainty. The problem is set as an
infinite time-horizon, two-dimensional degenerate singular stochastic control problem. In line
with the results recently obtained in a diffusive setting, we show that the optimal boundary is intimately
linked to the unique optional solution of an appropriate Bank-El Karoui representation
problem. Such a relation and the Wiener-Hopf factorization allow us to derive an integral equation
for the optimal investment boundary. In case the underlying Lévy process hits any point
in R with positive probability we show that the integral equation for the investment boundary
is uniquely satisfied by the unique solution of another equation which is easier to handle. As a
remarkable by-product we prove the continuity of the optimal investment boundary. The paper
is concluded with explicit results for profit functions of (i) Cobb-Douglas type and (ii) CES type.
In the first case the function is separable and in the second case non-separable.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_530.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901685/2901686/IMW_working_paper_530.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>free-boundary</topic><topic>irreversible investment</topic><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>optimal stopping</topic><topic>Lévy process</topic><topic>Bank and El Karoui's representation theorem</topic><topic>base capacity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29016857</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>530</number></detail><extent unit="pages">20</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Ferrari, G., Salminen, P.: Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 530. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, Giorgio, and Salminen, Paavo. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 530. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Ferrari, Giorgio, and Salminen, Paavo. &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 530.</mla>
<default>Ferrari G, Salminen P (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 530.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<wels>Ferrari, G.; Salminen, P. (2014): Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Salminen, P. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 530). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Salminen, P., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.530, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ferrari G, Salminen P (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 530.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Ferrari, and P.  Salminen, &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Ferrari G, Salminen P. &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 530. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G. &amp;amp; Salminen, P. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Ferrari, G., and Salminen, P. (2014). Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 530, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Salminen, P. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 530). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> G. Ferrari and P. Salminen, &lt;em&gt;Irreversible Investment under Lévy Uncertainty: an Equation for the Optimal Boundary&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 530,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901685</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-16T10:07:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>