<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901239</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Köster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45612304</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8867-3282</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>The Cognitive Service Robotics Apartment as Ambient Host (CSRA, LSP-01)</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="nkoester_memx2015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901239/2901242/nkoester_memx2015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29012399</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Köster, N., Wrede, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt; (Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</apa>
<harvard1>Köster, N., Wrede, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;, Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN), Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Köster, S. Wrede, and P. Cimiano, &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;, Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN),  Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop, 2015.</ieee>
<default>Köster N, Wrede S, Cimiano P (2015)  Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN).&lt;br /&gt;Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</default>
<mla>Köster, Norman, Wrede, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;. Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop, 2015. Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN).</mla>
<frontiers>Köster, N., Wrede, S., and Cimiano, P. (2015). Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN)&lt;/em&gt;, Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Köster, N., Wrede, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt; (Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Köster, N.; Wrede, S.; Cimiano, P. (2015): Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments. Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</wels>
<lncs> Köster, N., Wrede, S., Cimiano, P.: Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments. Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop, Kobe (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Köster, Norman, Wrede, Sebastian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Köster N, Wrede S, Cimiano P. &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop; 2015.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Köster, S.  Wrede, and P.  Cimiano, &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;, Memory Inspired Robot Architectures For Human-Robot Interaction Workshop, Kobe, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Köster N, Wrede S, Cimiano P (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN).&lt;br /&gt;Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Köster, N., Wrede, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Requirements for domain-specific data access of long-term interaction data in smart environments&lt;/em&gt; (Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (ROMAN). Kobe: Memory inspired robot architectures for human-robot interaction Workshop.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901239</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-01T19:44:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:55:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>