<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901250</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Janet Junqing</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mobarak Hossain</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Khan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11748069</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jahn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">52383182</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objectives University students in general face multiple challenges, which may affect their levels of perceived stress and life satisfaction. Chinese students currently face specific strains due to the One-Child Policy (OCP). The aim of this study was to assess (1) whether the levels of perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction are associated with only-child (OC) status after controlling for demographic and socio-economic characteristics and (2) whether these associations differ between Chinese and international students. Materials and Methods A cross-sectional health survey based on a self-administrated standardised questionnaire was conducted among 1,843 (1,543 Chinese, 300 international) students at two Chinese universities in 2010-2011. Cohen's Perceived Stress Scale (PSS-14) and Stock and Kraemer's Studying-related Life Satisfaction Scale were used to measure perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction respectively. Multivariable logistic regression analyses were used to examine the associations of OC status with perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction by sex for Chinese students and international students separately. Results The Chinese non-only-children (NOCs) were more likely to come from small cities. Multivariable regression models indicate that the Chinese NOCs were more stressed than OCs (OR = 1.39, 1.11-1.74) with a stronger association in men (OR = 1.48, 1.08-2.02) than women (OR = 1.26, 0.89-1.77). NOCs were also more dissatisfied than their OC fellows in the Chinese subsample (OR = 1.37, 1.09-1.73). Among international students, no associations between OC status and perceived stress or studying-related life satisfaction were found. Conclusions To promote equality between OCs and NOCs at Chinese universities, the causes of more stress and less studying-related life satisfaction among NOCs compared to OCs need further exploration.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0144947.chu.PDF">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901250/2906005/journal.pone.0144947.chu.PDF</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library Science</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Plos One</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">26675032</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000366722700077</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29012508</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0144947</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Chu, J. J.; Khan, M. H.; Jahn, H. J.; Krämer, A. (2015): Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;,10:(12):e0144947</wels>
<mla>Chu, Janet Junqing, Khan, Mobarak Hossain, Jahn, Heiko J., and Krämer, Alexander. “Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students”. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10.12 (2015): e0144947.</mla>
<frontiers>Chu, J. J., Khan, M. H., Jahn, H. J., and Krämer, A. (2015). Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10:e0144947.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, J. J., Khan, M. H., Jahn, H. J., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2015). Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0144947. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144947&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Chu JJ, Khan MH, Jahn HJ, Krämer A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10(12): e0144947.</default>
<harvard1>Chu, J.J., et al., 2015. Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, 10(12): e0144947.</harvard1>
<ieee> J.J. Chu, et al., “Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students”, &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2015, : e0144947.</ieee>
<apa>Chu, J. J., Khan, M. H., Jahn, H. J., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2015). Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0144947. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144947</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, J.J., Khan, M.H., Jahn, H.J. &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2015). Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12): e0144947. Public Library Science. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0144947.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J. J.  Chu, M. H.  Khan, H. J.  Jahn, and A.  Krämer, “Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students”, &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : e0144947.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Chu JJ, Khan MH, Jahn HJ, Krämer A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students.&lt;br /&gt;Plos One 10(12): e0144947.</bio1>
<ama>Chu JJ, Khan MH, Jahn HJ, Krämer A. Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;10(12): e0144947.</ama>
<lncs> Chu, J.J., Khan, M.H., Jahn, H.J., Krämer, A.: Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students. Plos One. 10, : e0144947 (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Chu, Janet Junqing, Khan, Mobarak Hossain, Jahn, Heiko J., and Krämer, Alexander. 2015. “Only-child status in relation to perceived stress and studying-related life satisfaction among university students in China: a comparison with international students”. &lt;em&gt;Plos One&lt;/em&gt; 10 (12): e0144947.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901250</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-02T07:15:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:45:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>