<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901641</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Categorization based Belief formations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bleile</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22693411</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">An agent needs to determine a belief over potential outcomes for a new problem based on past
observations gathered in her database (memory). There is a rich literature in cognitive science
showing that human minds process and order information in categories, rather than piece by piece.
We assume that agents are naturally equipped (by evolution) with a efficient heuristic intuition
how to categorize. Depending on how available categorized information is activated and processed,
we axiomatize two different versions of belief formation relying on categorizations. In one approach
an agent relies only on the estimates induced by the single pieces of information contained in so
called target categories that are activated by the problem for which a belief is asked for. Another
approach forms a prototype based belief by averaging over all category-based estimates (so called
prototypical estimates) corresponding to each category in the database. In both belief formations
the involved estimates are weighted according to their similarity or relevance to the new problem.
We impose normatively desirable and natural properties on the categorization of databases. On the
stage of belief formation our axioms specify the relationship between different categorized databases
and their corresponding induced (category or prototype based) beliefs. The axiomatization of a
belief formation in Billot et al. (Econometrica, 2005) is covered for the situation of a (trivial)
categorization of a database that consists only of singleton categories and agents basically do not
process information categorical.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_519.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901641/2902674/IMW_working_paper_519.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Belief formation</topic><topic>prior</topic><topic>case-based reasoning</topic><topic>similarity</topic><topic>categorization</topic><topic>prototype</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29016418</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>519</number></detail><extent unit="pages">41</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Bleile, J., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.519, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Bleile, &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 519,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Bleile, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 519). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<wels>Bleile, J. (2014): Categorization based Belief formations. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bleile, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 519). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bleile, Jörg. &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 519.</mla>
<frontiers>Bleile, J. (2014). Categorization based Belief formations. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 519, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Bleile J (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 519.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ama>Bleile J. &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 519. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bleile, Jörg. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 519. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bleile, J.: Categorization based Belief formations. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 519. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bleile, J. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Bleile, &lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bleile J (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Categorization based Belief formations&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 519.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901641</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-15T13:03:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>