<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901794</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Poggemeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Yaxin</namePart><namePart type="family">Bi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Supriya</namePart><namePart type="family">Kapoor</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rahul</namePart><namePart type="family">Bhatia</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Configuring complex products can be a challenge due to the huge number of configuration possibilities. In this paper, our goal is to foster the development of intelligent configuration assistants that can support customers in configuring
complex products. We formalize the task as a machine learning problem and in particular as a learning-to-rank problem. Given pairwise preferences elicited from experts, we show that we can train a model using support vector machines that ranks possible products according to their relevance to a given set of requirements specified by a user.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901794/2906469/preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">London, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Product Configuration</topic><topic>Ranking</topic><topic>Information Retrieval</topic><topic>Machine Learning</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29017949</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-56994-9_59</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>15</number></detail><extent unit="pages">866-879</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Poggemeier C, Hartung M, Cimiano P. Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In: Bi Y, Kapoor S, Bhatia R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems. Vol 15. Cham: Springer International Publishing;  2018: 866-879.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach (Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems). In Y. Bi, S. Kapoor &amp;amp; R. Bhatia (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt; (S. 866-879). Gehalten auf der SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016, Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-56994-9_59.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M., and Cimiano, P. (2018). “Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;, Bi, Y., Kapoor, S., and Bhatia, R. eds. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, vol. 15, (Cham: Springer International Publishing), 866-879.</frontiers>
<apa>Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In Y.  Bi, S.  Kapoor, &amp;amp; R.  Bhatia (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems: Vol. 15&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 866-879). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-56994-9_59</apa>
<ieee> C. Poggemeier, M. Hartung, and P. Cimiano, “Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;, Y. Bi, S. Kapoor, and R. Bhatia, eds., Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, vol. 15,  Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2018,  pp.866-879.</ieee>
<wels>Poggemeier, C.; Hartung, M.; Cimiano, P. (2018): Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In: Yaxin Bi; Supriya Kapoor; Rahul Bhatia (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1. Cham: Springer International Publishing. (Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, 15).  S. 866-879.</wels>
<harvard1>Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2018. Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In Y.  Bi, S.  Kapoor, &amp;amp; R.  Bhatia, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems. no.15  Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 866-879.</harvard1>
<bio1>Poggemeier C, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1. Bi Y, Kapoor S, Bhatia R (Eds); Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, 15. Cham: Springer International Publishing:  866-879.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In Y.  Bi, S.  Kapoor, &amp;amp; R.  Bhatia (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems: Vol. 15&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 866-879). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-56994-9_59&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Poggemeier, M.  Hartung, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: Y. Bi, S. Kapoor, R. Bhatia), Springer International Publishing, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 866-879.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Poggemeier, C., Hartung, M., Cimiano, P.: Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach. In: Bi, Y., Kapoor, S., and Bhatia, R. (eds.) Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems. 15, p. 866-879. Springer International Publishing, Cham (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poggemeier, Carsten, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2018. “Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Yaxin Bi, Supriya Kapoor, and Rahul Bhatia, 15:866-879. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems. Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Poggemeier, Carsten, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Providing Intelligent Assistance for Product Configuration in Manufacturing. A Learning-to-Rank Approach”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Yaxin Bi, Supriya Kapoor, and Rahul Bhatia. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2018.Vol. 15. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems. 866-879.</mla>
<default>Poggemeier C, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SAI Intelligent Systems Conference (IntelliSys) 2016. Vol. 1. Bi Y, Kapoor S, Bhatia R (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, 15.  Cham: Springer International Publishing:  866-879.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901794</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-21T13:34:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>