<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901478</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuzmics</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23538564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2732-2838</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this note I give a full characterization of all deterministic direct mechanisms
in the public good provision problem with independent private values that are dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_504.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901478/2901479/IMW_working_paper_504.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>public good provision</topic><topic>asymmetric information</topic><topic>dominant strategy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29014788</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>504</number></detail><extent unit="pages">5</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Kuzmics, C. (2014): A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Kuzmics C (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 504.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kuzmics, C., 2014. &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.504, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 504). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kuzmics C. &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 504. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<frontiers>Kuzmics, C. (2014). A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 504, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, C. (2014). &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kuzmics, C. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 504). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> C. Kuzmics, &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 504,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<lncs> Kuzmics, C.: A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 504. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuzmics, Christoph. 2014. &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 504. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kuzmics, Christoph. &lt;em&gt;A full characterization of all deterministic dominant strategy incentive compatible, ex-post individually rational, and ex-post budget balanced direct mechanisms in the public good provision problem with independent private values&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 504.</mla>
<default>Kuzmics C (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 504.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901478</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-11T10:30:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>