<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2901599</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herzberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Amartya Sen (1970) has shown that three natural
desiderata for social choice rules are inconsistent: universal domain,
respect for unanimity, and respect for some minimal rights — which can
be interpreted as either expert rights or liberal rights. Dietrich and List
(2008) have generalised this result to the setting of binary judgement
aggregation. This paper proves that the liberal paradox holds even in
the framework of probabilistic opinion pooling and discusses options to
circumvent this impossibility result: restricting the aggregator domain
to profiles with no potential for conflicting rights, or considering agendas
whose issues are not all mutually interdependent.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_513.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2901599/2901600/IMW_working_paper_513.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>probabilistic opinion pooling</topic><topic>Sen’s liberal paradox</topic><topic>expert rights</topic><topic>liberal rights</topic><topic>unanimity</topic><topic>general aggregation theory</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29015994</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>513</number></detail><extent unit="pages">6</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2908114</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Herzberg F. &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 513. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, Frederik. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 513. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herzberg, F.: Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 513. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Herzberg F (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 513.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Herzberg, F., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.513, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> F. Herzberg, &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 513,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Herzberg, F. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 513). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Herzberg, F. (2014). Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 513, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herzberg, F. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 513). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Herzberg, Frederik. &lt;em&gt;Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2014. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 513.</mla>
<wels>Herzberg, F. (2014): Respect for experts or respect for unanimity? The liberal paradox in probabilistic opinion pooling. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Herzberg F (2014)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 513.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2901599</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-03-14T14:47:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>