<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2903115</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Debbie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schepers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26714220</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26688158</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Morality as a key construct for the explanation of criminal behaviour has a long tradition in crim-inology, but research in moral development in childhood and adolescence is mainly based in psy-chological explanations. This article gives a theoretical and empirical outline of the development of morality, especially for the explanation of crime involvement. Situational Action Theory, in-troduced by Wikström and colleagues (SAT; e.g. Wikström et al. 2012), is a promising new de-veloped general theory of crime. SAT combines individual and contextual constructs into an in-tegrative explanatory framework. With crime propensity mainly based on moral judgement, in its basic assumption, SAT proposes that the interaction of propensity and exposure determines de-linquency. The probability of a criminal act to be committed depends on the criminal tendency (propensity) of a person in interaction with their exposure to criminogenic settings (exposure). To analyse the development of moral judgement during adolescence, the German panel study „Chances and Risks in the Life Course‟ will be used. The study, embedded within the project „The Development of Deviant and Delinquent Behavior over the Life Course and its Significance for Processes of Social Inequality‟ of the CRC 882 „From Heterogeneities to Inequalities‟ uses a cohort sequential design and was first conducted in 2012, with yearly follow up measurements. The sample consists of three interviewing time points of two age cohorts in the German cities of Dortmund (North-Rhine Westphalia) and Nuremberg (Bavaria). Moral development and its influ-ences will be examined by applying latent growth curve models. The strongest effect on the de-velopment of moral judgement appears to be the moral emotion shame with decreasing influences of family and increasing influences of peers during adolescence.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SFB_882_WP_0056_Schepers.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2903115/2903116/SFB_882_WP_0056_Schepers.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>moral development</topic><topic>Situational Action Theory</topic><topic>juvenile delinquency</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2193-9624</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29031156</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>56</number></detail><extent unit="pages">37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Schepers, D. (2016): The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</wels>
<frontiers>Schepers, D. (2016). The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence. &lt;em&gt;SFB 882 Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 56, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schepers, D. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 56). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Schepers, Debbie. &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2016. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. 56.</mla>
<default>Schepers D (2016)  SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 56.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</default>
<harvard1>Schepers, D., 2016. &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, no.56, Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Schepers, &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;, SFB 882 Working Paper Series, vol. 56,  Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, 2016.</ieee>
<apa>Schepers, D. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 56). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schepers, D. (2016). &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt; (SFB 882 Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Schepers, &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;, Dfg Research Center (Sfb) 882 From Heterogeneities To Inequalities, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schepers D (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series; 56.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.</bio1>
<ama>Schepers D. &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Vol 56. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities; 2016.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schepers, Debbie. 2016. &lt;em&gt;The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 56. SFB 882 Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schepers, D.: The development of morality: A theoretical and empirical review of its influences and change in adolescence. SFB 882 Working Paper Series, 56. DFG Research Center (SFB) 882 From Heterogeneities to Inequalities, Bielefeld (2016).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2903115</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-05-04T12:07:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>