<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2903605</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:590</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bischof</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22137</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dennis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eckmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keary</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25149567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Siegrid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Löwel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mayer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Neethu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Michael</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The visual wulst is the telencephalic target of the avian thalamofugal visual system. It contains several retinotopically organised representations of the contralateral visual field. We used optical imaging of intrinsic signals, electrophysiological recordings, and retrograde tracing with two fluorescent tracers to evaluate properties of these representations in the zebra finch, a songbird with laterally placed eyes. Our experiments revealed that there is some variability of the neuronal maps between individuals and also concerning the number of detectable maps. It was nonetheless possible to identify three different maps, a posterolateral, a posteromedial, and an anterior one, which were quite constant in their relation to each other. The posterolateral map was in contrast to the two others constantly visible in each successful experiment. The topography of the two other maps was mirrored against that map. Electrophysiological recordings in the anterior and the posterolateral map revealed that all units responded to flashes and to moving bars. Mean directional preferences as well as latencies were different between neurons of the two maps. Tracing experiments confirmed previous reports on the thalamo-wulst connections and showed that the anterior and the posterolateral map receive projections from separate clusters within the thalamic nuclei. Maps are connected to each other by wulst intrinsic projections. Our experiments confirm that the avian visual wulst contains several separate retinotopic maps with both different physiological properties and different thalamo-wulst afferents. This confirms that the functional organization of the visual wulst is very similar to its mammalian equivalent, the visual cortex.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0154927.bischof.PDF">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2903605/2903606/journal.pone.0154927.bischof.PDF</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLOS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">27139912</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000375675700076</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29036053</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0154927</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> H.-J. Bischof, et al., “Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2016, : e0154927.</ieee>
<apa>Bischof, H. - J., Eckmeier, D., Keary, N., Löwel, S., Mayer, U., &amp;amp; Michael, N. (2016). Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(5), e0154927. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0154927</apa>
<frontiers>Bischof, H. - J., Eckmeier, D., Keary, N., Löwel, S., Mayer, U., and Michael, N. (2016). Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 11:e0154927.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bischof, H.-J., Eckmeier, D., Keary, N., Löwel, S., Mayer, U. &amp;amp; Michael, N. (2016). Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(5): e0154927. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0154927.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bischof H-J, Eckmeier D, Keary N, Löwel S, Mayer U, Michael N. Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;11(5): e0154927.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H. - J.  Bischof, D.  Eckmeier, N.  Keary, S.  Löwel, U.  Mayer, and N.  Michael, “Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, : e0154927.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bischof, H. - J., Eckmeier, D., Keary, N., Löwel, S., Mayer, U., &amp;amp; Michael, N. (2016). Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(5), e0154927. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0154927&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bischof, H.-J., et al., 2016. Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 11(5): e0154927.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bischof H-J, Eckmeier D, Keary N, Löwel S, Mayer U, Michael N (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata).&lt;br /&gt;PLOS ONE 11(5): e0154927.</bio1>
<wels>Bischof, H. - J.; Eckmeier, D.; Keary, N.; Löwel, S.; Mayer, U.; Michael, N. (2016): Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata) &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,11:(5):e0154927</wels>
<default>Bischof H-J, Eckmeier D, Keary N, Löwel S, Mayer U, Michael N (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 11(5): e0154927.</default>
<mla>Bischof, Hans-Joachim, Eckmeier, Dennis, Keary, Nina, Löwel, Siegrid, Mayer, Uwe, and Michael, Neethu. “Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 11.5 (2016): e0154927.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bischof, Hans-Joachim, Eckmeier, Dennis, Keary, Nina, Löwel, Siegrid, Mayer, Uwe, and Michael, Neethu. 2016. “Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 11 (5): e0154927.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bischof, H.-J., Eckmeier, D., Keary, N., Löwel, S., Mayer, U., Michael, N.: Multiple Visual Field Representations in the Visual Wulst of a Laterally Eyed Bird, the Zebra Finch (Taeniopygia guttata). PLOS ONE. 11, : e0154927 (2016).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2903605</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-06-03T11:59:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>