<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2903894</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Roth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">38346305</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Lukas</namePart><namePart type="family">Rehm</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jochen</namePart><namePart type="family">Kemner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Olaf</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaltmeier</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38670945</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2903894/2943552/Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>WVT</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-86821-675-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29038944</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19</number></detail><extent unit="pages">73-96</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Roth, J. (2017). Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In L.  Rehm, J.  Kemner, &amp;amp; O.  Kaltmeier (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Inter-American Studies: Vol. 19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 73-96). Trier: WVT.</apa>
<ieee> J. Roth, “Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas”, &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, L. Rehm, J. Kemner, and O. Kaltmeier, eds., Inter-American Studies, vol. 19,  Trier: WVT, 2017,  pp.73-96.</ieee>
<harvard1>Roth, J., 2017. Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In L.  Rehm, J.  Kemner, &amp;amp; O.  Kaltmeier, eds. &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Inter-American Studies. no.19  Trier: WVT, pp. 73-96.</harvard1>
<default>Roth J (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives. Rehm L, Kemner J, Kaltmeier O (Eds);  Inter-American Studies, 19.  Trier: WVT:  73-96.</default>
<wels>Roth, J. (2017): Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In: Lukas Rehm; Jochen Kemner; Olaf Kaltmeier (Hrsg.):  Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives. Trier: WVT. (Inter-American Studies, 19).  S. 73-96.</wels>
<mla>Roth, Julia. “Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas”. &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Lukas Rehm, Jochen Kemner, and Olaf Kaltmeier. Trier: WVT, 2017.Vol. 19. Inter-American Studies. 73-96.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roth, J. (2017). Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In L.  Rehm, J.  Kemner, &amp;amp; O.  Kaltmeier (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Inter-American Studies: Vol. 19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 73-96). Trier: WVT.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Roth, J. (2017). “Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas” in &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Rehm, L., Kemner, J., and Kaltmeier, O. eds. Inter-American Studies, vol. 19, (Trier: WVT), 73-96.</frontiers>
<lncs> Roth, J.: Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In: Rehm, L., Kemner, J., and Kaltmeier, O. (eds.) Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives. Inter-American Studies. 19, p. 73-96. WVT, Trier (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roth, Julia. 2017. “Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas”. In &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Lukas Rehm, Jochen Kemner, and Olaf Kaltmeier, 19:73-96. Inter-American Studies. Trier: WVT.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Roth J. Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. In: Rehm L, Kemner J, Kaltmeier O, eds. &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Inter-American Studies. Vol 19. Trier: WVT;  2017: 73-96.</ama>
<bio1>Roth J (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives. Rehm L, Kemner J, Kaltmeier O (Eds); Inter-American Studies, 19. Trier: WVT:  73-96.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Roth, in &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: L. Rehm, J. Kemner, O. Kaltmeier), Wvt, Trier, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 73-96.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roth, J. (2017). Feminist Politics of Connectedness in the Americas (Inter-American Studies). In L. Rehm, J. Kemner &amp;amp; O. Kaltmeier (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Politics of Entanglement in the Americas. Connecting transnational flows and local perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (S. 73-96). Trier: WVT.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2903894</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-06-15T15:24:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-10-13T12:21:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>