<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2903600</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>

<targetAudience>general</targetAudience>


<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brandhorst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hautzinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Angelika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlarb</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46110571</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33700</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objective: Various research has shown that mothers of sleep-disturbed young children experience poorer physical and mental health, show more symptoms of depression or anxiety, and demonstrate a higher level of stress. Coping strategies and self-efficacy might play an important role in this context. In the present study we aimed to investigate psychosocial health, coping, and the sleep-related self-efficacy of parents participating in an Internetbased treatment for sleep-disturbed young children (six months to four years of age).

Methods: N=199 mothers and N=197 fathers answered questionnaires regarding psychosocial health, coping, and sleep-related self-efficacy before, immediately after, and three months after treatment. Two intervention conditions (written information only vs. additional telephone support) were compared to a waiting-list control condition. The treatment essentially addressed the child´s sleep situation but also included information on parental coping and psychosocial health.

Results: Both parents showed impaired psychosocial health (depression, compulsiveness) and more maladaptive coping (rumination, self-blame) before treatment. Feelings of aggression were reported by mothers only. More psychopathological symptoms in both parents were related to more maladaptive coping strategies and less sleep-related self-efficacy. Adaptive coping was associated with higher sleep-related self-efficacy, while maladaptive coping was related to lower sleep-related self-efficacy in mothers only. Mothers in both treatment conditions improved their psychosocial health (e.g., depression, somatization, anxiety, aggression) and their ability to cope in some scales (increase: relaxation, trivialization; decrease: rumination) after treatment. For fathers, only a few changes were observed. The impaired sleep-related self-efficacy of both parents improved with treatment. Personal telephone support rarely affected the results.

Conclusion: Teaching parents to treat their child´s sleep problem can improve impairments in psychosocial health, coping, and self-efficacy predominantly in mothers.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="improving-psychosocial-health-coping-and-selfefficacy-in-parents-of-sleepdisturbed-young-children-2161-0487-1000249.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2903600/2903601/improving-psychosocial-health-coping-and-selfefficacy-in-parents-of-sleepdisturbed-young-children-2161-0487-1000249.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>OMICS Publishing Group</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Psychology &amp; Psychotherapy</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2161-0487</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29036003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4172/2161-0487.1000249</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M., Schlarb, A.: Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy. 6, : 1000249 (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandhorst, Isabel, Hautzinger, Martin, and Schlarb, Angelika. 2016. “Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt; 6 (2): 1000249.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Brandhorst I, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A. Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;6(2): 1000249.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Brandhorst, M.  Hautzinger, and A.  Schlarb, “Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, : 1000249.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Brandhorst I, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy 6(2): 1000249.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M. &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2016). Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2): 1000249. OMICS Publishing Group. doi:10.4172/2161-0487.1000249.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2016). Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2), 1000249. doi:10.4172/2161-0487.1000249</apa>
<harvard1>Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A., 2016. Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, 6(2): 1000249.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Brandhorst, M. Hautzinger, and A. Schlarb, “Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 2016, : 1000249.</ieee>
<default>Brandhorst I, Hautzinger M, Schlarb A (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt; 6(2): 1000249.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2016). Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2), 1000249. doi:10.4172/2161-0487.1000249&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Brandhorst, Isabel, Hautzinger, Martin, and Schlarb, Angelika. “Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt; 6.2 (2016): 1000249.</mla>
<frontiers>Brandhorst, I., Hautzinger, M., and Schlarb, A. (2016). Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt; 6:1000249.</frontiers>
<wels>Brandhorst, I.; Hautzinger, M.; Schlarb, A. (2016): Improving Psychosocial Health, Coping, and Self-Efficacy in Parents of Sleep-Disturbed Young Children &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychology &amp;amp; Psychotherapy&lt;/em&gt;,6:(2):1000249</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2903600</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-06-03T10:14:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T11:26:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>