<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904178</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cosima</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Prahm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paaßen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49941564</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3899-2450</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34943216</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0739-612X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oskar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aszmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jaime</namePart><namePart type="family">Ibáñez</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">José</namePart><namePart type="family">Gonzáles-Vargas</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">José María</namePart><namePart type="family">Azorín</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Metin</namePart><namePart type="family">Akay</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">José Luis</namePart><namePart type="family">Pons</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>3rd International Conference on Neural Rehabilitation</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">For decades, researchers have attempted to provide patients with an intuitive method to control upper limb prostheses, enabling them to manipulate multiple degrees of freedom continuously and simultaneously using only simple myoelectric signals. However, such controlling schemes are still highly vulnerable to disturbances in the myoelectric signal, due to electrode shifts, posture changes, sweat, fatigue etc. Recent research has demonstrated that such robustness problems can be alleviated by rapid re-calibration of the prosthesis once a day, using only very small amounts of training data (less than one minute of training time). In this contribution, we propose such a re-calibration scheme for a pattern recognition controller based on transfer learning. In a pilot study with able-bodied subjects we demonstrate that high controller accuracy can be re-obtained after strong electrode shift, even for simultaneous movements in multiple degrees of freedom.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="prahm_paassen_schulz_hammer_aszmann_transfer_learning_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904178/2906343/prahm_paassen_schulz_hammer_aszmann_transfer_learning_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-octet-stream</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Segovia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29041788</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-46669-9_28</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">153--157</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Prahm, C., et al., 2016. Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In J.  Ibáñez, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;.  Springer, pp. 153--157.</harvard1>
<bio1>Prahm C, Paaßen B, Schulz A, Hammer B, Aszmann O (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016). Ibáñez J, Gonzáles-Vargas J, Azorín JM, Akay M, Pons JL (Eds); Springer:  153--157.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prahm, C., Paaßen, B., Schulz, A., Hammer, B., &amp;amp; Aszmann, O. (2016). Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In J.  Ibáñez, J.  Gonzáles-Vargas, J. M.  Azorín, M.  Akay, &amp;amp; J. L.  Pons (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153--157). Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46669-9_28&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Prahm, B.  Paaßen, A.  Schulz, B.  Hammer, and O.  Aszmann, in &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Ibáñez, J. Gonzáles-Vargas, J.M. Azorín, M. Akay, J.L. Pons), Springer, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 153--157.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Prahm, C.; Paaßen, B.; Schulz, A.; Hammer, B.; Aszmann, O. (2016): Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In: Jaime Ibáñez; José Gonzáles-Vargas; José María Azorín; Metin Akay; José Luis Pons (Hrsg.):  Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016). Springer.  S. 153--157.</wels>
<apa>Prahm, C., Paaßen, B., Schulz, A., Hammer, B., &amp;amp; Aszmann, O. (2016). Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In J.  Ibáñez, J.  Gonzáles-Vargas, J. M.  Azorín, M.  Akay, &amp;amp; J. L.  Pons (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153--157). Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46669-9_28</apa>
<ieee> C. Prahm, et al., “Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift”, &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;, J. Ibáñez, et al., eds., Springer, 2016,  pp.153--157.</ieee>
<ama>Prahm C, Paaßen B, Schulz A, Hammer B, Aszmann O. Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In: Ibáñez J, Gonzáles-Vargas J, Azorín JM, Akay M, Pons JL, eds. &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;. Springer;  2016: 153--157.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prahm, C., Paaßen, B., Schulz, A., Hammer, B. &amp;amp; Aszmann, O. (2016). Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In J. Ibáñez, J. Gonzáles-Vargas, J.M. Azorín, M. Akay &amp;amp; J.L. Pons (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 153--157). Gehalten auf der 3rd International Conference on Neural Rehabilitation, Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46669-9_28.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Prahm, C., Paaßen, B., Schulz, A., Hammer, B., and Aszmann, O. (2016). “Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift” in &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;, Ibáñez, J., Gonzáles-Vargas, J., Azorín, J. M., Akay, M., and Pons, J. L. eds. (Springer), 153--157.</frontiers>
<mla>Prahm, Cosima, Paaßen, Benjamin, Schulz, Alexander, Hammer, Barbara, and Aszmann, Oskar. “Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift”. &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jaime Ibáñez, José Gonzáles-Vargas, José María Azorín, Metin Akay, and José Luis Pons. Springer, 2016. 153--157.</mla>
<default>Prahm C, Paaßen B, Schulz A, Hammer B, Aszmann O (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016). Ibáñez J, Gonzáles-Vargas J, Azorín JM, Akay M, Pons JL (Eds);  Springer:  153--157.</default>
<lncs> Prahm, C., Paaßen, B., Schulz, A., Hammer, B., Aszmann, O.: Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift. In: Ibáñez, J., Gonzáles-Vargas, J., Azorín, J.M., Akay, M., and Pons, J.L. (eds.) Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016). p. 153--157. Springer (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prahm, Cosima, Paaßen, Benjamin, Schulz, Alexander, Hammer, Barbara, and Aszmann, Oskar. 2016. “Transfer Learning for Rapid Re-calibration of a Myoelectric Prosthesis after Electrode Shift”. In &lt;em&gt;Converging Clinical and Engineering Research on Neurorehabilitation II: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on NeuroRehabilitation (ICNR2016)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jaime Ibáñez, José Gonzáles-Vargas, José María Azorín, Metin Akay, and José Luis Pons, 153--157. Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904178</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-06-20T13:17:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>