<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904611</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Viktor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Richter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">52311626</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0301-0525</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Birte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Carlmeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46832369</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0957-2406</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer zu Borgsen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">50802023</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0887-5672</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kummert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10372</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10380</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4th Internation Conference on Human Agent Interaction</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>The Cognitive Service Robotics Apartment as Ambient Host (CSRA, LSP-01)</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present our humanoid robot “Meka”, partici- pating in a multi party human robot dialogue scenario. Active arbitration of the robot's attention based-on multi-modal stim- uli is utilised to attain persons which are outside of the robots field of view. We investigate the impact of this attention management and an addressee recognition on the robot's capability to distinguish utterances directed at it from communication between humans. Based on the results of a user study, we show that mutual gaze at the end of an utterance, as a means of yielding a turn, is a substantial cue for addressee recognition. Verification of a speaker through the detection of lip movements can be used to further increase precision. Further- more, we show that even a rather simplistic fusion of gaze and lip movement cues allows a considerable enhancement in addressee estimation, and can be altered to adapt to the requirements of a particular scenario.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904611/2912317/preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACM Digital Library</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Singapore</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29046115</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1145/2974804.2974823</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Richter V, Carlmeyer B, Lier F, Meyer zu Borgsen S, Schlangen D, Kummert F, Wachsmuth S, Wrede B (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction.  Singapore: ACM Digital Library.</default>
<wels>Richter, V.; Carlmeyer, B.; Lier, F.; Meyer zu Borgsen, S.; Schlangen, D.; Kummert, F.; Wachsmuth, S.; Wrede, B. (2016): Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. In: Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction. Singapore: ACM Digital Library. (Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction, ).</wels>
<frontiers>Richter, V., Carlmeyer, B., Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Schlangen, D., Kummert, F., Wachsmuth, S., and Wrede, B. (2016). “Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction (Singapore: ACM Digital Library).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Richter, V., Carlmeyer, B., Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Schlangen, D., Kummert, F., Wachsmuth, S., et al. (2016). Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction Singapore: ACM Digital Library. doi:10.1145/2974804.2974823&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Richter, Viktor, Carlmeyer, Birte, Lier, Florian, Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Schlangen, David, Kummert, Franz, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Britta. “Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Singapore: ACM Digital Library, 2016. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction.</mla>
<apa>Richter, V., Carlmeyer, B., Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Schlangen, D., Kummert, F., Wachsmuth, S., et al. (2016). Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction Singapore: ACM Digital Library. doi:10.1145/2974804.2974823</apa>
<harvard1>Richter, V., et al., 2016. Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction.  Singapore: ACM Digital Library.</harvard1>
<ieee> V. Richter, et al., “Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction,  Singapore: ACM Digital Library, 2016.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Richter, B.  Carlmeyer, F.  Lier, S.  Meyer zu Borgsen, D.  Schlangen, F.  Kummert, S.  Wachsmuth, and B.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Acm Digital Library, Singapore, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Richter V, Carlmeyer B, Lier F, Meyer zu Borgsen S, Schlangen D, Kummert F, Wachsmuth S, Wrede B (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction.  Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction,  Singapore: ACM Digital Library.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Richter, V., Carlmeyer, B., Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Schlangen, D., Kummert, F., Wachsmuth, S. &amp;amp; Wrede, B. (2016). Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees (Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 4th Internation Conference on Human Agent Interaction, Singapore: ACM Digital Library. doi:10.1145/2974804.2974823.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Richter, Viktor, Carlmeyer, Birte, Lier, Florian, Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Schlangen, David, Kummert, Franz, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Britta. 2016. “Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction. Singapore: ACM Digital Library.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Richter, V., Carlmeyer, B., Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Schlangen, D., Kummert, F., Wachsmuth, S., Wrede, B.: Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction.  ACM Digital Library, Singapore (2016).</lncs>
<ama>Richter V, Carlmeyer B, Lier F, et al. Are you talking to me? Improving the robustness of dialogue systems in a multi party HRI scenario by incorporating gaze direction and lip movement of attendees. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Human-agent Interaction. Singapore: ACM Digital Library;  2016.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904611</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-12T09:59:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:55:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>