<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904516</id><setSpec>research_data</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:ResearchData</setSpec><setSpec>research_dataFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>database</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Janet Junqing</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Alcohol use is reported in university students with discrepancy between countries. The study objectives were to assess prevalence and associated factors of alcohol consumption among university students in Germany and China.
Methods: Data were from 1,853 Chinese, and 3,306 German university students. Alcohol consumption frequency was measured by a question “How often did you drink alcohol in the last three months?” with possible options of “At least once a week”, “Less than once a week” and “Never”. Problem drinking was measured by the CAGE test, and defined as a CAGE score of two or more (four as the maximum). Simple and multivariable logistic regressions were used for data analyses.
Results: German students reported more often “At least once a week” drinking (59.8% vs. 9.0%). Among Germans, women drank less often “At least once a week” (OR = 0.40, 0.30-0.53). Among Chinese, higher BMI was associated with drinking “At least once a week” (OR = 1.09, 1.02-1.18). Age revealed a positive association with “At least once a week” drinking in Chinese (1.33, 1.21-1.46) but a negative association in Germans (OR = 0.97, 0.94-0.99). Having a father with high educational level was positively (OR = 4.25, 2.67-6.78 for Chinese, OR = 1.32, 1.01-1.72 for Germans) related to “At least once a week” drinking in both countries. Doing less than once a week physical exercise was negatively (OR = 0.27, 0.15-0.48 for Chinese, OR = 0.69, 0.49-0.96 for Germans) associated with “At least once a week” drinking in Chinese and German students. Among the German students 20.3% reported problem drinking. Being a female (OR = 0.32, 0.26-0.40) and performing less than once a week physical activity (OR = 0.72, 0.55-0.95) were negatively associated with problem drinking, while having a father with high educational level (OR = 1.31, 1.08-1.59) and experiencing higher level of perceived stress (OR = 1.09, 1.04-1.14) were positively related to problem drinking. 
Conclusions: Our findings underscore country-specific preventive strategies.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Sino-German comparison in alcohol consumption in university students  sav.sav">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904516/2904517/Sino-German comparison in alcohol consumption in university students  sav.sav</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/octet-stream</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://opendatacommons.org/licenses/pddl/summary/index.html</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>

<subject><topic>Alcohol consumption</topic><topic>Students' health</topic><topic>University students</topic><topic>Chinese students</topic><topic>German students</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2904516</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, Alexander, and Chu, Janet Junqing. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Krämer, A., Chu, J.J.: Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students. Bielefeld University (2016).</lncs>
<apa>Krämer, A., &amp;amp; Chu, J. J. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2904516</apa>
<ama>Krämer A, Chu JJ. &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University; 2016.</ama>
<harvard1>Krämer, A., &amp;amp; Chu, J.J., 2016. &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Krämer and J.J. Chu, &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, 2016.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Krämer, and J. J.  Chu, &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Krämer A, Chu JJ (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<default>Krämer A, Chu JJ (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, A. &amp;amp; Chu, J.J. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2904516.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Krämer, A., &amp;amp; Chu, J. J. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2904516&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Krämer, A., and Chu, J. J. (2016). Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students. Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<mla>Krämer, Alexander, and Chu, Janet Junqing. &lt;em&gt;Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University, 2016.</mla>
<wels>Krämer, A.; Chu, J. J. (2016): Alcohol consumption among university students:  A Sino-German comparison demonstrates a much lower consumption of alcohol  in Chinese students. Bielefeld University.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904516</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-05T14:06:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>