<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904502</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Verena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ertl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10287303</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Regina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Saile</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34401509</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neuner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9438235</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Catani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9988099</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33704</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">
Background

It is likely that alcohol use and abuse increase during and after violent conflicts. The most prominent explanation of this phenomenon has been referred to as self-medication hypothesis. It predicts that psychotropic substances are consumed to deal with conflict-related psychic strains and trauma. In northern Uganda, a region that has been affected by a devastating civil war and is characterized by high levels of alcohol abuse we examined the associations between war-trauma, childhood maltreatment and problems related to alcohol use. Deducing from the self-medication hypothesis we assumed alcohol consumption moderates the relationship between trauma-exposure and psychopathology.
Methods

A cross-sectional epidemiological survey targeting war-affected families in post-conflict northern Uganda included data of male (n = 304) and female (n = 365) guardians. We used standardized questionnaires in an interview format to collect data on the guardians’ socio-demography, trauma-exposure, alcohol consumption and symptoms of alcohol abuse, PTSD and depression.
Results

Symptoms of current alcohol use disorders were present in 46 % of the male and 1 % of the female respondents. A multiple regression model revealed the unique contributions of emotional abuse in the families of origin and trauma experienced outside the family-context in the prediction of men’s alcohol-related symptoms. We found that alcohol consumption moderated the dose-effect relationship between trauma-exposure and symptoms of depression and PTSD. Significant interactions indicated that men who reported more alcohol-related problems experienced less increase in symptoms of PTSD and depression with increasing trauma-exposure.
Conclusions

The gradual attenuation of the dose-effect the more alcohol-related problems were reported is consistent with the self-medication hypothesis. Hence, the functionality of alcohol consumption has to be considered when designing and implementing addiction treatment in post-conflict contexts.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bmc.psych.ertl.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904502/2904782/bmc.psych.ertl.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Trauma Addiction Alcohol Substance abuse Self-medication Depression PTSD Mental health Conflict War</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Psychiatry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-244X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">27342048</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000378841400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29045023</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12888-016-0905-7</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ertl, Verena, Saile, Regina, Neuner, Frank, and Catani, Claudia. 2016. “Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 16 (1): 202.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ertl, V., Saile, R., Neuner, F., Catani, C.: Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. BMC Psychiatry. 16, : 202 (2016).</lncs>
<ama>Ertl V, Saile R, Neuner F, Catani C. Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;16(1): 202.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Ertl, R.  Saile, F.  Neuner, and C.  Catani, “Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, : 202.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ertl V, Saile R, Neuner F, Catani C (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Psychiatry 16(1): 202.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ertl, V., Saile, R., Neuner, F. &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2016). Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1): 202. Springer. doi:10.1186/s12888-016-0905-7.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Ertl, V., Saile, R., Neuner, F., &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2016). Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 202. doi:10.1186/s12888-016-0905-7</apa>
<harvard1>Ertl, V., et al., 2016. Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, 16(1): 202.</harvard1>
<ieee> V. Ertl, et al., “Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2016, : 202.</ieee>
<default>Ertl V, Saile R, Neuner F, Catani C (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 16(1): 202.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ertl, V., Saile, R., Neuner, F., &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2016). Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 202. doi:10.1186/s12888-016-0905-7&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Ertl, V., Saile, R., Neuner, F., and Catani, C. (2016). Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 16:202.</frontiers>
<mla>Ertl, Verena, Saile, Regina, Neuner, Frank, and Catani, Claudia. “Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 16.1 (2016): 202.</mla>
<wels>Ertl, V.; Saile, R.; Neuner, F.; Catani, C. (2016): Drinking to ease the burden: a cross-sectional study on trauma, alcohol abuse and psychopathology in a post-conflict context &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,16:(1):202</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904502</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-05T09:48:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>