<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904445</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soufian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jebbara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">61955542</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4483-0933</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Harald</namePart><namePart type="family">Sack</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart><namePart type="family">Dietze</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anna</namePart><namePart type="family">Tordai</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart><namePart type="family">Lange</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>3rd SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="eswc2016.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904445/2906424/eswc2016.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Heraklion, Crete, Greece</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-46564-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29044455</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-46565-4_12</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>641</number></detail><extent unit="pages">153-170</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2906020</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2016. “Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture”. In &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Harald Sack, Stefan Dietze, Anna Tordai, and Christoph Lange, 641:153-170. Communications in Computer and Information Science. Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jebbara, S., Cimiano, P.: Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In: Sack, H., Dietze, S., Tordai, A., and Lange, C. (eds.) Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers. Communications in Computer and Information Science. 641, p. 153-170. Springer, Cham (2016).</lncs>
<default>Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers. Sack H, Dietze S, Tordai A, Lange C (Eds);  Communications in Computer and Information Science, 641.  Cham: Springer:  153-170.</default>
<mla>Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture”. &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Harald Sack, Stefan Dietze, Anna Tordai, and Christoph Lange. Cham: Springer, 2016.Vol. 641. Communications in Computer and Information Science. 153-170.</mla>
<wels>Jebbara, S.; Cimiano, P. (2016): Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In: Harald Sack; Stefan Dietze; Anna Tordai; Christoph Lange (Hrsg.):  Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers. Cham: Springer. (Communications in Computer and Information Science, 641).  S. 153-170.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Jebbara, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Sack, S. Dietze, A. Tordai, C. Lange), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 153-170.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2016. Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In H.  Sack, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Communications in Computer and Information Science. no.641  Cham: Springer, pp. 153-170.</harvard1>
<bio1>Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers. Sack H, Dietze S, Tordai A, Lange C (Eds); Communications in Computer and Information Science, 641. Cham: Springer:  153-170.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2016). Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In H.  Sack, S.  Dietze, A.  Tordai, &amp;amp; C.  Lange (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Communications in Computer and Information Science: Vol. 641&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153-170). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46565-4_12&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2016). Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture (Communications in Computer and Information Science). In H. Sack, S. Dietze, A. Tordai &amp;amp; C. Lange (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (S. 153-170). Gehalten auf der 3rd SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016, Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46565-4_12.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Jebbara, S., and Cimiano, P. (2016). “Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture” in &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, Sack, H., Dietze, S., Tordai, A., and Lange, C. eds. Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol. 641, (Cham: Springer), 153-170.</frontiers>
<ama>Jebbara S, Cimiano P. Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In: Sack H, Dietze S, Tordai A, Lange C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;. Communications in Computer and Information Science. Vol 641. Cham: Springer;  2016: 153-170.</ama>
<ieee> S. Jebbara and P. Cimiano, “Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture”, &lt;em&gt;Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt;, H. Sack, et al., eds., Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol. 641,  Cham: Springer, 2016,  pp.153-170.</ieee>
<apa>Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2016). Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using a Two-Step Neural Network Architecture. In H.  Sack, S.  Dietze, A.  Tordai, &amp;amp; C.  Lange (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Communications in Computer and Information Science: Vol. 641&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Semantic Web Challenges. Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016. Revised Selected Papers&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 153-170). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-46565-4_12</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904445</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-06-30T13:31:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>