<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904550</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hantzi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Efthymios</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lampridis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katerina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tsantila</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bohner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">44335</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0564-3625</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33698</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression scale measures contemporary beliefs about sexual aggression that tend to blame victims and exonerate perpetrators. A Greek version of the thirty-item AMMSA scale was administered to two diverse convenience samples, one in Greece and one in Cyprus. Convergent and discriminant construct validity were assessed via correlations with other constructs that were hypothesized to be strongly related to AMMSA (Illinois Rape Myth Acceptance; hostile sexism) or moderately related (benevolent sexism; social dominance orientation; right-wing authoritarianism). It was found that the Greek AMMSA was unidimensional, highly internally consistent, normally distributed, and showed good construct validity. When sociodemographic data were analyzed, age, gender, and nationality turned out to be significant predictors of AMMSA, with a U-shaped trend for age, higher scores for men than women, and higher scores for Cypriots than Greeks. In sum, the Greek AMMSA scale provides a highly useful instrument for further research on sexual aggression myths, their correlates, and effects on judgment and behavior.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Hantzi et al 2015 IJCV Greek AMMSA.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904550/2937821/Hantzi et al 2015 IJCV Greek AMMSA.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Inst Interdisciplinary Res</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>AMMSA</topic><topic>Cyprus</topic><topic>Greece</topic><topic>rape myths</topic><topic>scale validation</topic><topic>sexual violence</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Conflict and Violence</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1864-1385</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000377398000010</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29045507</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/ijcv-3072</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">121-133</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Hantzi, et al., “Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2015,  pp. 121-133.</ieee>
<apa>Hantzi, A., Lampridis, E., Tsantila, K., &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (2015). Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 121-133.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hantzi, A., Lampridis, E., Tsantila, K. &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (2015). Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 121-133. Inst Interdisciplinary Res.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hantzi, A., Lampridis, E., Tsantila, K., and Bohner, G. (2015). Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 9, 121-133.</frontiers>
<ama>Hantzi A, Lampridis E, Tsantila K, Bohner G. Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;. 2015;9(1):121-133.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Hantzi, E.  Lampridis, K.  Tsantila, and G.  Bohner, “Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 121-133.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hantzi, A., Lampridis, E., Tsantila, K., &amp;amp; Bohner, G. (2015). Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 121-133.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hantzi A, Lampridis E, Tsantila K, Bohner G (2015) &lt;br /&gt;Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence 9(1): 121-133.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hantzi, A., et al., 2015. Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, 9(1), p 121-133.</harvard1>
<wels>Hantzi, A.; Lampridis, E.; Tsantila, K.; Bohner, G. (2015): Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;,9:(1): 121-133.</wels>
<default>Hantzi A, Lampridis E, Tsantila K, Bohner G (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 9(1): 121-133.</default>
<mla>Hantzi, Alexandra, Lampridis, Efthymios, Tsantila, Katerina, and Bohner, Gerd. “Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 9.1 (2015): 121-133.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hantzi, Alexandra, Lampridis, Efthymios, Tsantila, Katerina, and Bohner, Gerd. 2015. “Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 9 (1): 121-133.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hantzi, A., Lampridis, E., Tsantila, K., Bohner, G.: Validation of the Greek Acceptance of Modern Myths about Sexual Aggression (AMMSA) Scale: Examining its relationships with sexist and conservative political beliefs. International Journal of Conflict and Violence. 9, 121-133 (2015).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904550</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-07T08:13:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-16T10:15:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>