<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2904605</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanheide</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lorenzo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Natale</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10341417</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jonathan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weisz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart><namePart type="family">Burgard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Even though research on autonomous robots and human-robot  interaction  accomplished  great  progress  in  recent  years,  and  reusable  soft-  and  hardware  components  are available,   many   of   the   reported   findings   are   only   hardly reproducible  by  fellow  scientists.  Usually,  reproducibility  is impeded because required information, such as the specification of software versions and their configuration, required data sets, and  experiment  protocols  are  not  mentioned  or  referenced in  most  publications.  In  order  to  address  these  issues,  we recently introduced an integrated tool chain and its underlying development  process  to  facilitate  reproducibility  in  robotics.
In  this  contribution  we  instantiate  the  complete  tool  chain  in a  unique  user  study  in  order  to  assess  its  applicability  and usability. To this end, we chose three different robotic systems
from  independent  institutions  and  modeled  them  in  our  tool chain,  including  three  exemplary  experiments.  Subsequently, we  asked  twelve  researchers  to  reproduce  one  of  the  formerly unknown systems and the associated experiment. We show that all twelve scientists were able to replicate a formerly unknown robotics  experiment  using  our  tool  chain.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="citk-flier-preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2904605/2905943/citk-flier-preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Daejeon, Korea</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29046050</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, Florian, Hanheide, Marc, Natale, Lorenzo, Schulz, Simon, Weisz, Jonathan, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2016. “Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics”. In &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Wolfram Burgard. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lier, F., Hanheide, M., Natale, L., Schulz, S., Weisz, J., Wachsmuth, S., Wrede, S.: Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In: Burgard, W. (ed.) 2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).  IEEE, Daejeon, Korea (2016).</lncs>
<default>Lier F, Hanheide M, Natale L, Schulz S, Weisz J, Wachsmuth S, Wrede S (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Burgard W (Ed);  International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).  Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.</default>
<mla>Lier, Florian, Hanheide, Marc, Natale, Lorenzo, Schulz, Simon, Weisz, Jonathan, Wachsmuth, Sven, and Wrede, Sebastian. “Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics”. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Wolfram Burgard. Daejeon, Korea: IEEE, 2016. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Hanheide, M., Natale, L., Schulz, S., Weisz, J., Wachsmuth, S. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics (International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). In W. Burgard (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Lier, F., Hanheide, M., Natale, L., Schulz, S., Weisz, J., Wachsmuth, S., and Wrede, S. (2016). “Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics” in &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;, Burgard, W. ed. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) (Daejeon, Korea: IEEE).</frontiers>
<ama>Lier F, Hanheide M, Natale L, et al. Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In: Burgard W, ed. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Daejeon, Korea: IEEE;  2016.</ama>
<ieee> F. Lier, et al., “Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics”, &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;, W. Burgard, ed., International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS),  Daejeon, Korea: IEEE, 2016.</ieee>
<apa>Lier, F., Hanheide, M., Natale, L., Schulz, S., Weisz, J., Wachsmuth, S., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In W.  Burgard (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. 2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt; Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.</apa>
<wels>Lier, F.; Hanheide, M.; Natale, L.; Schulz, S.; Weisz, J.; Wachsmuth, S.; Wrede, S. (2016): Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In: Wolfram Burgard (Hrsg.):  2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Daejeon, Korea: IEEE. (International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), ).</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Lier, M.  Hanheide, L.  Natale, S.  Schulz, J.  Weisz, S.  Wachsmuth, and S.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: W. Burgard), Ieee, Daejeon, Korea, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Hanheide, M., Natale, L., Schulz, S., Weisz, J., Wachsmuth, S., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In W.  Burgard (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. 2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt; Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Lier F, Hanheide M, Natale L, Schulz S, Weisz J, Wachsmuth S, Wrede S (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Burgard W (Ed); International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS),  Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.</bio1>
<harvard1>Lier, F., et al., 2016. Towards Automated System and Experiment Reproduction in Robotics. In W.  Burgard, ed. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).  Daejeon, Korea: IEEE.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2904605</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-07-11T15:35:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>