<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2905179</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rania</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rayyes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">63759632</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11608</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="RayyesSteil_GB_FloattingBase.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2905179/2906028/RayyesSteil_GB_FloattingBase.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29051793</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">56-63</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rayyes, R., &amp;amp; Steil, J. J. (2016). Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 56-63.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Rayyes, R., and Steil, J. J. (2016). “Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt; Machine Learning Reports, vol. 4, 56-63.</frontiers>
<mla>Rayyes, Rania, and Steil, Jochen J. “Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;. 2016.Vol. 4. Machine Learning Reports. 56-63.</mla>
<wels>Rayyes, R.; Steil, J. J. (2016): Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. In: Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation. (Machine Learning Reports, 4).  S. 56-63.</wels>
<default>Rayyes R, Steil JJ (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation. Machine Learning Reports, 4.   56-63.</default>
<ieee> R. Rayyes and J.J. Steil, “Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, vol. 4, 2016,  pp.56-63.</ieee>
<harvard1>Rayyes, R., &amp;amp; Steil, J.J., 2016. Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. no.4 pp. 56-63.</harvard1>
<apa>Rayyes, R., &amp;amp; Steil, J. J. (2016). Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 56-63.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rayyes, R. &amp;amp; Steil, J.J. (2016). Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot (Machine Learning Reports). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt; (S. 56-63).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Rayyes R, Steil JJ (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation.  Machine Learning Reports, 4. 56-63.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Rayyes, and J. J.  Steil, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 56-63.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Rayyes R, Steil JJ. Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. Vol 4. 2016: 56-63.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rayyes, Rania, and Steil, Jochen J. 2016. “Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation&lt;/em&gt;, 4:56-63. Machine Learning Reports.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Rayyes, R., Steil, J.J.: Goal Babbling with direction sampling for simultaneous exploration and learning of inverse kinematics of a humanoid robot. Proceedings of the workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation. Machine Learning Reports. 4, p. 56-63. (2016).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2905179</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-16T09:07:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>