<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2905467</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wienke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20991629</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4517-5368</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Unintended changes in the utilization of resources like CPU and memory can lead to severe problems for the operation of robotics and intelligent systems. Still, systematic testing for such performance regressions has largely been ignored in this domain. We present a method to specify
and execute performance tests for individual components of component-based robotics systems based on their component interfaces. The method includes an automatic analysis of each component revision against previous ones that reports potential changes to the resource usage characteristics. This informs developers about the impact of their changes. We describe the
design of the framework and present evaluation results for the automatic detection of performance changes based on tests for a variety of robotics components.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="simpar2016-perftest.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2905467/2908058/simpar2016-perftest.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">San Francisco, CA, USA</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>resource utilization</topic><topic>testing</topic><topic>regression testing</topic><topic>performance</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29054670</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/SIMPAR.2016.7862407</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2913636</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Wienke J, Wrede S (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR).  IEEE.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Wienke, and S.  Wrede, in &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots, IEEE. doi:10.1109/SIMPAR.2016.7862407.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, Johannes, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2016. “Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization”. In &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wienke, J., Wrede, S.: Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR).  IEEE (2016).</lncs>
<ama>Wienke J, Wrede S. Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. In:  &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE;  2016.</ama>
<default>Wienke J, Wrede S (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR). IEEE.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wienke, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt; IEEE. doi:10.1109/SIMPAR.2016.7862407&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wienke, Johannes, and Wrede, Sebastian. “Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization”. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE, 2016.</mla>
<frontiers>Wienke, J., and Wrede, S. (2016). “Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization” in &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt; (IEEE).</frontiers>
<wels>Wienke, J.; Wrede, S. (2016): Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. In: 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR). IEEE.</wels>
<apa>Wienke, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2016). Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt; IEEE. doi:10.1109/SIMPAR.2016.7862407</apa>
<ieee> J. Wienke and S. Wrede, “Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization”, &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE, 2016.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wienke, J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S., 2016. Continuous Regression Testing for Component Resource Utilization. In &lt;em&gt;2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and  Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&lt;/em&gt;.  IEEE.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2905467</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-02T11:02:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-19T13:29:41Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>