<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2905709</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Poth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26116405</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Werner X.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8139667</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33694</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Rapid saccadic eye movements bring the foveal region of the eye's retina onto objects for high-acuity vision. Saccades change the location and resolution of objects' retinal images. To perceive objects as visually stable across saccades, correspondence between the objects before and after the saccade must be established. We have previously shown that breaking object correspondence across the saccade causes a decrement in object recognition (Poth, Herwig, &amp; Schneider, 2015). Color and luminance can establish object correspondence, but it is unknown how these surface features contribute to transsaccadic visual processing. Here, we investigated whether changing the surface features color-and-luminance and color alone across saccades impairs postsaccadic object recognition. Participants made saccades to peripheral objects, which either maintained or changed their surface features across the saccade. After the saccade, participants briefly viewed a letter within the saccade target object (terminated by a pattern mask). Postsaccadic object recognition was assessed as participants' accuracy in reporting the letter. Experiment A used the colors green and red with different luminances as surface features, Experiment B blue and yellow with approximately the same luminances. Changing the surface features across the saccade deteriorated postsaccadic object recognition in both experiments. These findings reveal a link between object recognition and object correspondence relying on the surface features colors and luminance, which is currently not addressed in theories of transsaccadic perception. We interpret the findings within a recent theory ascribing this link to visual attention (Schneider, 2013).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="i1534-7362-16-11-1.poth.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2905709/2905710/i1534-7362-16-11-1.poth.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology (ARVO)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Vision</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1534-7362</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28558391</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000385756900001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29057094</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1167/16.11.1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>11</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poth, Christian H., and Schneider, Werner X. 2016. “Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt; 16 (11): 1.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Poth, C.H., Schneider, W.X.: Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. Journal of Vision. 16, : 1 (2016).</lncs>
<default>Poth CH, Schneider WX (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt; 16(11): 1.</default>
<mla>Poth, Christian H., and Schneider, Werner X. “Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt; 16.11 (2016): 1.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poth, C.H. &amp;amp; Schneider, W.X. (2016). Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(11): 1. Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology (ARVO). doi:10.1167/16.11.1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Poth, C. H., and Schneider, W. X. (2016). Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt; 16:1.</frontiers>
<ama>Poth CH, Schneider WX. Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;16(11): 1.</ama>
<ieee> C.H. Poth and W.X. Schneider, “Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2016, : 1.</ieee>
<apa>Poth, C. H., &amp;amp; Schneider, W. X. (2016). Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1. doi:10.1167/16.11.1</apa>
<wels>Poth, C. H.; Schneider, W. X. (2016): Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;,16:(11):1</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>C. H.  Poth, and W. X.  Schneider, “Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, : 1.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Poth, C. H., &amp;amp; Schneider, W. X. (2016). Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1. doi:10.1167/16.11.1&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Poth CH, Schneider WX (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Vision 16(11): 1.</bio1>
<harvard1>Poth, C.H., &amp;amp; Schneider, W.X., 2016. Breaking object correspondence across saccades impairs object recognition: The role of color and luminance. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vision&lt;/em&gt;, 16(11): 1.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2905709</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-14T10:06:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>