<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2905495</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Irla</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">34792979</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tonje M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heggeset</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingemar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Naerdal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lidia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paul</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tone</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haugen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simone B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Le</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Trygve</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brautaset</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17527752</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Bacillus methanolicus is a thermophilic methylotroph able to overproduce amino acids from methanol, a substrate not used for human or animal nutrition. Based on our previous RNA-seq analysis a mannitol inducible promoter and a putative mannitol activator gene mtlR were identified. The mannitol inducible promoter was applied for controlled gene expression using fluorescent reporter proteins and a flow cytometry analysis, and improved by changing the -35 promoter region and by co-expression of the mtlR regulator gene. For independent complementary gene expression control, the heterologous xylose-inducible system from B. megaterium was employed and a two-plasmid gene expression system was developed. Four different replicons for expression vectors were compared with respect to their copy number and stability. As an application example, methanol-based production of cadaverine was shown to be improved from 11.3 to 17.5 g/L when a heterologous lysine decarboxylase gene cadA was expressed from a theta-replicating rather than a rolling-circle replicating vector. The current work on inducible promoter systems and compatible theta- or rolling circle-replicating vectors is an important extension of the poorly developed B. methanolicus genetic toolbox, valuable for genetic engineering and further exploration of this bacterium.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fmicb-07-01481.wendisch.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2905495/2905950/fmicb-07-01481.wendisch.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Microbiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-302x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-302X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">27713731</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000383651200002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29054953</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2016.01481</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Irla, Marta, Heggeset, Tonje M., Naerdal, Ingemar, Paul, Lidia, Haugen, Tone, Le, Simone B., Brautaset, Trygve, and Wendisch, Volker F. “Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 7 (2016): 1481.</mla>
<default>Irla M, Heggeset TM, Naerdal I, Paul L, Haugen T, Le SB, Brautaset T, Wendisch VF (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1481.</default>
<lncs> Irla, M., Heggeset, T.M., Naerdal, I., Paul, L., Haugen, T., Le, S.B., Brautaset, T., Wendisch, V.F.: Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. Frontiers in Microbiology. 7, : 1481 (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, Marta, Heggeset, Tonje M., Naerdal, Ingemar, Paul, Lidia, Haugen, Tone, Le, Simone B., Brautaset, Trygve, and Wendisch, Volker F. 2016. “Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1481.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Irla, M., Heggeset, T. M., Naerdal, I., Paul, L., Haugen, T., Le, S. B., Brautaset, T., et al. (2016). Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1481. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2016.01481</apa>
<ieee> M. Irla, et al., “Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2016, : 1481.</ieee>
<ama>Irla M, Heggeset TM, Naerdal I, et al. Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2016;7: 1481.</ama>
<frontiers>Irla, M., Heggeset, T. M., Naerdal, I., Paul, L., Haugen, T., Le, S. B., Brautaset, T., and Wendisch, V. F. (2016). Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 7:1481.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, M., Heggeset, T.M., Naerdal, I., Paul, L., Haugen, T., Le, S.B., Brautaset, T. &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F. (2016). Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;: 1481. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2016.01481.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Irla, M., et al., 2016. Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, 7: 1481.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Irla, M., Heggeset, T. M., Naerdal, I., Paul, L., Haugen, T., Le, S. B., Brautaset, T., et al. (2016). Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1481. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2016.01481&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Irla M, Heggeset TM, Naerdal I, Paul L, Haugen T, Le SB, Brautaset T, Wendisch VF (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology 7: 1481.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Irla, T. M.  Heggeset, I.  Naerdal, L.  Paul, T.  Haugen, S. B.  Le, T.  Brautaset, and V. F.  Wendisch, “Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, : 1481.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Irla, M.; Heggeset, T. M.; Naerdal, I.; Paul, L.; Haugen, T.; Le, S. B.; Brautaset, T.; Wendisch, V. F. (2016): Genome-based genetic tool development for Bacillus methanolicus: theta- and rolling circle-replicating plasmids for inducible gene expression and application to methanol-based cadaverine production &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,7:1481</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2905495</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-06T06:50:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>