<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2906152</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">28264830</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2953-341X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kummert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10372</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Arvin</namePart><namePart type="family">Agah</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">John-John</namePart><namePart type="family">Cabibihan</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ayanna M</namePart><namePart type="family">Howard</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Miguel A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Salichs</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hongsheng</namePart><namePart type="family">He</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Eight International Conference on Social Robotics</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="icsr_sebschne.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2906152/2906902/icsr_sebschne.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Kansas City</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title> Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-47436-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29061526</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-47437-3_85</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9979</number></detail><extent unit="pages">870-879</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Schneider S, Kummert F (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:   Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics. Agah A, Cabibihan J-J, Howard AM, Salichs MA, He H (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 9979.  Cham: Springer:  870-879.</default>
<wels>Schneider, S.; Kummert, F. (2016): Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In: Arvin Agah; John-John Cabibihan; Ayanna M Howard; Miguel A. Salichs; Hongsheng He (Hrsg.):   Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics. Cham: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 9979).  S. 870-879.</wels>
<mla>Schneider, Sebastian, and Kummert, Franz. “Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot”. &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Arvin Agah, John-John Cabibihan, Ayanna M Howard, Miguel A. Salichs, and Hongsheng He. Cham: Springer, 2016.Vol. 9979. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 870-879.</mla>
<frontiers>Schneider, S., and Kummert, F. (2016). “Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot” in &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;, Agah, A., Cabibihan, J. - J., Howard, A. M., Salichs, M. A., and He, H. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 9979, (Cham: Springer), 870-879.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2016). Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In A.  Agah, J. - J.  Cabibihan, A. M.  Howard, M. A.  Salichs, &amp;amp; H.  He (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 9979&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 870-879). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-47437-3_85&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2016). Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In A.  Agah, J. - J.  Cabibihan, A. M.  Howard, M. A.  Salichs, &amp;amp; H.  He (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 9979&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 870-879). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-47437-3_85</apa>
<harvard1>Schneider, S., &amp;amp; Kummert, F., 2016. Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In A.  Agah, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.9979  Cham: Springer, pp. 870-879.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Schneider and F. Kummert, “Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot”, &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;, A. Agah, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 9979,  Cham: Springer, 2016,  pp.870-879.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Schneider, and F.  Kummert, in &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Agah, J.-J. Cabibihan, A.M. Howard, M.A. Salichs, H. He), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 870-879.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schneider S, Kummert F (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. &lt;br /&gt;In:   Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics. Agah A, Cabibihan J-J, Howard AM, Salichs MA, He H (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 9979. Cham: Springer:  870-879.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, S. &amp;amp; Kummert, F. (2016). Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In A. Agah, J.-J. Cabibihan, A.M. Howard, M.A. Salichs &amp;amp; H. He (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 870-879). Gehalten auf der Eight International Conference on Social Robotics, Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-47437-3_85.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Schneider, S., Kummert, F.: Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In: Agah, A., Cabibihan, J.-J., Howard, A.M., Salichs, M.A., and He, H. (eds.)  Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 9979, p. 870-879. Springer, Cham (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schneider, Sebastian, and Kummert, Franz. 2016. “Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot”. In &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Arvin Agah, John-John Cabibihan, Ayanna M Howard, Miguel A. Salichs, and Hongsheng He, 9979:870-879. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Schneider S, Kummert F. Motivational Effects of Acknowledging Feedback from a Socially Assistive Robot. In: Agah A, Cabibihan J-J, Howard AM, Salichs MA, He H, eds. &lt;em&gt; Social Robotics. ICSR 2016. Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 9979. Cham: Springer;  2016: 870-879.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2906152</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-13T08:34:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-28T13:28:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>