<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2906648</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Münster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">44264259</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Pia</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Knoeferle</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>

<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Stavros</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Skopeteas</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Language processing does not happen in isolation, but is often embedded in a rich
non-linguistic visual and social context. Yet, although many psycholinguistic studies
have investigated the close interplay between language and the visual context, the role
of social aspects and listener characteristics in real-time language processing remains
largely elusive. The present thesis aims at closing this gap.&lt;br /&gt;
Taking extant literature regarding the incrementality of language processing, the
close interplay between visual and linguistic context and the relevance for and effect
of social aspects on language comprehension into account, we argue for the necessity
to extend investigations on the influence of social information and listener
characteristics on real-time language processing. Crucially, we moreover argue for the
inclusion of social information and listener characteristics into real-time language
processing accounts. Up-to-date, extant accounts on language comprehension remain
elusive about the influence of social cues and listener characteristics on real-time
language processing. Yet a more comprehensive approach that takes these aspects
into account is highly desirable given that psycholinguistics aims at describing how
language processing happens in real-time in the mind of the comprehender.
In 6 eye-tracking studies, this thesis hence investigated the effect of two distinct
visual contextual cues on real-time language processing and thematic role assignment
in emotionally valenced non-canonical German sentences. We are using emotional
facial expressions of a speaker as a visual social cue and depicted actions as a visual
contextual cue that is directly mediated by the linguistic input. Crucially, we are also
investigating the effect of the age of the listener as one type of listener characteristics
in testing children and older and younger adults.&lt;br /&gt;
In our studies, participants were primed with a positive emotional facial
expression (vs. a non-emotional / negative expression). Following this they inspected
a target scene depicting two potential agents either performing or not performing an
action towards a patient. This scene was accompanied by a related positively valenced
German Object-Verb-Adverb-Subject sentence (e.g.,: The ladybug(accusative
object, patient) tickles happily the cat(nominative object, agent).). Anticipatory eye-movements to
the agent of the action, i.e., the sentential subject in sentence end position (vs.
distractor agent), were measured in order to investigate if, to what extent and how
rapidly positive emotional facial expressions and depicted actions
can facilitate thematic role assignment in children and older and younger adults.
Moreover, given the complex nature of emotional facial expressions, we also
investigated if the naturalness of the emotional face has an influence on the
integration of this social cue into real-time sentence processing. We hence used a
schematic depiction of an emotional face, i.e., a happy smiley, in half of the studies
and a natural human emotional face in the remaining studies.&lt;br /&gt;
Our results showed that all age groups could reliably use the depicted actions as a
cue to facilitate sentence processing and to assign thematic roles even before the
target agent had been mentioned. Crucially, only our adult listener groups could also
use the emotional facial expression for real-time sentence processing. When the
natural human facial expression instead of the schematic smiley was used to portray
the positive emotion, the use of the social cue was even stronger. Nevertheless, our
results have also suggested that the depicted action is a stronger cue than the social
cue, i.e., the emotional facial expression, for both adult age groups. Children on the
other hand do not yet seem to be able to also use emotional facial expressions as
visual social cues for language comprehension. Interestingly, we also found time
course differences regarding the integration of the two cues into real-time sentence
comprehension. Compared to younger adults, both older adults and children were
delayed by one word region in their visual cue effects.&lt;br /&gt;
Our on-line data is further supported by accuracy results. All age groups answered
comprehension questions for ‘who is doing what to whom’ more accurately when an
action was depicted (vs. was not depicted). However, only younger adults made use
of the emotional cue for answering the comprehension questions, although to a lesser
extent than they used depicted actions.&lt;br /&gt;
In conclusion, our findings suggest for the first time that different non-linguistic
cues, i.e., more direct referential cues such as depicted actions and more indirect
social cues such as emotional facial expressions, are integrated into situated language
processing to different degrees. Crucially, the time course and strength of the
integration of these cues varies as a function of age.&lt;br /&gt;
Hence our findings support our argument regarding the inclusion of social cues
and listener characteristics into real-time language processing accounts. Based on our
own results we have therefore outlined at the end of this thesis, how an account of
real-time language comprehension that already takes the influence of visual context
such as depicted actions into account (but fails to include social aspects and listener
characteristics) can be enriched to also include the effects of emotional facial
expressions and listener characteristics such as age.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Muenster_PhD thesis_published version.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2906648/2906918/Muenster_PhD thesis_published version.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:hbz:361-29066485</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2016-07-01</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Münster, K. (2016): Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Münster, &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Münster, K. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Münster K (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<harvard1>Münster, K., 2016. &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Münster, K. (2016). Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Münster, K. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Münster K. &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2016.</ama>
<ieee> K. Münster, &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2016.</ieee>
<apa>Münster, K. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Münster, Katja. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Münster, K.: Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2016).</lncs>
<default>Münster K (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Münster, Katja. &lt;em&gt;Effects of emotional facial expressions and depicted actions on situated language processing across the lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2016.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2906648</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-11-09T07:51:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>