<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2907785</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lucas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19496948</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dorothee</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staiger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81014</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Selahattin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Danisman</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27484493</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685209</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The analysis of circadian leaf movement rhythms is a simple yet effective method to study effects of treatments or gene mutations on the circadian clock of plants. Currently, leaf movements are analysed using time lapse photography and subsequent bioinformatics analyses of leaf movements. Programs that are used for this purpose either are able to perform one function (i.e. leaf tip detection or rhythm analysis) or their function is limited to specific computational environments. We developed a leaf movement analysis tool—PALMA—that works in command line and combines image extraction with rhythm analysis using Fast Fourier transformation and non-linear least squares fitting.
Results

We validated PALMA in both simulated time series and in experiments using the known short period mutant sensitivity to red light reduced 1 (srr1-1). We compared PALMA with two established leaf movement analysis tools and found it to perform equally well. Finally, we tested the effect of reduced iron conditions on the leaf movement rhythms of wild type plants. Here, we found that PALMA successfully detected period lengthening under reduced iron conditions.
Conclusions

PALMA correctly estimated the period of both simulated and real-life leaf movement experiments. As a platform-independent console-program that unites both functions needed for the analysis of circadian leaf movements it is a valid alternative to existing leaf movement analysis tools.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="plantmeht.art%3A10.1186%2Fs13007-016-0153-3.danisman.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2907785/2907786/plantmeht.art%3A10.1186%2Fs13007-016-0153-3.danisman.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Circadian clock Iron homeostasis Rhythmic leaf movement analysis Rhythmic cotyledon movement analysis PALMA</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Plant Methods</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1746-4811</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28053647</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000392253600002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29077855</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13007-016-0153-3</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Wagner L, Schmal C, Staiger D, Danisman S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt; 13(1): 2.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, L., Schmal, C., Staiger, D., &amp;amp; Danisman, S. (2017). The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 2. doi:10.1186/s13007-016-0153-3&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wagner, Lucas, Schmal, Christoph, Staiger, Dorothee, and Danisman, Selahattin. “The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana”. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt; 13.1 (2017): 2.</mla>
<frontiers>Wagner, L., Schmal, C., Staiger, D., and Danisman, S. (2017). The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt; 13:2.</frontiers>
<wels>Wagner, L.; Schmal, C.; Staiger, D.; Danisman, S. (2017): The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;,13:(1):2</wels>
<apa>Wagner, L., Schmal, C., Staiger, D., &amp;amp; Danisman, S. (2017). The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 2. doi:10.1186/s13007-016-0153-3</apa>
<harvard1>Wagner, L., et al., 2017. The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;, 13(1): 2.</harvard1>
<ieee> L. Wagner, et al., “The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana”, &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 13, 2017, : 2.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Wagner, C.  Schmal, D.  Staiger, and S.  Danisman, “The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana”, &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, : 2.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wagner L, Schmal C, Staiger D, Danisman S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana.&lt;br /&gt;Plant Methods 13(1): 2.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, L., Schmal, C., Staiger, D. &amp;amp; Danisman, S. (2017). The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1): 2. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13007-016-0153-3.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Lucas, Schmal, Christoph, Staiger, Dorothee, and Danisman, Selahattin. 2017. “The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana”. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt; 13 (1): 2.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wagner, L., Schmal, C., Staiger, D., Danisman, S.: The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. Plant Methods. 13, : 2 (2017).</lncs>
<ama>Wagner L, Schmal C, Staiger D, Danisman S. The plant leaf movement analyzer (PALMA): a simple tool for the analysis of periodic cotyledon and leaf movement in Arabidopsis thaliana. &lt;em&gt;Plant Methods&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;13(1): 2.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2907785</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-05T13:46:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>