<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2907331</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey.</title></titleInfo>




<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eva-Maria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Berens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22797466</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dominique</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vogt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31639902</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Melanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Messer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25211355</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hurrelmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21484</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Doris</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schaeffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">133014</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175759</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Health literacy is of increasing importance in public health research. It is a necessary pre-condition for the involvement in decisions about health and health care and related to health outcomes. Knowledge about limited health literacy in different age groups is crucial to better target public health interventions for subgroups of the population. However, little is known about health literacy in Germany. The study therefore assesses the prevalence of limited health literacy and associated factors among different age groups.
Methods

The Health Literacy Survey Germany is a cross-sectional study with 2,000 participants aged 15 years or older in private households. Perceived health literacy was assessed via computer-assisted personal interviews using the HLS-EU-Q-47 questionnaire. Descriptive analyses, chi-square tests and odds ratios were performed stratified for different age groups.
Results

The population affected by limited perceived health literacy increases by age. Of the respondents aged 15–29 years, 47.3 % had limited perceived health literacy and 47.2 % of those aged 30–45 years, whereas 55.2 % of the respondents aged 46–64 years and 66.4 % aged 65 years and older showed limited perceived health literacy. In all age groups, limited perceived health literacy was associated with limited functional health literacy, low social status, and a high frequency of doctor visits.
Conclusions

The results suggest a need to further investigate perceived health literacy in all phases of the life-course. Particular attention should be devoted to persons with lower social status, limited functional health literacy and/or a high number of doctor visits in all age groups.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bmc.phealth.art%3A10.1186%2Fs12889-016-3810-6.berens.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2907331/2907332/bmc.phealth.art%3A10.1186%2Fs12889-016-3810-6.berens.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Biomed Central</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Health literacy Socio-economic factors Doctor visits Germany General population Age groups Survey HLS-EU-Q</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">27829401</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000387602900007</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29073317</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3810-6</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Berens E-M, Vogt D, Messer M, Hurrelmann K, Schaeffer D. Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. In:  &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 16. Biomed Central;  2016.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, Eva-Maria, Vogt, Dominique, Messer, Melanie, Hurrelmann, Klaus, and Schaeffer, Doris. 2016. “Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey.”. In &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 16. Biomed Central: 1151.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Berens, E.-M., Vogt, D., Messer, M., Hurrelmann, K., Schaeffer, D.: Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. BMC Public Health. 16,  Biomed Central (2016).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, E.-M., Vogt, D., Messer, M., Hurrelmann, K. &amp;amp; Schaeffer, D. (2016). Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. Biomed Central. doi:10.1186/s12889-016-3810-6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>E. - M.  Berens, D.  Vogt, M.  Messer, K.  Hurrelmann, and D.  Schaeffer, in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, Biomed Central, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Berens E-M, Vogt D, Messer M, Hurrelmann K, Schaeffer D (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. &lt;br /&gt;In:  BMC Public Health. 16. Biomed Central.</bio1>
<harvard1>Berens, E.-M., et al., 2016. Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. In &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. no.16  Biomed Central.</harvard1>
<ieee> E.-M. Berens, et al., “Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey.”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 16, Biomed Central, 2016.</ieee>
<apa>Berens, E. - M., Vogt, D., Messer, M., Hurrelmann, K., &amp;amp; Schaeffer, D. (2016). Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt; Biomed Central. doi:10.1186/s12889-016-3810-6</apa>
<wels>Berens, E. - M.; Vogt, D.; Messer, M.; Hurrelmann, K.; Schaeffer, D. (2016): Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. In: BMC Public Health. Biomed Central. (16).</wels>
<frontiers>Berens, E. - M., Vogt, D., Messer, M., Hurrelmann, K., and Schaeffer, D. (2016). “Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey.” in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 16, (Biomed Central).</frontiers>
<mla>Berens, Eva-Maria, Vogt, Dominique, Messer, Melanie, Hurrelmann, Klaus, and Schaeffer, Doris. “Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey.”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. Biomed Central, 2016.Vol. 16.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, E. - M., Vogt, D., Messer, M., Hurrelmann, K., &amp;amp; Schaeffer, D. (2016). Health literacy among different age groups in Germany: results of a cross-sectional survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt; Biomed Central. doi:10.1186/s12889-016-3810-6&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Berens E-M, Vogt D, Messer M, Hurrelmann K, Schaeffer D (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  BMC Public Health., 16(1).  Biomed Central.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2907331</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-12-07T08:01:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-02-15T10:27:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>