<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2907859</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaupmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soufian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jebbara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">61955542</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4483-0933</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>EACL 2017</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Word embeddings have been shown to be highly effective in a variety of lexical semantic tasks. They tend to capture meaningful relational similarities between individual words, at the expense of lacking the capabilty of making the underlying semantic relation explicit. In this paper, we investigate the attribute relation that often holds between the constituents of adjective-noun phrases. We use CBOW word embeddings to represent word meaning and learn a compositionality function that combines the individual constituents into a phrase representation, thus capturing the compositional attribute meaning. The resulting embedding model, while being fully interpretable, outperforms count-
based distributional vector space models that are tailored to attribute meaning in the two tasks of attribute selection and phrase similarity prediction. Moreover, as the model captures a generalized layer of attribute meaning, it bears the potential to be used for predictions over various attribute inventories without re-training.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2907859/2913010/paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Valencia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29078593</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>Vol. 1 (Long Papers)</number></detail><extent unit="pages">54-64</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Hartung, M., Kaupmann, F., Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Vol. 1 (Long Papers)&lt;/em&gt;, 54-64.</apa>
<ieee> M. Hartung, et al., “Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, vol. Vol. 1 (Long Papers), 2017,  pp.54-64.</ieee>
<ama>Hartung M, Kaupmann F, Jebbara S, Cimiano P. Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol Vol. 1 (Long Papers). 2017: 54-64.</ama>
<frontiers>Hartung, M., Kaupmann, F., Jebbara, S., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, vol. Vol. 1 (Long Papers), 54-64.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, M., Kaupmann, F., Jebbara, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 54-64). Gehalten auf der EACL 2017.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, M., Kaupmann, F., Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Vol. 1 (Long Papers)&lt;/em&gt;, 54-64.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hartung M, Kaupmann F, Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL). Vol. 1 (Long Papers). 54-64.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hartung, M., et al., 2017. Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. no.Vol. 1 (Long Papers) pp. 54-64.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Hartung, F.  Kaupmann, S.  Jebbara, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 54-64.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hartung, M.; Kaupmann, F.; Jebbara, S.; Cimiano, P. (2017): Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. In: Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL). (Vol. 1 (Long Papers).  S. 54-64.</wels>
<mla>Hartung, Matthias, Kaupmann, Fabian, Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2017.Vol. Vol. 1 (Long Papers). 54-64.</mla>
<default>Hartung M, Kaupmann F, Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)., Vol. 1 (Long Papers).   54-64.</default>
<lncs> Hartung, M., Kaupmann, F., Jebbara, S., Cimiano, P.: Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases. Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL). Vol. 1 (Long Papers), p. 54-64. (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, Matthias, Kaupmann, Fabian, Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “Learning Compositionality Functions on Word Embeddings for Modelling Attribute Meaning in Adjective-Noun Phrases”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 15th Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 1 (Long Papers):54-64.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2907859</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-10T14:12:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>