<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908679</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yudit</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Namer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">86138649</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4988-755X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olga Selin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hünler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pereira</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">P.</namePart><namePart type="family">Costa</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21333</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Around the world, LGBT populations are under the risk of having traumatic experiences. LGBT individuals could
and do experience physical or sexual assaults, same-sex domestic violence, or bullying. Sometimes psychological/
psychiatric/legal interventions could be traumatic instead of alleviating.
In Turkey, albeit being LGBT is not illegal or prohibited, being LGBT makes people vulnerable to exclusion, stigma,
isolation, abuse or insult. LGBT organizations have a peculiar importance in this context. In Turkey, LGBT organizations
in different geographical locations have different target groups with slightly different political perspectives.
These organizations have wide variety of functions, such as creating public visibility, providing role models for
young LGBTs, educating and supporting families, offering legal counseling, providing social, emotional and economical
support and creating a peer group. Majority of these organizations are working on a volunteer basis. Unfortunately,
not only hectic workload and diversity of duties but also continuously witnessing survivors and sometimes
non-survivors of trauma could be exhausting for volunteers. Because of this reason, it is essential for LGBT organization
members/volunteers to understand the concept of trauma, be familiar with the types of it and be informed about
different ways of intervening and coping with it while supporting the traumatized member.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ebook1-1.196-200.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908679/2908680/ebook1-1.196-200.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Beira Interior</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-989-96996-1-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29086796</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">194-198</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Namer Y, Hünler OS (2014)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario. Pereira H, Costa P (Eds);  Lisbon: University of Beira Interior:  194-198.</default>
<aps> Y.  Namer and O. S.  Hünler, LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma, in &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;, edited by H.  Pereira and P.  Costa (University of Beira Interior, Lisbon, 2014), p. 194-198.</aps>
<mla>Namer, Yudit, and Hünler, Olga Selin. “LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma”. &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. H. Pereira and P. Costa. Lisbon: University of Beira Interior, 2014. 194-198.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Namer, Yudit, and Hünler, Olga Selin. 2014. “LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma”. In &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;, ed. H. Pereira and P. Costa, 194-198. Lisbon: University of Beira Interior.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Namer, Y., Hünler, O.S.: LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In: Pereira, H. and Costa, P. (eds.) Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario. p. 194-198. University of Beira Interior, Lisbon (2014).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>Y.  Namer, and O. S.  Hünler, in &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H. Pereira, P. Costa), University Of Beira Interior, Lisbon, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 194-198.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Namer, Y., &amp;amp; Hünler, O.S., 2014. LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In H.  Pereira &amp;amp; P.  Costa, eds. &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;.  Lisbon: University of Beira Interior, pp. 194-198.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Namer, Y., &amp;amp; Hünler, O. S. (2014). LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In H.  Pereira &amp;amp; P.  Costa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 194-198). Lisbon: University of Beira Interior.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Namer Y, Hünler OS (2014) &lt;br /&gt;LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario. Pereira H, Costa P (Eds); Lisbon: University of Beira Interior:  194-198.</bio1>
<wels>Namer, Y.; Hünler, O. S. (2014): LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In: H. Pereira; P. Costa (Hrsg.):  Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario. Lisbon: University of Beira Interior.  S. 194-198.</wels>
<ieee> Y. Namer and O.S. Hünler, “LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma”, &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;, H. Pereira and P. Costa, eds.,  Lisbon: University of Beira Interior, 2014,  pp.194-198.</ieee>
<apa>Namer, Y., &amp;amp; Hünler, O. S. (2014). LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In H.  Pereira &amp;amp; P.  Costa (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 194-198). Lisbon: University of Beira Interior.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Namer, Y. &amp;amp; Hünler, O.S. (2014). LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In H. Pereira &amp;amp; P. Costa (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt; (S. 194-198). Lisbon: University of Beira Interior.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Namer, Y., and Hünler, O. S. (2014). “LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma” in &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;, Pereira, H., and Costa, P. eds. (Lisbon: University of Beira Interior), 194-198.</frontiers>
<ama>Namer Y, Hünler OS. LGBT trauma in turkey and psychological consequences of working/volunteering with LGBT trauma. In: Pereira H, Costa P, eds. &lt;em&gt;Coming-out for LGBT psychology in the current international scenario&lt;/em&gt;. Lisbon: University of Beira Interior;  2014: 194-198.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908679</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-20T13:46:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>