<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908132</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Potthast</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">28338318</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neuner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9438235</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Catani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9988099</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

A growing body of research attempts to clarify the underlying mechanisms of the association between emotional maltreatment and alcohol dependence (AD). In a preceding study, we found considerable support for a specific priming effect in subjects with AD and emotional abuse experiences receiving alcohol rehabilitation treatment. We concluded that maltreatment related cues can automatically activate an associative memory network comprising cues eliciting craving as well as alcohol-related responses. Generalizability of the results to other treatment settings remains unclear because of considerable differences in German treatment settings as well as insufficiently clarified influences of selection effects. As replication studies in other settings are necessary, the current study aimed to replicate the specific priming effect in a qualified detoxification sample.
Results

22 AD subjects (n = 10 with emotional abuse vs. n = 12 without emotional abuse) participated in a priming experiment. Comparison data from 34 healthy control subjects were derived from the prior study. Contrary to our hypothesis, we did not find a specific priming effect.
Conclusions

We could not replicate the result of an automatic network activation by maltreatment related words in a sample of subjects with AD and emotional abuse experiences receiving qualified detoxification treatment. This discrepancy might be attributed to reasons related to treatment settings as well as to methodological limitations. Future work is required to determine the generalizability of the specific priming effect before valid conclusions regarding automatic activation can be drawn.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BMCRN.art%3A10.1186%2Fs13104-016-2324-8.potthast.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908132/2908133/BMCRN.art%3A10.1186%2Fs13104-016-2324-8.potthast.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Child abuse Emotional maltreatment Alcohol dependence Underlying mechanisms Priming Associative memory network Replication Qualified detoxification sample</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Research Notes</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1756-0500</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29081325</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13104-016-2324-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>17</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Potthast, N.; Neuner, F.; Catani, C. (2017): Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,10:(17):17</wels>
<bio1>Potthast N, Neuner F, Catani C (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Research Notes 10(17): 17.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Potthast, N., Neuner, F., &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2017). Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(17), 17. doi:10.1186/s13104-016-2324-8&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Potthast, N., Neuner, F., &amp;amp; Catani, C., 2017. Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, 10(17): 17.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Potthast, F.  Neuner, and C.  Catani, “Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 17.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Potthast N, Neuner F, Catani C. Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;10(17): 17.</ama>
<frontiers>Potthast, N., Neuner, F., and Catani, C. (2017). Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 10:17.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Potthast, N., Neuner, F. &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2017). Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(17): 17. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13104-016-2324-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Potthast, N., Neuner, F., &amp;amp; Catani, C. (2017). Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(17), 17. doi:10.1186/s13104-016-2324-8</apa>
<ieee> N. Potthast, F. Neuner, and C. Catani, “Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2017, : 17.</ieee>
<lncs> Potthast, N., Neuner, F., Catani, C.: Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting. BMC Research Notes. 10, : 17 (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Potthast, Nadine, Neuner, Frank, and Catani, Claudia. 2017. “Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 10 (17): 17.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Potthast, Nadine, Neuner, Frank, and Catani, Claudia. “Automatic activation of alcohol cues by child maltreatment related words: a replication attempt in a different treatment setting”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 10.17 (2017): 17.</mla>
<default>Potthast N, Neuner F, Catani C (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; 10(17): 17.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908132</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-24T07:23:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T12:36:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>