<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908811</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zarrieß</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51642361</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>EACL</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="E17-2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908811/2912648/E17-2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Valencia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29088119</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Zarrieß S, Schlangen D (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).</default>
<mla>Zarrieß, Sina, and Schlangen, David. “Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings”. &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2017.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zarrieß, Sina, and Schlangen, David. 2017. “Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings”. In &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Zarrieß, S., Schlangen, D.: Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).  (2017).</lncs>
<ieee> S. Zarrieß and D. Schlangen, “Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings”, &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zarrieß, S. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der EACL.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Zarrieß, S., and Schlangen, D. (2017). “Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings” in &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<ama>Zarrieß S, Schlangen D. Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. In:  &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2017.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Zarrieß, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Zarrieß S, Schlangen D (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL). .</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2017. Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. In &lt;em&gt;Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<wels>Zarrieß, S.; Schlangen, D. (2017): Is this a Child, a Girl, or a Car? Exploring the Contribution of Distributional Similarity to Learning Referential Word Meanings. In: Short Papers -- Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908811</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-28T14:48:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:40Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>