<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908813</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hough</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">48164400</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>EACL 2017</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="HoughSchlangen17EACL.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908813/2910242/HoughSchlangen17EACL.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Valencia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29088136</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">326-336</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Hough, J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2017. Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 326-336.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hough J, Schlangen D (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).  326-336.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 326-336.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hough, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 326-336.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hough, J.; Schlangen, D. (2017): Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. In: Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).  S. 326-336.</wels>
<apa>Hough, J., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 326-336.</apa>
<ieee> J. Hough and D. Schlangen, “Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 2017,  pp.326-336.</ieee>
<ama>Hough J, Schlangen D. Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2017: 326-336.</ama>
<frontiers>Hough, J., and Schlangen, D. (2017). “Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt; 326-336.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2017). Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 326-336). Gehalten auf der EACL 2017.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Hough, Julian, and Schlangen, David. “Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;. 2017. 326-336.</mla>
<default>Hough J, Schlangen D (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL).  326-336.</default>
<lncs> Hough, J., Schlangen, D.: Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech. Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL). p. 326-336. (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, Julian, and Schlangen, David. 2017. “Joint, Incremental Disfluency Detection and Utterance Segmentation from Speech”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the  European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)&lt;/em&gt;, 326-336.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908813</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-28T14:51:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T08:30:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>