<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908870</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Phillip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lücking</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41979092</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rohlfing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147957</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10380</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schilling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">172354</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0849-483X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44326656</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="FINAL_07846821.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908870/2908871/FINAL_07846821.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-5090-5069-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29088703</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/devlrn.2016.7846821</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Lücking P, Rohlfing K, Wrede B, Schilling M (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob). Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).</default>
<wels>Lücking, P.; Rohlfing, K.; Wrede, B.; Schilling, M. (2016): Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. In: 2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob). Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).</wels>
<frontiers>Lücking, P., Rohlfing, K., Wrede, B., and Schilling, M. (2016). “Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system” in &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt; (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, P., Rohlfing, K., Wrede, B., &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2016). Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). doi:10.1109/devlrn.2016.7846821&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Lücking, Phillip, Rohlfing, Katharina, Wrede, Britta, and Schilling, Malte. “Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system”. &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2016.</mla>
<apa>Lücking, P., Rohlfing, K., Wrede, B., &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2016). Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). doi:10.1109/devlrn.2016.7846821</apa>
<harvard1>Lücking, P., et al., 2016. Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. In &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;.  Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).</harvard1>
<ieee> P. Lücking, et al., “Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system”, &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2016.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Lücking, K.  Rohlfing, B.  Wrede, and M.  Schilling, in &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;, Institute Of Electrical And Electronics Engineers (Ieee), &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lücking P, Rohlfing K, Wrede B, Schilling M (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob).  Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, P., Rohlfing, K., Wrede, B. &amp;amp; Schilling, M. (2016). Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). doi:10.1109/devlrn.2016.7846821.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Lücking, P., Rohlfing, K., Wrede, B., Schilling, M.: Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. 2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob).  Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lücking, Phillip, Rohlfing, Katharina, Wrede, Britta, and Schilling, Malte. 2016. “Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system”. In &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Lücking P, Rohlfing K, Wrede B, Schilling M. Preschoolers' engagement in social interaction with an autonomous robotic system. In:  &lt;em&gt;2016 Joint IEEE International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE);  2016.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908870</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-03-01T14:43:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>