<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908802</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Betz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55883969</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3695-3861</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Voße</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">144560994</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1642-1569</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christoph</namePart><namePart type="family">Draxler</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Felicitas</namePart><namePart type="family">Kleber</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum (P und P12)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Betz_Wagner_Vosse_PP12_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908802/2908803/Betz_Wagner_Vosse_PP12_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>LMU</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">München, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29088020</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">19-22</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Betz, S.; Wagner, P.; Voße, J. (2016): Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In: Christoph Draxler; Felicitas Kleber (Hrsg.):  Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum. München: LMU.  S. 19-22.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Betz, P.  Wagner, and J.  Voße, in &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. Draxler, F. Kleber), Lmu, München, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 19-22.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Betz, S., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Voße, J., 2016. Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In C.  Draxler &amp;amp; F.  Kleber, eds. &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;.  München: LMU, pp. 19-22.</harvard1>
<bio1>Betz S, Wagner P, Voße J (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum. Draxler C, Kleber F (Eds); München: LMU:  19-22.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Betz, S., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Voße, J. (2016). Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In C.  Draxler &amp;amp; F.  Kleber (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 19-22). München: LMU.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Betz, S., Wagner, P., and Voße, J. (2016). “Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data” in &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;, Draxler, C., and Kleber, F. eds. (München: LMU), 19-22.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Betz, S., Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Voße, J. (2016). Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In C. Draxler &amp;amp; F. Kleber (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt; (S. 19-22). Gehalten auf der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum (P und P12), München: LMU.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Betz S, Wagner P, Voße J. Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In: Draxler C, Kleber F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;. München: LMU;  2016: 19-22.</ama>
<ieee> S. Betz, P. Wagner, and J. Voße, “Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data”, &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;, C. Draxler and F. Kleber, eds.,  München: LMU, 2016,  pp.19-22.</ieee>
<apa>Betz, S., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Voße, J. (2016). Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In C.  Draxler &amp;amp; F.  Kleber (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 19-22). München: LMU.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Betz, Simon, Wagner, Petra, and Voße, Jana. 2016. “Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data”. In &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Christoph Draxler and Felicitas Kleber, 19-22. München: LMU.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Betz, S., Wagner, P., Voße, J.: Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data. In: Draxler, C. and Kleber, F. (eds.) Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum. p. 19-22. LMU, München (2016).</lncs>
<default>Betz S, Wagner P, Voße J (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum. Draxler C, Kleber F (Eds);  München: LMU:  19-22.</default>
<mla>Betz, Simon, Wagner, Petra, and Voße, Jana. “Deriving a strategy for synthesizing lengthening disfluencies based on spontaneous conversational speech data”. &lt;em&gt;Tagungsband der 12. Tagung Phonetik und Phonologie im deutschsprachigen Raum&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Christoph Draxler and Felicitas Kleber. München: LMU, 2016. 19-22.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908802</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-02-28T13:41:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-21T15:22:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>