<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908165</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Milad</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malekzadeh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jeffrey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Queißer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">52684838</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9725-6971</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11608</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michel</namePart><namePart type="family">Verleysen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>COgnitive Development for Friendly RObots and Rehabilitation</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ESANN2017_draft.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908165/2917759/ESANN2017_draft.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ciaco</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Brügge, Belgium</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-2-87587-039-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29081656</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malekzadeh, Milad, Queißer, Jeffrey, and Steil, Jochen J. 2017. “Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michel Verleysen. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J., Steil, J.J.: Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In: Verleysen, M. (ed.) Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017.  Ciaco, Louvain-la-Neuve (2017).</lncs>
<default>Malekzadeh M, Queißer J, Steil JJ (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017. Verleysen M (Ed);  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.</default>
<mla>Malekzadeh, Milad, Queißer, Jeffrey, and Steil, Jochen J. “Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michel Verleysen. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco, 2017.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J. &amp;amp; Steil, J.J. (2017). Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In M. Verleysen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning, Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J., and Steil, J. J. (2017). “Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;, Verleysen, M. ed. (Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco).</frontiers>
<ama>Malekzadeh M, Queißer J, Steil JJ. Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In: Verleysen M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco;  2017.</ama>
<ieee> M. Malekzadeh, J. Queißer, and J.J. Steil, “Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;, M. Verleysen, ed.,  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J., &amp;amp; Steil, J. J. (2017). Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt; Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.</apa>
<wels>Malekzadeh, M.; Queißer, J.; Steil, J. J. (2017): Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In: Michel Verleysen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Malekzadeh, J.  Queißer, and J. J.  Steil, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Verleysen), Ciaco, Louvain-la-Neuve, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J., &amp;amp; Steil, J.J., 2017. Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In M.  Verleysen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt;.  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Malekzadeh, M., Queißer, J., &amp;amp; Steil, J. J. (2017). Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017&lt;/em&gt; Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Malekzadeh M, Queißer J, Steil JJ (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Imitation learning for a continuum trunk robot. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 25. European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. ESANN 2017. Verleysen M (Ed); Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908165</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-25T13:09:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:56:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>