<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908923</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koester</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11021779</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3940-8559</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Iris</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Güldenpenning</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">T.</namePart><namePart type="family">Barkowsky</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Z. F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Llansola</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.</namePart><namePart type="family">Schultheis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.</namePart><namePart type="family">van de Ven</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>13th Biannual Conference of the German cognitive science society</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Koesteretal16Proceedings_Cognitive_Sc_ERPs_high_jump.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908923/2908926/Koesteretal16Proceedings_Cognitive_Sc_ERPs_high_jump.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bremen</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bremen</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29089237</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">59-62</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Koester D, Schack T, Güldenpenning I (2016) &lt;br /&gt;Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society. Barkowsky T, Llansola ZF, Schultheis H, van de Ven J (Eds); Bremen: Universität Bremen:  59-62.</bio1>
<harvard1>Koester, D., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Güldenpenning, I., 2016. Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In T.  Barkowsky, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;.  Bremen: Universität Bremen, pp. 59-62.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koester, D., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Güldenpenning, I. (2016). Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In T.  Barkowsky, Z. F.  Llansola, H.  Schultheis, &amp;amp; J.  van de Ven (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-62). Bremen: Universität Bremen.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Koester, T.  Schack, and I.  Güldenpenning, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T. Barkowsky, Z.F. Llansola, H. Schultheis, J. van de Ven), Universität Bremen, Bremen, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 59-62.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Koester, D.; Schack, T.; Güldenpenning, I. (2016): Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In: T. Barkowsky; Z. F. Llansola; H. Schultheis; J. van de Ven (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society. Bremen: Universität Bremen.  S. 59-62.</wels>
<apa>Koester, D., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Güldenpenning, I. (2016). Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In T.  Barkowsky, Z. F.  Llansola, H.  Schultheis, &amp;amp; J.  van de Ven (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-62). Bremen: Universität Bremen.</apa>
<ieee> D. Koester, T. Schack, and I. Güldenpenning, “Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, T. Barkowsky, et al., eds.,  Bremen: Universität Bremen, 2016,  pp.59-62.</ieee>
<ama>Koester D, Schack T, Güldenpenning I. Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In: Barkowsky T, Llansola ZF, Schultheis H, van de Ven J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Bremen: Universität Bremen;  2016: 59-62.</ama>
<frontiers>Koester, D., Schack, T., and Güldenpenning, I. (2016). “Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, Barkowsky, T., Llansola, Z. F., Schultheis, H., and van de Ven, J. eds. (Bremen: Universität Bremen), 59-62.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koester, D., Schack, T. &amp;amp; Güldenpenning, I. (2016). Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In T. Barkowsky, Z.F. Llansola, H. Schultheis &amp;amp; J. van de Ven (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (S. 59-62). Gehalten auf der 13th Biannual Conference of the German cognitive science society, Bremen: Universität Bremen.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Koester, Dirk, Schack, Thomas, and Güldenpenning, Iris. “Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. T. Barkowsky, Z. F. Llansola, H. Schultheis, and J. van de Ven. Bremen: Universität Bremen, 2016. 59-62.</mla>
<default>Koester D, Schack T, Güldenpenning I (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society. Barkowsky T, Llansola ZF, Schultheis H, van de Ven J (Eds);  Bremen: Universität Bremen:  59-62.</default>
<lncs> Koester, D., Schack, T., Güldenpenning, I.: Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study. In: Barkowsky, T., Llansola, Z.F., Schultheis, H., and van de Ven, J. (eds.) Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society. p. 59-62. Universität Bremen, Bremen (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koester, Dirk, Schack, Thomas, and Güldenpenning, Iris. 2016. “Motor expertise facilitates the cognitive evaluation of body postures: An ERP study”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 13th Biannual Conference of the German Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, ed. T. Barkowsky, Z. F. Llansola, H. Schultheis, and J. van de Ven, 59-62. Bremen: Universität Bremen.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908923</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-03-02T14:53:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T08:30:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>