<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908092</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Günther</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21169444</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1853-3123</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lüpke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11724588</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stummer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18839152</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5495-5740</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38171018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">41399667</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET 2017) </namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GüntherLüpkeStummer_PICMET 2017 (pre-print).pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908092/2961470/GüntherLüpkeStummer_PICMET 2017 (pre-print).pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Portland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9781538629154</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29080926</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-9</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2954322</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Günther M, Lüpke L, Stummer C. Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE);  2017: 1-9.</ama>
<harvard1>Günther, M., Lüpke, L., &amp;amp; Stummer, C., 2017. Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;.  Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), pp. 1-9.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Günther, L. Lüpke, and C. Stummer, “Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2017,  pp.1-9.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, Markus, Lüpke, Lars, and Stummer, Christian. 2017. “Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-9. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Günther, M., Lüpke, L., Stummer, C.: Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET). p. 1-9. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) (2017).</lncs>
<apa>Günther, M., Lüpke, L., &amp;amp; Stummer, C. (2017). Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-9. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, M., Lüpke, L. &amp;amp; Stummer, C. (2017). Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-9). Gehalten auf der Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET 2017) , Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). doi:10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, M., Lüpke, L., &amp;amp; Stummer, C. (2017). Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-9. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.23919/PICMET.2017.8125434&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Günther, M., Lüpke, L., and Stummer, C. (2017). “Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt; (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 1-9.</frontiers>
<mla>Günther, Markus, Lüpke, Lars, and Stummer, Christian. “Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2017. 1-9.</mla>
<wels>Günther, M.; Lüpke, L.; Stummer, C. (2017): Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. In: Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET). Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE).  S. 1-9.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Günther, L.  Lüpke, and C.  Stummer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET)&lt;/em&gt;, Institute Of Electrical And Electronics Engineers (Ieee), &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-9.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Günther M, Lüpke L, Stummer C (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Cross-over between scenario analysis and agent-based market simulation for technology planning. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET).  Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE):  1-9.</bio1>
<default>Günther M, Lüpke L, Stummer C (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Portland International Conference on Management of Engineering and Technology (PICMET). Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE):  1-9.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908092</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-19T10:12:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-01T07:55:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>