<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2908201</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Göpfert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">70126969</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2517-4907</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lukas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfannschmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">54648671</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5521-0326</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michele</namePart><namePart type="family">Verleysen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">48167073</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>25th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Biomedical applications often aim for an identification of relevant features for a given classification task, since these carry the promise of semantic insight into the underlying process.
For correlated input dimensions, feature relevances are not unique, and the identification of meaningful subtle biomarkers remains a challenge.
One approach is to identify intervals for the possible relevance of given features, a problem related to all relevant feature determination.
In this contribution, we address the important case of linear classifiers and we transfer the problem how to infer feature relevance bounds to a convex optimization problem. 
We demonstrate the superiority of the resulting technique in comparison to popular feature-relevance determination methods in several benchmarks.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="goepfert_pfannschmidt_hammer_feature_selection_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908201/2911812/goepfert_pfannschmidt_hammer_feature_selection_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="es2017-67.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2908201/2913588/es2017-67.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ciaco - i6doc.com</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bruges</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-287587039-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29082012</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">187--192</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://github.com/lpfann/fri</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Göpfert, Christina, Pfannschmidt, Lukas, and Hammer, Barbara. “Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michele Verleysen. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, 2017. 187--192.</mla>
<frontiers>Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L., and Hammer, B. (2017). “Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, Verleysen, M. ed. (Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com), 187--192.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 187--192). Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Göpfert, C.; Pfannschmidt, L.; Hammer, B. (2017): Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In: Michele Verleysen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.  S. 187--192.</wels>
<default>Göpfert C, Pfannschmidt L, Hammer B (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed);  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com:  187--192.</default>
<ieee> C. Göpfert, L. Pfannschmidt, and B. Hammer, “Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, M. Verleysen, ed.,  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, 2017,  pp.187--192.</ieee>
<harvard1>Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2017. Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In M.  Verleysen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;.  Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com, pp. 187--192.</harvard1>
<apa>Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In M.  Verleysen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 187--192). Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In M. Verleysen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (S. 187--192). Gehalten auf der 25th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning (ESANN), Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Göpfert C, Pfannschmidt L, Hammer B (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. Verleysen M (Ed); Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com:  187--192.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Göpfert, L.  Pfannschmidt, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Verleysen), Ciaco - I6Doc.com, Louvain-la-Neuve, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 187--192.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Göpfert C, Pfannschmidt L, Hammer B. Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In: Verleysen M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com;  2017: 187--192.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, Christina, Pfannschmidt, Lukas, and Hammer, Barbara. 2017. “Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michele Verleysen, 187--192. Louvain-la-Neuve: Ciaco - i6doc.com.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Göpfert, C., Pfannschmidt, L., Hammer, B.: Feature Relevance Bounds for Linear Classification. In: Verleysen, M. (ed.) Proceedings of the ESANN, 24th European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks, Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning. p. 187--192. Ciaco - i6doc.com, Louvain-la-Neuve (2017).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2908201</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-01-26T11:46:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>