<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2909817</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Upmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper provides a model that integrates interjurisdictional tax
competition and environmental policy. Each local government supplies two
public goods - that benefit the local industry and the residents
respectively - which are financed through distortionary taxation on
industrial capital and pollutant emissions. In contrast to traditional
theory of tax competition, we find that overprovision of local public
goods may emerge in equilibrium. Since emission taxes serve to finance
public spendings, the supply of public goods and the environmental
quality are closely related. In the special case of a small region that
cannot affect the national after-tax return to capital, we have the
striking new result that in equilibrium two different regimes can occur.
Either we have underprovision of public goods and an inefficiently high
environmental quality, or we have overprovision of public goods and a
too low environmental quality. These inefficiencies persevere as long as
the federal government is not entitled to apply deliberate
taxation/subsidy schemes. Correspondingly, unless regions are perfectly
identical, we cannot hope to overcome the efficiency problem by
symmetrical cooperative solutions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_238.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2909817/2933171/IMW_working_paper_238.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>interjurisdictional tax competition</topic><topic>capital and emission taxation</topic><topic>efficient provision of public goods</topic><topic>environmental quality</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29098172</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>238</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Upmann, T. (1995): Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<mla>Upmann, Thorsten. &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1995. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 238.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Upmann, T. (1995).  &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 238). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Upmann, T. (1995). Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 238, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Upmann T (1995)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 238.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Upmann, T., 1995. &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.238, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Upmann, &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 238,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1995.</ieee>
<apa>Upmann, T. (1995).  &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 238). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Upmann, T. (1995). &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Upmann, &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Upmann T (1995) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 238.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Upmann T. &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 238. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 1995.</ama>
<lncs> Upmann, T.: Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 238. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (1995).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Upmann, Thorsten. 1995. &lt;em&gt;Interjurisdictional tax competition, provision of two local public goods, and environmental policy&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 238. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2909817</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-04T11:06:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>