<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2909806</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Till</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Requate</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_222.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2909806/2911478/IMW_working_paper_222.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29098067</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>222</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Requate, T. (1994). &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics) (revised version.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Requate, &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Requate T (1994) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 222, revised version.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Requate T. &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 222 revised version. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 1994.</ama>
<lncs> Requate, T.: Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 222, revised version. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (1994).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Requate, Till. 1994. &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;. revised version. Vol. 222. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Requate, T. (1994): Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits. revised version.  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Requate, T. (1994). Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 222, revised version. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Requate, Till. &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;. revised version. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1994. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 222.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Requate, T. (1994).  &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 222) revised version. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Requate T (1994)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 222, revised version.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Requate, T., 1994. &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.222, revised version., Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Requate, &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 222, revised version.,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1994.</ieee>
<apa>Requate, T. (1994).  &lt;em&gt;Incentives to innovate under emission taxes and tradeable permits&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 222) revised version. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2909806</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-04T11:06:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>