<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2909855</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62514</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Uphaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bodo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vogt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_287.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2909855/2910200/IMW_working_paper_287.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29098554</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>287</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> W. Albers, A. Uphaus, and B. Vogt, &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 287,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1998.</ieee>
<apa>Albers, W., Uphaus, A., &amp;amp; Vogt, B. (1998).  &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 287). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, W., Uphaus, A. &amp;amp; Vogt, B. (1998). &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Albers, W., Uphaus, A., and Vogt, B. (1998). A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 287, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Albers W, Uphaus A, Vogt B. &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 287. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 1998.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Albers, A.  Uphaus, and B.  Vogt, &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Albers W, Uphaus A, Vogt B (1998) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 287.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, W., Uphaus, A., &amp;amp; Vogt, B. (1998).  &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 287). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Albers, W., Uphaus, A., &amp;amp; Vogt, B., 1998. &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.287, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<wels>Albers, W.; Uphaus, A.; Vogt, B. (1998): A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Albers W, Uphaus A, Vogt B (1998)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 287.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Albers, Wulf, Uphaus, Andreas, and Vogt, Bodo. &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1998. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 287.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, Wulf, Uphaus, Andreas, and Vogt, Bodo. 1998. &lt;em&gt;A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 287. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Albers, W., Uphaus, A., Vogt, B.: A model of the concession behavior in the sequence of offers of the German electronic stock exchange trading market (IBIS) based on the prominence structure of the bid ask spread. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 287. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (1998).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2909855</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-04T11:07:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>