<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2910276</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kahl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">30411756</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8468-2808</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Glenn</namePart><namePart type="family">Gunzelmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andrew</namePart><namePart type="family">Howes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thora</namePart><namePart type="family">Tenbrink</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Eddy</namePart><namePart type="family">Davelaar</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>39th Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (CogSci 2017)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kahl_1_31_final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2910276/2911411/kahl_1_31_final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">London, UK</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-9911967-6-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29102763</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">2350-2355</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kahl S, Kopp S. Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In: Gunzelmann G, Howes A, Tenbrink T, Davelaar E, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society;  2017: 2350-2355.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kahl, S. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink &amp;amp; E. Davelaar (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (S. 2350-2355). Gehalten auf der 39th Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (CogSci 2017), Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kahl, S., and Kopp, S. (2017). “Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, Gunzelmann, G., Howes, A., Tenbrink, T., and Davelaar, E. eds. (Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society), 2350-2355.</frontiers>
<apa>Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In G.  Gunzelmann, A.  Howes, T.  Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E.  Davelaar (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 2350-2355). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.</apa>
<ieee> S. Kahl and S. Kopp, “Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, G. Gunzelmann, et al., eds.,  Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society, 2017,  pp.2350-2355.</ieee>
<wels>Kahl, S.; Kopp, S. (2017): Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In: Glenn Gunzelmann; Andrew Howes; Thora Tenbrink; Eddy Davelaar (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.  S. 2350-2355.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In G.  Gunzelmann, A.  Howes, T.  Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E.  Davelaar (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 2350-2355). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Kahl S, Kopp S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Gunzelmann G, Howes A, Tenbrink T, Davelaar E (Eds); Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society:  2350-2355.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kahl, S., &amp;amp; Kopp, S., 2017. Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In G.  Gunzelmann, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;.  Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society, pp. 2350-2355.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kahl, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, E. Davelaar), Cognitive Science Society, Austin, TX, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 2350-2355.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Kahl, S., Kopp, S.: Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing. In: Gunzelmann, G., Howes, A., Tenbrink, T., and Davelaar, E. (eds.) Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. p. 2350-2355. Cognitive Science Society, Austin, TX (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kahl, Sebastian, and Kopp, Stefan. 2017. “Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Glenn Gunzelmann, Andrew Howes, Thora Tenbrink, and Eddy Davelaar, 2350-2355. Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kahl, Sebastian, and Kopp, Stefan. “Self-other distinction in the motor system during social interaction: A computational model based on predictive processing”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Glenn Gunzelmann, Andrew Howes, Thora Tenbrink, and Eddy Davelaar. Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society, 2017. 2350-2355.</mla>
<default>Kahl S, Kopp S (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Gunzelmann G, Howes A, Tenbrink T, Davelaar E (Eds);  Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society:  2350-2355.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2910276</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-12T08:37:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>