<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2910475</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Phillip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lücking</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41979092</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joshua</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">de Leeuw</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Selma</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Šabanović</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Goldstone</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Fabio P.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bonsignorio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2017</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Thematic Network Interactive Intelligent Systems</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="icra-2017_ws_lier.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2910475/2910476/icra-2017_ws_lier.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Singapore</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Reproducibility</topic><topic>Robotics</topic><topic>Software Engineering</topic><topic>Software</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29104756</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Lier, P.  Lücking, J.  de Leeuw, S.  Wachsmuth, S.  Šabanović, and R.  Goldstone, in &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: F.P. Bonsignorio), Ieee, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Lier, F., et al., 2017. Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In F. P.  Bonsignorio, ed. &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore.  IEEE.</harvard1>
<bio1>Lier F, Lücking P, de Leeuw J, Wachsmuth S, Šabanović S, Goldstone R (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead. Bonsignorio FP (Ed); Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore,  IEEE.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Lücking, P., de Leeuw, J., Wachsmuth, S., Šabanović, S., &amp;amp; Goldstone, R. (2017). Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In F. P.  Bonsignorio (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt; IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Lier, F.; Lücking, P.; de Leeuw, J.; Wachsmuth, S.; Šabanović, S.; Goldstone, R. (2017): Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In: Fabio P. Bonsignorio (Hrsg.):  ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead. IEEE. (Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore, ).</wels>
<ieee> F. Lier, et al., “Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research”, &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;, F.P. Bonsignorio, ed., Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore, IEEE, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Lier, F., Lücking, P., de Leeuw, J., Wachsmuth, S., Šabanović, S., &amp;amp; Goldstone, R. (2017). Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In F. P.  Bonsignorio (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt; IEEE.</apa>
<frontiers>Lier, F., Lücking, P., de Leeuw, J., Wachsmuth, S., Šabanović, S., and Goldstone, R. (2017). “Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research” in &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;, Bonsignorio, F. P. ed. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore (IEEE).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Lücking, P., de Leeuw, J., Wachsmuth, S., Šabanović, S. &amp;amp; Goldstone, R. (2017). Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research (Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore). In F.P. Bonsignorio (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2017, IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Lier F, Lücking P, de Leeuw J, Wachsmuth S, Šabanović S, Goldstone R. Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In: Bonsignorio FP, ed. &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore. IEEE;  2017.</ama>
<default>Lier F, Lücking P, de Leeuw J, Wachsmuth S, Šabanović S, Goldstone R (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead. Bonsignorio FP (Ed);  Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore.  IEEE.</default>
<mla>Lier, Florian, Lücking, Phillip, de Leeuw, Joshua, Wachsmuth, Sven, Šabanović, Selma, and Goldstone, Robert. “Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research”. &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Fabio P. Bonsignorio. IEEE, 2017. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, Florian, Lücking, Phillip, de Leeuw, Joshua, Wachsmuth, Sven, Šabanović, Selma, and Goldstone, Robert. 2017. “Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research”. In &lt;em&gt;ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Fabio P. Bonsignorio. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore. IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lier, F., Lücking, P., de Leeuw, J., Wachsmuth, S., Šabanović, S., Goldstone, R.: Can we Reproduce it? Toward the Implementation of good Experimental Methodology in Interdisciplinary Robotics Research. In: Bonsignorio, F.P. (ed.) ICRA 2017 Workshop on Reproducible Research in Robotics: Current Status and Road Ahead. Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE Xplore.  IEEE (2017).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2910475</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-21T09:43:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T12:56:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>