<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2910671</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oktay</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sürücü</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701960</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sonja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brangewitz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10633183</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Behnud</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mir Djawadi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The asymmetric dominance effect refers to the phenomenon according to which the choice
probability of an alternative increases when an inferior alternative - the decoy - is included
into the choice set. The objective of this experimental study is twofold. First, we investigate
the asymmetric dominance effect on two-outcome lotteries with almost equal expected values.
We find that the impact of a decoy on low-variance lotteries (LVLs) is much higher than on
high-variance lotteries (HVLs). Second, we examine the asymmetric dominance effect in the
presence of two decoys. While the asymmetric dominance effect persists when the choice
set includes two decoys, the effect is not always further enhanced compared to the setting
with one decoy and again much stronger for LVLs than for HVLs. Controlling for subjects’
degrees of risk aversion, we find support for consistency between individual risk preferences
and choice behavior among the lotteries. However, we observe decoy effects of equal strength
irrespective of the subjects’ degree of risk aversion. Thus, our analysis indicates that to a
substantial extent the presence of decoys subtly makes decision-makers choose against their
risk preferences by favoring lotteries that entail risks contrary to their elicited individual
risk-taking profile.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_574.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2910671/2910672/IMW_working_paper_574.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Asymmetric dominance effect</topic><topic>decoy effects</topic><topic>multiple decoys</topic><topic>risk aversion</topic><topic>individual decision making</topic><topic>experimental economics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29106712</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>574</number></detail><extent unit="pages">24</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sürücü, Oktay, Brangewitz, Sonja, and Mir Djawadi, Behnud. 2017. &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 574. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S., Mir Djawadi, B.: Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 574. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2017).</lncs>
<default>Sürücü O, Brangewitz S, Mir Djawadi B (2017)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 574.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Sürücü, Oktay, Brangewitz, Sonja, and Mir Djawadi, Behnud. &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2017. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 574.</mla>
<wels>Sürücü, O.; Brangewitz, S.; Mir Djawadi, B. (2017): Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Sürücü, S.  Brangewitz, and B.  Mir Djawadi, &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S., &amp;amp; Mir Djawadi, B., 2017. &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.574, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Sürücü O, Brangewitz S, Mir Djawadi B (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 574.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S., &amp;amp; Mir Djawadi, B. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 574). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S. &amp;amp; Mir Djawadi, B. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S., and Mir Djawadi, B. (2017). Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 574, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Sürücü O, Brangewitz S, Mir Djawadi B. &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 574. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2017.</ama>
<ieee> O. Sürücü, S. Brangewitz, and B. Mir Djawadi, &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 574,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Sürücü, O., Brangewitz, S., &amp;amp; Mir Djawadi, B. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Asymmetric dominance effect with multiple decoys for low- and high-variance lotteries&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 574). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2910671</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-05-02T13:42:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>