<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2910336</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">ter Horst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36764835</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3244-6595</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jorge</namePart><namePart type="family">Gracia</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Francis</namePart><namePart type="family">Bond</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">John P.</namePart><namePart type="family">McCrae</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Buitelaar</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Chiarcos</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart><namePart type="family">Hellmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>1st International Conference on Language, Data, and Knowledge (LDK)</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Automatically Populating a Preclinical Spinal Cord Injury Knowledge Base to Support Clinical Translation</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">The problems of recognizing mentions of entities in texts and linking them to unique knowledge base identifiers have received considerable attention in recent years. In this paper we present a probabilistic system based on undirected graphical models that jointly addresses both the entity recognition and the linking task. Our framework considers the span of mentions of entities as well as the corresponding knowledge base identifier as random variables and models the joint assignment using a factorized distribution. We show that our approach can be easily applied to different technical domains by merely exchanging the underlying ontology. On the task of recognizing and linking disease names, we show that our approach outperforms the state-of-the-art systems DNorm and TaggerOne, as well as two strong lexicon-based baselines. On the task of recognizing and linking chemical names, our system achieves comparable performance to the state-of-the-art.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2910336/2912083/preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Galway, Ireland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Joint entity recognition and linking</topic><topic>Undirected probabilistic graphical models</topic><topic>Diseases</topic><topic>Chemicals</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29103365</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10318</number></detail><extent unit="pages">166-180</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  ter Horst, M.  Hartung, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Gracia, F. Bond, J.P. McCrae, P. Buitelaar, C. Chiarcos, S. Hellmann), Springer, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 166-180.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2017. Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In J.  Gracia, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. no.10318  Springer, pp. 166-180.</harvard1>
<bio1>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference). Gracia J, Bond F, McCrae JP, Buitelaar P, Chiarcos C, Hellmann S (Eds); Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 10318. Springer:  166-180.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In J.  Gracia, F.  Bond, J. P.  McCrae, P.  Buitelaar, C.  Chiarcos, &amp;amp; S.  Hellmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 10318&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 166-180). Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>ter Horst, H.; Hartung, M.; Cimiano, P. (2017): Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In: Jorge Gracia; Francis Bond; John P. McCrae; Paul Buitelaar; Christian Chiarcos; Sebastian Hellmann (Hrsg.):  Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference). Springer. (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 10318).  S. 166-180.</wels>
<ieee> H. ter Horst, M. Hartung, and P. Cimiano, “Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models”, &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;, J. Gracia, et al., eds., Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 10318, Springer, 2017,  pp.166-180.</ieee>
<apa>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In J.  Gracia, F.  Bond, J. P.  McCrae, P.  Buitelaar, C.  Chiarcos, &amp;amp; S.  Hellmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence: Vol. 10318&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 166-180). Springer.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, H., Hartung, M. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence). In J. Gracia, F. Bond, J.P. McCrae, P. Buitelaar, C. Chiarcos &amp;amp; S. Hellmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 166-180). Gehalten auf der 1st International Conference on Language, Data, and Knowledge (LDK), Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models” in &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;, Gracia, J., Bond, F., McCrae, J. P., Buitelaar, P., Chiarcos, C., and Hellmann, S. eds. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, vol. 10318, (Springer), 166-180.</frontiers>
<ama>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P. Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In: Gracia J, Bond F, McCrae JP, Buitelaar P, Chiarcos C, Hellmann S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Vol 10318. Springer;  2017: 166-180.</ama>
<default>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference). Gracia J, Bond F, McCrae JP, Buitelaar P, Chiarcos C, Hellmann S (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, 10318.  Springer:  166-180.</default>
<mla>ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models”. &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jorge Gracia, Francis Bond, John P. McCrae, Paul Buitelaar, Christian Chiarcos, and Sebastian Hellmann. Springer, 2017.Vol. 10318. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 166-180.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models”. In &lt;em&gt;Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jorge Gracia, Francis Bond, John P. McCrae, Paul Buitelaar, Christian Chiarcos, and Sebastian Hellmann, 10318:166-180. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Cimiano, P.: Joint Entity Recognition and Linking in Technical Domains Using Undirected Probabilistic Graphical Models. In: Gracia, J., Bond, F., McCrae, J.P., Buitelaar, P., Chiarcos, C., and Hellmann, S. (eds.) Language, Data, and Knowledge (Proceedings of the 1st International LDK Conference). Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence. 10318, p. 166-180. Springer (2017).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2910336</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-04-17T12:15:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>