<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2911537</id><setSpec>research_data</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:ResearchData</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>research_dataFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>database</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Günther</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Phenotypic Plasticity of Behaviour (DFG)</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">research group</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<abstract lang="eng">The prenatal social environment affects offspring
development in most studied taxa with potentially lifelong
consequences. To understand the adaptive significance of
such maternal influences on offspring development, it is important
to study their effects on fitness. In guinea pigs, social
instability during pregnancy leads to delayed development of
male offspring. This has been interpreted as an adaptation to
high social densities, where young males need to queue for
reproductive opportunities since they cannot out-compete
older dominant males. The consequences for male reproductive
success are, however, so far unknown. To study the effects
of different prenatal social densities on offspring reproductive
performance, we housed females individually or in small
groups during late pregnancy. Offspring from both treatments
were reared together in large groups until independence and
thereafter housed in same-sex pairs of the same treatment.We
then observed courtship, aggressive behavior, and reproductive
success in a low-density context with one male from each
treatment competing over access to two females. Sons born to
individually housed females initiated more fights, had more
social contacts, courted females more, and had a higher reproductive
success than sons of group-housed females. Sons born
to mothers experiencing low social densities before birth
therefore perform better at low social group sizes, suggesting
that male development may be adaptively adjusted to anticipated
social densities, although performance under high densities
still needs to be compared.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Guenther et al. 2014_Behavioural Ecology and Sociobiology.xlsx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2911537/2911541/Guenther et al. 2014_Behavioural Ecology and Sociobiology.xlsx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>

<subject><topic>Maternal programming . Transgenerational effects . Adaptive plasticity . Guinea pig</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2911537</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2701615</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, Anja. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Günther, A.: Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success. Bielefeld University (2014).</lncs>
<default>Günther A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</default>
<mla>Günther, Anja. &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University, 2014.</mla>
<frontiers>Günther, A. (2014). Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success. Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, A. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2911537.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Günther A. &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University; 2014.</ama>
<ieee> A. Günther, &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Günther, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2911537</apa>
<wels>Günther, A. (2014): Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success. Bielefeld University.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Günther, &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Günther, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2911537&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Günther, A., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<bio1>Günther A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data for Prenatal social conditions shape offspring adult phenotype and reproductive success&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2911537</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-05-16T08:55:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T14:48:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>