<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2911260</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62514</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_269.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2911260/2911261/IMW_working_paper_269.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29112601</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>269</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, W. (1997). &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Albers W (1997) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 269.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Albers, &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Albers W. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Vol 269. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 1997.</ama>
<lncs> Albers, W.: Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 269. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (1997).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, Wulf. 1997. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 269. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Albers, W. (1997): Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Albers, W. (1997).  &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 269). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Albers, Wulf. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1997. Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics. 269.</mla>
<frontiers>Albers, W. (1997). Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 269, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Albers W (1997)  Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics; 269.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ieee> W. Albers, &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, vol. 269,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 1997.</ieee>
<harvard1>Albers, W., 1997. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, no.269, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Albers, W. (1997).  &lt;em&gt;Foundations of a theory of prominence in the decimal system. Part III: Perception of numerical information, and relations to traditional solution concepts&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers. Institute of Mathematical Economics, 269). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2911260</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-05-10T14:11:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>