<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2912288</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:590</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anastasia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klimova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joseph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoffman</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23351084</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5895-8949</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jesus N.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gutierrez-Rivera</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jose</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Leon de la Luz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfredo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ortega-Rubio</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The complex geological and ecological processes that have generated high levels of biodiversity and endemism in the Baja California Peninsula have been the subject of intensive study. However, relatively little is known about phylogeography of the iconic endemic palm species of this region. We therefore analyzed a total of 2,294 bp of chloroplast and 738 bp of nuclear sequence data in 169 samples of five native palm species from Baja California, Sonora and Guadalupe Island. We found that Washingtonia and Brahea palms had low levels of genetic diversity and were highly structured, with the majority of species and major geographic regions being characterized by distinct haplotypes. We also found strong support for currently recognized species in Washingtonia, but our results were less clear cut for Brahea due to haplotype sharing. Furthermore, patterns of population structure were broadly consistent with historical vicariant events such as the inundation of the Isthmus of La Paz, the formation of the Sea of Cortez, and the more recent colonization and isolation of Guadalupe Island's palms. Our findings contribute toward a growing appreciation of the complexity of plant responses to past geological changes and also provide valuable baseline genetic data on relict American palm species.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ece33036.hoffman.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2912288/2912289/ece33036.hoffman.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ecology and Evolution</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2045-7758</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28690819</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000404645400037</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29122883</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/ece3.3036</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>13</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1-17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Klimova, A., Hoffman, J., Gutierrez-Rivera, J.N., Leon de la Luz, J., Ortega-Rubio, A.: Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. Ecology and Evolution. 7, 1-17 (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, Anastasia, Hoffman, Joseph, Gutierrez-Rivera, Jesus N., Leon de la Luz, Jose, and Ortega-Rubio, Alfredo. 2017. “Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 7 (13): 1-17.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Klimova, Anastasia, Hoffman, Joseph, Gutierrez-Rivera, Jesus N., Leon de la Luz, Jose, and Ortega-Rubio, Alfredo. “Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 7.13 (2017): 1-17.</mla>
<default>Klimova A, Hoffman J, Gutierrez-Rivera JN, Leon de la Luz J, Ortega-Rubio A (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 7(13): 1-17.</default>
<ama>Klimova A, Hoffman J, Gutierrez-Rivera JN, Leon de la Luz J, Ortega-Rubio A. Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;7(13):1-17.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, A., Hoffman, J., Gutierrez-Rivera, J.N., Leon de la Luz, J. &amp;amp; Ortega-Rubio, A. (2017). Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1-17. Wiley-Blackwell. doi:10.1002/ece3.3036.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Klimova, A., Hoffman, J., Gutierrez-Rivera, J. N., Leon de la Luz, J., and Ortega-Rubio, A. (2017). Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 7, 1-17.</frontiers>
<apa>Klimova, A., Hoffman, J., Gutierrez-Rivera, J. N., Leon de la Luz, J., &amp;amp; Ortega-Rubio, A. (2017). Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1-17. doi:10.1002/ece3.3036</apa>
<ieee> A. Klimova, et al., “Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2017,  pp. 1-17.</ieee>
<wels>Klimova, A.; Hoffman, J.; Gutierrez-Rivera, J. N.; Leon de la Luz, J.; Ortega-Rubio, A. (2017): Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,7:(13): 1-17.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, A., Hoffman, J., Gutierrez-Rivera, J. N., Leon de la Luz, J., &amp;amp; Ortega-Rubio, A. (2017). Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1-17. doi:10.1002/ece3.3036&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Klimova, A., et al., 2017. Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, 7(13), p 1-17.</harvard1>
<bio1>Klimova A, Hoffman J, Gutierrez-Rivera JN, Leon de la Luz J, Ortega-Rubio A (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island.&lt;br /&gt;Ecology and Evolution 7(13): 1-17.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Klimova, J.  Hoffman, J. N.  Gutierrez-Rivera, J.  Leon de la Luz, and A.  Ortega-Rubio, “Molecular genetic analysis of two native desert palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, from the Baja California Peninsula and Guadalupe Island”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1-17.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2912288</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-06-23T06:04:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T12:36:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>