<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2912599</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grünberger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">94700790</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christopher</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Probst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Antonia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiechert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frunzke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kohlheyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">110747676</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this protocol the fabrication, experimental setup and basic operation of the recently introduced microfluidic picoliter bioreactor (PLBR) is described in detail. The PLBR can be utilized for the analysis of single bacteria and microcolonies to investigate biotechnological and microbiological related questions concerning, e.g. cell growth, morphology, stress response, and metabolite or protein production on single-cell level. The device features continuous media flow enabling constant environmental conditions for perturbation studies, but in addition allows fast medium changes as well as oscillating conditions to mimic any desired environmental situation. To fabricate the single use devices, a silicon wafer containing sub micrometer sized SU-8 structures served as the replication mold for rapid polydimethylsiloxane casting. Chips were cut, assembled, connected, and set up onto a high resolution and fully automated microscope suited for time-lapse imaging, a powerful tool for spatio-temporal cell analysis. Here, the biotechnological platform organism Corynebacterium glutamicum was seeded into the PLBR and cell growth and intracellular fluorescence were followed over several hours unraveling time dependent population heterogeneity on single-cell level, not possible with conventional analysis methods such as flow cytometry. Besides insights into device fabrication, furthermore, the preparation of the preculture, loading, trapping of bacteria, and the PLBR cultivation of single cells and colonies is demonstrated. These devices will add a new dimension in microbiological research to analyze time dependent phenomena of single bacteria under tight environmental control. Due to the simple and relatively short fabrication process the technology can be easily adapted at any microfluidics lab and simply tailored towards specific needs.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="FZJ-2013-06207.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2912599/2912721/FZJ-2013-06207.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>JoVE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1940-087x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1940-087X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24336165</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000209229000005</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29125995</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3791/50560</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>82</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>82</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Grünberger A, Probst C, Heyer A, Wiechert W, Frunzke J, Kohlheyer D (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt; 82(82): e50560.</default>
<frontiers>Grünberger, A., Probst, C., Heyer, A., Wiechert, W., Frunzke, J., and Kohlheyer, D. (2013). Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt; 82:e50560.</frontiers>
<mla>Grünberger, Alexander, Probst, Christopher, Heyer, Antonia, Wiechert, Wolfgang, Frunzke, Julia, and Kohlheyer, Dietrich. “Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt; 82.82 (2013): e50560.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grünberger, A., Probst, C., Heyer, A., Wiechert, W., Frunzke, J., &amp;amp; Kohlheyer, D. (2013). Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;82&lt;/em&gt;(82), e50560. doi:10.3791/50560&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Grünberger, A.; Probst, C.; Heyer, A.; Wiechert, W.; Frunzke, J.; Kohlheyer, D. (2013): Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;,82:(82):e50560</wels>
<apa>Grünberger, A., Probst, C., Heyer, A., Wiechert, W., Frunzke, J., &amp;amp; Kohlheyer, D. (2013). Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;82&lt;/em&gt;(82), e50560. doi:10.3791/50560</apa>
<ieee> A. Grünberger, et al., “Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 82, 2013, : e50560.</ieee>
<harvard1>Grünberger, A., et al., 2013. Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;, 82(82): e50560.</harvard1>
<bio1>Grünberger A, Probst C, Heyer A, Wiechert W, Frunzke J, Kohlheyer D (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering 82(82): e50560.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Grünberger, C.  Probst, A.  Heyer, W.  Wiechert, J.  Frunzke, and D.  Kohlheyer, “Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;82&lt;/em&gt;, : e50560.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grünberger, A., Probst, C., Heyer, A., Wiechert, W., Frunzke, J. &amp;amp; Kohlheyer, D. (2013). Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;82&lt;/em&gt;(82): e50560. JoVE. doi:10.3791/50560.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grünberger, Alexander, Probst, Christopher, Heyer, Antonia, Wiechert, Wolfgang, Frunzke, Julia, and Kohlheyer, Dietrich. 2013. “Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt; 82 (82): e50560.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Grünberger, A., Probst, C., Heyer, A., Wiechert, W., Frunzke, J., Kohlheyer, D.: Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering. 82, : e50560 (2013).</lncs>
<ama>Grünberger A, Probst C, Heyer A, Wiechert W, Frunzke J, Kohlheyer D. Microfluidic Picoliter Bioreactor for Microbial Single-cell Analysis: Fabrication, System Setup, and Operation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of visualized experiments. Bioengineering&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;82(82): e50560.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2912599</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-07-05T12:09:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-23T15:48:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>