<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2912757</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franziska</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmidtke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vogel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Social media are used by an increasing number of political actors. A small subset of these is interested in pursuing extrem- ist motives such as mobilization, recruiting or radicalization activities. In order to counteract these trends, online providers and state institutions reinforce their monitoring efforts, mostly relying on manual workflows. We propose a machine learning approach to support manual attempts towards identifying right-wing extremist content in German Twitter profiles. Based on a fine-grained conceptualization of right- wing extremism, we frame the task as ranking each individual profile on a continuum spanning different degrees of right-wing extremism, based on a nearest neighbour approach. A quantitative evaluation reveals that our ranking model yields robust performance (up to 0.81 F1 score) when being used for predicting discrete class labels. At the same time, the model provides plausible continuous ranking scores for a small sample of borderline cases at the division of right-wing extremism and New Right political movements.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wassa-preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2912757/2912790/wassa-preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Copenhagen, Denmark</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>right wing extremism</topic><topic>social media monitoring</topic><topic>machine learning</topic><topic>ranking</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29127570</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.18653/v1/W17-5204</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">24-33</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Hartung M, Klinger R, Schmidtke F, Vogel L (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA). Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics:  24-33.</default>
<mla>Hartung, Matthias, Klinger, Roman, Schmidtke, Franziska, and Vogel, Lars. “Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;. Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2017. 24-33.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, Matthias, Klinger, Roman, Schmidtke, Franziska, and Vogel, Lars. 2017. “Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;, 24-33. Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hartung, M., Klinger, R., Schmidtke, F., Vogel, L.: Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA). p. 24-33. Association for Computational Linguistics, Stroudsburg PA (2017).</lncs>
<ieee> M. Hartung, et al., “Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;,  Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2017,  pp.24-33.</ieee>
<apa>Hartung, M., Klinger, R., Schmidtke, F., &amp;amp; Vogel, L. (2017). Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;, 24-33. Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. doi:10.18653/v1/W17-5204</apa>
<frontiers>Hartung, M., Klinger, R., Schmidtke, F., and Vogel, L. (2017). “Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt; (Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics), 24-33.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, M., Klinger, R., Schmidtke, F. &amp;amp; Vogel, L. (2017). Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 24-33). Gehalten auf der 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA), Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. doi:10.18653/v1/W17-5204.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hartung M, Klinger R, Schmidtke F, Vogel L. Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;. Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics;  2017: 24-33.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Hartung, R.  Klinger, F.  Schmidtke, and L.  Vogel, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;, Association For Computational Linguistics, Stroudsburg PA, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 24-33.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hartung M, Klinger R, Schmidtke F, Vogel L (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA).  Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics:  24-33.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hartung, M., et al., 2017. Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;.  Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 24-33.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hartung, M., Klinger, R., Schmidtke, F., &amp;amp; Vogel, L. (2017). Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA)&lt;/em&gt;, 24-33. Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. doi:10.18653/v1/W17-5204&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Hartung, M.; Klinger, R.; Schmidtke, F.; Vogel, L. (2017): Ranking right-wing extremist social media profiles by similarity to democratic and extremist groups. In: Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis (WASSA). Stroudsburg PA: Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 24-33.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2912757</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-07-12T18:29:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>