<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913019</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Judith E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Farnberger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elisabeth</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lorenz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16798970</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Richter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kroutil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background&lt;br /&gt;
Transaminases have become a key tool in biocatalysis to introduce the amine functionality into a range of molecules like prochiral α-ketoacids and ketones. However, due to the necessity of shifting the equilibrium towards the product side (depending on the amine donor) an efficient amination system may require three enzymes. So far, this well-established transformation has mainly been performed in vitro by assembling all biocatalysts individually, which comes along with elaborate and costly preparation steps. We present the design and characterization of a flexible approach enabling a quick set-up of single-cell biocatalysts producing the desired enzymes. By choosing an appropriate co-expression strategy, a modular system was obtained, allowing for flexible plug-and-play combination of enzymes chosen from the toolbox of available transaminases and/or recycling enzymes tailored for the desired application.&lt;br /&gt;
Results&lt;br /&gt;
By using a two-plasmid strategy for the recycling enzyme and the transaminase together with chromosomal integration of an amino acid dehydrogenase, two enzyme modules could individually be selected and combined with specifically tailored E. coli strains. Various plug-and-play combinations of the enzymes led to the construction of a series of single-cell catalysts suitable for the amination of various types of substrates. On the one hand the fermentative amination of α-ketoacids coupled both with metabolic and non-metabolic cofactor regeneration was studied, giving access to the corresponding α-amino acids in up to 96% conversion. On the other hand, biocatalysts were employed in a non-metabolic, “in vitro-type” asymmetric reductive amination of the prochiral ketone 4-phenyl-2-butanone, yielding the amine in good conversion (77%) and excellent stereoselectivity (ee = 98%).&lt;br /&gt;
Conclusions&lt;br /&gt;
The described modularized concept enables the construction of tailored single-cell catalysts which provide all required enzymes for asymmetric reductive amination in a flexible fashion, representing a more efficient approach for the production of chiral amines and amino acids.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2017_Farnberger_Microb-Cell-Fact-16-132_amination and NADH regeneration.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913019/2950585/2017_Farnberger_Microb-Cell-Fact-16-132_amination and NADH regeneration.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Microbial Cell Factories</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1475-2859</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1475-2859</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28754115</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000406701100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29130191</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12934-017-0750-5</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Farnberger, J.E., Lorenz, E., Richter, N., Wendisch, V.F., Kroutil, W.: In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. Microbial Cell Factories. 16, : 132 (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Farnberger, Judith E., Lorenz, Elisabeth, Richter, Nina, Wendisch, Volker F., and Kroutil, Wolfgang. 2017. “In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones”. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt; 16 (1): 132.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Farnberger, Judith E., Lorenz, Elisabeth, Richter, Nina, Wendisch, Volker F., and Kroutil, Wolfgang. “In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones”. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt; 16.1 (2017): 132.</mla>
<default>Farnberger JE, Lorenz E, Richter N, Wendisch VF, Kroutil W (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt; 16(1): 132.</default>
<ama>Farnberger JE, Lorenz E, Richter N, Wendisch VF, Kroutil W. In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;16(1): 132.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Farnberger, J.E., Lorenz, E., Richter, N., Wendisch, V.F. &amp;amp; Kroutil, W. (2017). In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1): 132. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1186/s12934-017-0750-5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Farnberger, J. E., Lorenz, E., Richter, N., Wendisch, V. F., and Kroutil, W. (2017). In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt; 16:132.</frontiers>
<apa>Farnberger, J. E., Lorenz, E., Richter, N., Wendisch, V. F., &amp;amp; Kroutil, W. (2017). In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 132. doi:10.1186/s12934-017-0750-5</apa>
<ieee> J.E. Farnberger, et al., “In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones”, &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2017, : 132.</ieee>
<wels>Farnberger, J. E.; Lorenz, E.; Richter, N.; Wendisch, V. F.; Kroutil, W. (2017): In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;,16:(1):132</wels>
<bio1>Farnberger JE, Lorenz E, Richter N, Wendisch VF, Kroutil W (2017) &lt;br /&gt;In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones.&lt;br /&gt;Microbial Cell Factories 16(1): 132.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Farnberger, J. E., Lorenz, E., Richter, N., Wendisch, V. F., &amp;amp; Kroutil, W. (2017). In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(1), 132. doi:10.1186/s12934-017-0750-5&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Farnberger, J.E., et al., 2017. In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones. &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;, 16(1): 132.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>J. E.  Farnberger, E.  Lorenz, N.  Richter, V. F.  Wendisch, and W.  Kroutil, “In vivo Plug-and-play: A Modular Multi-enzyme Single-cell Catalyst for the Asymmetric Amination of Ketoacids and Ketones”, &lt;em&gt;Microbial Cell Factories&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, : 132.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913019</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-07-25T16:27:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-27T10:53:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>