<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913482</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Borowi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">ter Horst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36764835</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3244-6595</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Veronica</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Estrada</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nicole</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brazda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>13th International Conference on Semantic Systems (SEMANTICS)</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Automatically Populating a Preclinical Spinal Cord Injury Knowledge Base to Support Clinical Translation</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">We present SCIExplorer, an interactive web application for browsing research data represented in RDF format. Offering an intuitive exploration of the data in a visual interface based on the data-describing ontology, SCIExplorer is designed to overcome the potentially high entrance barriers faced by human domain experts interested in investigating research results at a glance without the need to formulate complex queries. In contrast, SCIExplorer provides filter-driven dynamic generation of SPARQL queries without the need to specify them manually. We demonstrate that the tool can be effectively used to answer relevant competency questions in the domain of spinal cord injury, thus providing intuitive access to the results of preclinical studies which are represented in RDF. In particular, SCIExplorer offers drill-downs to individual preclinical results in order to visualize their core parameters at an interpretable level of abstraction that is guided by an underlying domain ontology.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paper4.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913482/2918222/paper4.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>RWTH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Amsterdam</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Visual Data Analytics</topic><topic>Open Research Data</topic><topic>Linked Data</topic><topic>RDF Browsing</topic><topic>Ontology-based Access</topic><topic>Spinal Cord Injury</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1613-0073</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29134823</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2044</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Borowi A, ter Horst H, Hartung M, Estrada V, Brazda N, Müller HW, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track. CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2044.  Aachen: RWTH.</default>
<wels>Borowi, A.; ter Horst, H.; Hartung, M.; Estrada, V.; Brazda, N.; Müller, H. W.; Cimiano, P. (2017): Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. In: Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track. Aachen: RWTH. (CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2044).</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borowi, A., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Estrada, V., Brazda, N., Müller, H. W., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, &lt;em&gt;2044&lt;/em&gt; Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Borowi, A., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Estrada, V., Brazda, N., Müller, H. W., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt; CEUR Workshop proceedings, vol. 2044, (Aachen: RWTH).</frontiers>
<mla>Borowi, Alexander, ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, Estrada, Veronica, Brazda, Nicole, Müller, Hans Werner, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;. Aachen: RWTH, 2017.Vol. 2044. CEUR Workshop proceedings.</mla>
<apa>Borowi, A., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Estrada, V., Brazda, N., Müller, H. W., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, &lt;em&gt;2044&lt;/em&gt; Aachen: RWTH.</apa>
<harvard1>Borowi, A., et al., 2017. Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop proceedings. no.2044  Aachen: RWTH.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Borowi, et al., “Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, vol. 2044,  Aachen: RWTH, 2017.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Borowi, H.  ter Horst, M.  Hartung, V.  Estrada, N.  Brazda, H. W.  Müller, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;, Rwth, Aachen, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Borowi A, ter Horst H, Hartung M, Estrada V, Brazda N, Müller HW, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track.  CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2044. Aachen: RWTH.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borowi, A., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Estrada, V., Brazda, N., Müller, H.W. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain (CEUR Workshop proceedings). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 13th International Conference on Semantic Systems (SEMANTICS), Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Borowi, Alexander, ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, Estrada, Veronica, Brazda, Nicole, Müller, Hans Werner, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 2044. CEUR Workshop proceedings. Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Borowi, A., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Estrada, V., Brazda, N., Müller, H.W., Cimiano, P.: Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track. CEUR Workshop proceedings. 2044,  RWTH, Aachen (2017).</lncs>
<ama>Borowi A, ter Horst H, Hartung M, et al. Ontology-driven Visual Exploration of Preclinical Research Data in the Spinal Cord Injury Domain. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the SEMANTICS 2017 Poster and Demo Track&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop proceedings. Vol 2044. Aachen: RWTH;  2017.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913482</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-28T09:32:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>