<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913603</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nicole</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brazda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">ter Horst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36764835</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3244-6595</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cord</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiljes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27436085</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2528-5391</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Veronica</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Estrada</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuchinke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>3rd Joint Ontology Workshops: Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Automatically Populating a Preclinical Spinal Cord Injury Knowledge Base to Support Clinical Translation</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="jowo-scio.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913603/2913881/jowo-scio.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>RWTH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bolzano, Italy</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1613-0073</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29136033</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2050</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Brazda N, ter Horst H, Hartung M, Wiljes C, Estrada V, Klinger R, Kuchinke W, Müller HW, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences.  CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2050. Aachen: RWTH.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brazda, N., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Wiljes, C., Estrada, V., Klinger, R., Kuchinke, W., et al. (2017). SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, &lt;em&gt;2050&lt;/em&gt; Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Brazda, N., et al., 2017. SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop proceedings. no.2050  Aachen: RWTH.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Brazda, H.  ter Horst, M.  Hartung, C.  Wiljes, V.  Estrada, R.  Klinger, W.  Kuchinke, H. W.  Müller, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, Rwth, Aachen, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Brazda, N.; ter Horst, H.; Hartung, M.; Wiljes, C.; Estrada, V.; Klinger, R.; Kuchinke, W.; Müller, H. W.; Cimiano, P. (2017): SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. In: Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences. Aachen: RWTH. (CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2050).</wels>
<apa>Brazda, N., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Wiljes, C., Estrada, V., Klinger, R., Kuchinke, W., et al. (2017). SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, &lt;em&gt;2050&lt;/em&gt; Aachen: RWTH.</apa>
<ieee> N. Brazda, et al., “SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, CEUR Workshop proceedings, vol. 2050,  Aachen: RWTH, 2017.</ieee>
<ama>Brazda N, ter Horst H, Hartung M, et al. SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop proceedings. Vol 2050. Aachen: RWTH;  2017.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brazda, N., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Wiljes, C., Estrada, V., Klinger, R., Kuchinke, W., Müller, H.W. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments (CEUR Workshop proceedings). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops: Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences, Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Brazda, N., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Wiljes, C., Estrada, V., Klinger, R., Kuchinke, W., Müller, H. W., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt; CEUR Workshop proceedings, vol. 2050, (Aachen: RWTH).</frontiers>
<mla>Brazda, Nicole, ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, Wiljes, Cord, Estrada, Veronica, Klinger, Roman, Kuchinke, Wolfgang, Müller, Hans Werner, and Cimiano, Philipp. “SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Aachen: RWTH, 2017.Vol. 2050. CEUR Workshop proceedings.</mla>
<default>Brazda N, ter Horst H, Hartung M, Wiljes C, Estrada V, Klinger R, Kuchinke W, Müller HW, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences. CEUR Workshop proceedings, 2050.  Aachen: RWTH.</default>
<lncs> Brazda, N., ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Wiljes, C., Estrada, V., Klinger, R., Kuchinke, W., Müller, H.W., Cimiano, P.: SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments. Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences. CEUR Workshop proceedings. 2050,  RWTH, Aachen (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brazda, Nicole, ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, Wiljes, Cord, Estrada, Veronica, Klinger, Roman, Kuchinke, Wolfgang, Müller, Hans Werner, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “SCIO: An Ontology to Support the Formalization of Pre-Clinical Spinal Cord Injury Experiments”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd Joint Ontology Workshops (JOWO): Ontologies and Data in the Life Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 2050. CEUR Workshop proceedings. Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913603</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-09-02T12:02:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>