<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913141</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sherzod</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hakimov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955317</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7421-6213</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soufian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jebbara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">61955542</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4483-0933</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart><namePart type="family">d'Amato</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Miriam</namePart><namePart type="family">Fernandez</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Valentina</namePart><namePart type="family">Tamma</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>16th International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2017)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The task of answering natural language questions over RDF data has
received wIde interest in recent years, in particular in the context of the series
of QALD benchmarks. The task consists of mapping a natural language question
to an executable form, e.g. SPARQL, so that answers from a given KB can
be extracted. So far, most systems proposed are i) monolingual and ii) rely on
a set of hard-coded rules to interpret questions and map them into a SPARQL
query. We present the first multilingual QALD pipeline that induces a model
from training data for mapping a natural language question into logical form as
probabilistic inference. In particular, our approach learns to map universal syntactic
dependency representations to a language-independent logical form based
on DUDES (Dependency-based Underspecified Discourse Representation Structures)
that are then mapped to a SPARQL query as a deterministic second step.
Our model builds on factor graphs that rely on features extracted from the dependency
graph and corresponding semantic representations.We rely on approximate
inference techniques, Markov Chain Monte Carlo methods in particular, as well
as Sample Rank to update parameters using a ranking objective. Our focus lies on
developing methods that overcome the lexical gap and present a novel combination
of machine translation and word embedding approaches for this purpose. As
a proof of concept for our approach, we evaluate our approach on the QALD-6
datasets for English, German &amp; Spanish.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paper.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913141/2913142/paper.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Vienna</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>question answering</topic><topic>multilinguality</topic><topic>QALD</topic><topic>probabilistic graphical models</topic><topic>factor graphs</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29131414</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-68288-4_20</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10587</number></detail><extent unit="pages">329-346</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Hakimov S, Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings. d'Amato C, Fernandez M, Tamma V (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 10587. Cham: Springer:  329-346.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In C.  d'Amato, M.  Fernandez, &amp;amp; V.  Tamma (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 10587&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 329-346). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-68288-4_20&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2017. AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In C.  d'Amato, M.  Fernandez, &amp;amp; V.  Tamma, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.10587  Cham: Springer, pp. 329-346.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Hakimov, S.  Jebbara, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. d'Amato, M. Fernandez, V. Tamma), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 329-346.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Hakimov, S.; Jebbara, S.; Cimiano, P. (2017): AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In: Claudia d'Amato; Miriam Fernandez; Valentina Tamma (Hrsg.):  The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings. Cham: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 10587).  S. 329-346.</wels>
<apa>Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In C.  d'Amato, M.  Fernandez, &amp;amp; V.  Tamma (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 10587&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 329-346). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-68288-4_20</apa>
<ieee> S. Hakimov, S. Jebbara, and P. Cimiano, “AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data”, &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, C. d'Amato, M. Fernandez, and V. Tamma, eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 10587,  Cham: Springer, 2017,  pp.329-346.</ieee>
<ama>Hakimov S, Jebbara S, Cimiano P. AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In: d'Amato C, Fernandez M, Tamma V, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 10587. Cham: Springer;  2017: 329-346.</ama>
<frontiers>Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data” in &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, d'Amato, C., Fernandez, M., and Tamma, V. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 10587, (Cham: Springer), 329-346.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In C. d'Amato, M. Fernandez &amp;amp; V. Tamma (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 329-346). Gehalten auf der 16th International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2017), Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-68288-4_20.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Hakimov, Sherzod, Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data”. &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Claudia d'Amato, Miriam Fernandez, and Valentina Tamma. Cham: Springer, 2017.Vol. 10587. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 329-346.</mla>
<default>Hakimov S, Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings. d'Amato C, Fernandez M, Tamma V (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 10587.  Cham: Springer:  329-346.</default>
<lncs> Hakimov, S., Jebbara, S., Cimiano, P.: AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data. In: d'Amato, C., Fernandez, M., and Tamma, V. (eds.) The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 10587, p. 329-346. Springer, Cham (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hakimov, Sherzod, Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “AMUSE: Multilingual Semantic Parsing for Question Answering over Linked Data”. In &lt;em&gt;The Semantic Web - ISWC 2017. 16th International Semantic Web Conference. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Claudia d'Amato, Miriam Fernandez, and Valentina Tamma, 10587:329-346. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913141</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-05T17:37:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T08:30:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>