<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913049</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">inpress</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hough</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">48164400</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zarrieß</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51642361</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="GroundedNLU2017.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913049/2913056/GroundedNLU2017.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stockholm, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29130490</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, Julian, Zarrieß, Sina, and Schlangen, David. In Press. “Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data”. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hough, J., Zarrieß, S., Schlangen, D.: Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden (In Press).</lncs>
<default>Hough J, Zarrieß S, Schlangen D (In Press)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</default>
<mla>Hough, Julian, Zarrieß, Sina, and Schlangen, David. “Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data”. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden, In Press.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J., Zarrieß, S. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (In Press). Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data. Gehalten auf der Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hough, J., Zarrieß, S., and Schlangen, D. (In Press).“Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data”. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</frontiers>
<ama>Hough J, Zarrieß S, Schlangen D. Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</ama>
<ieee> J. Hough, S. Zarrieß, and D. Schlangen, “Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data”, Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden, In Press.</ieee>
<apa>Hough, J., Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (In Press). &lt;em&gt;Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</apa>
<wels>Hough, J.; Zarrieß, S.; Schlangen, D. (In Press): Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hough, S.  Zarrieß, and D.  Schlangen, &lt;strong&gt;In Press&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hough J, Zarrieß S, Schlangen D (In Press) &lt;br /&gt;Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hough, J., Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., In Press. Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hough, J., Zarrieß, S., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (In Press). &lt;em&gt;Grounding Imperatives to Actions is Not Enough: A Challenge for Grounded NLU for Robots from Human-Human Data&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Grounding Language Understanding (GLU2017), Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913049</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-07-27T10:57:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>