<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913280</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pollmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40044</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">**Background and purpose**&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Although sport psychology literature focuses on psychological skills use to promote proficiency, it is still puzzling that current research has focused on psychological skills use only during competition. There remains a scarcity of empirical evidence to support the timing, and content of psychological skill application during the time preceding competition. This study examined the extent to which psychological skills usage are dynamic or stable over a 7-day pre-competitive period and whether any natural learning experiences might have accounted for the acquisition of these skills across gender and skill level.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Methods and results**&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Ninety elite and sub-elite table tennis players completed the Test of Performance Strategies (TOPS) at three different periods (7 days, 2 days, 1 hour) before competition. A MANOVA repeated measures with follow-up analyses revealed significant multivariate main effects for only skill level and time-to-competition with no interactions. Specifically, elite (international) athletes reported more usage than sub-elite (national) counterparts for self-talk, imagery and relaxation respectively. Time-to-competition effects showed imagery use decreased steadily across the three time points while reported usage of relaxation were almost at the same level on two time points (7 days and 1 hour) but decreased 2 days before competition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Conclusions**&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Findings suggest an implementation of formalized and periodized psychological skills training programs over continuous training cycles. This may foster a positive long-term athletes’ psychological state prior to the onset of competition.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0181814.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913280/2913281/journal.pone.0181814.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLOS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28786998</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000406998800010</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29132809</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0181814</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Hagan Jr., J.E., Pollmann, D., Schack, T.: Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. PLOS ONE. 12, : e0181814 (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Pollmann, Dietmar, and Schack, Thomas. 2017. “Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12 (8): e0181814.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Pollmann, Dietmar, and Schack, Thomas. “Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12.8 (2017): e0181814.</mla>
<default>Hagan Jr. JE, Pollmann D, Schack T (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12(8): e0181814.</default>
<wels>Hagan Jr., J. E.; Pollmann, D.; Schack, T. (2017): Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,12:(8):e0181814</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., J. E., Pollmann, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2017). Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0181814. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0181814&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Hagan Jr. JE, Pollmann D, Schack T (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes.&lt;br /&gt;PLOS ONE 12(8): e0181814.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hagan Jr., J.E., Pollmann, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T., 2017. Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 12(8): e0181814.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>J. E.  Hagan Jr., D.  Pollmann, and T.  Schack, “Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : e0181814.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hagan Jr. JE, Pollmann D, Schack T. Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;12(8): e0181814.</ama>
<frontiers>Hagan Jr., J. E., Pollmann, D., and Schack, T. (2017). Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12:e0181814.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., J.E., Pollmann, D. &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2017). Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(8): e0181814. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0181814.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Hagan Jr., J. E., Pollmann, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2017). Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(8), e0181814. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0181814</apa>
<ieee> J.E. Hagan Jr., D. Pollmann, and T. Schack, “Exploring temporal patterning of psychological skills usage during the week leading up to competition: Lessons for developing intervention programmes”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2017, : e0181814.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913280</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-15T07:45:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T12:36:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>