<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913587</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">59970828</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0997-5624</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fries</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9401158</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3296-9639</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wilde</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">170225</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1630-3263</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685601</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>12th Conference of the European Science Education Research Association (ESERA)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Fostering  students’  motivation  is  an  essential  characteristic  of  every  teaching  process. However, teachers  often  lack  practical  methods  to  support  it in  class.  There  are  several  approaches  to  foster  students’  motivation,  such  as  autonomy-supportive  teaching  behavior  (ASTB) based   on   Self-Determination    Theory   (Ryan   &amp;   Deci,   2017 ). Although   t hese approaches   are  at  disposal,  they   do  not  seem  to  find  their  way  into  practice.  Consequently,  efforts  are  needed  to  transfer  theoretical  and  empirical  findings  int o  the  classroom .  An  intervention for pre -service teachers providing theoretical and practical approaches to foster students’ motivation might be appropriate to deal with this situation. To   address   this   issue,   w e   conducted   a   pilot   study   with   58   science teacher   trainees (M age =25.18±3.79 years ;   M semester =7.78±1.23;   65%   female). The   experimental   group   consisted  of  35 teacher  trainees   that  took  part   in  an  intervention  about  ASTB. Teacher trainee s in the control group (n=23) did not participate in this intervention. We assessed the teacher trainees’ beliefs about the easy implementation and effectiveness of ASTB as well as their  future  intentions  to  apply  ASTB.  Further more ,  the  teacher  trainees’  t heoretical  and  practical knowledge were examined. The  r esults  reveal ed  significant  differences  concerning the teacher  trainees’  beliefs   about ASTB,  their  future  intentions  to  apply  ASTB  as  well  as  their  theoretical  and  practical  knowledge thereof   in  the  comparison  of  the  experimental  and  control  group. We  found  that  the t eacher trainees in the experimental group assumed ASTB to be more  effective and eas ier to implement than the teacher trainees in the control group after the intervention . Moreover , the teacher  trainees  in   the  experimental  group  showed  higher  scores  in  the  test  of  their  theoretical  and  practical  knowledge  and  stated  higher  intentions  to  apply  ASTB  than  the teacher trainees in  the control group after the intervention.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="grossmann_fries_wilde_autonomy-supportive teaching.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913587/2931377/grossmann_fries_wilde_autonomy-supportive teaching.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Dublin City University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Dublin</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Motivation</topic><topic>Teaching Practices</topic><topic>Initial Teacher Education (Pre- service)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-873769-84-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29135871</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1681-1691</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Großmann, N., Fries, S., Wilde, M.: Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13. p. 1681-1691. Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großmann, Nadine, Fries, Stefan, and Wilde, Matthias. 2018. “Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers”. In &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;, 1681-1691. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Großmann N, Fries S, Wilde M. Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. In:  &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University;  2018: 1681-1691.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Großmann, S.  Fries, and M.  Wilde, in &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1681-1691.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Großmann N, Fries S, Wilde M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13.  Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University:  1681-1691.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großmann, N., Fries, S. &amp;amp; Wilde, M. (2018). Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1681-1691). Gehalten auf der 12th Conference of the European Science Education Research Association (ESERA), Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Großmann, N., Fries, S., &amp;amp; Wilde, M. (2018). Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;, 1681-1691. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University.</apa>
<harvard1>Großmann, N., Fries, S., &amp;amp; Wilde, M., 2018. Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. In &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;.  Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University, pp. 1681-1691.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Großmann, S. Fries, and M. Wilde, “Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers”, &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;,  Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University, 2018,  pp.1681-1691.</ieee>
<default>Großmann N, Fries S, Wilde M (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University:  1681-1691.</default>
<wels>Großmann, N.; Fries, S.; Wilde, M. (2018): Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. In: Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University.  S. 1681-1691.</wels>
<mla>Großmann, Nadine, Fries, Stefan, and Wilde, Matthias. “Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers”. &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University, 2018. 1681-1691.</mla>
<frontiers>Großmann, N., Fries, S., and Wilde, M. (2018). “Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers” in &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt; (Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University), 1681-1691.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Großmann, N., Fries, S., &amp;amp; Wilde, M. (2018). Autonomy-supportive teaching behavior in science lessons - An intervention for pre-service teachers. &lt;em&gt;Electronic Proceedings of the ESERA 2017 Conference. Research, Practice and Collaboration in Science Education. Part 13&lt;/em&gt;, 1681-1691. Dublin, Ireland: Dublin City University.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913587</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-31T12:15:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-03-11T14:02:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>