<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913038</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Viktor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klassen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19636331</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olga</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blifernez-Klassen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7442431</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wibberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19653681</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winkler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">37406548</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Clemens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Posten</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olaf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22124</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9874-382X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4833667</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The fact that microalgae perform very efficiently photosynthetic conversion of sunlight into chemical energy has moved them into the focus of regenerative fuel research. Especially, biogas generation via anaerobic digestion is economically attractive due to the comparably simple apparative process technology and the theoretical possibility of converting the entire algal biomass to biogas/methane. In the last 60 years, intensive research on biogas production from microalgae biomass has revealed the microalgae as a rather challenging substrate for anaerobic digestion due to its high cell wall recalcitrance and unfavorable protein content, which requires additional pretreatment and co-fermentation strategies for sufficient fermentation. However, sustainable fuel generation requires the avoidance of cost/energy intensive biomass pretreatments to achieve positive net-energy process balance.
Results

Cultivation of microalgae in replete and limited nitrogen culture media conditions has led to the formation of protein-rich and low protein biomass, respectively, with the last being especially optimal for continuous fermentation. Anaerobic digestion of nitrogen limited biomass (low-N BM) was characterized by a stable process with low levels of inhibitory substances and resulted in extraordinary high biogas, and subsequently methane productivity [750 ± 15 and 462 ± 9 mLN g−1 volatile solids (VS) day−1, respectively], thus corresponding to biomass-to-methane energy conversion efficiency of up to 84%. The microbial community structure within this highly efficient digester revealed a clear predominance of the phyla Bacteroidetes and the family Methanosaetaceae among the Bacteria and Archaea, respectively. The fermentation of replete nitrogen biomass (replete-N BM), on the contrary, was demonstrated to be less productive (131 ± 33 mLN CH4 g−1VS day−1) and failed completely due to acidosis, caused through high ammonia/ammonium concentrations. The organization of the microbial community of the failed (replete-N) digester differed greatly compared to the stable low-N digester, presenting a clear shift to the phyla Firmicutes and Thermotogae, and the archaeal population shifted from acetoclastic to hydrogenotrophic methanogenesis.
Conclusions
The present study underlines the importance of cultivation conditions and shows the practicability of microalgae biomass usage as mono-substrate for highly efficient continuous fermentation to methane without any pretreatment with almost maximum practically achievable energy conversion efficiency (biomass to methane).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bmc.s13068-017-0871-4.kruse.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913038/2913109/bmc.s13068-017-0871-4.kruse.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Biofuel Biogas Methane Microalgae mono-substrate Nitrogen limitation Continuous anaerobic fermentation/digestion Maximal energy conversion efficiency Microbial community Ammonia/ammonium inhibition</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biotechnology for Biofuels</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1754-6834</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1754-6834</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28725266</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000405680400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29130384</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13068-017-0871-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2913130</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Klassen, O.  Blifernez-Klassen, D.  Wibberg, A.  Winkler, J.  Kalinowski, C.  Posten, and O.  Kruse, “Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 186.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Klassen, V., et al., 2017. Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, 10(1): 186.</harvard1>
<bio1>Klassen V, Blifernez-Klassen O, Wibberg D, Winkler A, Kalinowski J, Posten C, Kruse O (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass.&lt;br /&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels 10(1): 186.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klassen, V., Blifernez-Klassen, O., Wibberg, D., Winkler, A., Kalinowski, J., Posten, C., &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2017). Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 186. doi:10.1186/s13068-017-0871-4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Klassen, V.; Blifernez-Klassen, O.; Wibberg, D.; Winkler, A.; Kalinowski, J.; Posten, C.; Kruse, O. (2017): Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,10:(1):186</wels>
<ieee> V. Klassen, et al., “Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2017, : 186.</ieee>
<apa>Klassen, V., Blifernez-Klassen, O., Wibberg, D., Winkler, A., Kalinowski, J., Posten, C., &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2017). Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 186. doi:10.1186/s13068-017-0871-4</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klassen, V., Blifernez-Klassen, O., Wibberg, D., Winkler, A., Kalinowski, J., Posten, C. &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2017). Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1): 186. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13068-017-0871-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Klassen, V., Blifernez-Klassen, O., Wibberg, D., Winkler, A., Kalinowski, J., Posten, C., and Kruse, O. (2017). Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 10:186.</frontiers>
<ama>Klassen V, Blifernez-Klassen O, Wibberg D, et al. Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;10(1): 186.</ama>
<default>Klassen V, Blifernez-Klassen O, Wibberg D, Winkler A, Kalinowski J, Posten C, Kruse O (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 10(1): 186.</default>
<mla>Klassen, Viktor, Blifernez-Klassen, Olga, Wibberg, Daniel, Winkler, Anika, Kalinowski, Jörn, Posten, Clemens, and Kruse, Olaf. “Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 10.1 (2017): 186.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klassen, Viktor, Blifernez-Klassen, Olga, Wibberg, Daniel, Winkler, Anika, Kalinowski, Jörn, Posten, Clemens, and Kruse, Olaf. 2017. “Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology for Biofuels&lt;/em&gt; 10 (1): 186.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Klassen, V., Blifernez-Klassen, O., Wibberg, D., Winkler, A., Kalinowski, J., Posten, C., Kruse, O.: Highly efficient methane generation from untreated microalgae biomass. Biotechnology for Biofuels. 10, : 186 (2017).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913038</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-07-26T23:53:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>