<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913711</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soufian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jebbara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">61955542</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4483-0933</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="emnlp2017.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913711/2913712/emnlp2017.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Copenhagen, Denmark</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29137116</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> S. Jebbara and P. Cimiano, “Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;, Association for Computational Linguistics, 2017.</ieee>
<harvard1>Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2017. Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;.  Association for Computational Linguistics.</harvard1>
<apa>Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt; Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<wels>Jebbara, S.; Cimiano, P. (2017): Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. In: Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP. Association for Computational Linguistics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, S., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt; Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics, 2017.</mla>
<frontiers>Jebbara, S., and Cimiano, P. (2017). “Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt; (Association for Computational Linguistics).</frontiers>
<default>Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP. Association for Computational Linguistics.</default>
<aps> S.  Jebbara and P.  Cimiano, Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt; (Association for Computational Linguistics, 2017).</aps>
<ama>Jebbara S, Cimiano P. Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics;  2017.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, Soufian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2017. “Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;. Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Jebbara, S., Cimiano, P.: Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP.  Association for Computational Linguistics (2017).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Jebbara, S. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2017). Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Jebbara S, Cimiano P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Improving Opinion-Target Extraction with Character-Level Word Embeddings. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP.  Association for Computational Linguistics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Jebbara, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the First Workshop on Subword and Character Level Models in NLP&lt;/em&gt;, Association For Computational Linguistics, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913711</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-09-11T09:51:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>