<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913110</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kulis-Horn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17676795</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42238</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9722-4435</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Persicke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177004</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The eighth step of l-histidine biosynthesis is carried out by an enzyme called histidinol-phosphate phosphatase (HolPase). Three unrelated HolPase families are known so far. Two of them are well studied: HAD-type HolPases known from Gammaproteobacteria like Escherichia coli or Salmonella enterica and PHP-type HolPases known from yeast and Firmicutes like Bacillus subtilis. However, the third family of HolPases, the inositol monophosphatase (IMPase)-like HolPases, present in Actinobacteria like Corynebacterium glutamicum (HisN) and plants, are poorly characterized. Moreover, there exist several IMPase-like proteins in bacteria (e.g. CysQ, ImpA, and SuhB) which are very similar to HisN but most likely do not participate in l-histidine biosynthesis.
Results

Deletion of hisN, the gene encoding the IMPase-like HolPase in C. glutamicum, does not result in complete l-histidine auxotrophy. Out of four hisN homologs present in the genome of C. glutamicum (impA, suhB, cysQ, and cg0911), only cg0911 encodes an enzyme with HolPase activity. The enzymatic properties of HisN and Cg0911 were determined, delivering the first available kinetic data for IMPase-like HolPases.

Additionally, we analyzed the amino acid sequences of potential HisN, ImpA, SuhB, CysQ and Cg0911 orthologs from bacteria and identified six conserved sequence motifs for each group of orthologs. Mutational studies confirmed the importance of a highly conserved aspartate residue accompanied by several aromatic amino acid residues present in motif 5 for HolPase activity. Several bacterial proteins containing all identified HolPase motifs, but showing only moderate sequence similarity to HisN from C. glutamicum, were experimentally confirmed as IMPase-like HolPases, demonstrating the value of the identified motifs. Based on the confirmed IMPase-like HolPases two profile Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) were build using an iterative approach. These HMMs allow the fast, reliable detection and differentiation of the two paralog groups from each other and other IMPases.
Conclusion

The kinetic data obtained for HisN from C. glutamicum, as an example for an IMPase-like HolPases, shows remarkable differences in enzyme properties as compared to HAD- or PHP-type HolPases. The six sequence motifs and the HMMs presented in this study can be used to reliably differentiate between IMPase-like HolPases and IMPase-like proteins with no such activity, with the potential to enhance current and future genome annotations. A phylogenetic analysis reveals that IMPase-like HolPases are not only present in Actinobacteria and plant but can be found in further bacterial phyla, including, among others, Proteobacteria, Chlorobi and Planctomycetes.
Keywords</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="bmc.s12866-017-1069-4.persicke.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913110/2913111/bmc.s12866-017-1069-4.persicke.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>HisN Cg0911 Histidinol-phosphate phosphatase (HolPase) Inositol monophosphatase (IMPase)-like Corynebacterium glutamicum Kinetic data Sequence motifs Phylogenetic analysis</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Microbiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2180</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">28720084</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000405787400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29131106</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12866-017-1069-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>17</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kulis-Horn R, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Persicke M. Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;17(1): 161.</ama>
<frontiers>Kulis-Horn, R., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., and Persicke, M. (2017). Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 17:161.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kulis-Horn, R., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J. &amp;amp; Persicke, M. (2017). Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(1): 161. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s12866-017-1069-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Kulis-Horn, R., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Persicke, M. (2017). Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(1), 161. doi:10.1186/s12866-017-1069-4</apa>
<ieee> R. Kulis-Horn, et al., “Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 17, 2017, : 161.</ieee>
<wels>Kulis-Horn, R.; Rückert, C.; Kalinowski, J.; Persicke, M. (2017): Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,17:(1):161</wels>
<bio1>Kulis-Horn R, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Persicke M (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Microbiology 17(1): 161.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kulis-Horn, R., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Persicke, M. (2017). Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(1), 161. doi:10.1186/s12866-017-1069-4&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kulis-Horn, R., et al., 2017. Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, 17(1): 161.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Kulis-Horn, C.  Rückert, J.  Kalinowski, and M.  Persicke, “Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;, : 161.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Kulis-Horn, R., Rückert, C., Kalinowski, J., Persicke, M.: Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond. BMC Microbiology. 17, : 161 (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kulis-Horn, Robert, Rückert, Christian, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Persicke, Marcus. 2017. “Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 17 (1): 161.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kulis-Horn, Robert, Rückert, Christian, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Persicke, Marcus. “Sequence-based identification of inositol monophosphatase-like histidinol-phosphate phosphatases (HisN) in Corynebacterium glutamicum, Actinobacteria, and beyond”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 17.1 (2017): 161.</mla>
<default>Kulis-Horn R, Rückert C, Kalinowski J, Persicke M (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 17(1): 161.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913110</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-02T13:34:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>