<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2913138</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Renner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">39272387</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9640-8291</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>16th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR)</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">One area in which glasses-based augmented reality (AR) is successfully applied in industry is order picking in logistics (pick-byvision). Here, the almost hands-free operation and the direct integration into the digital workflow provided by augmented reality glasses are direct advantages.
A common non-AR guidance technique for order picking is pickby-light. This is an efficient approach for single users and low numbers of alternative targets. AR glasses have the potential to overcome these limitations. However, making a grounded decision on the specific AR device and the particular guidance techniques to choose for a specific scenario is difficult, given the diversity of device characteristics and the lack of experience with smart glasses
in industry at larger scale.
The contributions of the paper are twofold. First, we present a virtual reality (VR) simulation approach to ground design decisions for AR-based solutions and apply it to the scenario of order picking. Second, we present results from a simulator study with implemented simulations for monocular and binocular head-mounted displays and compared existing techniques for attention guiding with our own SWave approach and the integration of eye tracking.
Our results show clear benefits for the use of pick-by-vision compared to pick-by-light. In addition to that, we can show that binocular AR solutions outperform monocular ones in the attention guiding task.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ismar2017-attentionguidance-with_copyright.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2913138/2919607/ismar2017-attentionguidance-with_copyright.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Nantes</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Augmented Reality</topic><topic>Order Picking</topic><topic>Virtual Reality Simulation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ISMAR 2017</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29131389</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2017.59</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Renner, P.; Pfeiffer, T. (2017): [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. In: ISMAR 2017. Nantes: IEEE.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Renner, and T.  Pfeiffer, in &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Nantes, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Renner P, Pfeiffer T (2017) &lt;br /&gt;[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ISMAR 2017.  Nantes: IEEE.</bio1>
<harvard1>Renner, P., &amp;amp; Pfeiffer, T., 2017. [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. In &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;.  Nantes: IEEE.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Renner, P., &amp;amp; Pfeiffer, T. (2017). [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt; Nantes: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2017.59&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Renner, P., and Pfeiffer, T. (2017). “[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study” in &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt; (Nantes: IEEE).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Renner, P. &amp;amp; Pfeiffer, T. (2017). [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 16th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR), Nantes: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2017.59.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Renner P, Pfeiffer T. [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. In:  &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Nantes: IEEE;  2017.</ama>
<ieee> P. Renner and T. Pfeiffer, “[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study”, &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;,  Nantes: IEEE, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Renner, P., &amp;amp; Pfeiffer, T. (2017). [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt; Nantes: IEEE. doi:10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2017.59</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Renner, Patrick, and Pfeiffer, Thies. 2017. “[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study”. In &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Nantes: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Renner, P., Pfeiffer, T.: [POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study. ISMAR 2017.  IEEE, Nantes (2017).</lncs>
<default>Renner P, Pfeiffer T (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ISMAR 2017. Nantes: IEEE.</default>
<mla>Renner, Patrick, and Pfeiffer, Thies. “[POSTER]  Augmented Reality Assistance in the Central Field-of-View Outperforms Peripheral Displays for Order Picking: Results from a Virtual Reality Simulation Study”. &lt;em&gt;ISMAR 2017&lt;/em&gt;. Nantes: IEEE, 2017.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2913138</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-08-04T18:43:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>