<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2914935</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ting</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Han</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60454102</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4908-1337</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Casey</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kennington</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlangen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20699903</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2686-6887</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">26374437</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>The thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="aaai18.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2914935/2915103/aaai18.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">New Orleans</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29149356</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Han, T., Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D., 2018. Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;.  New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.</harvard1>
<bio1>Han T, Kennington C, Schlangen D (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18).  New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Han, T., Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2018). Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt; New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Han, C.  Kennington, and D.  Schlangen, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;, The Association For The Advancement Of Artificial Intelligence, New Orleans, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Han, T.; Kennington, C.; Schlangen, D. (2018): Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. In: Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18). New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.</wels>
<apa>Han, T., Kennington, C., &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2018). Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt; New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.</apa>
<ieee> T. Han, C. Kennington, and D. Schlangen, “Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;,  New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence, 2018.</ieee>
<ama>Han T, Kennington C, Schlangen D. Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;. New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence;  2018.</ama>
<frontiers>Han, T., Kennington, C., and Schlangen, D. (2018). “Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt; (New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Han, T., Kennington, C. &amp;amp; Schlangen, D. (2018). Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der The thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18), New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Han, Ting, Kennington, Casey, and Schlangen, David. “Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;. New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence, 2018.</mla>
<default>Han T, Kennington C, Schlangen D (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18). New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.</default>
<lncs> Han, T., Kennington, C., Schlangen, D.: Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions. Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18).  The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence, New Orleans (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Han, Ting, Kennington, Casey, and Schlangen, David. 2018. “Placing Objects in Gesture Space: Toward Real-Time Understanding of Spatial Descriptions”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence (AAAI18)&lt;/em&gt;. New Orleans: The association for the advancement of artificial intelligence.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2914935</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-08T05:54:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>