<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2914141</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Witali</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aswolinskiy</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53238236</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Real-world machine learning applications must be able to adapt to systematic changes in the data, e.g. a new subject or sensor displacement. This can be seen as a form of transfer learning, where the goal is to reuse the old (source) model by adapting the new (target) data. This is a challenging task, if no labels for the target data are available. Here, we propose to use the structure of the source and target data to find a transformation from the source to target space in an unsupervised manner. Our preliminary experiments on multivariate time series data show the feasibility of the approach, but also its limits.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="unsupervised time series transfer via self-predictive modelling.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2914141/2914955/unsupervised time series transfer via self-predictive modelling.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld, CITEC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Basel</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>domain adaptation</topic><topic>transductive transfer lerning</topic><topic>time series classification</topic><topic>predictive modelling</topic><topic>echo state networks</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1865-3960</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29141415</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03/2017</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Aswolinskiy, W., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2017. Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. no.03/2017  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.</harvard1>
<ieee> W. Aswolinskiy and B. Hammer, “Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, vol. 03/2017,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Aswolinskiy, W., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, &lt;em&gt;03/2017&lt;/em&gt; Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.</apa>
<mla>Aswolinskiy, Witali, and Hammer, Barbara. “Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC, 2017.Vol. 03/2017. Machine Learning Reports.</mla>
<frontiers>Aswolinskiy, W., and Hammer, B. (2017). “Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt; Machine Learning Reports, vol. 03/2017, (Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aswolinskiy, W., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;, Machine Learning Reports, &lt;em&gt;03/2017&lt;/em&gt; Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Aswolinskiy, W.; Hammer, B. (2017): Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC. (Machine Learning Reports, 03/2017).</wels>
<default>Aswolinskiy W, Hammer B (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2). Machine Learning Reports, 03/2017.  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.</default>
<ama>Aswolinskiy W, Hammer B. Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;. Machine Learning Reports. Vol 03/2017. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC;  2017.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aswolinskiy, Witali, and Hammer, Barbara. 2017. “Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03/2017. Machine Learning Reports. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Aswolinskiy, W., Hammer, B.: Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2). Machine Learning Reports. 03/2017,  Universität Bielefeld, CITEC, Bielefeld (2017).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aswolinskiy, W. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results (Machine Learning Reports). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2), Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Aswolinskiy, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2)&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Citec, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Aswolinskiy W, Hammer B (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Unsupervised Transfer Learning for Time Series via Self-Predictive Modelling - First Results. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Workshop on New Challenges in Neural Computation (NC2).  Machine Learning Reports, 03/2017. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, CITEC.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2914141</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-09-25T19:40:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>