<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2914589</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Opfermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ramin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Yaghoubzadeh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10271225</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Dialog modeling of making suggestions in human-agent interaction is a challenge due to the socially delicate nature of a suggestion and ensuing interactional negotiations. A basic first dialog model for making suggestions was tested in the context of schedule management assistance by an embodied conversational agent with elderly and mildly cognitively impaired persons. Analysis showed that users responded according to human social structures with most response types bearing potential challenges concerning the system's language understanding and the users' intention interpretation:next to explicit answers, users produced implicit versions for acceptance or resistance and further requests for information or modifications. Thus, an enhanced dialog model with a newly added clarification sequence and a new multi-conditional entry sequence was tested in a second study with the autonomous system. Initial observations show a promising performance of the dialog model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Opfermann-etal-2017-HAI.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2914589/2914590/Opfermann-etal-2017-HAI.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>ACM Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9781450351133</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29145893</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1145/3125739.3125752</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">161–170</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Opfermann C, Pitsch K, Yaghoubzadeh R, Kopp S (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction. ACM Press:  161–170.</default>
<mla>Opfermann, Christiane, Pitsch, Karola, Yaghoubzadeh, Ramin, and Kopp, Stefan. “The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. ACM Press, 2017. 161–170.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Opfermann, Christiane, Pitsch, Karola, Yaghoubzadeh, Ramin, and Kopp, Stefan. 2017. “The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 161–170. ACM Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Yaghoubzadeh, R., Kopp, S.: The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction. p. 161–170. ACM Press (2017).</lncs>
<ieee> C. Opfermann, et al., “The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, ACM Press, 2017,  pp.161–170.</ieee>
<apa>Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Yaghoubzadeh, R., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 161–170. ACM Press. doi:10.1145/3125739.3125752</apa>
<frontiers>Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Yaghoubzadeh, R., and Kopp, S. (2017). “The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (ACM Press), 161–170.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Yaghoubzadeh, R. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 161–170). Gehalten auf der 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction, ACM Press. doi:10.1145/3125739.3125752.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Opfermann C, Pitsch K, Yaghoubzadeh R, Kopp S. The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. ACM Press;  2017: 161–170.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Opfermann, K.  Pitsch, R.  Yaghoubzadeh, and S.  Kopp, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Acm Press, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 161–170.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Yaghoubzadeh, R., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2017). The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 161–170. ACM Press. doi:10.1145/3125739.3125752&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Opfermann C, Pitsch K, Yaghoubzadeh R, Kopp S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction.  ACM Press:  161–170.</bio1>
<harvard1>Opfermann, C., et al., 2017. The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction&lt;/em&gt;.  ACM Press, pp. 161–170.</harvard1>
<wels>Opfermann, C.; Pitsch, K.; Yaghoubzadeh, R.; Kopp, S. (2017): The Communicative Activity of “Making Suggestions” as an Interactional Process: Towards a Dialog Model for HAI. In: Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Human Agent Interaction. ACM Press.  S. 161–170.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2914589</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-10-19T13:14:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>