<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2914954</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46445464</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tino</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Köster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">13028045</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3984-9813</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nolte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51428492</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weinholdt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lewinski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">39725340</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ivo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grosse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dorothee</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Staiger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81014</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Functions for RNA-binding proteins in orchestrating plant development and environmental responses are well established. However, the lack of a genome-wide view of their in vivo binding targets and binding landscapes represents a gap in understanding the mode of action of plant RNA-binding proteins. Here, we adapt individual nucleotide resolution crosslinking and immunoprecipitation (iCLIP) genome-wide to determine the binding repertoire of the circadian clock-regulated Arabidopsis thaliana glycine-rich RNA-binding protein AtGRP7.
Results

iCLIP identifies 858 transcripts with significantly enriched crosslink sites in plants expressing AtGRP7-GFP that are absent in plants expressing an RNA-binding-dead AtGRP7 variant or GFP alone. To independently validate the targets, we performed RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP)-sequencing of AtGRP7-GFP plants subjected to formaldehyde fixation. Of the iCLIP targets, 452 were also identified by RIP-seq and represent a set of high-confidence binders. AtGRP7 can bind to all transcript regions, with a preference for 3′ untranslated regions. In the vicinity of crosslink sites, U/C-rich motifs are overrepresented. Cross-referencing the targets against transcriptome changes in AtGRP7 loss-of-function mutants or AtGRP7-overexpressing plants reveals a predominantly negative effect of AtGRP7 on its targets. In particular, elevated AtGRP7 levels lead to damping of circadian oscillations of transcripts, including DORMANCY/AUXIN ASSOCIATED FAMILY PROTEIN2 and CCR-LIKE. Furthermore, several targets show changes in alternative splicing or polyadenylation in response to altered AtGRP7 levels.
Conclusions

We have established iCLIP for plants to identify target transcripts of the RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. This paves the way to investigate the dynamics of posttranscriptional networks in response to exogenous and endogenous cues.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s13059-017-1332-x.staiger.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2914954/2917471/s13059-017-1332-x.staiger.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Circadian rhythm</topic><topic>Individual nucleotide resolution crosslinking and immunoprecipitation (iCLIP)</topic><topic>RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP)</topic><topic>RNA-binding protein</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Genome Biology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1474-760X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29084609</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000413970400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29149546</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13059-017-1332-x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Meyer K, Köster T, Nolte C, Weinholdt C, Lewinski M, Grosse I, Staiger D (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7.&lt;br /&gt;Genome Biology 18(1): 204.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Meyer, T.  Köster, C.  Nolte, C.  Weinholdt, M.  Lewinski, I.  Grosse, and D.  Staiger, “Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7”, &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 204.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer, K., Köster, T., Nolte, C., Weinholdt, C., Lewinski, M., Grosse, I. &amp;amp; Staiger, D. (2017). Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1): 204. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13059-017-1332-x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer, Katja, Köster, Tino, Nolte, Christine, Weinholdt, Claus, Lewinski, Martin, Grosse, Ivo, and Staiger, Dorothee. 2017. “Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7”. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt; 18 (1): 204.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Meyer, K., Köster, T., Nolte, C., Weinholdt, C., Lewinski, M., Grosse, I., Staiger, D.: Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. Genome Biology. 18, : 204 (2017).</lncs>
<ama>Meyer K, Köster T, Nolte C, et al. Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;18(1): 204.</ama>
<default>Meyer K, Köster T, Nolte C, Weinholdt C, Lewinski M, Grosse I, Staiger D (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt; 18(1): 204.</default>
<wels>Meyer, K.; Köster, T.; Nolte, C.; Weinholdt, C.; Lewinski, M.; Grosse, I.; Staiger, D. (2017): Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7 &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;,18:(1):204</wels>
<mla>Meyer, Katja, Köster, Tino, Nolte, Christine, Weinholdt, Claus, Lewinski, Martin, Grosse, Ivo, and Staiger, Dorothee. “Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7”. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt; 18.1 (2017): 204.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer, K., Köster, T., Nolte, C., Weinholdt, C., Lewinski, M., Grosse, I., &amp;amp; Staiger, D. (2017). Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1), 204. doi:10.1186/s13059-017-1332-x&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Meyer, K., Köster, T., Nolte, C., Weinholdt, C., Lewinski, M., Grosse, I., and Staiger, D. (2017). Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt; 18:204.</frontiers>
<apa>Meyer, K., Köster, T., Nolte, C., Weinholdt, C., Lewinski, M., Grosse, I., &amp;amp; Staiger, D. (2017). Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1), 204. doi:10.1186/s13059-017-1332-x</apa>
<ieee> K. Meyer, et al., “Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7”, &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2017, : 204.</ieee>
<harvard1>Meyer, K., et al., 2017. Adaptation of iCLIP to plants determines the binding landscape of the clock-regulated RNA-binding protein AtGRP7. &lt;em&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 18(1): 204.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2914954</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-08T16:56:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>