<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2914374</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aleksandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cwiek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">69555242</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wlodarczak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17662039</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mattias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heldner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jardar Eggesbø</namePart><namePart type="family">Abrahamsen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jacques</namePart><namePart type="family">Koreman</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wim A.</namePart><namePart type="family">van Dommelen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Nordic Prosody</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Breathing is fundamental for living and speech, and it has been a subject of linguistic research for years. Recently, there has been a renewed interest in tackling the question of possible communicative functions of breathing (e.g. Rochet-Capellan &amp; Fuchs, 2014; Aare, Włodarczak &amp; Heldner, 2014; Włodarczak &amp; Heldner, 2015; Włodarczak, Heldner, &amp; Edlund, 2015). The present study set out to determine acoustic markedness and communicative functions of pauses accompanied and non-accompanied by breathing. We hypothesised that an articulatory reset occurring in breathing pauses and an articulatory freeze in non-breathing pauses differentiates between the two types. A production experiment was conducted and some evidence in favour of such a phenomenon was found. Namely, in case of non-breathing pauses, we observed more coarticulation evidenced by a more frequent omission of plosive releases. Our findings thus give some evidence in favour of the communicative function of breathing.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Cwiek_Wlodarczak_Heldner_Wagner_2016.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2914374/2914375/Cwiek_Wlodarczak_Heldner_Wagner_2016.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Peter Lang Publishing Group</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Trondheim</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-631-72352-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29143743</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">83-91</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Cwiek, A., Wlodarczak, M., Heldner, M., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2017). Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In J. E.  Abrahamsen, J.  Koreman, &amp;amp; W. A.  van Dommelen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 83-91). Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group.</apa>
<harvard1>Cwiek, A., et al., 2017. Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In J. E.  Abrahamsen, J.  Koreman, &amp;amp; W. A.  van Dommelen, eds. &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group, pp. 83-91.</harvard1>
<ieee> A. Cwiek, et al., “Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals”, &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;, J.E. Abrahamsen, J. Koreman, and W.A. van Dommelen, eds.,  Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group, 2017,  pp.83-91.</ieee>
<default>Cwiek A, Wlodarczak M, Heldner M, Wagner P (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016. Abrahamsen JE, Koreman J, van Dommelen WA (Eds);  Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group:  83-91.</default>
<wels>Cwiek, A.; Wlodarczak, M.; Heldner, M.; Wagner, P. (2017): Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In: Jardar Eggesbø Abrahamsen; Jacques Koreman; Wim A. van Dommelen (Hrsg.):  Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016. Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group.  S. 83-91.</wels>
<mla>Cwiek, Aleksandra, Wlodarczak, Marcin, Heldner, Mattias, and Wagner, Petra. “Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals”. &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jardar Eggesbø Abrahamsen, Jacques Koreman, and Wim A. van Dommelen. Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group, 2017. 83-91.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cwiek, A., Wlodarczak, M., Heldner, M., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2017). Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In J. E.  Abrahamsen, J.  Koreman, &amp;amp; W. A.  van Dommelen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 83-91). Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Cwiek, A., Wlodarczak, M., Heldner, M., and Wagner, P. (2017). “Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals” in &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;, Abrahamsen, J. E., Koreman, J., and van Dommelen, W. A. eds. (Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group), 83-91.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cwiek, Aleksandra, Wlodarczak, Marcin, Heldner, Mattias, and Wagner, Petra. 2017. “Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals”. In &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jardar Eggesbø Abrahamsen, Jacques Koreman, and Wim A. van Dommelen, 83-91. Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Cwiek, A., Wlodarczak, M., Heldner, M., Wagner, P.: Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In: Abrahamsen, J.E., Koreman, J., and van Dommelen, W.A. (eds.) Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016. p. 83-91. Peter Lang Publishing Group, Frankfurt a.M. (2017).</lncs>
<ama>Cwiek A, Wlodarczak M, Heldner M, Wagner P. Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In: Abrahamsen JE, Koreman J, van Dommelen WA, eds. &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt;. Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group;  2017: 83-91.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Cwiek, M.  Wlodarczak, M.  Heldner, and P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.E. Abrahamsen, J. Koreman, W.A. van Dommelen), Peter Lang Publishing Group, Frankfurt a.M., &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 83-91.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Cwiek A, Wlodarczak M, Heldner M, Wagner P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016. Abrahamsen JE, Koreman J, van Dommelen WA (Eds); Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group:  83-91.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Cwiek, A., Wlodarczak, M., Heldner, M. &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2017). Acoustics and discourse function of two types of breathing signals. In J.E. Abrahamsen, J. Koreman &amp;amp; W.A. van Dommelen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Nordic Prosody: Proceedings of the XIIth Conference, Trondheim 2016&lt;/em&gt; (S. 83-91). Gehalten auf der Nordic Prosody, Frankfurt a.M.: Peter Lang Publishing Group.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2914374</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-10-03T21:20:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>