<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915398</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6471004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8865-7466</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neugart</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies the effectiveness of different types of cohesion
policies with respect to convergence of regions. A two-region agentbased
macroeconomic model is used to analyze short-, medium- and
long-term effects of policies improving human capital and fostering
adoption of technologies in lagging regions. With fully integrated labor
markets the human capital policy positively affects the economically
stronger region but reduces production in the targeted weaker region.
Subsidies for high technology investment in the weaker region have a
positive local output effect and a negative effect on the neighboring
region, thereby fostering convergence. When labor markets are not
integrated both policies support convergence.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_09_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915398/2915399/wpaper_09_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cohesion policies</topic><topic>technology adoption</topic><topic>skill complementarity</topic><topic>agent-based model</topic><topic>regional economics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29153983</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915398</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>09-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">44</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 09-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, M. &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 09-2013.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, M. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 09-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Harting, P., Neugart, M.: Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ieee> H. Dawid, P. Harting, and M. Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 09-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915398</apa>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., Harting, P., and Neugart, M. (2013). Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 09-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P. &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915398.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M. &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 09-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, P.  Harting, and M.  Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.09-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 09-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915398&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Harting, P.; Neugart, M. (2013): Spatial labor market frictions and economic convergence: policy implications from a heterogeneous agent model. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915398</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-30T13:53:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>