<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915142</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:580</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Urte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlueter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Colmsee</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Scholz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bräutigam</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">112481313</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5309-0527</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas P. M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zellerhoff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bucher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holger</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fahnenstich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sonnewald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">112482126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Abiotic stress causes disturbances in the cellular homeostasis. Re-adjustment of balance in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus metabolism therefore plays a central role in stress adaptation. However, it is currently unknown which parts of the primary cell metabolism follow common patterns under different stress conditions and which represent specific responses. Results: To address these questions, changes in transcriptome, metabolome and ionome were analyzed in maize source leaves from plants suffering low temperature, low nitrogen (N) and low phosphorus (P) stress. The selection of maize as study object provided data directly from an important crop species and the so far underexplored C-4 metabolism. Growth retardation was comparable under all tested stress conditions. The only primary metabolic pathway responding similar to all stresses was nitrate assimilation, which was down-regulated. The largest group of commonly regulated transcripts followed the expression pattern: down under low temperature and low N, but up under low P. Several members of this transcript cluster could be connected to P metabolism and correlated negatively to different phosphate concentration in the leaf tissue. Accumulation of starch under low temperature and low N stress, but decrease in starch levels under low P conditions indicated that only low P treated leaves suffered carbon starvation. Conclusions: Maize employs very different strategies to manage N and P metabolism under stress. While nitrate assimilation was regulated depending on demand by growth processes, phosphate concentrations changed depending on availability, thus building up reserves under excess conditions. Carbon and energy metabolism of the C-4 maize leaves were particularly sensitive to P starvation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Schlüter_et_al-2013-BMC_Genomics.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915142/2915958/Schlüter_et_al-2013-BMC_Genomics.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Abiotic stress</topic><topic>Nutrient stress</topic><topic>Transcriptome</topic><topic>Metabolome</topic><topic>Ionome</topic><topic>Maize</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Genomics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2164</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">23822863</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000321860500001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29151421</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-14-442</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Schlueter U, Colmsee C, Scholz U, Bräutigam A, Weber APM, Zellerhoff N, Bucher M, Fahnenstich H, Sonnewald U (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14(1): 442.</default>
<mla>Schlueter, Urte, Colmsee, Christian, Scholz, Uwe, Bräutigam, Andrea, Weber, Andreas P. M., Zellerhoff, Nina, Bucher, Marcel, Fahnenstich, Holger, and Sonnewald, Uwe. “Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14.1 (2013): 442.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlueter, Urte, Colmsee, Christian, Scholz, Uwe, Bräutigam, Andrea, Weber, Andreas P. M., Zellerhoff, Nina, Bucher, Marcel, Fahnenstich, Holger, and Sonnewald, Uwe. 2013. “Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14 (1): 442.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schlueter, U., Colmsee, C., Scholz, U., Bräutigam, A., Weber, A.P.M., Zellerhoff, N., Bucher, M., Fahnenstich, H., Sonnewald, U.: Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. BMC Genomics. 14, : 442 (2013).</lncs>
<ieee> U. Schlueter, et al., “Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 14, 2013, : 442.</ieee>
<apa>Schlueter, U., Colmsee, C., Scholz, U., Bräutigam, A., Weber, A. P. M., Zellerhoff, N., Bucher, M., et al. (2013). Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 442. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-442</apa>
<frontiers>Schlueter, U., Colmsee, C., Scholz, U., Bräutigam, A., Weber, A. P. M., Zellerhoff, N., Bucher, M., Fahnenstich, H., and Sonnewald, U. (2013). Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 14:442.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlueter, U., Colmsee, C., Scholz, U., Bräutigam, A., Weber, A.P.M., Zellerhoff, N., Bucher, M., Fahnenstich, H. &amp;amp; Sonnewald, U. (2013). Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1): 442. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-442.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schlueter U, Colmsee C, Scholz U, et al. Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;. 2013;14(1): 442.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Schlueter, C.  Colmsee, U.  Scholz, A.  Bräutigam, A. P. M.  Weber, N.  Zellerhoff, M.  Bucher, H.  Fahnenstich, and U.  Sonnewald, “Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;, : 442.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schlueter U, Colmsee C, Scholz U, Bräutigam A, Weber APM, Zellerhoff N, Bucher M, Fahnenstich H, Sonnewald U (2013) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 14(1): 442.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schlueter, U., Colmsee, C., Scholz, U., Bräutigam, A., Weber, A. P. M., Zellerhoff, N., Bucher, M., et al. (2013). Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(1), 442. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-14-442&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Schlueter, U., et al., 2013. Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, 14(1): 442.</harvard1>
<wels>Schlueter, U.; Colmsee, C.; Scholz, U.; Bräutigam, A.; Weber, A. P. M.; Zellerhoff, N.; Bucher, M.; Fahnenstich, H.; Sonnewald, U. (2013): Adaptation of maize source leaf metabolism to stress related disturbances in carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus balance &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,14:(1):442</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915142</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-22T09:24:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>