<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915136</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:580</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bräutigam</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">112481313</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5309-0527</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schliesky</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Canan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Külahoglu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Colin P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Osborne</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas P. M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">112482126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">C-4 photosynthesis affords higher photosynthetic carbon conversion efficiency than C-3 photosynthesis and it therefore represents an attractive target for engineering efforts aiming to improve crop productivity. To this end, blueprints are required that reflect C-4 metabolism as closely as possible. Such blueprints have been derived from comparative transcriptome analyses of C-3 species with related C-4 species belonging to the NAD-malic enzyme (NAD-ME) and NADP-ME subgroups of C-4 photosynthesis. However, a comparison between C-3 and the phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase (PEP-CK) subtype of C-4 photosynthesis is still missing. An integrative analysis of all three C-4 subtypes has also not been possible to date, since no comparison has been available for closely related C-3 and PEP-CK C-4 species. To generate the data, the guinea grass Megathyrsus maximus, which represents a PEP-CK species, was analysed in comparison with a closely related C-3 sister species, Dichanthelium clandestinum, and with publicly available sets of RNA-Seq data from C-4 species belonging to the NAD-ME and NADP-ME subgroups. The data indicate that the core C-4 cycle of the PEP-CK grass M. maximus is quite similar to that of NAD-ME species with only a few exceptions, such as the subcellular location of transfer acid production and the degree and pattern of up-regulation of genes encoding C-4 enzymes. One additional mitochondrial transporter protein was associated with the core cycle. The broad comparison identified sucrose and starch synthesis, as well as the prevention of leakage of C-4 cycle intermediates to other metabolic pathways, as critical components of C-4 metabolism. Estimation of intercellular transport fluxes indicated that flux between cells is increased by at least two orders of magnitude in C-4 species compared with C-3 species. In contrast to NAD-ME and NADP-ME species, the transcription of photosynthetic electron transfer proteins was unchanged in PEP-CK. In summary, the PEP-CK blueprint of M. maximus appears to be simpler than those of NAD-ME and NADP-ME plants.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bräutigam_et_al-2014-Journal_of_Experimental_Botany.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915136/2915868/Bräutigam_et_al-2014-Journal_of_Experimental_Botany.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>C-4 photosynthesis</topic><topic>Dichanthelium clandestinum</topic><topic>Megathyrsus maximus</topic><topic>PEP-CK</topic><topic>RNA-Seq</topic><topic>transcriptomics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Experimental Botany</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0022-0957</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1460-2431</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24642845</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000339953400022</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29151362</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/jxb/eru100</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>65</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>13</number></detail><extent unit="pages">3579-3593</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Bräutigam, S.  Schliesky, C.  Külahoglu, C. P.  Osborne, and A. P. M.  Weber, “Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;65&lt;/em&gt;, 3579-3593.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bräutigam, A., Schliesky, S., Külahoglu, C., Osborne, C. P., &amp;amp; Weber, A. P. M. (2014). Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;65&lt;/em&gt;(13), 3579-3593. doi:10.1093/jxb/eru100&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bräutigam, A., et al., 2014. Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;, 65(13), p 3579-3593.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bräutigam A, Schliesky S, Külahoglu C, Osborne CP, Weber APM (2014) &lt;br /&gt;Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany 65(13): 3579-3593.</bio1>
<wels>Bräutigam, A.; Schliesky, S.; Külahoglu, C.; Osborne, C. P.; Weber, A. P. M. (2014): Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;,65:(13): 3579-3593.</wels>
<ieee> A. Bräutigam, et al., “Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 65, 2014,  pp. 3579-3593.</ieee>
<apa>Bräutigam, A., Schliesky, S., Külahoglu, C., Osborne, C. P., &amp;amp; Weber, A. P. M. (2014). Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;65&lt;/em&gt;(13), 3579-3593. doi:10.1093/jxb/eru100</apa>
<frontiers>Bräutigam, A., Schliesky, S., Külahoglu, C., Osborne, C. P., and Weber, A. P. M. (2014). Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt; 65, 3579-3593.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bräutigam, A., Schliesky, S., Külahoglu, C., Osborne, C.P. &amp;amp; Weber, A.P.M. (2014). Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;65&lt;/em&gt;(13), 3579-3593. Oxford University Press (OUP). doi:10.1093/jxb/eru100.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bräutigam A, Schliesky S, Külahoglu C, Osborne CP, Weber APM. Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt;. 2014;65(13):3579-3593.</ama>
<default>Bräutigam A, Schliesky S, Külahoglu C, Osborne CP, Weber APM (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt; 65(13): 3579-3593.</default>
<mla>Bräutigam, Andrea, Schliesky, Simon, Külahoglu, Canan, Osborne, Colin P., and Weber, Andreas P. M. “Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt; 65.13 (2014): 3579-3593.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bräutigam, Andrea, Schliesky, Simon, Külahoglu, Canan, Osborne, Colin P., and Weber, Andreas P. M. 2014. “Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Botany&lt;/em&gt; 65 (13): 3579-3593.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bräutigam, A., Schliesky, S., Külahoglu, C., Osborne, C.P., Weber, A.P.M.: Towards an integrative model of C-4 photosynthetic subtypes: insights from comparative transcriptome analysis of NAD-ME, NADP-ME, and PEP-CK C-4 species. Journal of Experimental Botany. 65, 3579-3593 (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915136</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-22T09:24:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:40Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>