<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915483</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bondarev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29231575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4572-2405</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper combines horizontal and vertical innovations to build an endogenous
growth model that allows for structural change. Older technologies are
continuously replaced by newer ones due to creative destruction and new technologies
appear as a result of horizontal innovations and as a result of consumers’
preferences for variety. We assume fixed operational costs for the manufacturing
sector and an endogenously determined price of the patent for each new technology.
The duration of a patent is not limited but every industry is profitable
only for a certain period of time, thus making the effective time of existence of
the technology endogenous and finite. We demonstrate that such an economy
exhibits constant growth rates that are proportional to the average productivity
growth, despite the ongoing disappearance of older technologies from the industry.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_03-2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915483/2915484/wpaper_03-2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Endogenous growth</topic><topic>creative destruction</topic><topic>endogenous structural change</topic><topic>horizontal innovation</topic><topic>endogenous patents</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154839</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915483</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Bondarev and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 03-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.03-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915483</apa>
<wels>Bondarev, A.; Greiner, A. (2014): Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Bondarev, A., and Greiner, A. (2014). Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 03-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 03-2014.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915483&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2014)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ama>Bondarev A, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 03-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03-2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bondarev, A., Greiner, A.: Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915483.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Bondarev, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Endogenous growth and structural change through vertical and horizontal innovations&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915483</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-04T14:25:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>