<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915525</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michel Y.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keoula</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kort</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study in a dynamic framework how product innovation activities of a
firm are influenced by its production capacity investments for an established
product and vice versa. The firm initially has capacity to sell an established
product, and it also has the option to undertake an R&amp;D project, which
upon completion allows the firm to introduce a new vertically and horizontally
differentiated product to the market, thereby extending its product range. The
breakthrough probability of detecting the new product depends on both the
value of the firm’s R&amp;D stock and its current R&amp;D investment. It is shown
that the initial production capacity for the established product influences the
intensity of R&amp;D activities of the firm. In particular, there are constellations
such that for large initial production capacity for the established product the
firm never invests in R&amp;D and the new product is never introduced. For small
initial capacity the firm keeps investing in R&amp;D implying that eventually the
new product is always introduced. Finally, for an intermediate range of initial
capacity levels the firm initially invests in product R&amp;D, but then reduces
these investments to zero. In this scenario the new product is introduced with
a positive probability, which is however substantially smaller than 1. From a
technical perspective this analysis gives the example of a new type of Skiba
threshold phenomenon in the framework of a multi-mode optimization model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_11_2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915525/2915526/wpaper_11_2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>product innovation</topic><topic>multi-product firm</topic><topic>R&amp;D</topic><topic>piecewise deterministic optimal control</topic><topic>Skiba curve</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29155251</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915525</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">38</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2694394</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kopel M, Kort PM. &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 11-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Keoula, M.Y., Kopel, M., Kort, P.M.: Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, Keoula, Michel Y., Kopel, Michael, and Kort, Peter M. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 11-2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Keoula, M.Y., Kopel, M. &amp;amp; Kort, P.M. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915525.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, M. Y.  Keoula, M.  Kopel, and P. M.  Kort, &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kopel M, Kort PM (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 11-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., et al., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.11-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Dawid, et al., &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 11-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., Kopel, M., &amp;amp; Kort, P. M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915525</apa>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Keoula, M. Y.; Kopel, M.; Kort, P. M. (2014): Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, Keoula, Michel Y., Kopel, Michael, and Kort, Peter M. &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 11-2014.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., Kopel, M., &amp;amp; Kort, P. M. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915525&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., Kopel, M., and Kort, P. M. (2014). Product Innovation Incentives by an Incumbent Firm: A Dynamic Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 11-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kopel M, Kort PM (2014)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 11-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915525</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-05T15:08:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>