<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915405</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benteng</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present a differential game model of two firms with different
technologies producing the same good and selling in the same world market.
The firm equipped with advanced technology is deciding whether to outsource parts
of its production to the home country of its competitor, where wages and the level of
technology are lower. Outsourcing reduces production costs but is associated with
spillovers to the foreign competitor. The degree to which the foreign competitor can
absorb these spillovers depends on its absorptive effort. Using numerical methods
the properties of a Markov Perfect Equilibrium of this game are characterized and
the implications of the variation of different key parameters are examined.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_12_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915405/2915407/wpaper_12_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154050</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915405</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> H. Dawid and B. Zou, &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 12-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Zou, B., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.12-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915405</apa>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Zou, B. (2013): Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915405&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, and Zou, Benteng. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 12-2013.</mla>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., and Zou, B. (2013). Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 12-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Dawid H, Zou B (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ama>Dawid H, Zou B. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 12-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Zou, B.: Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, and Zou, Benteng. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H. &amp;amp; Zou, B. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915405.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Dawid H, Zou B (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, and B.  Zou, &lt;em&gt;Strategies of Foreign Direct Investment in the Presence of Technological Spillovers&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915405</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-30T14:48:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>