<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915563</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we analyze an endogenous growth model with human capital that
results from public educational spending. We allow for public debt and analyze
three different debt policies: a balanced government budget, a slight deficit policy
where debt grows but less than GDP, and a strong deficit policy where debt grows at
the same rate as GDP. We find that the balanced budget policy and the policy with
a slightly growing public debt are equivalent as concerns long-run economic growth.
Further, those two rules yield higher growth than a debt policy where public debt
grows at the same rate as GDP, unless the government is a creditor. As concerns
welfare, it can be demonstrated that a strong deficit policy yields lower welfare
than a balanced budget and a slight deficit, unless initial debt ratios are low and
the intertemporal elasticity of substituion is high. Finally, it is demonstrated that
there may exist an inverted U-shaped relation between welfare and deficit financed
educational spending.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_05-2015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915563/2915564/wpaper_05-2015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Public Debt</topic><topic>Human Capital Formation</topic><topic>Economic Growth</topic><topic>Welfare</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29155638</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915563</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>05-2015</number></detail><extent unit="pages">25</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2907024</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 05-2015.</mla>
<default>Greiner A (2015)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<lncs> Greiner, A.: Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2015. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 05-2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Greiner A (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915563&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.05-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Greiner, A. (2015): Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa>Greiner, A. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915563</apa>
<ieee> A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 05-2015,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<ama>Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 05-2015. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2015.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915563.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Greiner, A. (2015). Human capital formation and public debt: Growth and welfare effects of three different deficit policies. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 05-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915563</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-07T10:04:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>