<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915820</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maren</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32825682</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kolip</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14955037</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1052-5869</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21334</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Decision aids can support informed choice in mammography screening, but for the German mammography screening programme no systematically evaluated decision aid exists to date. We developed a decision aid for women invited to this programme for the first time based on the criteria of the International Patient Decision Aids Standards Collaboration.
Objective

To determine whether a decision aid increases informed choice about mammography screening programme participation.
Methods

A representative sample of 7,400 women aged 50 was drawn from registration offices in Westphalia-Lippe, Germany. Women were randomised to receive usual care (i.e., the standard information brochure sent with the programme’s invitation letter) or the decision aid. Data were collected online at baseline, post-intervention, and 3 months follow-up. The primary outcome was informed choice. Secondary outcomes were the constituents of informed choice (knowledge, attitude, intention/uptake), decisional conflict, decision regret, and decision stage. Outcomes were analysed using latent structural equation models and χ2-tests.
Results

1,206 women participated (response rate of 16.3%). The decision aid increased informed choice. Women in the control group had lower odds to make an informed choice at post-intervention (OR 0.26, 95% CI 0.18-0.37) and at follow-up (OR 0.66, 95% CI 0.46-0.94); informed choices remained constant at 30%. This was also reflected in lower knowledge and more decisional conflict. Post-intervention, the uptake intention was higher in the control group, whereas the uptake rate at follow-up was similar. Women in the control group had a more positive attitude at follow-up than women receiving the decision aid. Decision regret and decision stage were not influenced by the intervention.
Conclusion

This paper describes the first systematic evaluation of a newly developed decision aid for the German mammography screening programme in a randomised controlled trial. Our decision aid proved to be an effective tool to enhance the rate of informed choice and was made accessible to the public.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="journal.pone.0189148.reder.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915820/2917247/journal.pone.0189148.reder.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLOS ONE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1932-6203</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29236722</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000417884100046</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29158205</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0189148</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Reder M, Kolip P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12(12): e0189148.</default>
<bio1>Reder M, Kolip P (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial.&lt;br /&gt;PLOS ONE 12(12): e0189148.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Reder, and P.  Kolip, “Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : e0189148.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Reder, M.; Kolip, P. (2017): Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,12:(12):e0189148</wels>
<frontiers>Reder, M., and Kolip, P. (2017). Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12:e0189148.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reder, M., &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2017). Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0189148. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0189148&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Reder, Maren, and Kolip, Petra. “Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12.12 (2017): e0189148.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reder, M. &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2017). Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(12): e0189148. Public Library of Science (PLoS). doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0189148.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Reder, M., &amp;amp; Kolip, P. (2017). Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(12), e0189148. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0189148</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Reder, Maren, and Kolip, Petra. 2017. “Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial”. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 12 (12): e0189148.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Reder, M., Kolip, P.: Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. PLOS ONE. 12, : e0189148 (2017).</lncs>
<ieee> M. Reder and P. Kolip, “Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial”, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2017, : e0189148.</ieee>
<harvard1>Reder, M., &amp;amp; Kolip, P., 2017. Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, 12(12): e0189148.</harvard1>
<ama>Reder M, Kolip P. Does a decision aid improve informed choice in mammography screening? Results from a randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;. 2017;12(12): e0189148.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915820</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-14T10:49:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:46:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>