<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915428</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zaharieva</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22426124</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper develops a labour market model with on-the-job search, match-specific pro-
ductivity draws and an endogenous irreversible schooling decision. The choice of schooling
is modeled as an optimal stopping problem which gives rise to the equilibrium heterogeneity
of workers with respect to the formal education. The optimal schooling decision is charac-
terized by the reservation productivity of students which is a monotonic function of time.
Moreover, this reservation productivity is lower in expansions when job-to-job mobility is
more intensive. Therefore, the model is compatible with the empirical evidence that expan-
sions have a positive effect on the probability of a school dropout. The schooling density
is downward-sloping and the equilibrium wage distribution is right-skewed with a unique
interior mode. This means that the majority of workers earn wages in the middle range of
the earnings distribution. At the same time there is a small proportion of employees in the
beginning of their career with wages in the left tail of the earnings distribution and a small
proportion of high-skilled workers earning wages in the right tail of the distribution.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_19_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915428/2915429/wpaper_19_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Optimal schooling</topic><topic>uncertainty</topic><topic>on-the-job search</topic><topic>wage dispersion</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154287</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915428</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Zaharieva, &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Zaharieva A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 19-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 19-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915428&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Zaharieva, A., 2013. &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.19-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<wels>Zaharieva, A. (2013): On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<ieee> A. Zaharieva, &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 19-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Zaharieva, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 19-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915428</apa>
<frontiers>Zaharieva, A. (2013). On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 19-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, A. (2013). &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915428.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Zaharieva A. &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 19-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<default>Zaharieva A (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 19-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Zaharieva, Anna. &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 19-2013.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zaharieva, Anna. 2013. &lt;em&gt;On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 19-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Zaharieva, A.: On-the-Job Search and Optimal Schooling under Uncertainty and Irreversibility. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 19-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915428</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-01T12:45:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>