<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915478</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bondarev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29231575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4572-2405</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We analyze how different budgetary rules affect the stability of an economy
in a basic endogenous growth model with public debt and a state-dependent consumption
tax rate. We show that a discretionary policy implies that the government
violates its inter-temporal budget constraint along a balanced growth path, whereas
a balanced budget rule guarantees that the economy is stable. A rule based debt
policy gives rise to stability if the reaction of the primary surplus to higher public
debt is sufficiently large. Further, in case of a strongly regressive consumption tax
rate over a certain range, multiple balanced growth paths may emerge. The main
results can be generalized to hold for any endogenous growth model with infinitely
lived households.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_02-2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915478/2915482/wpaper_02-2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Budget rules</topic><topic>public debt</topic><topic>inter-temporal budget constraint</topic><topic>stability</topic><topic>endogenous growth</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154781</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915478</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>02-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">23</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Greiner, A.; Bondarev, A. (2014): Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Greiner A, Bondarev A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Bondarev, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915478&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Bondarev, A., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.02-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, and A.  Bondarev, &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Greiner A, Bondarev A. &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 02-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. &amp;amp; Bondarev, A. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915478.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Greiner, A., and Bondarev, A. (2014). Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 02-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Bondarev, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915478</apa>
<ieee> A. Greiner and A. Bondarev, &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 02-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<lncs> Greiner, A., Bondarev, A.: Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred, and Bondarev, Anton. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 02-2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred, and Bondarev, Anton. &lt;em&gt;Public debt and aggregate stability with endogenous growth and a state-dependent consumption tax&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 02-2014.</mla>
<default>Greiner A, Bondarev A (2014)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915478</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-04T14:19:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>