<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915423</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Testing the reaction of the primary surplus to variations in public debt, relative
to GDP respectively, has been frequently resorted to in order to test for sustainabil-
ity of a given debt policy. In this contribution, we analyze theoretically under which
condition a positive reaction of the primary surplus to variations in debt implies
a sustainable debt policy. We demonstrate that the evolution of the debt to GDP
ratio plays a decisive role as concerns the validity of the test outcome. In addition,
we demonstrate that a positive reaction coefficient does not guarantee sustainability
unless it exceeds at least the difference between the interest rate on public debt and
the GDP growth grate. Thus, this test allows judgements about sustainability of
public debt policies only if the interest rate and the GDP growth rate are known.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_17_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915423/2915424/wpaper_17_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Debt sustainability</topic><topic>critical debt</topic><topic>primary surplus</topic><topic>reaction function</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154234</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915423</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>17-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">9</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Greiner A (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 17-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<bio1>Greiner A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 17-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Greiner, A. (2013): How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 17-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915423&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Greiner, A. (2013). How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 17-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 17-2013.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. (2013). &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915423.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 17-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915423</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred. 2013. &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 17-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Greiner, A.: How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 17-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ieee> A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 17-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., 2013. &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.17-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ama>Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;How to test for debt sustainability? Some theoretical reflections on an empirical test&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 17-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915423</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-01T12:15:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>