<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915557</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fincke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5537351</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies fiscal policy behavior with regard to sustainability for the
group of the eight eastern new member states (NMS) which joined the European
Union (EU) in 2004. Using the approach of Bohn (1995, 1998) the fiscal reaction
function is estimated for the years 1995 until 2013. Further, by separating the response
in periods before and after accession, it is possible to study potential changes
in fiscal sustainability. The results of the panel regressions reveal a positive statistically
significant reaction coefficient, indicating sustainable behavior. Moreover, the
separated responses before and after 2004 signify a stronger reaction ahead of the
accession. Plus, effects of the crisis should be taken into account.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_03-2015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915557/2915560/wpaper_03-2015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Fiscal Sustainability</topic><topic>Public Finances</topic><topic>New EU Member States</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29155575</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915557</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03-2015</number></detail><extent unit="pages">18</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Fincke, B., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.03-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Fincke, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 03-2015,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<ama>Fincke B. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 03-2015. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2015.</ama>
<apa>Fincke, B. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915557</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, Bettina. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03-2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Fincke, B.: Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2015. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<wels>Fincke, B. (2015): Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, B. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915557.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Fincke, B. (2015). Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 03-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, B. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915557&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Fincke, Bettina. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 03-2015.</mla>
<default>Fincke B (2015)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Fincke, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Fincke B (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability: Does EU Membership Change Policy Behavior? Empirical Evidence from Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915557</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-07T09:22:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>