<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915274</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Göpfert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">70126969</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2517-4907</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan Philip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Göpfert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27345942</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1982-9399</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="nips_2017_goepfert_preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915274/2915286/nips_2017_goepfert_preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Long Beach</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29152742</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Göpfert, Christina, Göpfert, Jan Philip, and Hammer, Barbara. “Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;. 2017.</mla>
<default>Göpfert C, Göpfert JP, Hammer B (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments.</default>
<lncs> Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J.P., Hammer, B.: Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments.  (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, Christina, Göpfert, Jan Philip, and Hammer, Barbara. 2017. “Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Göpfert C, Göpfert JP, Hammer B (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments. .</bio1>
<harvard1>Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J.P., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2017. Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J. P., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Göpfert, J. P.  Göpfert, and B.  Hammer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Göpfert, C.; Göpfert, J. P.; Hammer, B. (2017): Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. In: Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments.</wels>
<apa>Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J. P., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ieee> C. Göpfert, J.P. Göpfert, and B. Hammer, “Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;, 2017.</ieee>
<ama>Göpfert C, Göpfert JP, Hammer B. Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;. 2017.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J.P. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2017). Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Göpfert, C., Göpfert, J. P., and Hammer, B. (2017). “Analyzing Feature Relevance for Linear Reject Option SVM using Relevance Intervals” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2017 NIPS workshop on Transparent and Interpretable  Machine Learning in Safety Critical Environments&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915274</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-26T12:48:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>