<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915430</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The role of R&amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bondarev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29231575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4572-2405</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we develop an economic growth model that includes anthropogenic
climate change. We explicitly include a research sector that creates new technologies
and simultaneously expands productivities of existing technologies. The environment
is affected by R&amp;D activities both negatively, through increase of output
from productivity growth, as well as positively, as new technologies are less harmful
for the environment. We consider three different versions of the model. In the first
version, there are no constraints with respect to research spending, while the R&amp;D
sector affects the rest of the economy. In this version, the environmental damages
are lower than in the model with simple exogenous technical change. Next, we
consider the research dynamics with a constant R&amp;D budget set by the agent. We
find that there exist two different steady states of this economy, one with higher
productivities and less new technologies being developed, and the other with more
technologies being created. In the last version, finally, we allow for dynamic R&amp;D
spending. For this version, it is demonstrated that sustained economic growth with
preservation of the environment is possible given certain conditions as regards the
technology and R&amp;D spending.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_20_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915430/2915431/wpaper_20_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Climate change</topic><topic>green growth</topic><topic>vertical and horizontal innovations</topic><topic>optimal control</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154300</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915430</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>20-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">35</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2013). &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915430.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 20-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Bondarev, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Bondarev A, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 20-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. 2013. &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 20-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bondarev, A., Greiner, A.: The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 20-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<wels>Bondarev, A.; Greiner, A. (2013): The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<mla>Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 20-2013.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 20-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915430&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bondarev, A., and Greiner, A. (2013). The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 20-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 20-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ieee> A. Bondarev and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 20-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2013. &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.20-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;The role of R&amp;amp;D with a continuum of technologies and environmental degradation: An optimal control approach&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 20-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915430</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915430</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-01T12:51:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>