<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915408</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hale</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Utar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42546710</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luis B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Torres-Ruiz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Effects of the competition between the two South locations (Mexico and China) in the North-
ern market (U.S.) is analyzed. By employing a new plant-level data set that covers the universe
of Mexican export assembly plants (maquiladoras) from 1990 to 2006 and exploiting the ex-
ogenous acceleration of Chinese imports in conjunction with the WTO accession of China, the
empirical analysis reveals substantial effect of intensified Chinese competition on maquiladoras.
In particular, competition from China has negative and significant impact on employment and
plant growth, both through the intensive and the extensive margin, on the most unskilled labor
intensive sectors of those threatened by competition from China, leading to sectoral reallocation.
No major effect is found through reallocative channels within industries, but significant increases
in plant productivity and skill intensity are quantified in maquiladoras attributable to competi-
tion from China. The results lend substance to field studies and anecdotal evidence on industrial
upgrading in Mexican Maquiladoras in response to competition with low-wage locations such as
China.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_13_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915408/2915412/wpaper_13_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154088</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915408</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">62</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Utar H, Torres-Ruiz LB (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Utar, Hale, and Torres-Ruiz, Luis B. &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 13-2013.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, Hale, and Torres-Ruiz, Luis B. 2013. &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 13-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Utar, H., Torres-Ruiz, L.B.: International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<ieee> H. Utar and L.B. Torres-Ruiz, &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 13-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Utar, H., &amp;amp; Torres-Ruiz, L. B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915408</apa>
<frontiers>Utar, H., and Torres-Ruiz, L. B. (2013). International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 13-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, H. &amp;amp; Torres-Ruiz, L.B. (2013). &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915408.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Utar H, Torres-Ruiz LB. &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 13-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Utar, and L. B.  Torres-Ruiz, &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Utar H, Torres-Ruiz LB (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Utar, H., &amp;amp; Torres-Ruiz, L.B., 2013. &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.13-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Utar, H., &amp;amp; Torres-Ruiz, L. B. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915408&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Utar, H.; Torres-Ruiz, L. B. (2013): International Competition and Industrial Evolution: Evidence from the Impact of Chinese Competition on Mexican Maquiladoras. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915408</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-30T14:57:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:40Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>