<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915438</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fincke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5537351</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">There is no clear-cut evidence on how the adoption of the European
fiscal standards in
uences discretionary fiscal policies within the Member
States. This study investigates that phenomenon on the example of the
2004 enlargement. The results show that the effects of the adoption of EU
fiscal rules bring a statistically significant change towards more counter-
cyclical behavior. The results are robust for different model specifications,
including alternative time spans and correcting for the possible influence
of the financial crises and political forces. Interestingly, the year 2004
did not have any significant impact on the change in fiscal policies in the
Old Member States, suggesting that the EU entry might motivate new
members to run more prudent budgetary policies.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_25_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915438/2915439/wpaper_25_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>discretionary fiscal policy</topic><topic>New Member States</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154382</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915438</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>25-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">18</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, Bettina, and Wolski, Marcin. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 25-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Fincke, B., Wolski, M.: Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 25-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<default>Fincke B, Wolski M (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 25-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Fincke, Bettina, and Wolski, Marcin. &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 25-2013.</mla>
<frontiers>Fincke, B., and Wolski, M. (2013). Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 25-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, B. &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915438.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Fincke B, Wolski M. &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 25-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<ieee> B. Fincke and M. Wolski, &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 25-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<apa>Fincke, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 25-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915438</apa>
<wels>Fincke, B.; Wolski, M. (2013): Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Fincke, and M.  Wolski, &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Fincke, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 25-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915438&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Fincke, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.25-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Fincke B, Wolski M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are European fiscal rules that bad? Discretionary fiscal policies in New Member States&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 25-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915438</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-01T14:22:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>