<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915495</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bondarev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29231575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4572-2405</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we present and analyze a stylized model of endogenous growth
with international technology spillover effects from the North to the South. The
model allows for endogenous structural change and environmental degradation
that reduces world output. We find that within this framework the costless
technological spillovers foster structural change in both more and less advanced
economies. Moreover, we can show that under technological spillovers the degradation
of the environment is expected to be lower even without government interventions
and we highlight the role of endogenous structural change in generating
this outcome.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_09-2014.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915495/2915496/wpaper_09-2014.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Technological Spillovers</topic><topic>Endogenous Growth</topic><topic>Environmental Impact</topic><topic>Endogenous Structural Change</topic><topic>Creative Destruction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154950</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915495</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>09-2014</number></detail><extent unit="pages">34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Bondarev and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 09-2014,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014.</ieee>
<apa>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915495</apa>
<frontiers>Bondarev, A., and Greiner, A. (2014). A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 09-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014). &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915495.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bondarev A, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 09-2014. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2014.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Bondarev, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 09-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2014). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915495&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2014. &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.09-2014, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<wels>Bondarev, A.; Greiner, A. (2014): A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2014)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 09-2014.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 09-2014.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. 2014. &lt;em&gt;A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 09-2014. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bondarev, A., Greiner, A.: A North-South model with technological spillovers, environmental degradation and structural change. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 09-2014. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2014).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915495</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-04T15:28:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>