<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915440</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6471004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8865-7466</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neugart</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Regions within the European Union differ substantially not only
with respect to per capita GDP, but also with respect to income inequality
within the regions. This paper studies the effects of different
types of technology-oriented cohesion policies, aiming at the reduction
of regional differences, on the convergence of regions and the dynamics
of income inequality within regions. In particular, policies are
analyzed using a two-region agent-based macroeconomic model – the
Eurace@Unibi model – where firms in the lagging region receive subsidies
for investment in physical capital. It is demonstrated that the
short-, medium- and long-term effects of the policies on per-capita
output and between as well as within regional inequality differ substantially
depending on how successful the policy is in incentivizing
firms to choose best available capital vintages and on how flexible labor
markets are in the targeted region.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_26_2013.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915440/2915441/wpaper_26_2013.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cohesion policies</topic><topic>technology adoption</topic><topic>agent-based model</topic><topic>inequality</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29154403</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915440</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>26-2013</number></detail><extent unit="pages">44</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 26-2013. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2013.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, Michael. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 26-2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Harting, P., Neugart, M.: Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 26-2013. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2013).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P. &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915440.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2013) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 26-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, P.  Harting, and M.  Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> H. Dawid, P. Harting, and M. Neugart, &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 26-2013,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013.</ieee>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M., 2013. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.26-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 26-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915440</apa>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Harting, P.; Neugart, M. (2013): Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, and Neugart, Michael. &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2013. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 26-2013.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Neugart, M. (2013).  &lt;em&gt;Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 26-2013). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915440&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., Harting, P., and Neugart, M. (2013). Cohesion Policy and Inequality Dynamics: Insights from a Heterogeneous Agents Macroeconomic Model. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 26-2013, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Dawid H, Harting P, Neugart M (2013)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 26-2013.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915440</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-01T14:32:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T12:59:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>