<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915177</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Silja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitkänen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This article analyses representations of children in the photographs published in the
Soviet propaganda magazine SSSR na Stroike (USSR in Construction), concentrating
on the volumes devoted to different Soviet Socialist Republics. The changes in
the Soviet Union’s nationality policies during the 1930s are clearly visible in the images.
The article begins with classification of the child-related photographs. Next, images
are analysed using representation theory, developed by cultural theorist Stuart
Hall, and the theory of orientalism, presented by literature theorist Edward Said. It is
also considered how the representations of children were used as a part of the Soviet
nation-building process.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BGHS_WP_02_Pitkaenen_S.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915177/2915911/BGHS_WP_02_Pitkaenen_S.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>children</topic><topic>nation-building</topic><topic>orientalism</topic><topic>othering</topic><topic>photography</topic><topic>propaganda</topic><topic>representations</topic><topic>Soviet Union</topic><topic>Soviet Socialist Republics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2512-8051</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29151775</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Pitkänen, &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld Graduate School In History And Sociology, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitkänen, S. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series, 2). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Pitkänen S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;. BGHS Working Paper Series; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</bio1>
<harvard1>Pitkänen, S., 2017. &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;, BGHS Working Paper Series, no.2, Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</harvard1>
<wels>Pitkänen, S. (2017): Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</wels>
<ieee> S. Pitkänen, &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;, BGHS Working Paper Series, vol. 2,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology, 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Pitkänen, S. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series, 2). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</apa>
<frontiers>Pitkänen, S. (2017). Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike. &lt;em&gt;BGHS Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 2, Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitkänen, S. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Pitkänen S. &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;. BGHS Working Paper Series. Vol 2. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology; 2017.</ama>
<default>Pitkänen S (2017)  BGHS Working Paper Series; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.</default>
<mla>Pitkänen, Silja. &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology, 2017. BGHS Working Paper Series. 2.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Pitkänen, Silja. 2017. &lt;em&gt;Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 2. BGHS Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Pitkänen, S.: Smiling children of the Soviet Socialist Republics: Representations of children of the Soviet Socialist Republics in the propaganda photographs published in the magazine SSSR na Stroike. BGHS Working Paper Series, 2. Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology, Bielefeld (2017).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915177</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-11-22T13:25:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>