<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915594</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michel Y.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keoula</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kort</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents a numerical method for the characterization of Markov-perfect
equilibria of symmetric differential games exhibiting coexisting stable steady states.
The method relying on the calculation of ’local value functions’ through collocation
in overlapping parts of the state space, is applicable for games with multiple state
variables. It is applied to analyze a piecewise deterministic game capturing the dynamic
competition between two oligopolistic firms, which are active in an established
market and invest in R&amp;D. Both R&amp;D investment and an evolving public knowledge
stock positively influence a breakthrough probability, where the breakthrough generates
the option to introduce an innovative product on the market. Additionally, firms
engage in activities influencing the appeal of the established and new product to consumers.
Markov-perfect equilibrium profiles are numerically determined for different
parameter settings and it is shown that for certain constellations the new product
is introduced with probability one if the initial strength of the established market is
below a threshold, which depends on the initial level of public knowledge. In case the
initial strength of the established market is above this threshold, the R&amp;D effort of
both firms quickly goes to zero and with a high probability the new product is never
introduced. Furthermore, it is shown that after the introduction of the new product
the innovator engages in activities weakening the established market, although it is
still producing positive quantities of that product.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_05_2016.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915594/2915595/wpaper_05_2016.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Markov-Perfect Equilibrium</topic><topic>Skiba Curve</topic><topic>Collocation</topic><topic>R&amp;D Competition</topic><topic>Product Innovation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29155943</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915594</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>05-2016</number></detail><extent unit="pages">21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2901660</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kort PM (2016)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2016.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Keoula, M. Y.; Kort, P. M. (2016): Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., &amp;amp; Kort, P. M. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2016). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915594&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, Keoula, Michel Y., and Kort, Peter M. &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2016. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 05-2016.</mla>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., and Kort, P. M. (2016). Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 05-2016, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Dawid, H., Keoula, M. Y., &amp;amp; Kort, P. M. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2016). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915594</apa>
<ieee> H. Dawid, M.Y. Keoula, and P.M. Kort, &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 05-2016,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2016.</ieee>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., Keoula, M.Y., &amp;amp; Kort, P.M., 2016. &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.05-2016, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kort PM (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2016.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, M. Y.  Keoula, and P. M.  Kort, &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., Keoula, M.Y. &amp;amp; Kort, P.M. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915594.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Keoula, M.Y., Kort, P.M.: Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2016. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, Keoula, Michel Y., and Kort, Peter M. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 05-2016. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Dawid H, Keoula MY, Kort PM. &lt;em&gt;Numerical Analysis of Markov-Perfect Equilibria with Multiple Stable Steady States: A Duopoly Application with Innovative Firms&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 05-2016. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2016.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915594</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-07T13:04:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-29T20:24:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>