<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2915574</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Juanxi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper establishes an agent-based model to describe the dynamic behaviour
of the financial market with mutual fund managers and investors under two types
of compensation contracts: asset-based fees and performance-based fees, and using
two types of adaptive expectation: trend chaser and contrarian. Our results show
that both of trading strategies of trend chaser and contrarian destabilise the market.
However, trend chasers always trigger significant fluctuations, while contrarian
traders bring along the slight up and down oscillations. The types of compensation
contracts change the behaviour of contrarian traders, but have no influence to trend
chaser. We also find that inertia parameter decrease the stability of market and induce
market price to be underestimated. In particular, the heterogenous analysis
under different compensation contracts shows that asset maximisers dominate the
whole market and produce higher returns, which can be used to explain the current
situation in real market that most of mutual funds choose asset-based contract.
Moreover, the coexistence of two compensation schemes may amplify market fluctuations
and create bubbles.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_10_2015.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2915574/2915576/wpaper_10_2015.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>mutual fund manager</topic><topic>compensation contract</topic><topic>bounded rationality</topic><topic>adaptive expectation</topic><topic>nonlinear dynamics</topic><topic>risk taking behaviour</topic><topic>heterogenity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29155748</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2915574</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10-2015</number></detail><extent unit="pages">37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Wang J. &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 10-2015. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2015.</ama>
<lncs> Wang, J.: Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents. Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2015. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2015).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, Juanxi. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 10-2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, J. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915574.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Wang J (2015) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Wang, &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> J. Wang, &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 10-2015,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wang, J., 2015. &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;, Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.10-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Wang, J. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915574</apa>
<wels>Wang, J. (2015): Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wang, J. (2015).  &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt; (Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2015). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2915574&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wang, Juanxi. &lt;em&gt;Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2015. Working Papers in Economics and Management. 10-2015.</mla>
<frontiers>Wang, J. (2015). Incentives and Adaptive Expectations in a Financial Market with Heterogenous Agents. &lt;em&gt;Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 10-2015, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Wang J (2015)  Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2015.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2915574</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2017-12-07T11:01:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>