<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916908</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:490</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Niko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Partanen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">KyungTae</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rießler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">110388077</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2397-2860</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thierry</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Poibeau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tommi A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pirinen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Rießler</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jack</namePart><namePart type="family">Rueter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Trond</namePart><namePart type="family">Trosterud</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Francis M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Tyers</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4961795</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4th International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="W18-0201.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916908/2916909/W18-0201.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Helsinki</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29169083</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, N., KyungTae, L., Rießler, M. &amp;amp; Poibeau, T. (2018). Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In T.A. Pirinen, M. Rießler, J. Rueter, T. Trosterud &amp;amp; F.M. Tyers (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-17). Gehalten auf der 4th International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages, Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Partanen, L.  KyungTae, M.  Rießler, and T.  Poibeau, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T.A. Pirinen, M. Rießler, J. Rueter, T. Trosterud, F.M. Tyers), Association For Computational Linguistics, Helsinki, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-17.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Partanen N, KyungTae L, Rießler M, Poibeau T (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Pirinen TA, Rießler M, Rueter J, Trosterud T, Tyers FM (Eds); Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics:  1-17.</bio1>
<ama>Partanen N, KyungTae L, Rießler M, Poibeau T. Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In: Pirinen TA, Rießler M, Rueter J, Trosterud T, Tyers FM, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics;  2018: 1-17.</ama>
<aps> N.  Partanen, et al., Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, edited by T. A.  Pirinen, et al. (Association for Computational Linguistics, Helsinki, 2018), p. 1-17.</aps>
<lncs> Partanen, N., KyungTae, L., Rießler, M., Poibeau, T.: Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In: Pirinen, T.A., Rießler, M., Rueter, J., Trosterud, T., and Tyers, F.M. (eds.) Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. p. 1-17. Association for Computational Linguistics, Helsinki (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, Niko, KyungTae, Lim, Rießler, Michael, and Poibeau, Thierry. 2018. “Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Tommi A. Pirinen, Michael Rießler, Jack Rueter, Trond Trosterud, and Francis M. Tyers, 1-17. Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Partanen, N., KyungTae, L., Rießler, M., and Poibeau, T. (2018). “Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, Pirinen, T. A., Rießler, M., Rueter, J., Trosterud, T., and Tyers, F. M. eds. (Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics), 1-17.</frontiers>
<mla>Partanen, Niko, KyungTae, Lim, Rießler, Michael, and Poibeau, Thierry. “Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Tommi A. Pirinen, Michael Rießler, Jack Rueter, Trond Trosterud, and Francis M. Tyers. Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2018. 1-17.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, N., KyungTae, L., Rießler, M., &amp;amp; Poibeau, T. (2018). Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In T. A.  Pirinen, M.  Rießler, J.  Rueter, T.  Trosterud, &amp;amp; F. M.  Tyers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-17). Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Partanen, N.; KyungTae, L.; Rießler, M.; Poibeau, T. (2018): Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In: Tommi A. Pirinen; Michael Rießler; Jack Rueter; Trond Trosterud; Francis M. Tyers (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 1-17.</wels>
<default>Partanen N, KyungTae L, Rießler M, Poibeau T (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Pirinen TA, Rießler M, Rueter J, Trosterud T, Tyers FM (Eds);  Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics:  1-17.</default>
<harvard1>Partanen, N., et al., 2018. Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In T. A.  Pirinen, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;.  Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 1-17.</harvard1>
<ieee> N. Partanen, et al., “Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, T.A. Pirinen, et al., eds.,  Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2018,  pp.1-17.</ieee>
<apa>Partanen, N., KyungTae, L., Rießler, M., &amp;amp; Poibeau, T. (2018). Dependency parsing of code-switching data with cross-lingual feature representations. In T. A.  Pirinen, M.  Rießler, J.  Rueter, T.  Trosterud, &amp;amp; F. M.  Tyers (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop for Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-17). Helsinki: Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916908</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-20T09:01:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T08:30:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>