<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916995</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anton</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bondarev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29231575</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4572-2405</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we develop an economic growth model that includes anthropogenic
climate change. We include a publicly funded research sector that creates new technologies
and simultaneously expands the productivities of existing technologies. The
environment is affected by R&amp;D activities both negatively, through the increase of
output from productivity growth, as well as positively as new technologies are less
harmful for the environment. We find that there may exist two different steadystates
of the economy, depending on the amount of research spending: one with less
new technologies being developed and the other with more technologies. Thus, a
lock-in effect may arise that, however, can be overcome by raising R&amp;D spending
sufficiently such that the steady-state becomes unique. We derive the combinations
of fiscal policy instruments for which that can be achieved and we study the implications
for the economy and for the environment. In particular, the double dividend
hypothesis may hold only under some specific conditions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_03_2018.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916995/2916996/wpaper_03_2018.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Climate change</topic><topic>doubly-differentiated R&amp;D</topic><topic>double dividend</topic><topic>fiscal policy instruments</topic><topic>technology lock-in</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29169958</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2916995</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03-2018</number></detail><extent unit="pages">31</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Bondarev, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.03-2018, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2018.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2018). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916995&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Bondarev, A.; Greiner, A. (2018): Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<ieee> A. Bondarev and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 03-2018,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Bondarev, A., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2018). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916995</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, A. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916995.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bondarev, A., and Greiner, A. (2018). Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 03-2018, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Bondarev A, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 03-2018. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2018.</ama>
<default>Bondarev A, Greiner A (2018)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2018.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2018. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 03-2018.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bondarev, Anton, and Greiner, Alfred. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03-2018. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bondarev, A., Greiner, A.: Global warming and technical change: Multiple steady-states and policy options. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2018. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916995</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-26T09:20:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>