<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916862</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:490</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rießler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">110388077</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2397-2860</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joshua</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wilbur</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Erich</namePart><namePart type="family">Kasten</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Katja</namePart><namePart type="family">Roller</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Joshua</namePart><namePart type="family">Wilbur</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4961795</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="orhili_riessler_wilbur(1).pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916862/2916911/orhili_riessler_wilbur(1).pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Kulturstiftung Sibirien</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Oral history meets linguistics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-942883-30-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29168622</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">31-64</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Rießler, M.; Wilbur, J. (2017): Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In: Erich Kasten; Katja Roller; Joshua Wilbur (Hrsg.):  Oral history meets linguistics. Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien. (Exhibitions and Symposia, ).  S. 31-64.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rießler, M. &amp;amp; Wilbur, J. (2017). Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples (Exhibitions and Symposia). In E. Kasten, K. Roller &amp;amp; J. Wilbur (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 31-64). Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rießler, M., &amp;amp; Wilbur, J. (2017). Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In E.  Kasten, K.  Roller, &amp;amp; J.  Wilbur (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Exhibitions and Symposia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-64). Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Rießler, Michael, and Wilbur, Joshua. “Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples”. &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Erich Kasten, Katja Roller, and Joshua Wilbur. Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien, 2017. Exhibitions and Symposia. 31-64.</mla>
<frontiers>Rießler, M., and Wilbur, J. (2017). “Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples” in &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, Kasten, E., Roller, K., and Wilbur, J. eds. Exhibitions and Symposia (Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien), 31-64.</frontiers>
<default>Rießler M, Wilbur J (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Oral history meets linguistics. Kasten E, Roller K, Wilbur J (Eds);  Exhibitions and Symposia.  Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien:  31-64.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Rießler, and J.  Wilbur, in &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. Kasten, K. Roller, J. Wilbur), Kulturstiftung Sibirien, Fürstenberg, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 31-64.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Rießler M, Wilbur J (2017) &lt;br /&gt;Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Oral history meets linguistics. Kasten E, Roller K, Wilbur J (Eds); Exhibitions and Symposia,  Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien:  31-64.</bio1>
<harvard1>Rießler, M., &amp;amp; Wilbur, J., 2017. Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In E.  Kasten, K.  Roller, &amp;amp; J.  Wilbur, eds. &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. Exhibitions and Symposia.  Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien, pp. 31-64.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Rießler and J. Wilbur, “Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples”, &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, E. Kasten, K. Roller, and J. Wilbur, eds., Exhibitions and Symposia,  Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien, 2017,  pp.31-64.</ieee>
<ama>Rießler M, Wilbur J. Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In: Kasten E, Roller K, Wilbur J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. Exhibitions and Symposia. Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien;  2017: 31-64.</ama>
<apa>Rießler, M., &amp;amp; Wilbur, J. (2017). Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In E.  Kasten, K.  Roller, &amp;amp; J.  Wilbur (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Exhibitions and Symposia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 31-64). Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien.</apa>
<lncs> Rießler, M., Wilbur, J.: Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples. In: Kasten, E., Roller, K., and Wilbur, J. (eds.) Oral history meets linguistics. Exhibitions and Symposia. p. 31-64. Kulturstiftung Sibirien, Fürstenberg (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rießler, Michael, and Wilbur, Joshua. 2017. “Documenting endangered oral histories of the Arctic: A proposed symbiosis for language documentation and oral history research, illustrated by Saami and Komi examples”. In &lt;em&gt;Oral history meets linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Erich Kasten, Katja Roller, and Joshua Wilbur, 31-64. Exhibitions and Symposia. Fürstenberg: Kulturstiftung Sibirien.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916862</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-18T10:40:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-20T08:31:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>