<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916933</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lazar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Obradović</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We consider a robust version of the full information best choice
problem (Gilbert and Mosteller (1966)): there is ambiguity (represented
by a set of priors) about the measure driving the observed
process. We solve the problem under a very general class of multiple
priors in the setting of Riedel (2009). As in the classical case, it is
optimal to stop if the current observation is a running maximum that
exceeds certain thresholds. We characterize the decreasing sequence
of thresholds, as well as the (history dependent) minimizing measure.
We introduce locally constant ambiguity neighborhood (LCAn) which
has connections to coherent risk measures. Sensitivity analysis is performed
using LCAn and exponential neighborhood from Riedel (2009).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_580.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916933/2916934/IMW_working_paper_580.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29169338</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>580</number></detail><extent unit="pages">39</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Obradović, Lazar. &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 580.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Obradović, L. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 580). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Obradović, L. (2018). Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 580, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Obradović, L. (2018): Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Obradović L (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 580.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ieee> L. Obradović, &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 580,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<harvard1>Obradović, L., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.580, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Obradović, L. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 580). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Obradović, L. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Obradović L (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 580.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Obradović, &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Obradović L. &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 580. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
<lncs> Obradović, L.: Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 580. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Obradović, Lazar. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Robust Maximum Detection: Full Information Best Choice Problem under Multiple Priors&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 580. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916933</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-22T14:34:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>