<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916849</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoepfner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51220325</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">There are different approaches for the detection of market phase changes in stock markets. Most
of them utilize various assumptions and constraints which makes these methods somewhat arbitrary.
This paper develops an algorithm which identifies bull and bear markets retrospectively in
a very robust way without using exogenous parameters. At the same time the algorithm is very
easy to execute, can be applied to several time series frequencies and is intended to identify rather
longer subperiods than shorter ones. Knowing the different phases one can investigate a multitude
of characteristics of bull and bear markets.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_01_2018.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916849/2916852/wpaper_01_2018.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>bull market</topic><topic>bear market</topic><topic>time series</topic><topic>algorithm</topic><topic>market phase changes</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29168499</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2916849</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>01-18</number></detail><extent unit="pages">21</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Hoepfner M. &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 01-18. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2018.</ama>
<lncs> Hoepfner, M.: Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-18. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoepfner, Marcel. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 01-18. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoepfner, M. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916849.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Hoepfner, &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hoepfner M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-18.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hoepfner, M., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.01-18, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Hoepfner, &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 01-18,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Hoepfner, M. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-18). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916849</apa>
<frontiers>Hoepfner, M. (2018). Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 01-18, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hoepfner, M. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-18). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2916849&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hoepfner, Marcel. &lt;em&gt;Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2018. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 01-18.</mla>
<wels>Hoepfner, M. (2018): Retrospective Identification of Bull and Bear Markets: A new, but simple Algorithm. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Hoepfner M (2018)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-18.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916849</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-17T14:45:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:00:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>