<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2916283</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabell</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Diekmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">127282160</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Established research on islamophobia like the Group-focused Enmity project of the Institute for Interdisciplinary Research on Conflict and Violence combines attitude measures directed against Islam as a religion and Muslims
as individuals in a single measure, as both is defined as islamophobia. The current research raises the question whether it is worthwhile to establish a more profound perspective and to distinguish between prejudices directed against Muslims as persons, and against Islam as religion. According to Social Identity Theory, the category’s salience depends on specific contexts. Consequently, for some respondents the religious affiliation might not be salient and Muslims are perceived as individuals, independent from Islam, whereas others do not distinguish between the two. Devaluation of Islam might therefore not necessarily include devaluation of Muslims. This study analyses a sample of 29 respondents in Bielefeld, a mediumsized city in western Germany, using quantitative methods to test whether the devaluation of Islam and Muslims are two different phenomena, and whether specific conditions (education, contact,  elf-reported religiousness, general criticism of religion, national identity) have an impact on the perception of the  evaluation of Islam as a religion and Muslims as individuals. An explorative factor analysis reveals two latent factors that distinguish between hostile statements on Muslims and on Islam. In addition, the variable “general criticism on  eligion” is highly interesting, as it seems to increase the devaluation of Islam and at the same time has a negative, prejudice reducing effect on the devaluation of Muslims. All in all, there is theoretical as well as empirical evidence for a  ifferentiation between Muslims as individuals and Islam as religion. Accordingly, future research should pay attention to  he correct terminology and specify more carefully: devaluation of Islam vs. devaluation of Muslims.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WP12_Diekmann.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2916283/2916284/WP12_Diekmann.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IKG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29162838</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><extent unit="pages">46</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Diekmann I (2017)  IKG Working Paper; 12.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: IKG.</default>
<mla>Diekmann, Isabell. &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: IKG, 2017. IKG Working Paper. 12.</mla>
<frontiers>Diekmann, I. (2017). Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene. &lt;em&gt;IKG Working Paper&lt;/em&gt;, 12, Bielefeld: IKG.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diekmann, I. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt; (IKG Working Paper, 12). Bielefeld: IKG.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Diekmann, I. (2017): Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene. Bielefeld: IKG.</wels>
<apa>Diekmann, I. (2017).  &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt; (IKG Working Paper, 12). Bielefeld: IKG.</apa>
<harvard1>Diekmann, I., 2017. &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;, IKG Working Paper, no.12, Bielefeld: IKG.</harvard1>
<ieee> I. Diekmann, &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;, IKG Working Paper, vol. 12,  Bielefeld: IKG, 2017.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Diekmann, &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;, Ikg, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Diekmann I (2017) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;. IKG Working Paper; 12.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: IKG.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diekmann, I. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt; (IKG Working Paper). Bielefeld: IKG.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Diekmann, I.: Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene. IKG Working Paper, 12. IKG, Bielefeld (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Diekmann, Isabell. 2017. &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12. IKG Working Paper. Bielefeld: IKG.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Diekmann I. &lt;em&gt;Islamfeindlichkeit oder MuslimInnenfeindlichkeit? Empirische Datenanalyse zur Differenzierung zweier Phänomene&lt;/em&gt;. IKG Working Paper. Vol 12. Bielefeld: IKG; 2017.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2916283</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-01-03T09:39:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-05-21T12:15:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>