<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2917709</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kühl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4312658</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Margit</namePart><namePart type="family">Szöllösi-Janze</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kühl,_Stefan,_2001,_The_Relationship_between_Eugenics_and_the_so-called_Euthanasia_Action_in_Nazi_Germany.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2917709/2917710/Kühl,_Stefan,_2001,_The_Relationship_between_Eugenics_and_the_so-called_Euthanasia_Action_in_Nazi_Germany.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Berg</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Science in the Third Reich</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">1-85973-421-9</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29177096</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><extent unit="pages">185-210</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Kühl, S. (2001). The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In M.  Szöllösi-Janze (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;German historical perspectives series: Vol. 12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 185-210). Oxford: Berg.</apa>
<ieee> S. Kühl, “The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War”, &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;, M. Szöllösi-Janze, ed., German historical perspectives series, vol. 12,  Oxford: Berg, 2001,  pp.185-210.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kühl, S., 2001. The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In M.  Szöllösi-Janze, ed. &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;. German historical perspectives series. no.12  Oxford: Berg, pp. 185-210.</harvard1>
<default>Kühl S (2001)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Science in the Third Reich. Szöllösi-Janze M (Ed);  German historical perspectives series, 12.  Oxford: Berg:  185-210.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (2001). The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In M.  Szöllösi-Janze (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;German historical perspectives series: Vol. 12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 185-210). Oxford: Berg.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kühl, Stefan. “The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War”. &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Margit Szöllösi-Janze. Oxford: Berg, 2001.Vol. 12. German historical perspectives series. 185-210.</mla>
<frontiers>Kühl, S. (2001). “The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War” in &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;, Szöllösi-Janze, M. ed. German historical perspectives series, vol. 12, (Oxford: Berg), 185-210.</frontiers>
<wels>Kühl, S. (2001): The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In: Margit Szöllösi-Janze (Hrsg.):  Science in the Third Reich. Oxford: Berg. (German historical perspectives series, 12).  S. 185-210.</wels>
<lncs> Kühl, S.: The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In: Szöllösi-Janze, M. (ed.) Science in the Third Reich. German historical perspectives series. 12, p. 185-210. Berg, Oxford (2001).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, Stefan. 2001. “The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War”. In &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Margit Szöllösi-Janze, 12:185-210. German historical perspectives series. Oxford: Berg.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Kühl S. The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. In: Szöllösi-Janze M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt;. German historical perspectives series. Vol 12. Oxford: Berg;  2001: 185-210.</ama>
<bio1>Kühl S (2001) &lt;br /&gt;The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Science in the Third Reich. Szöllösi-Janze M (Ed); German historical perspectives series, 12. Oxford: Berg:  185-210.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kühl, in &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: M. Szöllösi-Janze), Berg, Oxford, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 185-210.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (2001). The Relationship between Eugenics and the so-called Euthanasia Action in Nazi Germany: A Eugenically Motivated Peace Policy and the Killing of Mentally Handicapped during the Second World War (German historical perspectives series). In M. Szöllösi-Janze (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Science in the Third Reich&lt;/em&gt; (S. 185-210). Oxford: Berg.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2917709</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-02-16T11:00:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>