<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2917713</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kühl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4312658</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michael</namePart><namePart type="family">Berenbaum</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Abraham J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Peck</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kühl,_Stefan,_1998,_The_Cooperation_of_German_Racial_Hygienists_and_American_Eugenicists_before_and_after_1933.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2917713/2917714/Kühl,_Stefan,_1998,_The_Cooperation_of_German_Racial_Hygienists_and_American_Eugenicists_before_and_after_1933.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Indiana University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-253-33374-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29177136</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">134-151</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Kühl, S., 1998. The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In M.  Berenbaum &amp;amp; A. J.  Peck, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;.  Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press, pp. 134-151.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Kühl, “The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933”, &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;, M. Berenbaum and A.J. Peck, eds.,  Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press, 1998,  pp.134-151.</ieee>
<apa>Kühl, S. (1998). The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In M.  Berenbaum &amp;amp; A. J.  Peck (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 134-151). Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press.</apa>
<wels>Kühl, S. (1998): The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In: Michael Berenbaum; Abraham J. Peck (Hrsg.):  The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined. Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press.  S. 134-151.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (1998). The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In M.  Berenbaum &amp;amp; A. J.  Peck (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 134-151). Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kühl, Stefan. “The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933”. &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Michael Berenbaum and Abraham J. Peck. Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press, 1998. 134-151.</mla>
<frontiers>Kühl, S. (1998). “The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933” in &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;, Berenbaum, M., and Peck, A. J. eds. (Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press), 134-151.</frontiers>
<default>Kühl S (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined. Berenbaum M, Peck AJ (Eds);  Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press:  134-151.</default>
<ama>Kühl S. The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In: Berenbaum M, Peck AJ, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;. Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press;  1998: 134-151.</ama>
<lncs> Kühl, S.: The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In: Berenbaum, M. and Peck, A.J. (eds.) The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined. p. 134-151. Indiana University Press, Bloomington, Indianapolis (1998).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, Stefan. 1998. “The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933”. In &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Michael Berenbaum and Abraham J. Peck, 134-151. Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kühl, S. (1998). The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. In M. Berenbaum &amp;amp; A.J. Peck (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt; (S. 134-151). Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kühl, in &lt;em&gt;The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Berenbaum, A.J. Peck), Indiana University Press, Bloomington, Indianapolis, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 134-151.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kühl S (1998) &lt;br /&gt;The Cooperation of German Racial Hygienists and American Eugenicists Before and After 1933. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Holocaust and History. The Known, the Unknown, the Disputed and the Reexamined. Berenbaum M, Peck AJ (Eds); Bloomington, Indianapolis: Indiana University Press:  134-151.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2917713</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-02-16T11:09:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>