<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2917260</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan-Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lamm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">24699806</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yury</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vishnevskiy</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">24700277</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eric</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ziemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Beate</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20154</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Georg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stammler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20167</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norbert W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mitzel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4468926</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17966</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Reactions between 1,8-dichloroanthracenes with substituents in position 10 and ortho-chloroaryne afford mixtures of 1,8,13- (syn) and 1,8,16-trichlorotriptycenes (anti). The syn/anti ratio is dependent on these substituents. Electropositive substituents like SiMe3 and GeMe3 lead to preferred formation of the syn-isomer, whereas CMe3 groups exclusively afford the anti-isomer. Different quantum chemical calculations including location of transition states give conflicting results, but indicate the importance of dispersion forces for an at least qualitative prediction of results. The syn-trichlorotriptycenes with SiMe3 and GeMe3 substituents were characterized by using NMR spectroscopy, mass spectrometry, and X-ray diffraction experiments.

Triptycene represents one of a few rigid organic frameworks of D3h symmetry without any (Lewis-basic) heteroatoms. It was first synthesized by Bartlett et al. in 1942 using a multi-step procedure starting from anthracene and p-benzoquinone.[1] In 1956, Wittig and Ludwig reported a more efficient access to triptycene in one step from anthracene by reacting it with in situ-formed benzyne.[2] The symmetry and rigidity of triptycene have inspired a plethora of applications in fundamental and applied chemical research.[3-5] Substituted triptycenes are widely used, for example, as building blocks for fluorescent or non-fluorescent organic macromolecules, polymers, and liquid crystals,[3, 6] as rigid spacers in several Pd complexes used for cross coupling reactions,[7] as devices in molecular machines,[8] in crystal engineering processes,[9, 10] and as a basis for the design of highly porous organic materials with numerous applications.[11]

Although the chemistry of triptycenes and their functionalization is generally in an advanced state, the 1,8,13-trisubstitution motif remains a challenge for synthesis. However, exactly this pattern is interesting to introduce three functionalities oriented in the same direction. We try to make use of such 1,8,13-trisubstituted triptycenes (also called syn-triptycenes) as rigid organic frameworks for constructing directed polydentate Lewis acids,[12, 13] but many other applications might be envisioned.

syn-Triptycenes can be obtained through Diels–Alder reactions of 1,8-disubstituted anthracenes with ortho-functionalized arynes, a protocol introduced by Rogers and Averill in 1986.[14] The drawback of this method is that the corresponding anti-trisubstituted 1,8,16-isomer is always formed as the main product when, for example, Cl-functionalized anthracenes and arynes are used.[12, 14] In 2010, we reported attempts to increase the syn/anti ratio by making use of the steric interference of the (bulky) anthracene substituent at C-10 with the chlorine atom of the chloroaryne (Scheme 1). We expected this strategy to provide an increased formation of the syn-isomer. However, the steric influence of the C-10 substituent turned out to be minimal, whereas the electronic properties are dominant;[12] of all substituents tested, the biggest R=C(CH3)3 led to the formation of 100 % anti-isomer, despite the formation of an extremely deformed product by mutual repulsion of the Cl and R substituents, as indicated in Scheme 1 b.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Lamm_et_al-2018-ChemistryOpen.mitzel.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2917260/2917262/Lamm_et_al-2018-ChemistryOpen.mitzel.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ChemistryOpen</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2191-1363</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29344439</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000423763200012</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29172607</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/open.201700196</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">111-114</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J. - H.  Lamm, Y.  Vishnevskiy, E.  Ziemann, B.  Neumann, H. - G.  Stammler, and N. W.  Mitzel, “Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors”, &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 111-114.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lamm, J. - H., Vishnevskiy, Y., Ziemann, E., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Mitzel, N. W. (2018). Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-114. doi:10.1002/open.201700196&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Lamm J-H, Vishnevskiy Y, Ziemann E, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Mitzel NW (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors.&lt;br /&gt;ChemistryOpen 7(1): 111-114.</bio1>
<harvard1>Lamm, J.-H., et al., 2018. Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;, 7(1), p 111-114.</harvard1>
<wels>Lamm, J. - H.; Vishnevskiy, Y.; Ziemann, E.; Neumann, B.; Stammler, H. - G.; Mitzel, N. W. (2018): Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;,7:(1): 111-114.</wels>
<ieee> J.-H. Lamm, et al., “Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors”, &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2018,  pp. 111-114.</ieee>
<apa>Lamm, J. - H., Vishnevskiy, Y., Ziemann, E., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Mitzel, N. W. (2018). Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-114. doi:10.1002/open.201700196</apa>
<frontiers>Lamm, J. - H., Vishnevskiy, Y., Ziemann, E., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., and Mitzel, N. W. (2018). Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt; 7, 111-114.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lamm, J.-H., Vishnevskiy, Y., Ziemann, E., Neumann, B., Stammler, H.-G. &amp;amp; Mitzel, N.W. (2018). Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-114. Wiley-Blackwell. doi:10.1002/open.201700196.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Lamm J-H, Vishnevskiy Y, Ziemann E, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Mitzel NW. Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;7(1):111-114.</ama>
<default>Lamm J-H, Vishnevskiy Y, Ziemann E, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Mitzel NW (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt; 7(1): 111-114.</default>
<mla>Lamm, Jan-Hendrik, Vishnevskiy, Yury, Ziemann, Eric, Neumann, Beate, Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Mitzel, Norbert W. “Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors”. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt; 7.1 (2018): 111-114.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lamm, Jan-Hendrik, Vishnevskiy, Yury, Ziemann, Eric, Neumann, Beate, Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Mitzel, Norbert W. 2018. “Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors”. &lt;em&gt;ChemistryOpen&lt;/em&gt; 7 (1): 111-114.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lamm, J.-H., Vishnevskiy, Y., Ziemann, E., Neumann, B., Stammler, H.-G., Mitzel, N.W.: Regiochemical Control in Triptycene Formation-An Exercise in Subtle Balancing Multiple Factors. ChemistryOpen. 7, 111-114 (2018).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2917260</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-02-01T10:03:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T12:36:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>