<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2918683</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaiser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">25328236</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">René</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Griessl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32916230</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagemeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">30629226</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jungewelter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26309520</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">96183421</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sarah</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pilz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">96183218</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Porrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32337297</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1005-5753</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Micha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">vor dem Berge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krupop</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Super Computing SC'17</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="h2rc_2017_abstract_mkaiser_heterogeneous_microserver.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2918683/2918687/h2rc_2017_abstract_mkaiser_heterogeneous_microserver.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, CO</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>HPC, Cloud Computing, Heterogeneous Microserver, Accelerator, OpenCL, High-Speed Low Latency Communication, Energy Efficiency, Scale-Out Server</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29186831</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaiser, M., Griessl, R., Hagemeyer, J., Jungewelter, D., Porrmann, F., Pilz, S., Porrmann, M., vor dem Berge, M. &amp;amp; Krupop, S. (2017). A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der Super Computing SC'17, Denver, CO.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Kaiser, R.  Griessl, J.  Hagemeyer, D.  Jungewelter, F.  Porrmann, S.  Pilz, M.  Porrmann, M.  vor dem Berge, and S.  Krupop, in &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;, Denver, CO, &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kaiser M, Griessl R, Hagemeyer J, Jungewelter D, Porrmann F, Pilz S, Porrmann M, vor dem Berge M, Krupop S (2017) &lt;br /&gt;A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17).  Denver, CO.</bio1>
<ama>Kaiser M, Griessl R, Hagemeyer J, et al. A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. In:  &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;. Denver, CO;  2017.</ama>
<lncs> Kaiser, M., Griessl, R., Hagemeyer, J., Jungewelter, D., Porrmann, F., Pilz, S., Porrmann, M., vor dem Berge, M., Krupop, S.: A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17).  Denver, CO (2017).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaiser, Martin, Griessl, René, Hagemeyer, Jens, Jungewelter, Dirk, Porrmann, Florian, Pilz, Sarah, Porrmann, Mario, vor dem Berge, Micha, and Krupop, Stefan. 2017. “A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing”. In &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;. Denver, CO.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Kaiser, M.; Griessl, R.; Hagemeyer, J.; Jungewelter, D.; Porrmann, F.; Pilz, S.; Porrmann, M.; vor dem Berge, M.; Krupop, S. (2017): A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. In: Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17). Denver, CO.</wels>
<frontiers>Kaiser, M., Griessl, R., Hagemeyer, J., Jungewelter, D., Porrmann, F., Pilz, S., Porrmann, M., vor dem Berge, M., and Krupop, S. (2017). “A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing” in &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt; (Denver, CO).</frontiers>
<mla>Kaiser, Martin, Griessl, René, Hagemeyer, Jens, Jungewelter, Dirk, Porrmann, Florian, Pilz, Sarah, Porrmann, Mario, vor dem Berge, Micha, and Krupop, Stefan. “A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing”. &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;. Denver, CO, 2017.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kaiser, M., Griessl, R., Hagemeyer, J., Jungewelter, D., Porrmann, F., Pilz, S., Porrmann, M., et al. (2017). A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt; Denver, CO.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Kaiser M, Griessl R, Hagemeyer J, Jungewelter D, Porrmann F, Pilz S, Porrmann M, vor dem Berge M, Krupop S (2017)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17). Denver, CO.</default>
<harvard1>Kaiser, M., et al., 2017. A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. In &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;.  Denver, CO.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Kaiser, et al., “A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing”, &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt;,  Denver, CO: 2017.</ieee>
<apa>Kaiser, M., Griessl, R., Hagemeyer, J., Jungewelter, D., Porrmann, F., Pilz, S., Porrmann, M., et al. (2017). A Reconfigurable Heterogeneous Microserver Architecture for Energy-efficient Computing. &lt;em&gt;Third International Workshop on Heterogeneous High-performance Reconfigurable Computing (H2RC'17)&lt;/em&gt; Denver, CO.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2918683</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-03-20T09:31:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>