<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2918436</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Denise Margaret</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Matias</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cleovi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mosuela</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">47818411</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The frequency and intensity of natural disasters from climate events have been increasing in
the last few years. While scientists are careful in causally linking these natural disasters to
climate change, the record-breaking extreme climate events such as typhoon Haiyan in the
Philippines speak for itself. Formerly a laggard in climate talks, adaptation has now gained
footing not just in the UNFCCC but also among different countries. Decision 1/CP.16 also
known as The Cancun Agreements invites all parties to the UNFCCC to enhance action on
adaptation and undertake measures with regard to climate change induced displacement
and migration. It is exactly this COP decision, which motivated the governments of Norway
and Switzerland to establish the Nansen Initiative and craft a protection agenda for people
who are at risk of disaster-induced cross-border displacement. Despite these efforts, there
has yet to be a legally binding migration treaty that climate change victims can invoke. In this
paper, we will look into the feasibility of immigration opportunities as humanitarian aid for
victims of extreme climate events. Inspired by US and Canada immigration relief measures
for typhoon Haiyan victims in the Philippines, we use a socio-political approach in constructing
an immigration humanitarian model, which we would like to recommend as a potential
humanitarian intervention after climate disasters. This recommendation is not only intended
to address UNFCCC’s Decision 2/CP.19 (the Warsaw International Mechanism on Loss and
Damage) but to also provoke ambition and compassion from countries that are historically
responsible for climate change.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ssoar-2016-matias_et_al-International_migration_opportunities_as_post-disaster.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2918436/2918437/ssoar-2016-matias_et_al-International_migration_opportunities_as_post-disaster.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29184368</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>141</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Matias, D.M. &amp;amp; Mosuela, C. (2016). &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers). Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Matias DM, Mosuela C (2016) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers; 141.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D. M.  Matias, and C.  Mosuela, &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;, Centre On Migration, Citizenship And Development (Comcad), Fakultät Für Soziologie, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Matias DM, Mosuela C. &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers. Vol 141. Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie; 2016.</ama>
<aps> D. M.  Matias and C.  Mosuela, International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers (Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie, Bielefeld, 2016).</aps>
<lncs> Matias, D.M., Mosuela, C.: International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 141. Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie, Bielefeld (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Matias, Denise Margaret, and Mosuela, Cleovi. 2016. &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 141. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers. Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Matias, Denise Margaret, and Mosuela, Cleovi. &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie, 2016. COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers. 141.</mla>
<frontiers>Matias, D. M., and Mosuela, C. (2016). International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention. &lt;em&gt;COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 141, Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Matias, D. M., &amp;amp; Mosuela, C. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 141). Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Matias, D. M.; Mosuela, C. (2016): International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention. Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</wels>
<default>Matias DM, Mosuela C (2016)  COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers; 141.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</default>
<ieee> D.M. Matias and C. Mosuela, &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, vol. 141,  Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie, 2016.</ieee>
<harvard1>Matias, D.M., &amp;amp; Mosuela, C., 2016. &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt;, COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, no.141, Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</harvard1>
<apa>Matias, D. M., &amp;amp; Mosuela, C. (2016).  &lt;em&gt;International migration opportunities as post-disaster humanitarian intervention&lt;/em&gt; (COMCAD Arbeitspapiere - Working Papers, 141). Bielefeld: Centre on Migration, Citizenship and Development (COMCAD), Fakultät für Soziologie.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2918436</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-03-08T12:47:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>