<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2918157</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Risto</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kõiva</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">143311</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7219-775X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schwank</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Guillaume</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Walck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">48012793</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33056</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5842-9991</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Deep Familiarization and Learning Grounded in Cooperative manual Action and Language - from Analysis to Implementation (FAMULA, LSP-02)</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">Our fingernails help us to accomplish a variety of manual tasks, but surprisingly only a few robotic hands are equipped with nails. In this paper, we present a sensorized fingernail for mechatronic hands that can capture static and dynamic interaction forces with the nail. Over the course of several iterations, we have developed a very compact working prototype that fits together with our previously developed multi-cell tactile fingertip sensor into the cavity of the distal phalange of a human-sized robotic hand. We present the construction details, list the key performance characteristics and demonstrate an example application of finding the end of an adhesive tape roll using the signals captured by the sensors integrated in the nail. We conclude with a discussion about improvement ideas for future versions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Mechatronic Fingernail.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2918157/2931337/Mechatronic Fingernail.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Madrid, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Force and Tactile Sensing</topic><topic>Multifingered Hands</topic><topic>Dexterous Manipulation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29181570</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/IROS.2018.8594207</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> R. Kõiva, et al., “Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing”, &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;, 2018.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kõiva, R., et al., 2018. Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. In &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa>Kõiva, R., Schwank, T., Walck, G., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2018). Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1109/IROS.2018.8594207</apa>
<wels>Kõiva, R.; Schwank, T.; Walck, G.; Haschke, R.; Ritter, H. (2018): Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. In: International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).</wels>
<mla>Kõiva, Risto, Schwank, Tobias, Walck, Guillaume, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. “Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing”. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. 2018.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kõiva, R., Schwank, T., Walck, G., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2018). Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1109/IROS.2018.8594207&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kõiva, R., Schwank, T., Walck, G., Haschke, R., and Ritter, H. (2018). “Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing” in &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<default>Kõiva R, Schwank T, Walck G, Haschke R, Ritter H (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).</default>
<ama>Kõiva R, Schwank T, Walck G, Haschke R, Ritter H. Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. In:  &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. 2018.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kõiva, Risto, Schwank, Tobias, Walck, Guillaume, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. 2018. “Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing”. In &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kõiva, R., Schwank, T., Walck, G., Haschke, R., Ritter, H.: Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS).  (2018).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kõiva, R., Schwank, T., Walck, G., Haschke, R. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2018). Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). doi:10.1109/IROS.2018.8594207.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kõiva R, Schwank T, Walck G, Haschke R, Ritter H (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Mechatronic fingernail with static and dynamic force sensing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Kõiva, T.  Schwank, G.  Walck, R.  Haschke, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2918157</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-02-23T14:37:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-03T11:24:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>