<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2918982</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Korthals</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42006529</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4297-7197</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mikkel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kragh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Christiansen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Henrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Karstoft</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rasmus N.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jørgensen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Today, agricultural vehicles are available that can automatically perform tasks such as weed detection and spraying, mowing, and sowing while being steered automatically. However, for such systems to be fully autonomous and self-driven, not only their specific agricultural tasks must be automated. An accurate and robust perception system automatically detecting and avoiding all obstacles must also be realized to ensure safety of humans, animals, and other surroundings. In this paper, we present a multi-modal obstacle and environment detection and recognition approach for process evaluation in agricultural fields. The proposed pipeline detects and maps static and dynamic obstacles globally, while providing process-relevant information along the traversed trajectory. Detection algorithms are introduced for a variety of sensor technologies, including range sensors (lidar and radar) and cameras (stereo and thermal). Detection information is mapped globally into semantical occupancy grid maps and fused across all sensors with late fusion, resulting in accurate traversability assessment and semantical mapping of process-relevant categories (e.g., crop, ground, and obstacles). Finally, a decoding step uses a Hidden Markov model to extract relevant process-specific parameters along the trajectory of the vehicle, thus informing a potential control system of unexpected structures in the planned path. The method is evaluated on a public dataset for multi-modal obstacle detection in agricultural fields. Results show that a combination of multiple sensor modalities increases detection performance and that different fusion strategies must be applied between algorithms detecting similar and dissimilar classes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="frobt-05-00028.korthals.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2918982/2918983/frobt-05-00028.korthals.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Robotics and AI</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2296-9144</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33500915</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000428446600002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29189826</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/frobt.2018.00028</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Korthals, T.; Kragh, M.; Christiansen, P.; Karstoft, H.; Jørgensen, R. N.; Rückert, U. (2018): Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;,5:26</wels>
<mla>Korthals, Timo, Kragh, Mikkel, Christiansen, Peter, Karstoft, Henrik, Jørgensen, Rasmus N., and Rückert, Ulrich. “Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt; 5 (2018): 26.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, T., Kragh, M., Christiansen, P., Karstoft, H., Jørgensen, R. N., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2018). Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 26. doi:10.3389/frobt.2018.00028&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Korthals, T., Kragh, M., Christiansen, P., Karstoft, H., Jørgensen, R. N., and Rückert, U. (2018). Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt; 5:26.</frontiers>
<default>Korthals T, Kragh M, Christiansen P, Karstoft H, Jørgensen RN, Rückert U (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt; 5: 26.</default>
<harvard1>Korthals, T., et al., 2018. Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, 5: 26.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Korthals, et al., “Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 5, 2018, : 26.</ieee>
<apa>Korthals, T., Kragh, M., Christiansen, P., Karstoft, H., Jørgensen, R. N., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2018). Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 26. doi:10.3389/frobt.2018.00028</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, T., Kragh, M., Christiansen, P., Karstoft, H., Jørgensen, R.N. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2018). Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;: 26. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/frobt.2018.00028.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Korthals, M.  Kragh, P.  Christiansen, H.  Karstoft, R. N.  Jørgensen, and U.  Rückert, “Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, : 26.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Korthals T, Kragh M, Christiansen P, Karstoft H, Jørgensen RN, Rückert U (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI 5: 26.</bio1>
<ama>Korthals T, Kragh M, Christiansen P, Karstoft H, Jørgensen RN, Rückert U. Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;5: 26.</ama>
<lncs> Korthals, T., Kragh, M., Christiansen, P., Karstoft, H., Jørgensen, R.N., Rückert, U.: Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation. Frontiers in Robotics and AI. 5, : 26 (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, Timo, Kragh, Mikkel, Christiansen, Peter, Karstoft, Henrik, Jørgensen, Rasmus N., and Rückert, Ulrich. 2018. “Multi-Modal Detection and Mapping of Static and Dynamic Obstacles in Agriculture for Process Evaluation”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt; 5: 26.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2918982</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-04-04T08:25:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-09T10:27:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>