<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2919957</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer zu Borgsen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">50802023</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0887-5672</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Renner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">39272387</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9640-8291</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thies</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfeiffer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182991</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6619-749X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="main.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2919957/2932326/main.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Chicago</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29199579</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2919957</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Renner, P., Lier, F., Pfeiffer, T., and Wachsmuth, S. (2018). “Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques” in &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Renner, P., Lier, F., Pfeiffer, T. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2018). Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. doi:10.4119/unibi/2919957.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Meyer zu Borgsen S, Renner P, Lier F, Pfeiffer T, Wachsmuth S. Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. In:  &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. 2018.</ama>
<ieee> S. Meyer zu Borgsen, et al., “Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques”, &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Renner, P., Lier, F., Pfeiffer, T., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2018). Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.4119/unibi/2919957</apa>
<wels>Meyer zu Borgsen, S.; Renner, P.; Lier, F.; Pfeiffer, T.; Wachsmuth, S. (2018): Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. In: VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Meyer zu Borgsen, P.  Renner, F.  Lier, T.  Pfeiffer, and S.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Meyer zu Borgsen, S., et al., 2018. Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. In &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Renner, P., Lier, F., Pfeiffer, T., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, S. (2018). Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.4119/unibi/2919957&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Meyer zu Borgsen S, Renner P, Lier F, Pfeiffer T, Wachsmuth S (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. &lt;br /&gt;In:  VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings. .</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Renner, Patrick, Lier, Florian, Pfeiffer, Thies, and Wachsmuth, Sven. 2018. “Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques”. In &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Renner, P., Lier, F., Pfeiffer, T., Wachsmuth, S.: Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques. VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings.  (2018).</lncs>
<default>Meyer zu Borgsen S, Renner P, Lier F, Pfeiffer T, Wachsmuth S (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings.</default>
<mla>Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Renner, Patrick, Lier, Florian, Pfeiffer, Thies, and Wachsmuth, Sven. “Improving Human-Robot Handover Research by Mixed Reality Techniques”. &lt;em&gt;VAM-HRI 2018. The Inaugural International Workshop on Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality for Human-Robot Interaction. Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. 2018.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2919957</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-05-22T12:15:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-22T10:17:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>