<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2920106</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:590</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anastasia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klimova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfredo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ortega-Rubio</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vendrami</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60621733</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joseph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoffman</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23351084</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5895-8949</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Comparative studies can provide powerful insights into processes that affect population divergence and thereby help to elucidate the mechanisms by which contemporary populations may respond to environmental change. Furthermore, approaches such as genotyping by sequencing (GBS) provide unprecedented power for resolving genetic differences among species and populations. We therefore used GBS to provide a genomewide perspective on the comparative population structure of two palm genera, Washingtonia and Brahea, on the Baja California peninsula, a region of high landscape and ecological complexity. First, we used phylogenetic analysis to address taxonomic uncertainties among five currently recognized species. We resolved three main clades, the first corresponding to W. robusta and W. filifera, the second to B. brandegeei and B. armata, and the third to B. edulis from Guadalupe Island. Focusing on the first two clades, we then delved deeper by investigating the underlying population structure. Striking differences were found, with GBS uncovering four distinct Washingtonia populations and identifying a suite of loci associated with temperature, consistent with ecologically mediated divergence. By contrast, individual mountain ranges could be resolved in Brahea and few loci were associated with environmental variables, implying a more prominent role of neutral divergence. Finally, evidence was found for long‐distance dispersal events in Washingtonia but not Brahea, in line with knowledge of the dispersal mechanisms of these palms including the possibility of human‐mediated dispersal. Overall, our study demonstrates the power of GBS together with a comparative approach to elucidate markedly different patterns of genomewide divergence mediated by multiple effectors.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Klimova_et_al-2018-Ecology_and_Evolution(1).hoffman.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2920106/2920107/Klimova_et_al-2018-Ecology_and_Evolution(1).hoffman.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ecology and Evolution</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2045-7758</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29938100</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000435776600057</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29201060</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/ece3.4125</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>11</number></detail><extent unit="pages">5873-5890</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2935718</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Klimova, A., Ortega-Rubio, A., Vendrami, D., Hoffman, J.: Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. Ecology and Evolution. 8, 5873-5890 (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, Anastasia, Ortega-Rubio, Alfredo, Vendrami, David, and Hoffman, Joseph. 2018. “Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 8 (11): 5873-5890.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Klimova, Anastasia, Ortega-Rubio, Alfredo, Vendrami, David, and Hoffman, Joseph. “Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 8.11 (2018): 5873-5890.</mla>
<default>Klimova A, Ortega-Rubio A, Vendrami D, Hoffman J (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 8(11): 5873-5890.</default>
<ama>Klimova A, Ortega-Rubio A, Vendrami D, Hoffman J. Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;8(11):5873-5890.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, A., Ortega-Rubio, A., Vendrami, D. &amp;amp; Hoffman, J. (2018). Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(11), 5873-5890. Wiley. doi:10.1002/ece3.4125.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Klimova, A., Ortega-Rubio, A., Vendrami, D., and Hoffman, J. (2018). Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 8, 5873-5890.</frontiers>
<apa>Klimova, A., Ortega-Rubio, A., Vendrami, D., &amp;amp; Hoffman, J. (2018). Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(11), 5873-5890. doi:10.1002/ece3.4125</apa>
<ieee> A. Klimova, et al., “Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2018,  pp. 5873-5890.</ieee>
<wels>Klimova, A.; Ortega-Rubio, A.; Vendrami, D.; Hoffman, J. (2018): Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,8:(11): 5873-5890.</wels>
<bio1>Klimova A, Ortega-Rubio A, Vendrami D, Hoffman J (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms.&lt;br /&gt;Ecology and Evolution 8(11): 5873-5890.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klimova, A., Ortega-Rubio, A., Vendrami, D., &amp;amp; Hoffman, J. (2018). Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(11), 5873-5890. doi:10.1002/ece3.4125&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Klimova, A., et al., 2018. Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, 8(11), p 5873-5890.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Klimova, A.  Ortega-Rubio, D.  Vendrami, and J.  Hoffman, “Genotyping by sequencing reveals contrasting patterns of population structure, ecologically mediated divergence, and long-distance dispersal in North American palms”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 5873-5890.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2920106</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-05-28T12:24:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T12:36:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>