<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2920199</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kluth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">54885831</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Holger</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schultheis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marco</namePart><namePart type="family">Idiart</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alessandro</namePart><namePart type="family">Lenci</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thierry</namePart><namePart type="family">Poibeau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Aline</namePart><namePart type="family">Villavicencio</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015562</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing, co-located with the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present two methods that improve the assessment of cognitive models. The first method is applicable to models computing average acceptability ratings. For these models, we propose an extension that simulates a full rating distribution (instead of average ratings) and allows generating individual ratings. Our second method enables Bayesian inference for models generating individual data. To this end, we propose to use the cross-match test (Rosenbaum, 2005) as a likelihood function. We exemplarily present both methods using cognitive models from the domain of spatial language use. For spatial language use, determining linguistic acceptability judgments of a spatial preposition for a depicted spatial relation is assumed to be a crucial process (Logan and Sadler, 1996). Existing models of this process compute an average acceptability rating. We extend the models and – based on existing data – show that the extended models allow extracting more information from the empirical data and yield more readily interpretable information about model successes and failures. Applying Bayesian inference, we find that model performance relies less on mechanisms of capturing geometrical aspects than on mapping the captured geometry to a rating interval.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="acl2018_workshop_long.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2920199/2920200/acl2018_workshop_long.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Melbourne, Australia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cognitive modeling</topic><topic>linguistic judgments</topic><topic>Bayesian inference</topic><topic>spatial language</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29201995</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">47 - 55</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2918231</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Kluth, Thomas, and Schultheis, Holger. “Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Marco Idiart, Alessandro Lenci, Thierry Poibeau, and Aline Villavicencio. Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2018. 47-55.</mla>
<default>Kluth T, Schultheis H (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing. Idiart M, Lenci A, Poibeau T, Villavicencio A (Eds);  Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics:  47-55.</default>
<lncs> Kluth, T., Schultheis, H.: Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In: Idiart, M., Lenci, A., Poibeau, T., and Villavicencio, A. (eds.) Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing. p. 47-55. Association for Computational Linguistics, Melbourne, Australia (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, Thomas, and Schultheis, Holger. 2018. “Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Marco Idiart, Alessandro Lenci, Thierry Poibeau, and Aline Villavicencio, 47-55. Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Kluth T, Schultheis H (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing. Idiart M, Lenci A, Poibeau T, Villavicencio A (Eds); Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics:  47-55.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Schultheis, H. (2018). Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In M.  Idiart, A.  Lenci, T.  Poibeau, &amp;amp; A.  Villavicencio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 47-55). Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Schultheis, H., 2018. Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In M.  Idiart, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;.  Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 47-55.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Kluth, and H.  Schultheis, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: M. Idiart, A. Lenci, T. Poibeau, A. Villavicencio), Association For Computational Linguistics, Melbourne, Australia, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 47-55.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Kluth, T.; Schultheis, H. (2018): Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In: Marco Idiart; Alessandro Lenci; Thierry Poibeau; Aline Villavicencio (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing. Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 47-55.</wels>
<apa>Kluth, T., &amp;amp; Schultheis, H. (2018). Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In M.  Idiart, A.  Lenci, T.  Poibeau, &amp;amp; A.  Villavicencio (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 47-55). Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<ieee> T. Kluth and H. Schultheis, “Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;, M. Idiart, et al., eds.,  Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2018,  pp.47-55.</ieee>
<ama>Kluth T, Schultheis H. Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In: Idiart M, Lenci A, Poibeau T, Villavicencio A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;. Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics;  2018: 47-55.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kluth, T. &amp;amp; Schultheis, H. (2018). Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use. In M. Idiart, A. Lenci, T. Poibeau &amp;amp; A. Villavicencio (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt; (S. 47-55). Gehalten auf der Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing, co-located with the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kluth, T., and Schultheis, H. (2018). “Rating Distributions and Bayesian Inference. Enhancing Cognitive Models of Spatial Language Use” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning and Processing&lt;/em&gt;, Idiart, M., Lenci, A., Poibeau, T., and Villavicencio, A. eds. (Melbourne, Australia: Association for Computational Linguistics), 47-55.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2920199</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-05-31T14:51:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-08-26T11:10:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>