<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2920166</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brandt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60898191</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cyra</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Farina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Freigang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36196531</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nicole</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kummert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10372</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Opfermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lars</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schillingmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4357831</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carolin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Straßmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eduard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wall</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62585505</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ramin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Yaghoubzadeh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10271225</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Elizabeth</namePart><namePart type="family">André</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Timothy</namePart><namePart type="family">Bickmore</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefanos</namePart><namePart type="family">Vrochidis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Leo</namePart><namePart type="family">Wanner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>AAMAS 2018 Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Conversational agents can provide valuable cognitive and/or emotional assistance to elderly users or people with cognitive impairments who often have difficulties in organizing and following a structured day schedule. Previous research showed that a virtual assistant that can interact in spoken language would be a desirable help for those users. However, these user groups pose specific requirements for spoken dialogue interaction that existing systems hardly meet. This paper presents work on a virtual conversational assistant that was designed for, and together with, elderly as well as cognitively handicapped users. It has been specifically developed to enable ‘socially cooperative dialogue’ – adaptive and aware conversational interaction in which mutual understanding is co-constructed and ensured collaboratively. The technical approach is described and results of evaluation studies are reported.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Kopp-etal-2018-ICAHoGeCA.pdf.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2920166/2934509/Kopp-etal-2018-ICAHoGeCA.pdf.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>RWTH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stockholm, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>conversational assistants</topic><topic>elderly users</topic><topic>cooperative dialogue</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1613-0073</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29201667</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2338</number></detail><extent unit="pages">10–17</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Kopp S, Brandt M, Buschmeier H, et al. Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In: André E, Bickmore T, Vrochidis S, Wanner L, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. Vol 2338. Aachen: RWTH;  2018: 10–17.</ama>
<lncs> Kopp, S., Brandt, M., Buschmeier, H., Cyra, K., Freigang, F., Krämer, N., Kummert, F., Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Schillingmann, L., Straßmann, C., Wall, E., Yaghoubzadeh, R.: Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In: André, E., Bickmore, T., Vrochidis, S., and Wanner, L. (eds.) Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. 2338, p. 10–17. RWTH, Aachen (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, Stefan, Brandt, Mara, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Cyra, Katharina, Freigang, Farina, Krämer, Nicole, Kummert, Franz, et al. 2018. “Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Elizabeth André, Timothy Bickmore, Stefanos Vrochidis, and Leo Wanner, 2338:10–17. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Kopp, S., Brandt, M., Buschmeier, H., Cyra, K., Freigang, F., Krämer, N., Kummert, F., Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Schillingmann, L., et al. (2018). “Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, André, E., Bickmore, T., Vrochidis, S., and Wanner, L. eds. CEUR Workshop Proceedings, vol. 2338, (Aachen: RWTH), 10–17.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Brandt, M., Buschmeier, H., Cyra, K., Freigang, F., Krämer, N., Kummert, F., Opfermann, C., Pitsch, K., Schillingmann, L., Straßmann, C., Wall, E. &amp;amp; Yaghoubzadeh, R. (2018). Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue (CEUR Workshop Proceedings). In E. André, T. Bickmore, S. Vrochidis &amp;amp; L. Wanner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt; (S. 10–17). Gehalten auf der AAMAS 2018 Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications, Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Kopp, Stefan, Brandt, Mara, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Cyra, Katharina, Freigang, Farina, Krämer, Nicole, Kummert, Franz, Opfermann, Christiane, Pitsch, Karola, Schillingmann, Lars, Straßmann, Carolin, Wall, Eduard, and Yaghoubzadeh, Ramin. “Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Elizabeth André, Timothy Bickmore, Stefanos Vrochidis, and Leo Wanner. Aachen: RWTH, 2018.Vol. 2338. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. 10–17.</mla>
<apa>Kopp, S., Brandt, M., Buschmeier, H., Cyra, K., Freigang, F., Krämer, N., Kummert, F., et al. (2018). Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In E.  André, T.  Bickmore, S.  Vrochidis, &amp;amp; L.  Wanner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;CEUR Workshop Proceedings: Vol. 2338&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt; (p. 10–17). Aachen: RWTH.</apa>
<ieee> S. Kopp, et al., “Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, E. André, et al., eds., CEUR Workshop Proceedings, vol. 2338,  Aachen: RWTH, 2018,  pp.10–17.</ieee>
<default>Kopp S, Brandt M, Buschmeier H, Cyra K, Freigang F, Krämer N, Kummert F, Opfermann C, Pitsch K, Schillingmann L, Straßmann C, et al. (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting. André E, Bickmore T, Vrochidis S, Wanner L (Eds);  CEUR Workshop Proceedings, 2338.  Aachen: RWTH:  10–17.</default>
<wels>Kopp, S.; Brandt, M.; Buschmeier, H.; Cyra, K.; Freigang, F.; Krämer, N.; Kummert, F.; Opfermann, C.; Pitsch, K.; Schillingmann, L.; Straßmann, C.; Wall, E.; Yaghoubzadeh, R. (2018): Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In: Elizabeth André; Timothy Bickmore; Stefanos Vrochidis; Leo Wanner (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting. Aachen: RWTH. (CEUR Workshop Proceedings, 2338).  S. 10–17.</wels>
<harvard1>Kopp, S., et al., 2018. Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In E.  André, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt;. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. no.2338  Aachen: RWTH, pp. 10–17.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kopp, S., Brandt, M., Buschmeier, H., Cyra, K., Freigang, F., Krämer, N., Kummert, F., et al. (2018). Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. In E.  André, T.  Bickmore, S.  Vrochidis, &amp;amp; L.  Wanner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;CEUR Workshop Proceedings: Vol. 2338&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt; (p. 10–17). Aachen: RWTH.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Kopp S, Brandt M, Buschmeier H, Cyra K, Freigang F, Krämer N, Kummert F, Opfermann C, Pitsch K, Schillingmann L, Straßmann C, Wall E, Yaghoubzadeh R (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Conversational Assistants for Elderly Users – The Importance of Socially Cooperative Dialogue. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting. André E, Bickmore T, Vrochidis S, Wanner L (Eds); CEUR Workshop Proceedings, 2338. Aachen: RWTH:  10–17.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kopp, M.  Brandt, H.  Buschmeier, K.  Cyra, F.  Freigang, N.  Krämer, F.  Kummert, C.  Opfermann, K.  Pitsch, L.  Schillingmann, et al., in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the AAMAS Workshop on Intelligent Conversation Agents in Home and Geriatric Care Applications co-located with the Federated AI Meeting&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: E. André, T. Bickmore, S. Vrochidis, L. Wanner), Rwth, Aachen, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 10–17.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2920166</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-05-30T09:10:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-03-27T10:27:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>