<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2921296</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:006</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja Kristina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Philippsen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Recent speech recognition and speech synthesis systems still lack the flexibility and adaptivity of humans beings. There are two main reasons for that: First, they handle recognition and synthesis as separate problems. The link between perception and production is missing, whereas in infants' learning those two modalities are closely interconnected. Second, state-of-the-art systems model the mature system. Infants' speech processing skills, in contrast, develop gradually over time.
In this thesis, I present a model for learning articulatory control that is inspired by the babbling behavior of infants. The implemented system explores in a goal-directed way and learns to produce vowel and syllable sounds with an articulatory speech synthesizer that is based on a three-dimensional vocal tract model.
A focus of this thesis resides on modeling the influence of ambient language on the learning process. A low-dimensional embedding is derived from a set of ambient speech sounds.
In this way, the system's perception is shaped by the speech it is exposed to in its environment.
Using this low-dimensional embedding space as a goal space for goal-directed exploration, the system autonomously learns to produce vowel and syllable sounds that are present in ambient speech. Articulatory trajectories are represented with a dynamic system using articulatory motor primitives. Time variation in the acoustic features is integrated using the model space of a recurrent neural network.
Because of its developmental nature, the implemented framework is not only applicable to speech production in robots, but also a valuable tool for reproducing and investigating aspects of human speech acquisition. Specifically, I examine the influence of infant-directed speech on articulatory learning by training models with different ambient speech backgrounds, and I demonstrate that the learned models, analogously to human listeners, exhibit categorical speech perception.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Philippsen_Dissertation.zip">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2921296/2921297/Philippsen_Dissertation.zip</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/zip</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29212968</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">206 </extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2018-02-28</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Philippsen, Anja Kristina. &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2018.</mla>
<default>Philippsen AK (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<lncs> Philippsen, A.K.: Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Philippsen, Anja Kristina. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Philippsen, A. K. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> A.K. Philippsen, &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2018.</ieee>
<ama>Philippsen AK. &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2018.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Philippsen, A.K. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Philippsen, A. K. (2018). Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Philippsen, A.K., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Philippsen, A. K. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Philippsen AK (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A. K.  Philippsen, &lt;em&gt;Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Philippsen, A. K. (2018): Learning How to Speak. Goal Space Exploration for Articulatory Skill Acquisition. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2921296</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-18T00:16:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T14:50:39Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>