<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2921305</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Muhammad</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakria Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rubeena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mudasir</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mustafa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aisha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jalil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fischer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">35453272</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4388-1245</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Pakistan has the highest rate of stillbirths globally. Not much attention has been given so far to exploring the sociocultural factors hindering the reportage of stillbirths and the causes of death. Therefore, the aim of this study was to assess the perspectives of parents, communities and healthcare providers regarding the sociocultural practices and health system-related factors contributing to stillbirths and their underreporting.
Methods

This study used a qualitative approach including in-depth interviews and 14 focus group discussions to collect data from four districts of Pakistan. We conducted 285 in-depth interviews and 14 focus group discussions with health professionals – mainly active in the areas of maternal and child health – and parents who had experienced stillbirth. Constant comparative method and analytical induction method were performed to analyze the data.
Results

The results of this study show that stillbirth is frequently misclassified and, therefore, an underreported phenomenon in Pakistan. It is an outcome of sociocultural practices, such as the social meaning of stillbirth and their understanding about the conflict between cultural and medical anatomy. In addition to grief and psychological distress, it endangers the maternal identity and worth in society in contrast to the mothers of live-born children.
Conclusion

The misclassification of stillbirth, especially by healthcare providers, is a significant impediment to designing preventive strategies for stillbirth. We recommend that the reporting system for stillbirth should be aligned with the WHO definition of stillbirth to avoid its underreporting. Reporting procedures at a more administrative level need to be made uniform and simplified.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s12884-018-1924-9.fischer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2921305/2921306/s12884-018-1924-9.fischer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Stillbirths</topic><topic>Pakistan</topic><topic>Gestational health</topic><topic>Cause of death</topic><topic>Underreporting</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2393</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30012104</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000438779600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29213052</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12884-018-1924-9</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>18</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Zakria Zakar, M., et al., 2018. Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, 18(18): 302.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Zakria Zakar, et al., “Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2018, : 302.</ieee>
<apa>Zakria Zakar, M., Zakar, R., Mustafa, M., Jalil, A., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(18), 302. doi:10.1186/s12884-018-1924-9</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakria Zakar, M., Zakar, R., Mustafa, M., Jalil, A., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(18), 302. doi:10.1186/s12884-018-1924-9&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Zakria Zakar, Muhammad, Zakar, Rubeena, Mustafa, Mudasir, Jalil, Aisha, and Fischer, Florian. “Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 18.18 (2018): 302.</mla>
<frontiers>Zakria Zakar, M., Zakar, R., Mustafa, M., Jalil, A., and Fischer, F. (2018). Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 18:302.</frontiers>
<wels>Zakria Zakar, M.; Zakar, R.; Mustafa, M.; Jalil, A.; Fischer, F. (2018): Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;,18:(18):302</wels>
<default>Zakria Zakar M, Zakar R, Mustafa M, Jalil A, Fischer F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 18(18): 302.</default>
<ama>Zakria Zakar M, Zakar R, Mustafa M, Jalil A, Fischer F. Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;18(18): 302.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakria Zakar, Muhammad, Zakar, Rubeena, Mustafa, Mudasir, Jalil, Aisha, and Fischer, Florian. 2018. “Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt; 18 (18): 302.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Zakria Zakar, M., Zakar, R., Mustafa, M., Jalil, A., Fischer, F.: Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth. 18, : 302 (2018).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakria Zakar, M., Zakar, R., Mustafa, M., Jalil, A. &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(18): 302. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s12884-018-1924-9.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Zakria Zakar, R.  Zakar, M.  Mustafa, A.  Jalil, and F.  Fischer, “Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 302.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Zakria Zakar M, Zakar R, Mustafa M, Jalil A, Fischer F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Underreporting of stillbirths in Pakistan: perspectives of the parents, community and healthcare providers.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth 18(18): 302.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2921305</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-18T11:51:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>