<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2921311</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rubeena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Muhammad Zakria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zakar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lubna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zaheer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fischer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">35453272</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4388-1245</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Exclusive breastfeeding is significantly associated with strong infant immunity and optimal development. The importance of breastfeeding is underestimated. Parental lack of knowledge and unhealthy practices regarding breastfeeding deprive infants of their basic right to mother’s milk. In developing countries, including Pakistan, with high child mortality and malnutrition, healthy breastfeeding practices can bring positive changes in child health status. From this perspective, the present study aims to understand parents’ knowledge, attitudes and practical encounters with breastfeeding practices and the factors that prevent them from adopting such practices.
Methods

A qualitative study was carried out in both rural and urban settings in Rajanpur District of Punjab Province, Pakistan. We conducted 12 focus-group discussions (FGDs) that involved 38 mothers and 40 fathers with children aged under two years who were being breastfed. A thematic content analysis of data collected through FGDs was performed manually. The themes were both inductive and deductive in nature.
Results

The study found that a majority of participants believed that the first thing given to an infant after birth should not be breast milk but honey, rose flower, or goat’s milk from the hands of an elder in the family or a religious person. No cleanliness measures were practised in this regard. The participants had misconceptions about the benefits of colostrum, which frequently prevented it being given to newborns. Participants reported many factors, such as: insufficient milk syndrome (slow growth of infants due to insufficient daily breast milk intake), a mother’s high workload, lack of social support, the influence of culturally designated advisors, and the promotion and marketing strategies of infant formula companies, that undermined exclusive breastfeeding efforts and encouraged mothers to switch to infant formula.
Conclusions

Culturally acceptable and integrated public health interventions are needed to improve the breastfeeding-related health literacy and practices of parents, grandparents and communities. This will ultimately reduce the high infant mortality and malnutrition rates in Pakistan.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s13006-018-0171-z.fischer.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2921311/2921312/s13006-018-0171-z.fischer.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Exclusive breastfeeding</topic><topic>Parental perceptions</topic><topic>Breastfeeding knowledge</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Breastfeeding Journal</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1746-4358</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29988704</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000437289600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29213111</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13006-018-0171-z</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> R. Zakar, et al., “Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan”, &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 13, 2018, : 24.</ieee>
<harvard1>Zakar, R., et al., 2018. Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;, 13(1): 24.</harvard1>
<apa>Zakar, R., Zakar, M. Z., Zaheer, L., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 24. doi:10.1186/s13006-018-0171-z</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakar, R., Zakar, M. Z., Zaheer, L., &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 24. doi:10.1186/s13006-018-0171-z&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Zakar, Rubeena, Zakar, Muhammad Zakria, Zaheer, Lubna, and Fischer, Florian. “Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan”. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt; 13.1 (2018): 24.</mla>
<frontiers>Zakar, R., Zakar, M. Z., Zaheer, L., and Fischer, F. (2018). Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt; 13:24.</frontiers>
<wels>Zakar, R.; Zakar, M. Z.; Zaheer, L.; Fischer, F. (2018): Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;,13:(1):24</wels>
<default>Zakar R, Zakar MZ, Zaheer L, Fischer F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt; 13(1): 24.</default>
<ama>Zakar R, Zakar MZ, Zaheer L, Fischer F. Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;13(1): 24.</ama>
<lncs> Zakar, R., Zakar, M.Z., Zaheer, L., Fischer, F.: Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. International Breastfeeding Journal. 13, : 24 (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakar, Rubeena, Zakar, Muhammad Zakria, Zaheer, Lubna, and Fischer, Florian. 2018. “Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan”. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt; 13 (1): 24.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zakar, R., Zakar, M.Z., Zaheer, L. &amp;amp; Fischer, F. (2018). Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan. &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1): 24. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s13006-018-0171-z.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Zakar R, Zakar MZ, Zaheer L, Fischer F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan.&lt;br /&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal 13(1): 24.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Zakar, M. Z.  Zakar, L.  Zaheer, and F.  Fischer, “Exploring parental perceptions and knowledge regarding breastfeeding practices in Rajanpur, Punjab Province, Pakistan”, &lt;em&gt;International Breastfeeding Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, : 24.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2921311</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-18T13:10:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>