<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2921397</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Deep throat as a source of information</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mattias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heldner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Włodarczak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Åsa</namePart><namePart type="family">Abelin</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Yasuko</namePart><namePart type="family">Nagano-Madsen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>FONETIK 2018</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="vq.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2921397/2921399/vq.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>sitebuilder/download</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Gothenburg, Sweden</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings  FONETIK 2018</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29213975</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heldner, Mattias, Wagner, Petra, and Włodarczak, Marcin. 2018. “Deep throat as a source of information”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Åsa Abelin and Yasuko Nagano-Madsen. Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Heldner, M., Wagner, P., Włodarczak, M.: Deep throat as a source of information. In: Abelin, Å. and Nagano-Madsen, Y. (eds.) Proceedings  FONETIK 2018.  University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science, Göteborg (2018).</lncs>
<default>Heldner M, Wagner P, Włodarczak M (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings  FONETIK 2018. Abelin Å, Nagano-Madsen Y (Eds);  Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.</default>
<mla>Heldner, Mattias, Wagner, Petra, and Włodarczak, Marcin. “Deep throat as a source of information”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Åsa Abelin and Yasuko Nagano-Madsen. Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science, 2018.</mla>
<wels>Heldner, M.; Wagner, P.; Włodarczak, M. (2018): Deep throat as a source of information. In: Åsa Abelin; Yasuko Nagano-Madsen (Hrsg.):  Proceedings  FONETIK 2018. Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Heldner, P.  Wagner, and M.  Włodarczak, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: Å. Abelin, Y. Nagano-Madsen), University Of Gothenburg, Department Of Languages And Literatures Department Of Philosophy, Linguistics And Theory Of Science, Göteborg, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Heldner M, Wagner P, Włodarczak M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Deep throat as a source of information. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings  FONETIK 2018. Abelin Å, Nagano-Madsen Y (Eds); Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.</bio1>
<harvard1>Heldner, M., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Włodarczak, M., 2018. Deep throat as a source of information. In Å.  Abelin &amp;amp; Y.  Nagano-Madsen, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;.  Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heldner, M., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Włodarczak, M. (2018). Deep throat as a source of information. In Å.  Abelin &amp;amp; Y.  Nagano-Madsen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt; Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Heldner, M., Wagner, P., and Włodarczak, M. (2018). “Deep throat as a source of information” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Abelin, Å., and Nagano-Madsen, Y. eds. (Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Heldner, M., Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Włodarczak, M. (2018). Deep throat as a source of information. In Å. Abelin &amp;amp; Y. Nagano-Madsen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der FONETIK 2018, Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Heldner M, Wagner P, Włodarczak M. Deep throat as a source of information. In: Abelin Å, Nagano-Madsen Y, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science;  2018.</ama>
<ieee> M. Heldner, P. Wagner, and M. Włodarczak, “Deep throat as a source of information”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Å. Abelin and Y. Nagano-Madsen, eds.,  Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Heldner, M., Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Włodarczak, M. (2018). Deep throat as a source of information. In Å.  Abelin &amp;amp; Y.  Nagano-Madsen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings  FONETIK 2018&lt;/em&gt; Göteborg: University of Gothenburg, Department of Languages and Literatures Department of Philosophy, Linguistics and Theory of Science.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2921397</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-23T09:44:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-24T13:01:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>