<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2921144</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Malte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bödeker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32194814</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6376-564X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21334</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Neighborhood walkability contributes to older adults’ walking. However, associations vary depending on the neighborhood definition applied as well as between objective and perceived walkability measures. Therefore, this study aimed to comparatively assess walkability indices for commonly used pedestrian network buffers and perceived neighborhood areas. A total of 97 adults aged ≥65 years answered a written physical activity questionnaire and 69 respondents participated in face-to-face interviews that involved mental mapping, i.e., to draw perceived neighborhood delineations on paper maps. Hierarchical regression analyses were used to compare the contribution of walkability indices for pre-set buffers and self-defined neighborhoods to older adults’ walking after adjusting for covariates. Results show that older adults’ self-defined neighborhoods are significantly larger, less home-centered, and more walkable than commonly used buffers. Furthermore, the variance accounted for in neighborhood walking increased from 35.9% to 40.4% (ΔR2 = 0.046; p = 0.029), when the walkability index was calculated for self-defined neighborhoods rather than pre-set buffers. Therefore, the study supports that geometric differences between pre-set buffers and older adults’ spatial ideas of perceived neighborhoods have a significant influence on estimated walkability effects and that exposure areas should be matched with the spatial dimension of outcome variables in future research.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijerph-15-01363.boedeker.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2921144/2921145/ijerph-15-01363.boedeker.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>older adults</topic><topic>physical activity</topic><topic>walking</topic><topic>built environment</topic><topic>walkability</topic><topic>neighborhood</topic><topic>exposure area</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">29958469</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000445543500069</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29211443</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph15071363</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>15</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>7</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bödeker M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15(7): 1363.</default>
<mla>Bödeker, Malte. “Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15.7 (2018): 1363.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bödeker, Malte. 2018. “Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15 (7): 1363.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bödeker, M.: Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 15, : 1363 (2018).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Bödeker, “Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;, : 1363.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Bödeker, M., 2018. Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 15(7): 1363.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bödeker M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 15(7): 1363.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bödeker, M. (2018). Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1363. doi:10.3390/ijerph15071363&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Bödeker, M. (2018): Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,15:(7):1363</wels>
<ieee> M. Bödeker, “Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 15, 2018, : 1363.</ieee>
<apa>Bödeker, M. (2018). Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1363. doi:10.3390/ijerph15071363</apa>
<frontiers>Bödeker, M. (2018). Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 15:1363.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bödeker, M. (2018). Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(7): 1363. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph15071363.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bödeker M. Walking and Walkability in Pre-Set and Self-Defined Neighborhoods: A Mental Mapping Study in Older Adults. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;15(7): 1363.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2921144</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-07-11T08:11:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-27T10:35:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>