<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930952</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">ter Horst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">36764835</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3244-6595</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">45955539</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6549-066X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart><namePart type="family">d'Amato</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Martin</namePart><namePart type="family">Theobald</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>14th International Reasoning Web Summer School 2018</namePart>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Automatically Populating a Preclinical Spinal Cord Injury Knowledge Base to Support Clinical Translation</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">In this tutorial we discuss how Conditional Random Fields can be applied to knowledge base population tasks. We are in particular interested in the cold-start setting which assumes as given an ontology that models classes and properties relevant for the domain of interest, and an empty knowledge base that needs to be populated from unstructured
text. More specifically, cold-start knowledge base population consists in predicting semantic structures from an input document that instantiate classes and properties as defined in the ontology. Considering knowledge base population as structure prediction, we frame the task as a statistical inference problem which aims at predicting the most likely assignment to a set of ontologically grounded output variables given an input document. In order to model the conditional distribution of these output variables given the input variables derived from the text, we follow the approach adopted in Conditional Random Fields. We decompose the cold-start knowledge base population task into the specific problems of entity recognition, entity linking and slot-filling, and show how they can be modeled using Conditional Random Fields.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="luxlog-cskbp.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930952/2930953/luxlog-cskbp.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Luxembourg</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Cold-start Knowledge Base Population</topic><topic>Ontology-based Information Extraction</topic><topic>Slot Filling</topic><topic>Conditional Random Fields</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title> Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">9783030003371</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29309529</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11078</number></detail><extent unit="pages">78-109</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., Cimiano, P.: Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In: d'Amato, C. and Theobald, M. (eds.)  Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 11078, p. 78-109. Springer (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2018. “Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields”. In &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Claudia d'Amato and Martin Theobald, 11078:78-109. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P. Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In: d'Amato C, Theobald M, eds. &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 11078. Springer;  2018: 78-109.</ama>
<bio1>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. &lt;br /&gt;In:   Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability. d'Amato C, Theobald M (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 11078. Springer:  78-109.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  ter Horst, M.  Hartung, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: C. d'Amato, M. Theobald), Springer, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 78-109.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, H., Hartung, M. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In C. d'Amato &amp;amp; M. Theobald (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; (S. 78-109). Gehalten auf der 14th International Reasoning Web Summer School 2018, Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In C.  d'Amato &amp;amp; M.  Theobald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 11078&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 78-109). Springer.</apa>
<ieee> H. ter Horst, M. Hartung, and P. Cimiano, “Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields”, &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt;, C. d'Amato and M. Theobald, eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 11078, Springer, 2018,  pp.78-109.</ieee>
<harvard1>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2018. Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In C.  d'Amato &amp;amp; M.  Theobald, eds. &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.11078  Springer, pp. 78-109.</harvard1>
<default>ter Horst H, Hartung M, Cimiano P (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:   Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability. d'Amato C, Theobald M (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 11078.  Springer:  78-109.</default>
<wels>ter Horst, H.; Hartung, M.; Cimiano, P. (2018): Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In: Claudia d'Amato; Martin Theobald (Hrsg.):   Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.. Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 11078).  S. 78-109.</wels>
<frontiers>ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., and Cimiano, P. (2018). “Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields” in &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt;, d'Amato, C., and Theobald, M. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 11078, (Springer), 78-109.</frontiers>
<mla>ter Horst, Hendrik, Hartung, Matthias, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields”. &lt;em&gt; Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; Ed. Claudia d'Amato and Martin Theobald. Springer, 2018.Vol. 11078. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 78-109.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;ter Horst, H., Hartung, M., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2018). Cold-Start Knowledge Base Population Using Ontology-Based Information Extraction with Conditional Random Fields. In C.  d'Amato &amp;amp; M.  Theobald (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 11078&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  Reasoning Web. Learning, Uncertainty, Streaming, and Scalability.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 78-109). Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930952</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-09-10T15:32:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-09-25T21:51:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>