<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930570</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bienvenido</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barraz Martínez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Denk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jairo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hernández Monzón</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kammerlander</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Max</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nendel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">127338064</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We consider a transmission problem where a structurally
damped plate equation is coupled with a damped or undamped wave equation
by transmission conditions. We show that exponential stability holds
in the damped-damped situation and polynomial stability (but no exponential
stability) holds in the damped-undamped case. Additionally, we show
that the solutions first defined by the weak formulation, in fact have higher
Sobolev space regularity.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_596.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930570/2930571/IMW_working_paper_596.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29305709</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>596</number></detail><extent unit="pages">24</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Barraz Martínez, B.; Denk, R.; Hernández Monzón, J.; Kammerlander, F.; Nendel, M. (2018): Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<mla>Barraz Martínez, Bienvenido, Denk, Robert, Hernández Monzón, Jairo, Kammerlander, Felix, and Nendel, Max. &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 596.</mla>
<frontiers>Barraz Martínez, B., Denk, R., Hernández Monzón, J., Kammerlander, F., and Nendel, M. (2018). Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 596, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barraz Martínez, B., Denk, R., Hernández Monzón, J., Kammerlander, F., &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 596). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Barraz Martínez B, Denk R, Hernández Monzón J, Kammerlander F, Nendel M (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 596.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Barraz Martínez, B., et al., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.596, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Barraz Martínez, et al., &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 596,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Barraz Martínez, B., Denk, R., Hernández Monzón, J., Kammerlander, F., &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 596). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barraz Martínez, B., Denk, R., Hernández Monzón, J., Kammerlander, F. &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Barraz Martínez, R.  Denk, J.  Hernández Monzón, F.  Kammerlander, and M.  Nendel, &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Barraz Martínez B, Denk R, Hernández Monzón J, Kammerlander F, Nendel M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 596.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Barraz Martínez B, Denk R, Hernández Monzón J, Kammerlander F, Nendel M. &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 596. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
<lncs> Barraz Martínez, B., Denk, R., Hernández Monzón, J., Kammerlander, F., Nendel, M.: Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 596. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barraz Martínez, Bienvenido, Denk, Robert, Hernández Monzón, Jairo, Kammerlander, Felix, and Nendel, Max. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Regularity and Asymptotic Behaviour for a Damped Plate-Membrane Transmission Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 596. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930570</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-22T13:30:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>