<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930261</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streib</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40417</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3633-4785</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Constantin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">12248214</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81208</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0871-0720</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralph W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hood</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Amy L.</namePart><namePart type="family">Ai</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kevin A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Harris</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paul</namePart><namePart type="family">Wink</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ray</namePart><namePart type="family">Paloutzian</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10034</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this chapter, we suggest the use of Hood’s Mysticism Scale (M-scale) for a differential assessment of subjective spirituality. We base this view on the conceptualization of mysticism and its relation to spirituality, and on the definition of spirituality as individualized experience-orientated religiosity. This perspective was empirically tested in the Bielefeld-based Cross-cultural Study on Spirituality, which explored in comprehensive semantic analyses how participants in the USA and Germany define spirituality and revealed that more spiritual than religious people preferably associate spirituality with experiences of all-connectedness, search for a higher self, existential truth, and humanistic morality. Moreover, structural equations modeling based on this and other recent data sets reveal that the M-scale and its factors have considerable effects on self-rated spirituality. Thus, we recommend the M-scale as measure for subjective spirituality, which avoids the widespread problem of many extant measures that assess spirituality primarily in terms of either (Christian) religiosity or psychosocial well-being. The M-scale may be very useful in research that intends to assess the subjective spirituality of a diversity of participants who might affiliate with various religious traditions and worldviews, including the non-religious, atheists, and non-theists. Besides the well-established 32-item version of the M-scale, the chapter additionally presents an economic 8-item short form of the M-scale and its psychometric properties.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Streib-Klein-Keller-Hood_2020_M-Scale.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930261/2935534/Streib-Klein-Keller-Hood_2020_M-Scale.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-030-52140-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29302617</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">45</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/gwj2c</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, Heinz, Klein, Constantin, Keller, Barbara, and Hood, Ralph W. 2021. “The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form”. In &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Amy L. Ai, Kevin A. Harris, Paul Wink, and Ray Paloutzian, 45. New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Streib, H., Klein, C., Keller, B., Hood, R.W.: The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In: Ai, A.L., Harris, K.A., Wink, P., and Paloutzian, R. (eds.) Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective. p. 45. Springer, New York (2021).</lncs>
<ama>Streib H, Klein C, Keller B, Hood RW. The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In: Ai AL, Harris KA, Wink P, Paloutzian R, eds. &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Springer;  2021: 45.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Streib, C.  Klein, B.  Keller, and R. W.  Hood, in &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A.L. Ai, K.A. Harris, P. Wink, R. Paloutzian), Springer, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 45.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Streib H, Klein C, Keller B, Hood RW (2021) &lt;br /&gt;The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective. Ai AL, Harris KA, Wink P, Paloutzian R (Eds); New York: Springer:  45.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H., Klein, C., Keller, B. &amp;amp; Hood, R.W. (2021). The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In A.L. Ai, K.A. Harris, P. Wink &amp;amp; R. Paloutzian (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (S. 45). New York: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Streib, H., Klein, C., Keller, B., &amp;amp; Hood, R. W. (2021). The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In A. L.  Ai, K. A.  Harris, P.  Wink, &amp;amp; R.  Paloutzian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (p. 45). New York: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Streib, H., et al., 2021. The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In A. L.  Ai, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: Springer, pp. 45.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Streib, et al., “The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form”, &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, A.L. Ai, et al., eds.,  New York: Springer, 2021,  pp.45.</ieee>
<default>Streib H, Klein C, Keller B, Hood RW (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective. Ai AL, Harris KA, Wink P, Paloutzian R (Eds);  New York: Springer:  45.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Streib, H., Klein, C., Keller, B., &amp;amp; Hood, R. W. (2021). The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In A. L.  Ai, K. A.  Harris, P.  Wink, &amp;amp; R.  Paloutzian (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (p. 45). New York: Springer. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-52140-0_19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Streib, H., Klein, C., Keller, B., and Hood, R. W. (2021). “The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form” in &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Ai, A. L., Harris, K. A., Wink, P., and Paloutzian, R. eds. (New York: Springer), 45.</frontiers>
<mla>Streib, Heinz, Klein, Constantin, Keller, Barbara, and Hood, Ralph W. “The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form”. &lt;em&gt;Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Amy L. Ai, Kevin A. Harris, Paul Wink, and Ray Paloutzian. New York: Springer, 2021. 45.</mla>
<wels>Streib, H.; Klein, C.; Keller, B.; Hood, R. W. (2021): The Mysticism Scale as Measure for Subjective Spirituality: New Results with Hood's M-Scale and the Development of a Short Form. In: Amy L. Ai; Kevin A. Harris; Paul Wink; Ray Paloutzian (Hrsg.):  Assessing Spirituality and Religion in a Diversified World: Beyond the Mainstream Perspective. New York: Springer.  S. 45.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930261</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-02T12:52:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-11T00:01:59Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>