<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930597</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Claas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17867857</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies the implications of a segmented labor market with efficient wage–
employment bargaining on the internal labor market and a competitive external labor
market on the temporary equilibrium of a closed monetary macroeconomy of the AS–
AD type with government activity, fiat money, and expectations. Workers have identical
preferences, those on the internal labor market are represented by a labor union. There
is no mobility between the labor markets.
Union power measured by the share of the production surplus allotted to the union
and union density measured by the fraction of workers who are union members impact
the functional income distribution, but neither affect the individual employment levels
nor the aggregate employment level and the aggregate supply function. The wage on the
internal labor market is above the wage on the external labor market if and only if the
profit share of total revenue is smaller than under a fully competitive labor market.
Unique temporary equilibria exist for all combinations of union power and union density.
The paper provides a complete comparative-statics analysis showing in particular a
negative price effect of union power and a positive price effect of union density. In general,
the effects of union power and union density on any equilibrium value are usually of
opposite signs. Single-labor-market models with a fully competitive or a fully unionized
labor market are special or limiting cases of the segmented-labor-market model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_600.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930597/2930598/IMW_working_paper_600.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29305975</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>600</number></detail><extent unit="pages">42</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Claas, O. (2018): Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Claas, &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Claas O (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 600.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Claas, O., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.600, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Claas, O. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 600). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Claas, O. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Claas, O. (2018). Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 600, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Claas O. &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 600. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
<ieee> O. Claas, &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 600,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<apa>Claas, O. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 600). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Claas, Oliver. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 600. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Claas, O.: Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 600. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<default>Claas O (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 600.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Claas, Oliver. &lt;em&gt;Labor Market Segmentation and Efficient Bargaining in a Macroeconomic Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 600.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930597</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-23T14:22:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>