<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930694</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ole</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Oeltjen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">136874656</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Katherine</namePart><namePart type="family">Braun</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">107034251</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Notwithstanding strong media attention, operators of asylum seekers’ accommodation centers have been largely overlooked by academic debate. This article focuses on the role of these non-profit and for-profit organizations in the production of knowledge about the accommodation – and especially about the accommodated. Drawing on qualitative interviews conducted in Berlin in 2016 and 2017, the article argues that these organizations and their employees are a crucial part of reproducing a humanitarian and orientalist discourse that depicts the accommodated asylum seekers as backward and dependent. While supposedly lobbying for the interests of their occupants, they therefore participate in silencing these voices and legitimize the precarious accommodation system.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Oeltjen_2018_Die Interessenvertretung der Anderen. Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930694/2942835/Oeltjen_2018_Die Interessenvertretung der Anderen. Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>transcript</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>asylum accommodation centers</topic><topic>humanitarian government</topic><topic>third sector</topic><topic>othering</topic><topic>victimization</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Wissensproduktionen der Migration</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-8376-4245-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29306946</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4(1)</number></detail><extent unit="pages">133-146</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Oeltjen, O. (2018). Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In K.  Braun (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies: Vol. 4(1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 133-146). Bielefeld: transcript.</apa>
<ieee> O. Oeltjen, “Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende”, &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;, K. Braun, ed., movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies, vol. 4(1),  Bielefeld: transcript, 2018,  pp.133-146.</ieee>
<harvard1>Oeltjen, O., 2018. Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In K.  Braun, ed. &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;. movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies. no.4(1)  Bielefeld: transcript, pp. 133-146.</harvard1>
<default>Oeltjen O (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Wissensproduktionen der Migration. Braun K (Ed);  movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies, 4(1).  Bielefeld: transcript:  133-146.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Oeltjen, O. (2018). Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In K.  Braun (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies: Vol. 4(1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 133-146). Bielefeld: transcript.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Oeltjen, O. (2018). “Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende” in &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;, Braun, K. ed. movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies, vol. 4(1), (Bielefeld: transcript), 133-146.</frontiers>
<mla>Oeltjen, Ole. “Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende”. &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Katherine Braun. Bielefeld: transcript, 2018.Vol. 4(1). movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies. 133-146.</mla>
<wels>Oeltjen, O. (2018): Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In: Katherine Braun (Hrsg.):  Wissensproduktionen der Migration. Bielefeld: transcript. (movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies, 4(1).  S. 133-146.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Oeltjen, Ole. 2018. “Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende”. In &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Katherine Braun, 4(1):133-146. movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies. Bielefeld: transcript.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Oeltjen, O.: Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In: Braun, K. (ed.) Wissensproduktionen der Migration. movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies. 4(1), p. 133-146. transcript, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<ama>Oeltjen O. Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. In: Braun K, ed. &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt;. movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies. Vol 4(1). Bielefeld: transcript;  2018: 133-146.</ama>
<bio1>Oeltjen O (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Wissensproduktionen der Migration. Braun K (Ed); movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies, 4(1). Bielefeld: transcript:  133-146.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Oeltjen, in &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: K. Braun), Transcript, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 133-146.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Oeltjen, O. (2018). Die Interessenvertretung der "Anderen". Unterkunftsbetreiber als neue Akteure der Wissensproduktion über Asylsuchende (movements. Journal for Critical Migration and Border Regime Studies). In K. Braun (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Wissensproduktionen der Migration&lt;/em&gt; (S. 133-146). Bielefeld: transcript.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930694</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-29T12:34:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-23T08:50:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>