<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930384</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ghislain-Herman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Demeze-Jouatsa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53496285</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4368-0504</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we present a model of finitely repeated games in which
players can strategically make use of objective ambiguity. In each round of a finite rep-
etition of a finite stage-game, in addition to the classic pure and mixed actions, players
can employ objectively ambiguous actions by using imprecise probabilistic devices such
as Ellsberg urns to conceal their intentions. We find that adding an infinitesimal level
of ambiguity can be enough to approximate collusive payoffs via subgame perfect equi-
librium strategies of the finitely repeated game. Our main theorem states that if each
player has many continuation equilibrium payoffs in ambiguous actions, any feasible pay-
off vector of the original stage-game that dominates the mixed strategy maxmin payoff
vector is (ex-ante and ex-post) approachable by means of subgame perfect equilibrium
strategies of the finitely repeated game with discounting. Our condition is also necessary.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_585.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930384/2930385/IMW_working_paper_585.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Objective Ambiguity</topic><topic>Ambiguity Aversion</topic><topic>Finitely Repeated Games</topic><topic>Subgame Perfect Equilibrium</topic><topic>Ellsberg Urns</topic><topic>Ellsberg Strategies</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29303844</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>585</number></detail><extent unit="pages">28</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Demeze-Jouatsa G-H (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 585.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>G. - H.  Demeze-Jouatsa, &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Demeze-Jouatsa G-H (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 585.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<wels>Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H. (2018): Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H. (2018). Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 585, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 585). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Demeze-Jouatsa, Ghislain-Herman. &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 585.</mla>
<apa>Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 585). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Demeze-Jouatsa, Ghislain-Herman. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 585. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H.: Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 585. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<harvard1>Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.585, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> G.-H. Demeze-Jouatsa, &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 585,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<ama>Demeze-Jouatsa G-H. &lt;em&gt;Repetition and cooperation: A model of finitely repeated games with objective ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 585. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930384</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-13T09:22:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>