<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930378</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hölzermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">119470561</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">It is shown how to construct an arbitrage-free short rate model under uncertainty about the
drift and the volatility. The uncertainty is represented by a set of priors, which naturally
leads to a G-Brownian motion. Within this framework, it is shown how to characterize the
whole term structure without admitting arbitrage. The pricing of zero-coupon bonds in such
a setting differs substantially from the traditional models, since the prices need to be chosen
in a different way in order to exclude arbitrage.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_582.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930378/2930379/IMW_working_paper_582.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Robust Finance</topic><topic>Knightian Uncertainty</topic><topic>Short Rate Model</topic><topic>No-Arbitrage</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29303783</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>582</number></detail><extent unit="pages">23</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hölzermann, &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hölzermann J (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 582.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hölzermann, J. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Hölzermann, J.: Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 582. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hölzermann, Julian. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 582. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Hölzermann J. &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 582. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
<default>Hölzermann J (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 582.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<wels>Hölzermann, J. (2018): Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Hölzermann, J. (2018). Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 582, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hölzermann, J. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 582). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hölzermann, Julian. &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 582.</mla>
<apa>Hölzermann, J. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 582). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<harvard1>Hölzermann, J., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.582, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Hölzermann, &lt;em&gt;Bond Pricing under Knightian Uncertainty. A Short Rate Model with Drift and Volatility Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 582,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930378</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-13T08:43:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>