<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2930599</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hawkar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ibrahim</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Verena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ertl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10287303</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Catani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9988099</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Azad Ali</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ismail</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neuner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9438235</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33704</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist (PCL) is a valid and reliable self-report measure for the assessment of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD). Recently the PCL was updated according to the DSM-5 criteria for PTSD. So far only a few studies have examined the psychometric properties of the PCL-5, and all of these are restricted to populations living in industrialized countries. The aim of this study was to determine the psychometric properties and diagnostic utility of the PCL-5 as a screening instrument for war-affected displaced Kurdish and Arab populations. The specific goal was to determine a contextually valid cut-off score for a probable diagnosis of PTSD.
Methods

The PCL-5 was translated into Arabic and two Kurdish dialects. Trained interviewers administered these translations as assisted self-reports to 206 adults living in camps for displaced people in Iraq, together with depression and war-exposure instruments. Two weeks later, 98 randomly chosen subjects were reassessed by expert clinical psychologists. In the absence of a gold-standard instrument with proven validity in this context, the expert interviewers applied the PCL-5 items in the form of a clinical interview and used a DSM-5-algorithm to determine a diagnosis of PTSD. Receiver operator characteristics (ROC) were performed to determine a valid cutoff-score.
Results

The internal consistency of the PCL-5 was high (alpha = .85) and the instrument showed an adequate convergent validity. Using the cut-off score of 23, the PCL-5 achieved the optimal balance of sensitivity and specificity (area under the curve = .82, p &lt; .001; sensitivity = .82, specificity = .70).
Conclusions

Given that the comparison of the two assessments included both a re-test interval and validation by different interviewers, our results indicate that the PCL-5 can be recommended as an assessment and screening instrument for Kurdish and Arab populations.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s12888-018-1839-z.hawkar.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2930599/2930610/s12888-018-1839-z.hawkar.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>BioMed Central</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>PCL     PTSD     Validation     Arab spring     Displaced people</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Psychiatry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-244x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1471-244X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30115040</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000441850800002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29305993</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12888-018-1839-z</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Ibrahim, H., Ertl, V., Catani, C., Ismail, A. A., and Neuner, F. (2018). The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 18:259.</frontiers>
<mla>Ibrahim, Hawkar, Ertl, Verena, Catani, Claudia, Ismail, Azad Ali, and Neuner, Frank. “The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 18.1 (2018): 259.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ibrahim, H., Ertl, V., Catani, C., Ismail, A. A., &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2018). The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1), 259. doi:10.1186/s12888-018-1839-z&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ibrahim, H., Ertl, V., Catani, C., Ismail, A.A. &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2018). The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1): 259. BioMed Central. doi:10.1186/s12888-018-1839-z.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Ibrahim, H.; Ertl, V.; Catani, C.; Ismail, A. A.; Neuner, F. (2018): The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,18:(1):259</wels>
<bio1>Ibrahim H, Ertl V, Catani C, Ismail AA, Neuner F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Psychiatry 18(1): 259.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Ibrahim, V.  Ertl, C.  Catani, A. A.  Ismail, and F.  Neuner, “The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 259.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Ibrahim H, Ertl V, Catani C, Ismail AA, Neuner F (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 18(1): 259.</default>
<ama>Ibrahim H, Ertl V, Catani C, Ismail AA, Neuner F. The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;18(1): 259.</ama>
<ieee> H. Ibrahim, et al., “The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2018, : 259.</ieee>
<harvard1>Ibrahim, H., et al., 2018. The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, 18(1): 259.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ibrahim, Hawkar, Ertl, Verena, Catani, Claudia, Ismail, Azad Ali, and Neuner, Frank. 2018. “The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 18 (1): 259.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ibrahim, H., Ertl, V., Catani, C., Ismail, A.A., Neuner, F.: The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. BMC Psychiatry. 18, : 259 (2018).</lncs>
<apa>Ibrahim, H., Ertl, V., Catani, C., Ismail, A. A., &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2018). The validity of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) as screening instrument with Kurdish and Arab displaced populations living in the Kurdistan region of Iraq. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(1), 259. doi:10.1186/s12888-018-1839-z</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2930599</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-08-24T06:30:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>