<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2931607</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:320</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aanor</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Roland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">96379134</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6697-7533</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Basham</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The European sovereign debt crisis represents an interesting opportunity to investigate
the reaction of the European Central Bank as a crisis fighting institution and the
importance of central bank personalities in policy execution. Accordingly, this paper aims
at investigating to what extent the policy-making of the ECB during the crisis has been
influenced by Trichet’s and Draghi’s different personalities. Based on Friedman’s hypothesis
that “accidents of personality” have a great impact on the functioning of a rulebased
institution, we find that the clear differences in policy-making between Trichet and
Draghi can be explained by specific features of their respective personalities. Institutions
matter, but so do personalities.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ipe_working_paper_38.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2931607/2931608/ipe_working_paper_38.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>European Central Bank</topic><topic>Central Bankers</topic><topic>Personality Theory</topic><topic>European Sovereign Debt Crisis</topic><topic>Monetary Policy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn"> 1869-6406</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29316073</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>38</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Roland, Aanor, and Basham, James. &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;. Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy, 2014. IPE Working Paper. 38.</mla>
<default>Roland A, Basham J (2014)  IPE Working Paper; 38.&lt;br /&gt;Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</default>
<lncs> Roland, A., Basham, J.: Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter? IPE Working Paper, 38. Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy, Berlin (2014).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roland, Aanor, and Basham, James. 2014. &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 38. IPE Working Paper. Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Roland, A., &amp;amp; Basham, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt; (IPE Working Paper, 38). Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</apa>
<ieee> A. Roland and J. Basham, &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;, IPE Working Paper, vol. 38,  Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy, 2014.</ieee>
<ama>Roland A, Basham J. &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;. IPE Working Paper. Vol 38. Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy; 2014.</ama>
<frontiers>Roland, A., and Basham, J. (2014). Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter? &lt;em&gt;IPE Working Paper&lt;/em&gt;, 38, Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roland, A. &amp;amp; Basham, J. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt; (IPE Working Paper). Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Roland, A., &amp;amp; Basham, J., 2014. &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;, IPE Working Paper, no.38, Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</harvard1>
<bio1>Roland A, Basham J (2014) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;. IPE Working Paper; 38.&lt;br /&gt;Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Roland, A., &amp;amp; Basham, J. (2014).  &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt; (IPE Working Paper, 38). Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Roland, and J.  Basham, &lt;em&gt;Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?&lt;/em&gt;, Berlin School Of Economics And Law. Institute For International Political Economy, Berlin, &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Roland, A.; Basham, J. (2014): Policy-making of the European Central Bank during the crisis: Do personalities matter?. Berlin: Berlin School of Economics and Law. Institute for International Political Economy.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2931607</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-10-17T09:09:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-10-18T09:00:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>