<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2931836</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bohle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">39118150</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3580-6533</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anja</namePart><namePart type="family">Bandau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Anne</namePart><namePart type="family">Brüske</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Natascha</namePart><namePart type="family">Ueckmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791099</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">38670945</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="314-69-82628-1-10-20181024.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2931836/2931837/314-69-82628-1-10-20181024.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Heidelberg University Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-946054-88-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29318362</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">245-254</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>https://doi.org//10.17885/heiup.314.534</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>
<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Bohle, J., 2018. Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In A.  Bandau, A.  Brüske, &amp;amp; N.  Ueckmann, eds. &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;.  Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing, pp. 245-254.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bohle J (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections. Bandau A, Brüske A, Ueckmann N (Eds); Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing:  245-254.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bohle, J. (2018). Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In A.  Bandau, A.  Brüske, &amp;amp; N.  Ueckmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 245-254). Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Bohle, in &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Bandau, A. Brüske, N. Ueckmann), Heidelberg University Publishing, Heidelberg, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 245-254.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Bohle, J. (2018): Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In: Anja Bandau; Anne Brüske; Natascha Ueckmann (Hrsg.):  Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections. Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing.  S. 245-254.</wels>
<apa>Bohle, J. (2018). Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In A.  Bandau, A.  Brüske, &amp;amp; N.  Ueckmann (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 245-254). Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing.</apa>
<ieee> J. Bohle, “Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron”, &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;, A. Bandau, A. Brüske, and N. Ueckmann, eds.,  Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing, 2018,  pp.245-254.</ieee>
<ama>Bohle J. Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In: Bandau A, Brüske A, Ueckmann N, eds. &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;. Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing;  2018: 245-254.</ama>
<frontiers>Bohle, J. (2018). “Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron” in &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;, Bandau, A., Brüske, A., and Ueckmann, N. eds. (Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing), 245-254.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bohle, J. (2018). Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In A. Bandau, A. Brüske &amp;amp; N. Ueckmann (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt; (S. 245-254). Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<mla>Bohle, Johannes. “Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron”. &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Anja Bandau, Anne Brüske, and Natascha Ueckmann. Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing, 2018. 245-254.</mla>
<default>Bohle J (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections. Bandau A, Brüske A, Ueckmann N (Eds);  Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing:  245-254.</default>
<lncs> Bohle, J.: Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron. In: Bandau, A., Brüske, A., and Ueckmann, N. (eds.) Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections. p. 245-254. Heidelberg University Publishing, Heidelberg (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bohle, Johannes. 2018. “Sustainable Urban Planning? Reflections on Bon Air and Trénelle-Citron”. In &lt;em&gt;Reshaping Glocal Dynamics of the Caribbean. Relaciones y Desconexiones – Relations et Déconnexions – Relations and Disconnections&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Anja Bandau, Anne Brüske, and Natascha Ueckmann, 245-254. Heidelberg: Heidelberg University Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2931836</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-10-26T16:29:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-10-29T10:06:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>