<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2932196</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abendroth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27919701</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mareike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reimann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40670923</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8007-4840</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sampson Lee</namePart><namePart type="family">Blair</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Josip</namePart><namePart type="family">Obradovic</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Forschungsschwerpunkt Digitale Zukunft</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Abendroth_Reimann_2018_TELEWORK AND WORK–FAMILY CONFLICT ACROSS WORKPLACES.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2932196/2953871/Abendroth_Reimann_2018_TELEWORK AND WORK–FAMILY CONFLICT ACROSS WORKPLACES.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Emerald Published</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title> The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-78769-112-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29321963</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail><extent unit="pages">323-348</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Abendroth and M. Reimann, “Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures”, &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;, S.L. Blair and J. Obradovic, eds., Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research, vol. 13,  Bingley: Emerald Published, 2018,  pp.323-348.</ieee>
<harvard1>Abendroth, A., &amp;amp; Reimann, M., 2018. Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In S. L.  Blair &amp;amp; J.  Obradovic, eds. &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research. no.13  Bingley: Emerald Published, pp. 323-348.</harvard1>
<ama>Abendroth A, Reimann M. Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In: Blair SL, Obradovic J, eds. &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research. Vol 13. Bingley: Emerald Published;  2018: 323-348.</ama>
<apa>Abendroth, A., &amp;amp; Reimann, M. (2018). Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In S. L.  Blair &amp;amp; J.  Obradovic (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research: Vol. 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 323-348). Bingley: Emerald Published.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, Anja, and Reimann, Mareike. 2018. “Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures”. In &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sampson Lee Blair and Josip Obradovic, 13:323-348. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research. Bingley: Emerald Published.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Abendroth, A., Reimann, M.: Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In: Blair, S.L. and Obradovic, J. (eds.)  The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research. 13, p. 323-348. Emerald Published, Bingley (2018).</lncs>
<wels>Abendroth, A.; Reimann, M. (2018): Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In: Sampson Lee Blair; Josip Obradovic (Hrsg.):   The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges. Bingley: Emerald Published. (Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research, 13).  S. 323-348.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A., &amp;amp; Reimann, M. (2018). Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. In S. L.  Blair &amp;amp; J.  Obradovic (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research: Vol. 13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.  The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 323-348). Bingley: Emerald Published.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Abendroth, Anja, and Reimann, Mareike. “Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures”. &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sampson Lee Blair and Josip Obradovic. Bingley: Emerald Published, 2018.Vol. 13. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research. 323-348.</mla>
<frontiers>Abendroth, A., and Reimann, M. (2018). “Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures” in &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt;, Blair, S. L., and Obradovic, J. eds. Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research, vol. 13, (Bingley: Emerald Published), 323-348.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abendroth, A. &amp;amp; Reimann, M. (2018). Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures (Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research). In S.L. Blair &amp;amp; J. Obradovic (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt; (S. 323-348). Bingley: Emerald Published.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Abendroth A, Reimann M (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:   The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges. Blair SL, Obradovic J (Eds);  Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research, 13.  Bingley: Emerald Published:  323-348.</default>
<bio1>Abendroth A, Reimann M (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Telework and Work-Family Conflict across Workplaces. Investigating the Implications of Work-Family-Supportive and High-Demand Workplace Clutures. &lt;br /&gt;In:   The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges. Blair SL, Obradovic J (Eds); Contemporary Perspectives in Family Research, 13. Bingley: Emerald Published:  323-348.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Abendroth, and M.  Reimann, in &lt;em&gt; The Work-Family Interface: Spillover, Complications, and Challenges&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S.L. Blair, J. Obradovic), Emerald Published, Bingley, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 323-348.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2932196</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-16T09:41:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-13T08:57:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>