<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2932018</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olga</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abramov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4258787</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-6547-1415</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Németh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">121675971</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1578-9388</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friederike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kern</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27917271</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0591-2397</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mertens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rohlfing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">147957</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart> KogWis 2018 Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Previous work by [1] studied gesture-speech interaction in adults. [1] focussed on temporal and semantic coordination of gesture and speech and found that while adult speech is mostly coordinated (or redundant) with gestures, semantic coordination increases the temporal synchrony. These observations do not necessarily hold for children (in particular with respect to iconic gestures, see [2]), where the speech and gesture systems are still under development. We studied the semantic and temporal coordination of speech and gesture in 4-year old children using a corpus of 40 children producing action descriptions in task oriented dialogues. In particular, we examined what kinds of information are transmitted verbally vs. non-verbally and how they are related. To account for this, we extended the semantic features (SFs) developed in [3] for object descriptions in order to include the semantics of actions. We coded the SFs on the children’s speech and gestures separately using video data. In our presentation, we will focus on the quantitative distribution of SFs across gesture and speech. Our results indicate that speech and gestures of 4-year olds are less integrated than those of the adults, although there is a large variability among the children. We will discuss the results with respect to the cognitive processes (e.g., visual memory, language) underlying children’s abilities at this stage of development. Our work paves the way for the cognitive architecture of speech-gesture interaction in preschoolers which to our knowledge is missing so far. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="kogwis2018.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2932018/2932019/kogwis2018.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Darmstadt</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Speech-gesture integration</topic><topic>semantic features</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29320189</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Abramov, Olga, Kopp, Stefan, Németh, Anne, Kern, Friederike, Mertens, Ulrich, and Rohlfing, Katharina. “Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children”. &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. 2018.</mla>
<default>Abramov O, Kopp S, Németh A, Kern F, Mertens U, Rohlfing K (2018)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science. Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Ed); .</default>
<lncs> Abramov, O., Kopp, S., Németh, A., Kern, F., Mertens, U., Rohlfing, K.: Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In: Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (ed.) KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science.  (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abramov, Olga, Kopp, Stefan, Németh, Anne, Kern, Friederike, Mertens, Ulrich, and Rohlfing, Katharina. 2018. “Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children”. In &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Abramov O, Kopp S, Németh A, Kern F, Mertens U, Rohlfing K (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. &lt;br /&gt;In:  KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science. Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Ed);.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abramov, O., Kopp, S., Németh, A., Kern, F., Mertens, U., &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2018). Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Abramov, O., et al., 2018. Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V., ed. &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Abramov, S.  Kopp, A.  Németh, F.  Kern, U.  Mertens, and K.  Rohlfing, in &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V.), &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Abramov, O.; Kopp, S.; Németh, A.; Kern, F.; Mertens, U.; Rohlfing, K. (2018): Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In: Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Hrsg.):  KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science.</wels>
<apa>Abramov, O., Kopp, S., Németh, A., Kern, F., Mertens, U., &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2018). Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<ieee> O. Abramov, et al., “Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children”, &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V., ed., 2018.</ieee>
<ama>Abramov O, Kopp S, Németh A, Kern F, Mertens U, Rohlfing K. Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In: Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V., ed. &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;. 2018.</ama>
<frontiers>Abramov, O., Kopp, S., Németh, A., Kern, F., Mertens, U., and Rohlfing, K. (2018). “Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children” in &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. ed.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abramov, O., Kopp, S., Németh, A., Kern, F., Mertens, U. &amp;amp; Rohlfing, K. (2018). Towards a Computational Model of Child Gesture-Speech Production. How information is spread across modalities in pre-school children. In Gesellschaft für Kognitionswissenschaft e.V. (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;KogWis2018: Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der  KogWis 2018 Computational Approaches to Cognitive Science.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2932018</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-11-05T09:42:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-29T08:51:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>