<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2932567</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Torsten Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bollweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55128610</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0147-6890</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53811697</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1714-4783</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart><namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ullrich</namePart><namePart type="family">Bauer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Diane</namePart><namePart type="family">Levin-Zamir</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paulo</namePart><namePart type="family">Pinheiro</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kristine</namePart><namePart type="family">Sørensen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">7978137</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bollweg_2019_Measuring_Childrens_Health_Literacy.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2932567/2936768/Bollweg_2019_Measuring_Childrens_Health_Literacy.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Policy Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4473-4451-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29325675</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">83-97</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> T.M. Bollweg and O. Okan, “Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges”, &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;, O. Okan, et al., eds.,  Bristol: Policy Press, 2019,  pp.83-97.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bollweg, T.M., &amp;amp; Okan, O., 2019. Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In O.  Okan, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;.  Bristol: Policy Press, pp. 83-97.</harvard1>
<apa>Bollweg, T. M., &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, P.  Pinheiro, &amp;amp; K.  Sørensen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 83-97). Bristol: Policy Press.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, T. M., &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, P.  Pinheiro, &amp;amp; K.  Sørensen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 83-97). Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bollweg, T. M., and Okan, O. (2019). “Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges” in &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;, Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Pinheiro, P., and Sørensen, K. eds. (Bristol: Policy Press), 83-97.</frontiers>
<mla>Bollweg, Torsten Michael, and Okan, Orkan. “Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges”. &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Paulo Pinheiro, and Kristine Sørensen. Bristol: Policy Press, 2019. 83-97.</mla>
<wels>Bollweg, T. M.; Okan, O. (2019): Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In: Orkan Okan; Ullrich Bauer; Diane Levin-Zamir; Paulo Pinheiro; Kristine Sørensen (Hrsg.):  International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span. Bristol: Policy Press.  S. 83-97.</wels>
<default>Bollweg TM, Okan O (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen K (Eds);  Bristol: Policy Press:  83-97.</default>
<ama>Bollweg TM, Okan O. Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In: Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen K, eds. &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;. Bristol: Policy Press;  2019: 83-97.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, Torsten Michael, and Okan, Orkan. 2019. “Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges”. In &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Paulo Pinheiro, and Kristine Sørensen, 83-97. Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bollweg, T.M., Okan, O.: Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In: Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Pinheiro, P., and Sørensen, K. (eds.) International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span. p. 83-97. Policy Press, Bristol (2019).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, T.M. &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. In O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, P. Pinheiro &amp;amp; K. Sørensen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt; (S. 83-97). Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Bollweg TM, Okan O (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Measuring children’s health literacy. Current approaches and challenges. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen K (Eds); Bristol: Policy Press:  83-97.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T. M.  Bollweg, and O.  Okan, in &lt;em&gt;International handbook of health literacy. Research, practice and policy across the life-span&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, P. Pinheiro, K. Sørensen), Policy Press, Bristol, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 83-97.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2932567</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-05T08:52:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-22T13:10:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>