<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2932994</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jodi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dianetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">116356476</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We consider a class of N-player stochastic games of multi-dimensional singular
control, in which each player faces a minimization problem of monotone-follower type with
submodular costs. We call these games monotone-follower games. In a not necessarily
Markovian setting, we establish the existence of Nash equilibria. Moreover, we introduce
a sequence of approximating games by restricting, for each n ∈ ℕ, the players' admissible
strategies to the set of Lipschitz processes with Lipschitz constant bounded by n. We prove
that, for each n ∈ ℕ, there exists a Nash equilibrium of the approximating game and that the
sequence of Nash equilibria converges, in the Meyer-Zheng sense, to a weak (distributional)
Nash equilibrium of the original game of singular control. As a byproduct, such a convergence
also provides approximation results of the equilibrium values across the two classes of games.
We finally show how our results can be employed to prove existence of open-loop Nash
equilibria in an N-player stochastic differential game with singular controls, and we propose
an algorithm to determine a Nash equilibrium for the monotone-follower game.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_605.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2932994/2932998/IMW_working_paper_605.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>nonzero-sum games</topic><topic>singular control</topic><topic>submodular games</topic><topic>Meyer-Zheng topology</topic><topic>maximum principle</topic><topic>Nash equilibrium</topic><topic>stochastic differential games</topic><topic>monotone-follower problem.</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29329948</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>605</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Dianetti J, Ferrari G (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 605.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Dianetti, Jodi, and Ferrari, Giorgio. &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 605.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, Jodi, and Ferrari, Giorgio. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 605. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G.: Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 605. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<ieee> J. Dianetti and G. Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 605,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Dianetti, J., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 605). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Dianetti, J., and Ferrari, G. (2019). Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 605, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, J. &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Dianetti J, Ferrari G. &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 605. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Dianetti, and G.  Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Dianetti, J., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.605, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Dianetti J, Ferrari G (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 605.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, J., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 605). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Dianetti, J.; Ferrari, G. (2019): Nonzero-Sum Submodular Monotone-Follower Games. Existence and Approximation of Nash Equilibria. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2932994</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-09T10:15:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>