<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2932764</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koepff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian Carsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sachs</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiechert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kohlheyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Noeh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marco</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Oldiges</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grünberger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">94700790</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">110747676</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Quantitative single-cell cultivation has provided fundamental contributions to our understanding of heterogeneity among industrially used microorganisms. Filamentous growing Streptomyces species are emerging platform organisms for industrial production processes, but their exploitation is still limited due to often reported high batch-to-batch variations and unexpected growth and production differences. Population heterogeneity is suspected to be one responsible factor, which is so far not systematically investigated at the single-cell level. Novel microfluidic single-cell cultivation devices offer promising solutions to investigate these phenomena. In this study, we investigated the germination and growth behavior of Streptomyces lividans TK24 under varying medium compositions on different complexity levels (i.e., mycelial growth, hyphal growth and tip elongation) on single-cell level. Our analysis reveals a remarkable stability within growth and germination of spores and early mycelium development when exposed to constant and defined environments. We show that spores undergo long metabolic adaptation processes of up to &gt; 30 h to adjust to new medium conditions, rather than using a "persister" strategy as a possibility to cope with rapidly changing environments. Due to this uniform behavior, we conclude that S. lividans can be cultivated quite robustly under constant environmental conditions as provided by microfluidic cultivation approaches. Failure and non-reproducible cultivations are thus most likely to be found in less controllable larger-scale cultivation workflows and as a result of environmental gradients within large-scale cultivations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fmicb-09-02680.gruenberger.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2932764/2933194/fmicb-09-02680.gruenberger.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Streptomyces lividans</topic><topic>filamentous growth</topic><topic>microfluidics</topic><topic>single-cell</topic><topic>cultivation</topic><topic>germination</topic><topic>tip elongation rate</topic><topic>heterogeneity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-302x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-302X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30524383</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000450890100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29327647</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2018.02680</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Koepff, Joachim, Sachs, Christian Carsten, Wiechert, Wolfgang, Kohlheyer, Dietrich, Noeh, Katharina, Oldiges, Marco, and Grünberger, Alexander. “Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions”. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9 (2018): 2680.</mla>
<default>Koepff J, Sachs CC, Wiechert W, Kohlheyer D, Noeh K, Oldiges M, Grünberger A (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9: 2680.</default>
<lncs> Koepff, J., Sachs, C.C., Wiechert, W., Kohlheyer, D., Noeh, K., Oldiges, M., Grünberger, A.: Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY. 9, : 2680 (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koepff, Joachim, Sachs, Christian Carsten, Wiechert, Wolfgang, Kohlheyer, Dietrich, Noeh, Katharina, Oldiges, Marco, and Grünberger, Alexander. 2018. “Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions”. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9: 2680.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Koepff, J., Sachs, C. C., Wiechert, W., Kohlheyer, D., Noeh, K., Oldiges, M., &amp;amp; Grünberger, A. (2018). Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 2680. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2018.02680</apa>
<ieee> J. Koepff, et al., “Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions”, &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2018, : 2680.</ieee>
<ama>Koepff J, Sachs CC, Wiechert W, et al. Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;9: 2680.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koepff, J., Sachs, C.C., Wiechert, W., Kohlheyer, D., Noeh, K., Oldiges, M. &amp;amp; Grünberger, A. (2018). Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;: 2680. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2018.02680.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Koepff, J., Sachs, C. C., Wiechert, W., Kohlheyer, D., Noeh, K., Oldiges, M., and Grünberger, A. (2018). Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9:2680.</frontiers>
<bio1>Koepff J, Sachs CC, Wiechert W, Kohlheyer D, Noeh K, Oldiges M, Grünberger A (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions.&lt;br /&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY 9: 2680.</bio1>
<harvard1>Koepff, J., et al., 2018. Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 9: 2680.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koepff, J., Sachs, C. C., Wiechert, W., Kohlheyer, D., Noeh, K., Oldiges, M., &amp;amp; Grünberger, A. (2018). Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions. &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 2680. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2018.02680&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Koepff, C. C.  Sachs, W.  Wiechert, D.  Kohlheyer, K.  Noeh, M.  Oldiges, and A.  Grünberger, “Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions”, &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, : 2680.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Koepff, J.; Sachs, C. C.; Wiechert, W.; Kohlheyer, D.; Noeh, K.; Oldiges, M.; Grünberger, A. (2018): Germination and Growth Analysis of Streptomyces lividans at the Single-Cell Level Under Varying Medium Compositions &lt;em&gt;FRONTIERS IN MICROBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,9:2680</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2932764</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2018-12-18T15:09:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:40Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>