<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2933276</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:090</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Niko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Partanen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rießler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">110388077</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2397-2860</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Tommi A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Pirinen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given"> Heiki-Jaan</namePart><namePart type="family">Kaalep</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Francis M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Tyers</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4961795</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Language</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper presents experiments done in order to build a functional OCR model for the Unified Northern Alphabet. This writing system was used between 1931 and 1937 for 16 (Uralic and non-Uralic) minority languages spoken in the Soviet Union. The character accuracy of the developed model reaches more than 98% and clearly shows cross-linguistic applicability. The tests described here therefore also include general guidelines for the amount of training data needed to boot-strap an OCR system under similar conditions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="partanenetal2019a.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2933276/2933277/partanenetal2019a.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Tartu</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-948087-92-6</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29332762</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">77-89</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Partanen, N., and Rießler, M. (2019). “An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet” in &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, Pirinen, T. A., Kaalep,  H. - J., Tyers, F. M., and Association for Computational Linguistics eds. (Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics), 77-89.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, N. &amp;amp; Rießler, M. (2019). An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In T.A. Pirinen, H.-J. Kaalep, F.M. Tyers &amp;amp; Association for Computational Linguistics (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (S. 77-89). Gehalten auf der The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Language, Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Partanen N, Rießler M. An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In: Pirinen TA, Kaalep  H-J, Tyers FM, Association for Computational Linguistics, eds. &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics;  2019: 77-89.</ama>
<ieee> N. Partanen and M. Rießler, “An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet”, &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, T.A. Pirinen, et al., eds.,  Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2019,  pp.77-89.</ieee>
<apa>Partanen, N., &amp;amp; Rießler, M. (2019). An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In T. A.  Pirinen, H. - J.  Kaalep, F. M.  Tyers, &amp;amp; Association for Computational Linguistics (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-89). Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics.</apa>
<wels>Partanen, N.; Rießler, M. (2019): An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In: Tommi A. Pirinen; Heiki-Jaan Kaalep; Francis M. Tyers; Association for Computational Linguistics (Hrsg.):  The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics.  S. 77-89.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Partanen, and M.  Rießler, in &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T.A. Pirinen, H.-J. Kaalep, F.M. Tyers, Association for Computational Linguistics), Association For Computational Linguistics, Tartu, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 77-89.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Partanen, N., &amp;amp; Rießler, M., 2019. An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In T. A.  Pirinen, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;.  Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 77-89.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, N., &amp;amp; Rießler, M. (2019). An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In T. A.  Pirinen, H. - J.  Kaalep, F. M.  Tyers, &amp;amp; Association for Computational Linguistics (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 77-89). Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Partanen N, Rießler M (2019) &lt;br /&gt;An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Pirinen TA, Kaalep  H-J, Tyers FM, Association for Computational Linguistics (Eds); Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics:  77-89.</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Partanen, Niko, and Rießler, Michael. 2019. “An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet”. In &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Tommi A. Pirinen, Heiki-Jaan Kaalep, Francis M. Tyers, and Association for Computational Linguistics, 77-89. Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Partanen, N., Rießler, M.: An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet. In: Pirinen, T.A., Kaalep,  H.-J., Tyers, F.M., and Association for Computational Linguistics (eds.) The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. p. 77-89. Association for Computational Linguistics, Tartu (2019).</lncs>
<default>Partanen N, Rießler M (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages. Pirinen TA, Kaalep  H-J, Tyers FM, Association for Computational Linguistics (Eds);  Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics:  77-89.</default>
<mla>Partanen, Niko, and Rießler, Michael. “An OCR system for the Unified Northern Alphabet”. &lt;em&gt;The fifth International Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Uralic Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Tommi A. Pirinen, Heiki-Jaan Kaalep, Francis M. Tyers, and Association for Computational Linguistics. Tartu: Association for Computational Linguistics, 2019. 77-89.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2933276</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-22T20:28:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-24T09:55:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>