<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2933813</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Neofytos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rodosthenous</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We solve an infinite time-horizon bounded-variation stochastic control problem with regime
switching between *N* states. This is motivated by the problem of a government that wants to control
the country's debt-to-GDP (gross domestic product) ratio. In our formulation, the debt-to-GDP ratio
evolves stochastically in continuous time, and its drift - given by the interest rate on government debt,
net of the growth rate of GDP - is affected by an exogenous macroeconomic risk process modelled by a
continuous-time Markov chain with *N* states. The government can act on the public debt by increasing
or decreasing its level, and it aims at minimising a net expected cost functional. Without relying on a
guess-and-verify approach, but performing a direct probabilistic study, we show that it is optimal to keep
the debt-to-GDP ratio in an interval, whose boundaries depend on the states of the risk process. These
boundaries are given through a zero-sum optimal stopping game with regime switching with *N* states and
we completely characterise them as solutions to a system of nonlinear algebraic equations with constraints.
To the best of our knowledge, such a result appears here for the first time. Finally, we put in practice our
methodology in a case study of a Markov chain with *N* = 2 states; we provide a thorough analysis and
we complement our theoretical results by a detailed numerical study on the sensitivity of the optimal debt
ratio management policy with respect to the problem's parameters.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_589a.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2933813/2933814/IMW_working_paper_589a.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>zero-sum optimal stopping game</topic><topic>free-boundary problem</topic><topic>regime switching</topic><topic>debt-to-GDP ratio</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29338135</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>589</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> G. Ferrari and N. Rodosthenous, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019.,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 589) Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<frontiers>Ferrari, G., and Rodosthenous, N. (2019). Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G. &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers) (Aktual. Version Februar 2019.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 589 Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Ferrari, and N.  Rodosthenous, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019., Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 589) Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Ferrari, G.; Rodosthenous, N. (2019): Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy. Aktual. Version Februar 2019.  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<default>Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<mla>Ferrari, Giorgio, and Rodosthenous, Neofytos. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;. Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 589.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ferrari, Giorgio, and Rodosthenous, Neofytos. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy&lt;/em&gt;. Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Vol. 589. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ferrari, G., Rodosthenous, N.: Optimal Control of Debt-To-GDP Ratio in an N-State Regime Switching Economy. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 589, Aktual. Version Februar 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2933813</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-02-18T10:36:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>