<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2933667</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fernando</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Perez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42903143</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luciana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fernandes de Brito</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42903063</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Pipecolic acid or L-PA is a cyclic amino acid derived from L-lysine which has gained interest in the recent years within the pharmaceutical and chemical industries. L-PA can be produced efficiently using recombinant Corynebacterium glutamicum strains by expanding the natural L-lysine biosynthetic pathway. L-PA is a six-membered ring homolog of the five-membered ring amino acid L-proline, which serves as compatible solute in C. glutamicum.

Here, we show that de novo synthesized or externally added L-PA partially is beneficial for growth under hyper-osmotic stress conditions. C. glutamicum cells accumulated L-PA under elevated osmotic pressure and released it after an osmotic down shock. In the absence of the mechanosensitive channel YggB intracellular L-PA concentrations increased and its release after osmotic down shock was slower. The proline permease ProP was identified as a candidate L-PA uptake system since RNAseq analysis revealed increased proP RNA levels upon L-PA production. Under hyper-osmotic conditions, a ΔproP strain showed similar growth behavior than the parent strain when L-proline was added externally. By contrast, the growth impairment of the ΔproP strain under hyper-osmotic conditions could not be alleviated by addition of L-PA unless proP was expressed from a plasmid. This is commensurate with the view that L-proline can be imported into the C. glutamicum cell by ProP and other transporters such as EctP and PutP, while ProP appears of major importance for L-PA uptake under hyper-osmotic stress conditions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fmicb-10-00340 (2).wendisch.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2933667/2934306/fmicb-10-00340 (2).wendisch.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in  Microbiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-302x</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-302X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30858843</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000459596600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29336676</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2019.00340</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><extent unit="pages">340</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Perez, F.; Fernandes de Brito, L.; Wendisch, V. F. (2019): Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,10: 340.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Perez, L.  Fernandes de Brito, and V. F.  Wendisch, “Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 340.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2019). Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 340. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2019.00340&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Perez F, Fernandes de Brito L, Wendisch VF (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology 10: 340.</bio1>
<harvard1>Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F., 2019. Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, 10, p 340.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L., and Wendisch, V. F. (2019). Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 10, 340.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L. &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F. (2019). Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 340. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2019.00340.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Perez F, Fernandes de Brito L, Wendisch VF. Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;10:340.</ama>
<ieee> F. Perez, L. Fernandes de Brito, and V.F. Wendisch, “Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2019,  pp. 340.</ieee>
<apa>Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2019). Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 340. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2019.00340</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Perez, Fernando, Fernandes de Brito, Luciana, and Wendisch, Volker F. 2019. “Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 10: 340.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Perez, F., Fernandes de Brito, L., Wendisch, V.F.: Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions. Frontiers in  Microbiology. 10, 340 (2019).</lncs>
<default>Perez F, Fernandes de Brito L, Wendisch VF (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 10: 340.</default>
<mla>Perez, Fernando, Fernandes de Brito, Luciana, and Wendisch, Volker F. “Function of L-Pipecolic acid as compatible solute in Corynebacterium glutamicum as basis for its production under hyperosmolar conditions”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in  Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; 10 (2019): 340.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2933667</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-02-08T10:06:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>