<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2933212</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hofmanová</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">106484011</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart><namePart type="family">Eberle</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Martin</namePart><namePart type="family">Grothaus</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Walter</namePart><namePart type="family">Hoh</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Moritz</namePart><namePart type="family">Kassmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wilhelm</namePart><namePart type="family">Stannat</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Geralt</namePart><namePart type="family">Trutnau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ON  THE  ROUGH  GRONWALL  LEMMA  AND  ITS  APPLICATION.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2933212/2933213/ON  THE  ROUGH  GRONWALL  LEMMA  AND  ITS  APPLICATION.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-319-74929-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29332122</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-74929-7_21</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">333-344</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofmanová, M. (2016). On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications (Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics ). In A. Eberle, M. Grothaus, W. Hoh, M. Kassmann, W. Stannat &amp;amp; G. Trutnau (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (S. 333-344). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-74929-7_21.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Hofmanová M (2016) &lt;br /&gt;On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany. Eberle A, Grothaus M, Hoh W, Kassmann M, Stannat W, Trutnau G (Eds); Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics ,  Cham: Springer:  333-344.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Hofmanová, in &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Eberle, M. Grothaus, W. Hoh, M. Kassmann, W. Stannat, G. Trutnau), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 333-344.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Hofmanová M. On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In: Eberle A, Grothaus M, Hoh W, Kassmann M, Stannat W, Trutnau G, eds. &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics . Cham: Springer;  2016: 333-344.</ama>
<lncs> Hofmanová, M.: On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In: Eberle, A., Grothaus, M., Hoh, W., Kassmann, M., Stannat, W., and Trutnau, G. (eds.) Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics . p. 333-344. Springer, Cham (2016).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofmanová, Martina. 2016. “On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications”. In &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Andreas Eberle, Martin Grothaus, Walter Hoh, Moritz Kassmann, Wilhelm Stannat, and Geralt Trutnau, 333-344. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics . Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hofmanová, M. (2016). On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In A.  Eberle, M.  Grothaus, W.  Hoh, M.  Kassmann, W.  Stannat, &amp;amp; G.  Trutnau (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 333-344). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-74929-7_21&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hofmanová, Martina. “On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications”. &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Andreas Eberle, Martin Grothaus, Walter Hoh, Moritz Kassmann, Wilhelm Stannat, and Geralt Trutnau. Cham: Springer, 2016. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics . 333-344.</mla>
<frontiers>Hofmanová, M. (2016). “On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications” in &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Eberle, A., Grothaus, M., Hoh, W., Kassmann, M., Stannat, W., and Trutnau, G. eds. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics  (Cham: Springer), 333-344.</frontiers>
<wels>Hofmanová, M. (2016): On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In: Andreas Eberle; Martin Grothaus; Walter Hoh; Moritz Kassmann; Wilhelm Stannat; Geralt Trutnau (Hrsg.):  Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany. Cham: Springer. (Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics , ).  S. 333-344.</wels>
<default>Hofmanová M (2016)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany. Eberle A, Grothaus M, Hoh W, Kassmann M, Stannat W, Trutnau G (Eds);  Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics .  Cham: Springer:  333-344.</default>
<ieee> M. Hofmanová, “On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications”, &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;, A. Eberle, et al., eds., Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics ,  Cham: Springer, 2016,  pp.333-344.</ieee>
<harvard1>Hofmanová, M., 2016. On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In A.  Eberle, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics .  Cham: Springer, pp. 333-344.</harvard1>
<apa>Hofmanová, M. (2016). On the Rough Gronwall lemma and it's aplications. In A.  Eberle, M.  Grothaus, W.  Hoh, M.  Kassmann, W.  Stannat, &amp;amp; G.  Trutnau (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Springer Proceedings in Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Stochastic Partial Differential Equations and Related Fields. In Honor of Michael Röckner SPDERF, Bielefeld, Germany&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 333-344). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-74929-7_21</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2933212</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-22T09:55:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-23T15:54:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>