<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2933147</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Miryana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grigorova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marie-Claire</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Quenez</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Agnès</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sulem</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper studies the superhedging prices and the associated superhedging strategies
for European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default.
We present the seller's and the buyer's point of view. The underlying market
model consists of a risk-free asset and a risky asset driven by a Brownian motion and
a compensated default martingale. The portfolio process follows non-linear dynamics
with a non-linear driver ƒ. By using a dynamic programming approach, we first
provide a dual formulation of the seller's (superhedging) price for the European option
as the supremum over a suitable set of equivalent probability measures *Q* ∈ $\mathcal{Q}$  of
the ƒ-evaluation/expectation under *Q* of the payoff. We also provide an infinitesimal
characterization of this price as the minimal supersolution of a constrained BSDE with
default. By a form of symmetry, we derive corresponding results for the buyer. We also
give a dual representation of the seller's (superhedging) price for the American option
associated with an irregular payoff (ξ&lt;sub&gt;*t*&lt;/sub&gt;) (not necessarily càdlàg) in terms of the value of
a non-linear mixed control/stopping problem. We also provide an infinitesimal characterization
of this price in terms of a constrained reflected BSDE. When ξ is càdlàg,
we show a duality result for the buyer's price. These results rely on first establishing a
non-linear optional decomposition for processes which are $\mathcal{E}$&lt;sup&gt;ƒ&lt;/sup&gt; -strong supermartingales
under *Q*, for all *Q* ∈ $\mathcal{Q}$ .</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_607.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2933147/2933148/IMW_working_paper_607.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>European options</topic><topic>American options</topic><topic>incomplete markets</topic><topic>non-linear pricing</topic><topic>BSDEs with constraints</topic><topic>constrained re ected BSDEs</topic><topic>ƒ-expectation</topic><topic>control problems with non-linear expectation</topic><topic>optimal stopping with non-linear expectation</topic><topic>non-linear optional decomposition</topic><topic>pricing-hedging duality</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29331479</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>607</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Grigorova, M., Quenez, M. - C., &amp;amp; Sulem, A. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 607). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<lncs> Grigorova, M., Quenez, M.-C., Sulem, A.: Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 607. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2018).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grigorova, Miryana, Quenez, Marie-Claire, and Sulem, Agnès. 2018. &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 607. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> M. Grigorova, M.-C. Quenez, and A. Sulem, &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 607,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018.</ieee>
<harvard1>Grigorova, M., Quenez, M.-C., &amp;amp; Sulem, A., 2018. &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.607, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ama>Grigorova M, Quenez M-C, Sulem A. &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 607. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2018.</ama>
<default>Grigorova M, Quenez M-C, Sulem A (2018)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 607.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<bio1>Grigorova M, Quenez M-C, Sulem A (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 607.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Grigorova, M. - C.  Quenez, and A.  Sulem, &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Grigorova, M.; Quenez, M. - C.; Sulem, A. (2018): Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Grigorova, M., Quenez, M. - C., and Sulem, A. (2018). Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 607, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Grigorova, Miryana, Quenez, Marie-Claire, and Sulem, Agnès. &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2018. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 607.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grigorova, M., Quenez, M. - C., &amp;amp; Sulem, A. (2018).  &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 607). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Grigorova, M., Quenez, M.-C. &amp;amp; Sulem, A. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Superhedging prices of European and American options in a non-linear incomplete market with default&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2933147</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-01-18T08:45:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>