<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2934511</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sonja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stange</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">83293033</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Teena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">145592345</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christopher</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">119682237</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">14743</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4047-9277</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In order to establish long-term relationships with users, social companion robots and their behaviors need to be comprehensible. Purely reactive behavior such as answering questions or following commands can be readily interpreted by users. However, the robot's proactive behaviors, included in order to increase liveliness and improve the user experience, often raise a need for explanation. In this paper, we provide a concept to produce accessible “why-explanations” for the goal-directed behavior an autonomous, lively robot might produce. To this end we present an architecture that provides reasons for behaviors in terms of comprehensible needs and strategies of the robot, and we propose a model for generating different kinds of explanations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Stange-etal-2019-MM-Cog.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2934511/2936125/Stange-etal-2019-MM-Cog.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Montréal, Canada</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29345114</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Stange, H.  Buschmeier, T.  Hassan, C.  Ritter, and S.  Kopp, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Stange S, Buschmeier H, Hassan T, Ritter C, Kopp S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</bio1>
<default>Stange S, Buschmeier H, Hassan T, Ritter C, Kopp S (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stange, S., Buschmeier, H., Hassan, T., Ritter, C. &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2019). Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture. Gehalten auf der AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Stange, S., Buschmeier, H., Hassan, T., Ritter, C., and Kopp, S. (2019).“Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture”. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</frontiers>
<mla>Stange, Sonja, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Hassan, Teena, Ritter, Christopher, and Kopp, Stefan. “Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture”. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada, 2019.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stange, S., Buschmeier, H., Hassan, T., Ritter, C., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Stange, S.; Buschmeier, H.; Hassan, T.; Ritter, C.; Kopp, S. (2019): Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stange, Sonja, Buschmeier, Hendrik, Hassan, Teena, Ritter, Christopher, and Kopp, Stefan. 2019. “Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture”. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Stange, S., Buschmeier, H., Hassan, T., Ritter, C., Kopp, S.: Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada (2019).</lncs>
<apa>Stange, S., Buschmeier, H., Hassan, T., Ritter, C., &amp;amp; Kopp, S. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</apa>
<ama>Stange S, Buschmeier H, Hassan T, Ritter C, Kopp S. Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</ama>
<harvard1>Stange, S., et al., 2019. Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture. Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Stange, et al., “Towards self-explaining social robots. Verbal explanation strategies for a needs-based architecture”, Presented at the AAMAS 2019 Workshop on Cognitive Architectures for HRI: Embodied Models of Situated Natural Language Interactions (MM-Cog), Montréal, Canada, 2019.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2934511</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-03-26T08:31:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-06-24T09:47:35Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>