<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2934916</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heidemarie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winkel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55972923</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The article starts with a discussion of history’s and historical sociology’s influence on gender sociology. It is argued that the reconstruction of gender-historical developments as institutionally and socio-culturally sequential processes, or as historical figurations and their causal mechanisms, is a marginal research agenda in gender sociology. As a result, colonial history and its gendered legacy—which is considered pivotal for a comprehensive conceptual understanding of contemporary society—is (still) relegated to a back seat in gender sociology. This is reflected in the way how current anti-genderist controversies in European societies are discussed in terms of theory; gender sociology misses both to consult gender-historical and postcolonial perspectives systematically in the analysis of anti-genderism, although postcolonial approaches have become prominent in global historical sociology in the last decade. I suggest conceiving anti-genderists’ stance clearly as an indicator of European societies’ colonial (epistemic) legacy and as a result of the consistent (re)nationalization of gender throughout the twentieth century. Against this backdrop, the contribution starts from the question to what extent a global historical sociology can enable gender sociology to decolonize its body of knowledge and to decode the continuing (re)nationalization of gender as a colonial legacy. This includes a reflection on the extent to which gender sociology is built on a colonial body of white gender knowledge and how gender can be made visible as a colonial category of knowledge production. Accordingly, the deconstruction of gender sociology’s blind spot vis-a-vis its own imperial standpoint and its enmeshment with colonial epistemic legacies is envisioned as a central task. This is evidenced by the way how gender was inserted in national discourse throughout the second half of the twentieth century, namely as a medium that allows for the assertion of cultural differences between »us« and »them«. This finally led into a new, European nationalism after Germany’s so-called reunification, in which gender’s symbolic role once more became central, such as in the »headscarf debates« in the early 2000s, at a time when the NSU terror spread. At large it is argued that decolonial thinking reveals how classifications in terms of race and nation are unfolding as a cornerstone of the bourgeois, heteronormative gender order and how this is fostering the coloniality of gender, namely as part of (re)nationalization processes throughout the twentieth century up to now. As a consequence, recent anti-genderism affects white women and women of color alike, albeit in very different ways; but first and foremost, anti-genderism involves white women against women of color.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="1073-Article Text-4098-2-10-20190208(1).pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2934916/2950777/1073-Article Text-4098-2-10-20190208(1).pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://www.hbz-nrw.de/produkte/open-access/lizenzen/dppl/dppl/DPPL_v3_en_11-2008.pdf</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld, BGHS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2191-6721</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29349165</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/indi-1073</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">95-142</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Winkel H (2018) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt; 9(2): 95-142.</default>
<mla>Winkel, Heidemarie. “Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender”. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt; 9.2 (2018): 95-142.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Winkel, Heidemarie. 2018. “Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender”. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt; 9 (2): 95-142.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Winkel, H.: Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology. 9, 95-142 (2018).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Winkel, “Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender”, &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 95-142.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Winkel H (2018) &lt;br /&gt;Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender.&lt;br /&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology 9(2): 95-142.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Winkel, H. (2018). Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 95-142. doi:10.4119/indi-1073&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Winkel, H., 2018. Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, 9(2), p 95-142.</harvard1>
<wels>Winkel, H. (2018): Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;,9:(2): 95-142.</wels>
<ieee> H. Winkel, “Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender”, &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2018,  pp. 95-142.</ieee>
<apa>Winkel, H. (2018). Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 95-142. doi:10.4119/indi-1073</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Winkel, H. (2018). Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 95-142. Universität Bielefeld, BGHS. doi:10.4119/indi-1073.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Winkel, H. (2018). Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt; 9, 95-142.</frontiers>
<ama>Winkel H. Global Historical Sociology and Connected Gender Sociologies. On the Re-Nationalization and Coloniality of Gender. &lt;em&gt;Interdisciplines. Journal of History and Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. 2018;9(2):95-142.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2934916</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-11T13:24:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-01T17:13:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>