<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2934760</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ramsia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sreij</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">40853850</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dargel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">80738467</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schweins</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sylvain</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Prévost</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rajeev</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dattani</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19511146</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2394-5846</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17981</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The saponin aescin, a mixture of triterpenoid saponins, is obtained from the seeds of the horse chestnut tree Aesculus hippocastanum. The β-form employed in this study is haemolytically active. The haemolytic activity results from the ability of aescin to form strong complexes with cholesterol in the red blood cell membrane. In this study, we provide a structural analysis on the complex formation of aescin and cholesterol when embedded in a phospholipid model membrane formed by 1,2-dimyristoyl-sn-glycero-3-phosphocholine (DMPC). In this work, the temperatures investigated extend from DMPC’s Lβ′ to its Lα phase in dependence of different amounts of the saponin (0–6 mol% for calorimetric and 0–1 mol% for structural analyses) and the steroid (1–10 mol%). At these aescin contents model membranes are conserved in the form of small unilamellar vesicles (SUVs) and major overall structural modifications are avoided. Additionally, interactions between aescin and cholesterol can be studied for both phase states of the lipid, the gel and the fluid state. From calorimetric experiments by differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), it could be shown that both, the steroid and the saponin content, have a significant impact on the cooperative phase transition behaviour of the DMPC molecules. In addition, it becomes clearly visible that the entire phase behaviour is dominated by phase separation which indeed also depends on the complexes formed between aescin and cholesterol. We show by various methods that the addition of cholesterol alters the impact of aescin on structural parameters ranging from the acyl chain correlation to vesicle-vesicle interactions. While the specific saponin-phospholipid interaction is reduced, addition of cholesterol leads to deformation of SUVs. The analyses of the structures formed were performed by wide-angle X-ray scattering (WAXS), small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS), and small-angle neutron scattering (SANS).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s41598-019-41865-z.hellweg.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2934760/2934761/s41598-019-41865-z.hellweg.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Scientific Reports</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2045-2322</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2045-2322</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30944386</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000463178500003</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29347604</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-41865-z</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sreij, R., Dargel, C., Schweins, R., Prévost, S., Dattani, R., &amp;amp; Hellweg, T. (2019). Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 5542. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-41865-z&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Sreij, R., Dargel, C., Schweins, R., Prévost, S., Dattani, R., and Hellweg, T. (2019). Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt; 9:5542.</frontiers>
<mla>Sreij, Ramsia, Dargel, Carina, Schweins, Ralf, Prévost, Sylvain, Dattani, Rajeev, and Hellweg, Thomas. “Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study”. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt; 9.1 (2019): 5542.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sreij, R., Dargel, C., Schweins, R., Prévost, S., Dattani, R. &amp;amp; Hellweg, T. (2019). Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1): 5542. Springer Nature. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-41865-z.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Sreij, R.; Dargel, C.; Schweins, R.; Prévost, S.; Dattani, R.; Hellweg, T. (2019): Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;,9:(1):5542</wels>
<bio1>Sreij R, Dargel C, Schweins R, Prévost S, Dattani R, Hellweg T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study.&lt;br /&gt;Scientific Reports 9(1): 5542.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Sreij, C.  Dargel, R.  Schweins, S.  Prévost, R.  Dattani, and T.  Hellweg, “Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study”, &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, : 5542.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Sreij R, Dargel C, Schweins R, Prévost S, Dattani R, Hellweg T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt; 9(1): 5542.</default>
<ama>Sreij R, Dargel C, Schweins R, Prévost S, Dattani R, Hellweg T. Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;9(1): 5542.</ama>
<ieee> R. Sreij, et al., “Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study”, &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2019, : 5542.</ieee>
<harvard1>Sreij, R., et al., 2019. Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, 9(1): 5542.</harvard1>
<lncs> Sreij, R., Dargel, C., Schweins, R., Prévost, S., Dattani, R., Hellweg, T.: Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. Scientific Reports. 9, : 5542 (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sreij, Ramsia, Dargel, Carina, Schweins, Ralf, Prévost, Sylvain, Dattani, Rajeev, and Hellweg, Thomas. 2019. “Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study”. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt; 9 (1): 5542.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Sreij, R., Dargel, C., Schweins, R., Prévost, S., Dattani, R., &amp;amp; Hellweg, T. (2019). Aescin-Cholesterol Complexes in DMPC Model Membranes: A DSC and Temperature-Dependent Scattering Study. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(1), 5542. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-41865-z</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2934760</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-04T08:32:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>