<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2934296</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:620</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sugeeth</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gopinathan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55534672</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Jochen J.</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Steil</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Recent advancements in physical human-robot interaction (pHRI) makes it possible for
compliant robots to assist the human counterpart while closely working together. An ideal
control mode designed for pHRI should be easy to handle, intuitive to use, ergonomic
and adaptive to human habits and preferences. The major stumbling block in achieving
this is that each user has varying physical capabilities and characteristics. This variance
in the user behavior and other features is often high and rather unpredictable, which
hinders the development of such systems. To tackle this problem, the idea of personalized
adaptive stiffness control for pHRI is introduced in this thesis. Extensive user-studies are
conducted in scope of this thesis and various control modes for pHRI are proposed and
evaluated using appropriate user-studies. Both naive and expert users were considered in
the user-studies and inferences from each study were used to improve the control mode
to be better suited for pHRI.&lt;br /&gt;
The thesis follows a meticulous research plan, an initial user-study confirms the im-
portance of pHRI and kinesthetic guidance in industrial tasks. Subsequently, the user
interactive force based adaptation is proposed and a second user-study is conducted where
it is compared with standard control modes for pHRI. Importance of task specific param-
eters and the need for combining the task and human factors emerged from the results
of the second user-study. In the next phase manipulability based approaches which com-
bine both task and human parameters are proposed and validated by conducting a third
user-study. In the final phase a fourth user-study is conducted where the proposed con-
trol modes are compared against more complex methods that have been proposed in the
literature.&lt;br /&gt;
The importance of human physical factors and needs for human centered systems for
pHRI is validated in this thesis. The results show that including these human factors not
only improve the performance but also improves the interaction quality and reduces the
complexity of the pHRI.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Sugeeth_thesis.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2934296/2934297/Sugeeth_thesis.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29342961</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2934296</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2018-12-20</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Gopinathan, S. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2934296</apa>
<harvard1>Gopinathan, S., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Gopinathan, &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</ieee>
<default>Gopinathan S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<wels>Gopinathan, S. (2019): Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gopinathan, S. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2934296&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Gopinathan, Sugeeth. &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</mla>
<frontiers>Gopinathan, S. (2019). Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<lncs> Gopinathan, S.: Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gopinathan, Sugeeth. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Gopinathan S. &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2019.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Gopinathan, &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Gopinathan S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gopinathan, S. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Personalization and Adaptation in Physical Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2934296.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2934296</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-03-11T15:13:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-03-19T14:46:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>