<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2935007</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schrieber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">78068579</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sabrina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Catherina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wypior</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Diana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoehlig</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephen R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabell</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hensen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susanne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lachmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Inbreeding and enemy infestation are common in plants and can synergistically reduce their performance. This inbreeding xenvironment (I x E) interaction may be of particular importance for the success of plant invasions if introduced populations experience a release from attack by natural enemies relative to their native conspecifics. Here, we investigate whether inbreeding affects plant infestation damage, whether inbreeding depression in growth and reproduction is mitigated by enemy release, and whether this effect is more pronounced in invasive than native plant populations. We used the invader Silene latifolia and its natural enemies as a study system. We performed two generations of experimental out- and inbreeding within eight native (European) and eight invasive (North American) populations under controlled conditions using field-collected seeds. Subsequently, we exposed the offspring to an enemy exclusion and inclusion treatment in a common garden in the species' native range to assess the interactive effects of population origin (range), breeding treatment, and enemy treatment on infestation damage, growth, and reproduction. Inbreeding increased flower and leaf infestation damage in plants from both ranges, but had opposing effects on fruit damage in native versus invasive plants. Inbreeding significantly reduced plant fitness; whereby, inbreeding depression in fruit number was higher in enemy inclusions than exclusions. This effect was equally pronounced in populations from both distribution ranges. Moreover, the magnitude of inbreeding depression in fruit number was lower in invasive than native populations. These results support that inbreeding has the potential to reduce plant defenses in S. latifolia, which magnifies inbreeding depression in the presence of enemies. However, future studies are necessary to further explore whether enemy release in the invaded habitat has actually decreased inbreeding depression and thus facilitated the persistence of inbred founder populations and invasion success.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ece3.4990.schrieber.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2935007/2941993/ece3.4990.schrieber.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>biological invasion</topic><topic>plant defense</topic><topic>evolution</topic><topic>genetic paradox</topic><topic>herbivory</topic><topic>inbreeding</topic><topic>purging</topic><topic>Silene latifolia</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ecology and Evolution</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2045-7758</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2045-7758</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">30962911</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000462384800035</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29350072</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/ece3.4990</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">3564-3576</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schrieber, Karin, Wolf, Sabrina, Wypior, Catherina, Hoehlig, Diana, Keller, Stephen R., Hensen, Isabell, and Lachmuth, Susanne. 2019. “Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 9 (6): 3564-3576.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schrieber, K., Wolf, S., Wypior, C., Hoehlig, D., Keller, S.R., Hensen, I., Lachmuth, S.: Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. Ecology and Evolution. 9, 3564-3576 (2019).</lncs>
<default>Schrieber K, Wolf S, Wypior C, Hoehlig D, Keller SR, Hensen I, Lachmuth S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 9(6): 3564-3576.</default>
<mla>Schrieber, Karin, Wolf, Sabrina, Wypior, Catherina, Hoehlig, Diana, Keller, Stephen R., Hensen, Isabell, and Lachmuth, Susanne. “Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations”. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 9.6 (2019): 3564-3576.</mla>
<wels>Schrieber, K.; Wolf, S.; Wypior, C.; Hoehlig, D.; Keller, S. R.; Hensen, I.; Lachmuth, S. (2019): Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,9:(6): 3564-3576.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Schrieber, S.  Wolf, C.  Wypior, D.  Hoehlig, S. R.  Keller, I.  Hensen, and S.  Lachmuth, “Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 3564-3576.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schrieber K, Wolf S, Wypior C, Hoehlig D, Keller SR, Hensen I, Lachmuth S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations.&lt;br /&gt;Ecology and Evolution 9(6): 3564-3576.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schrieber, K., Wolf, S., Wypior, C., Hoehlig, D., Keller, S. R., Hensen, I., &amp;amp; Lachmuth, S. (2019). Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(6), 3564-3576. doi:10.1002/ece3.4990&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Schrieber, K., et al., 2019. Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, 9(6), p 3564-3576.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Schrieber, K., Wolf, S., Wypior, C., Hoehlig, D., Keller, S. R., Hensen, I., and Lachmuth, S. (2019). Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt; 9, 3564-3576.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schrieber, K., Wolf, S., Wypior, C., Hoehlig, D., Keller, S.R., Hensen, I. &amp;amp; Lachmuth, S. (2019). Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(6), 3564-3576. Wiley. doi:10.1002/ece3.4990.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schrieber K, Wolf S, Wypior C, et al. Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;9(6):3564-3576.</ama>
<ieee> K. Schrieber, et al., “Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations”, &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2019,  pp. 3564-3576.</ieee>
<apa>Schrieber, K., Wolf, S., Wypior, C., Hoehlig, D., Keller, S. R., Hensen, I., &amp;amp; Lachmuth, S. (2019). Release from natural enemies mitigates inbreeding depression in native and invasive Silene latifolia populations. &lt;em&gt;Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(6), 3564-3576. doi:10.1002/ece3.4990</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2935007</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-15T07:03:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:59:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>