<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2935170</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:004</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pablo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">d'Angelo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18304588</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart> ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS 2007</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">This paper describes a method to photometrically align registered and overlapping images which have been subject to vignetting (radial light falloff), exposure variations, white balance variation and nonlinear camera response. Applications include estimation of vignetting and camera response; vignetting and exposure compensation for image image mosaicing; and creation of high dynamic range mosaics. Compared to previous work white balance changes can be compensated and a computationally efficient algorithm is presented. The method is evaluated with synthetic and real images and is shown to produce better results than comparable methods.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="239-Artikeltext-329-1-10-20190603.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2935170/2956460/239-Artikeltext-329-1-10-20190603.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bielefeld, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29351706</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;d'Angelo, Pablo. 2007. “Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> d'Angelo, P.: Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007.  Bielefeld University, Bielefeld (2007).</lncs>
<ama>d'Angelo P. Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University;  2007.</ama>
<bio1>d'Angelo P (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007.  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  d'Angelo, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;d'Angelo, P. (2007). Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der  ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS 2007, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University. doi:10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>d'Angelo, P. (2007). Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt; Bielefeld: Bielefeld University. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> P. d'Angelo, “Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, 2007.</ieee>
<harvard1>d'Angelo, P., 2007. Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<default>d'Angelo P (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</default>
<frontiers>d'Angelo, P. (2007). “Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt; (Bielefeld: Bielefeld University).</frontiers>
<mla>d'Angelo, Pablo. “Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, 2007.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;d'Angelo, P. (2007). Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007&lt;/em&gt; Bielefeld: Bielefeld University. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.2390/BIECOLL-ICVS2007-179&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>d'Angelo, P. (2007): Radiometric alignment and vignetting calibration. In: Proceedings of the ICVS Workshop on Camera Calibration Methods for Computer Vision Systems - CCMVS2007. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2935170</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-18T11:11:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-26T14:11:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>