<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2935433</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:790</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given"> Bright Opoku </namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah </namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family"> Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given"> Joseph Kwame</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mintah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Francis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sambah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hormenu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background and Purpose: Given that Ghana continues to record higher rates of adolescent pregnancy among rural dwellers, notably, those living in the Brong Ahafo, Central and Volta regions, it is surprising that scholarly information related to socio-cultural determinants of this sequel in these mentioned areas of the country is limited. This study sought to examine the socio-cultural factors associated with pregnancy among adolescent girls in Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem (KEEA) Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana.

Methods and results: Using a matched case-control design with a 1:1 ratio, a facility-based sampling approach was used to select 400 adolescent females aged between 15 and 19 years. Chi-square analyses on the strictness level of rules and regulations in family [χ2(1) = 62.010, p &lt; 0.05], freedom within the family to discuss issues related to sexuality [χ2(1) = 9.600, p &lt; 0.05], religious support of sex before marriage [χ2(1) = 4.312, p &lt; 0.05], peer influence to engage in sexual intercourse [χ2(1) = 7.793, p &lt; 0.05], reaction of parents toward pregnancy [χ2(1) = 70.064, p &lt; 0.05], and reaction of siblings toward pregnancy [χ2(1) = 66.702, p &lt; 0.05] were significantly related to adolescents' pregnancy status. Additionally, binary logistic regression analysis also showed that non-pregnant adolescents were seven times more likely to belong to families with strict rules and regulations compared to pregnant adolescents [OR = 0.14, 95% CI = (0.07–0.25), p ≤ 0.01]. Non-pregnant adolescents were 3 times more likely to have freedom within the family to discuss issues related to sexuality compared to pregnant adolescents [OR = 0.33, 95% CI = (0.18–0.59), p ≤ 0.01]. However, pregnant adolescents were 3 times more likely to be influenced by their peers to engage in sexual intercourse [OR = 2.63, 95% CI = (1.46–4.74), p ≤ 0.001] and 3 times more likely to have parents with positive reaction toward adolescent pregnancy compared to non-pregnant adolescents [OR = 2.97, 95% CI = (1.15–7.70), p ≤ 0.05]. Additionally, these pregnant adolescents were eight times more likely to have siblings with positive reaction toward adolescent pregnancy [OR = 7.74, 95% CI = (2.59–21.4), p ≤ 0.001] compared to their non-pregnant counterparts.

Conclusion: Adolescent pregnancy heightens the risk of negating birth outcomes that is independent of recognized confounding variables. Therefore, adolescent girls in the KEEA Municipality are likely to experience continuous exposure to the risk of pregnancy with the existence of negative socio-cultural norms. Specific strategies need to involve multifaceted interventions that include education, competency-based skill training and support for young people, especially pregnant adolescents. Further research ought to determine which other factors would help us better understand circumstances that may lead to adolescent pregnancies in other areas of the region and perhaps among other subgroups.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpubh-07-00093-1.hagan.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2935433/2935575/fpubh-07-00093-1.hagan.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2296-2565</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2296-2565</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31069207</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000466970000002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29354335</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2019.00093</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Ahinkorah   BO, Hagan Jr. JE, Seidu A-A, et al. Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;7: 93.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah ,  Bright Opoku, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Mintah,  Joseph Kwame, Sambah, Francis, Schack, Thomas, and Hormenu, Thomas. 2019. “Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7: 93.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ahinkorah ,  B.O., Hagan Jr., J.E., Seidu, A.-A., Mintah,  J.K., Sambah, F., Schack, T., Hormenu, T.: Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. Frontiers in Public Health. 7, : 93 (2019).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah ,  B.O., Hagan Jr., J.E., Seidu, A.-A., Mintah,  J.K., Sambah, F., Schack, T. &amp;amp; Hormenu, T. (2019). Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;: 93. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00093.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Ahinkorah   BO, Hagan Jr. JE, Seidu A-A, Mintah  JK, Sambah F, Schack T, Hormenu T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Public Health 7: 93.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B. O.   Ahinkorah, J. E.  Hagan Jr., A. - A.   Seidu, J. K.  Mintah, F.  Sambah, T.  Schack, and T.  Hormenu, “Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, : 93.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> B.O.  Ahinkorah, et al., “Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2019, : 93.</ieee>
<harvard1>Ahinkorah ,  B.O., et al., 2019. Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 7: 93.</harvard1>
<apa>Ahinkorah ,  B. O., Hagan Jr., J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Mintah,  J. K., Sambah, F., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Hormenu, T. (2019). Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 93. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00093</apa>
<wels>Ahinkorah ,  B. O.; Hagan Jr., J. E.; Seidu, A. - A.; Mintah,  J. K.; Sambah, F.; Schack, T.; Hormenu, T. (2019): Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,7:93</wels>
<mla>Ahinkorah ,  Bright Opoku, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Mintah,  Joseph Kwame, Sambah, Francis, Schack, Thomas, and Hormenu, Thomas. “Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7 (2019): 93.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah ,  B. O., Hagan Jr., J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Mintah,  J. K., Sambah, F., Schack, T., &amp;amp; Hormenu, T. (2019). Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 93. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00093&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Ahinkorah ,  B. O., Hagan Jr., J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Mintah,  J. K., Sambah, F., Schack, T., and Hormenu, T. (2019). Examining Pregnancy Related Socio-Cultural Factors Among Adolescent Girls in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana: A Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7:93.</frontiers>
<default>Ahinkorah   BO, Hagan Jr. JE, Seidu A-A, Mintah  JK, Sambah F, Schack T, Hormenu T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7: 93.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2935433</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-29T11:27:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>