<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2935500</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:600</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">epub_ahead</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wojtynek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55534887</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen Jakob</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steil</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">76091</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0029-8188</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5408013</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">44327211</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The transformation of today's manufacturing lines into truly adaptive systems facilitating individualized mass production requires new approaches for the efficient integration, configuration and control of robotics and automation components.
Recently, various types of Plug-and-Produce architectures were proposed that support the discovery, integration and configuration of field devices, automation equipment or industrial robots during commissioning or even operation of manufacturing systems.
However, in many of these approaches, the configuration possibilities are limited, which is a particular problem if robots operate in dynamic environments with constrained workspaces and exchangeable automation components as typically required for flexible manufacturing processes.

In this article, we introduce an extended Plug-and-Produce concept based on dynamic motion planning, co-simulation and a collaborative human-robot interaction scheme that facilitates the quick adaptation of robotics behaviors in the context of a modular production system. 
To confirm our hypothesis on the efficiency and usability of this concept, we carried out a feasibility study where participants performed a flexible workcell setup. 
The results indicate that the assistance and features for planning effectively support the users in tasks of different complexity and that a quick adaption is indeed possible. 
Based on our observations, we identify further research challenges in the context of Plug, Plan and Produce applied to smart manufacturing.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ki-2019-mwojtynek.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2935500/2935850/ki-2019-mwojtynek.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0933-1875</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000469478800008</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29355003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s13218-019-00595-0</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>33</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">151-161</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Wojtynek, M.; Steil, J. J.; Wrede, S. (2019): Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;,33:(2): 151-161.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wojtynek, M., Steil, J.J. &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2019). Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(2), 151-161. Springer . doi:10.1007/s13218-019-00595-0.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Wojtynek, M., Steil, J. J., and Wrede, S. (2019). Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; 33, 151-161.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wojtynek, M., Steil, J. J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2019). Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(2), 151-161. doi:10.1007/s13218-019-00595-0&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Wojtynek, Michael, Steil, Jochen Jakob, and Wrede, Sebastian. “Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories”. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; 33.2 (2019): 151-161.</mla>
<default>Wojtynek M, Steil JJ, Wrede S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; 33(2): 151-161.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Wojtynek, J. J.  Steil, and S.  Wrede, “Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories”, &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;, 151-161.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Wojtynek M, Steil JJ, Wrede S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories.&lt;br /&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence 33(2): 151-161.</bio1>
<harvard1>Wojtynek, M., Steil, J.J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S., 2019. Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, 33(2), p 151-161.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Wojtynek, J.J. Steil, and S. Wrede, “Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories”, &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 33, 2019,  pp. 151-161.</ieee>
<ama>Wojtynek M, Steil JJ, Wrede S. Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;33(2):151-161.</ama>
<apa>Wojtynek, M., Steil, J. J., &amp;amp; Wrede, S. (2019). Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(2), 151-161. doi:10.1007/s13218-019-00595-0</apa>
<lncs> Wojtynek, M., Steil, J.J., Wrede, S.: Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories. KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence. 33, 151-161 (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wojtynek, Michael, Steil, Jochen Jakob, and Wrede, Sebastian. 2019. “Plug, Plan and Produce as Enabler for Easy Workcell Setup and Collaborative Robot Programming in Smart Factories”. &lt;em&gt;KI - Künstliche Intelligenz. German Journal of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; 33 (2): 151-161.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2935500</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-05-06T13:20:45Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-06-24T08:41:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>