<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2935374</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Salvatore</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Federico</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4244291</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4291-6610</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Röckner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10585</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study a class of infinite-dimensional singular stochastic control problems with
applications in economic theory and finance. The control process linearly affects an abstract
evolution equation on a suitable partially-ordered infinite-dimensional space X, it takes values in
the positive cone of X, and it has right-continuous and nondecreasing paths. We first provide a
rigorous formulation of the problem by properly defining the controlled dynamics and integrals
with respect to the control process. We then exploit the concave structure of our problem
and derive necessary and sufficient first-order conditions for optimality. The latter are finally
exploited in a specification of the model where we find an explicit expression of the optimal
control. The techniques used are those of semigroup theory, vector-valued integration, convex
analysis, and general theory of stochastic processes.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_614.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2935374/2935375/IMW_working_paper_614.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>infinite-dimensional singular stochastic control</topic><topic>semigroup theory</topic><topic>vector-valued integration</topic><topic>first-order conditions</topic><topic>Bank-El Karoui's representation theorem</topic><topic>irreversible investment.</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29353747</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>614</number></detail><extent unit="pages">22</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, Salvatore, Ferrari, Giorgio, Riedel, Frank, and Röckner, Michael. 2019. &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 614. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., Röckner, M.: On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 614. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<ama>Federico S, Ferrari G, Riedel F, Röckner M. &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 614. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Federico, G.  Ferrari, F.  Riedel, and M.  Röckner, &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Federico S, Ferrari G, Riedel F, Röckner M (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 614.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F. &amp;amp; Röckner, M. (2019). &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., &amp;amp; Röckner, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 614). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<harvard1>Federico, S., et al., 2019. &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.614, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Federico, et al., &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 614,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<default>Federico S, Ferrari G, Riedel F, Röckner M (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 614.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<wels>Federico, S.; Ferrari, G.; Riedel, F.; Röckner, M. (2019): On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., and Röckner, M. (2019). On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 614, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Federico, Salvatore, Ferrari, Giorgio, Riedel, Frank, and Röckner, Michael. &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 614.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Riedel, F., &amp;amp; Röckner, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;On a Class of Infinite-Dimensional Singular Stochastic Control Problems&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 614). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2935374</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-04-26T09:57:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>