<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2936963</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kurtenbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81097710</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rauf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">118920773</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Youth violence remains a concern in Germany, particularly in specific "risky" neighborhoods that tend to be socially segregated and ethnically diverse. In this paper we critically compare the results of twenty-seven qualitative interviews conducted in three risky neighborhoods in the German Ruhr area with the code of the street. While this theoretical framework is frequently cited in explaining youth violence, it was based on research in an ethnically homogenous neighborhood in the United States and thus does not engage with questions of diversity. Our findings show that the core of the code of the street is also applicable in heterogeneous contexts, thus extending the generalizability of the theoretical framework. Manifestations of manhood, reputation, and symbolic power were found to be major elements of street culture, although characterized somewhat differently than in the original work.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="3121-Article Text-15013-1-10-20191028.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2936963/2953274/3121-Article Text-15013-1-10-20191028.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem><accessCondition type="use and reproduction">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</accessCondition>
<originInfo><publisher>Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld Univ.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>youth violence</topic><topic>diversity</topic><topic>code of the street</topic><topic>urban sociology</topic><topic>Germany</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Conflict and Violence</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1864-1385</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000478760900002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29369631</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kurtenbach S, Rauf A (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 13: a653.</default>
<mla>Kurtenbach, Sebastian, and Rauf, Abdul. “The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 13 (2019): a653.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtenbach, Sebastian, and Rauf, Abdul. 2019. “The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 13: a653.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kurtenbach, S., Rauf, A.: The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. International Journal of Conflict and Violence. 13, : a653 (2019).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kurtenbach, and A.  Rauf, “The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, : a653.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kurtenbach S, Rauf A (2019) &lt;br /&gt;The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence 13: a653.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtenbach, S., &amp;amp; Rauf, A. (2019). The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, a653. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Kurtenbach, S., &amp;amp; Rauf, A., 2019. The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, 13: a653.</harvard1>
<wels>Kurtenbach, S.; Rauf, A. (2019): The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;,13:a653</wels>
<ieee> S. Kurtenbach and A. Rauf, “The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 13, 2019, : a653.</ieee>
<apa>Kurtenbach, S., &amp;amp; Rauf, A. (2019). The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, a653. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kurtenbach, S. &amp;amp; Rauf, A. (2019). The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;: a653. Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld Univ. doi:10.4119/UNIBI/ijcv.653.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kurtenbach, S., and Rauf, A. (2019). The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt; 13:a653.</frontiers>
<ama>Kurtenbach S, Rauf A. The Impact of Segregated Diversity on the Code of the Street.  An Analysis of Violence-related Norms in Selected Post-Industrial Neighborhoods in Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Conflict and Violence&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;13: a653.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2936963</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-08-16T09:02:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-25T15:00:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>