<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2936736</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carolin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kunz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46901328</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656025</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model is well-established in explaining work-related stress and health differences. A lack of reciprocity between efforts and rewards at the workplace is central to the theory. The third component (over-commitment) was defined to be a moderator of high-cost/low gain-working conditions increasing the risk of ill-health. Although the theory has been widely supported empirically, all underlying hypotheses have not been sufficiently tested. This article examines whether the strength of the effect of the effort-reward imbalance ratio on health indicators is bigger than the effects of efforts and rewards individually. Another research gap on the interaction with over-commitment is addressed and health measures are compared.
Methods

This study applied the effort-reward imbalance model on health satisfaction and the SF-12v2™ indicators physical health composite score (PCS) and mental health composite score (MCS) within a representative sample of German employees. After confirmatory factor analyses of the items of the components effort, reward and over-commitment were applied, multiple linear regression models and interaction effects were calculated for more than 7000 respondents within the German Socio-Economic Panel (GSOEP) study.
Results

Against the model’s hypothesis, effort and especially reward had a stronger effect on health satisfaction and mental health individually than the effort-reward imbalance ratio. Over-commitment exerted a negative influence on health indicators and its interaction with the effort-reward imbalance ratio intensified this effect significantly for mental health. Overall, the best model fit was reached for mental health, which is in line with the model’s stress theory foundation.
Conclusions

Although the ERI model has been applied for more than 20 years, theoretical and methodological demands can no longer be neglected. This article contributes to the revision of the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and demonstrates possible starting points for prevention programs focusing on rewards.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s12889-019-7187-1.kunz.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2936736/2936737/s12889-019-7187-1.kunz.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31357973</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000477839500006</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29367365</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12889-019-7187-1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kunz, C. (2019). The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(1): 1009. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s12889-019-7187-1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kunz, C. (2019). The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 19:1009.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kunz, C. (2019). The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1009. doi:10.1186/s12889-019-7187-1&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kunz, Carolin. “The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP)”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 19.1 (2019): 1009.</mla>
<wels>Kunz, C. (2019): The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP) &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,19:(1):1009</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Kunz, “The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP)”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;, : 1009.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kunz C (2019) &lt;br /&gt;The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP).&lt;br /&gt;BMC Public Health 19(1): 1009.</bio1>
<default>Kunz C (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 19(1): 1009.</default>
<ama>Kunz C. The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;19(1): 1009.</ama>
<harvard1>Kunz, C., 2019. The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 19(1): 1009.</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Kunz, “The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP)”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 19, 2019, : 1009.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kunz, Carolin. 2019. “The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP)”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 19 (1): 1009.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kunz, C.: The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). BMC Public Health. 19, : 1009 (2019).</lncs>
<apa>Kunz, C. (2019). The influence of working conditions on health satisfaction, physical and mental health: testing the effort-reward imbalance (ERI) model and its moderation with over-commitment using a representative sample of German employees (GSOEP). &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1009. doi:10.1186/s12889-019-7187-1</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2936736</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-30T12:50:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>