<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2936380</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinhold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Häb-Umbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mattias</namePart><namePart type="family">Heldner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Proceedings from FONETIK 2019</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we present first evidence for a potential application of novel speech technological methods as a valuable tool for basic phonetics research. We describe a research program aiming at identifying the complex phonetic realizations underlying various dimensions of phonetic variation. This will be addressed with the help of recent approaches in unsupervised voice conversion and waveform generation. Concretely, we present a model for disentangling speakers' voice qualities and their linguistic-phonetic content, which can then be used to perform voice conversion across different dimensions of phonetic variation. The resulting signals are then "audible versions" of the phonetic dimensions of interest, and lend themselves to straightforward phonetic interpretation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="13.Fonetik2019_wagner_haeb-umbach-1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2936380/2936381/13.Fonetik2019_wagner_haeb-umbach-1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Department of Linguistics, Stockholm</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Stockholm</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0282-6690</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29363804</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>XXVII</number></detail><extent unit="pages">79-83</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Wagner, P., Häb-Umbach, R.: Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm. XXVII, 79-83 (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra, and Häb-Umbach, Reinhold. 2019. “Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics”, PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm,  XXVII: 79-83.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Wagner, Petra, and Häb-Umbach, Reinhold. “Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics”. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt; XXVII (2019): 79-83.</mla>
<default>Wagner P, Häb-Umbach R (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt; XXVII: 79-83.</default>
<ama>Wagner P, Häb-Umbach R. Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;XXVII:79-83.</ama>
<frontiers>Wagner, P., and Häb-Umbach, R. (2019). Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt; XXVII, 79-83.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P. &amp;amp; Häb-Umbach, R. (2019). Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics (PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm).  (M. Heldner, Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;XXVII&lt;/em&gt;, 79-83. Gehalten auf der Proceedings from FONETIK 2019, Stockholm: Department of Linguistics, Stockholm.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Häb-Umbach, R. (2019). Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;XXVII&lt;/em&gt;, 79-83.</apa>
<ieee> P. Wagner and R. Häb-Umbach, “Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics”, &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. XXVII, 2019,  pp. 79-83.</ieee>
<wels>Wagner, P.; Häb-Umbach, R. (2019): Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics, In: Mattias Heldner (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;,XXVII: 79-83.</wels>
<bio1>Wagner P, Häb-Umbach R (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics.&lt;br /&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm XXVII: 79-83.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Häb-Umbach, R. (2019). Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;XXVII&lt;/em&gt;, 79-83.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., &amp;amp; Häb-Umbach, R., 2019. Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics. &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;, XXVII, p 79-83.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, and R.  Häb-Umbach, “Disentangling the Dimensions of Phonetic Variation: First Steps towards and Explanatory and Exploratory Research Tool in Phonetics”, &lt;em&gt;PERILUS: Phonetic experimental research at the Institute of Linguistics, University of Stockholm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;XXVII&lt;/em&gt;, 79-83.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2936380</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-08T15:14:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-09T11:31:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>