<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2936369</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction</title></titleInfo>




<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nataliya</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bryhadyr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84787706</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schröer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Previous research identified a differential contribution of information
structure and the visibility of facial and contextual information
to the acoustic-prosodic expression of pitch accents.
However, it is unclear whether pitch accent shapes are affected
by these conditions as well. To investigate whether varying
context cues have a differentiated impact on pitch accent trajectories
produced in conversational interaction, we modified
the visibility conditions in a spontaneous dyadic interaction
task, i.e. a verbalized version of TicTacToe. Besides varying
visibility, the game task allows for measuring the impact of
information-structure on pitch accent trajectories, differentiating
important and unpredictable game moves. Using GAMMs
on four speaker groups (identified by a cluster analysis), we
could isolate varying strategies of prosodic adaptation to contextual
change. While few speaker groups showed a reaction to
the availability of visible context cues (facial prosody or executed
game moves), all groups differentiated the verbalization
of unpredictable and predictable game moves with a groupspecific
trajectory adaptation. The importance of game moves
resulted in differentiated adaptations in two out of four speaker
groups. The detected strategic trajectory adaptations were characterized
by different characteristics of boundary tones, adaptations
of the global f0-level, or the shape of the corresponding
pitch accent.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IS2019___pitch_trajectories_tictactoe-3.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2936369/2936370/IS2019___pitch_trajectories_tictactoe-3.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Graz, Austria</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>dialogue</topic><topic>prosody</topic><topic>pitch accents</topic><topic>visibility</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of Interspeech</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29363695</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Wagner, Petra, Bryhadyr, Nataliya, and Schröer, Marin. “Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;. 2019.</mla>
<frontiers>Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N., and Schröer, M. (2019). “Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N., &amp;amp; Schröer, M. (2019). Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Wagner, P.; Bryhadyr, N.; Schröer, M. (2019): Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. In: Proceedings of Interspeech.</wels>
<default>Wagner P, Bryhadyr N, Schröer M (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Interspeech.</default>
<ieee> P. Wagner, N. Bryhadyr, and M. Schröer, “Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;, 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N., &amp;amp; Schröer, M., 2019. Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa>Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N., &amp;amp; Schröer, M. (2019). Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N. &amp;amp; Schröer, M. (2019). Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Wagner P, Bryhadyr N, Schröer M (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of Interspeech. .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Wagner, N.  Bryhadyr, and M.  Schröer, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Wagner P, Bryhadyr N, Schröer M. Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;. 2019.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wagner, Petra, Bryhadyr, Nataliya, and Schröer, Marin. 2019. “Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of Interspeech&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Wagner, P., Bryhadyr, N., Schröer, M.: Pitch Accent Trajectories across Different Conditions of Visibility and Information Structure - Evidence from Spontaneous Dyadic Interaction. Proceedings of Interspeech.  (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2936369</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-08T10:59:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-08T15:21:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>