<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2936699</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jodi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dianetti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">116356476</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Markus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fischer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Max</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nendel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">127338064</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study mean field games with scalar Itô-type dynamics and costs that are
submodular with respect to a suitable order relation on the state and measure space. The
submodularity assumption has a number of interesting consequences. Firstly, it allows us to
prove existence of solutions via an application of Tarski's fixed point theorem, covering cases
with discontinuous dependence on the measure variable. Secondly, it ensures that the set
of solutions enjoys a lattice structure: in particular, there exist a minimal and a maximal
solution. Thirdly, it guarantees that those two solutions can be obtained through a simple
learning procedure based on the iterations of the best-response-map. The mean field game
is first defined over ordinary stochastic controls, then extended to relaxed controls. Our
approach allows also to treat a class of submodular mean field games with common noise in
which the representative player at equilibrium interacts with the (conditional) mean of its
state's distribution.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_621.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2936699/2936700/IMW_working_paper_621.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Mean field games</topic><topic>submodular cost function</topic><topic>complete lattice</topic><topic>first order stochastic dominance</topic><topic>Tarski's fixed point theorem.</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29366991</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>621</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G., Fischer, M., Nendel, M.: Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 621. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, Jodi, Ferrari, Giorgio, Fischer, Markus, and Nendel, Max. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 621. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Dianetti, Jodi, Ferrari, Giorgio, Fischer, Markus, and Nendel, Max. &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 621.</mla>
<default>Dianetti J, Ferrari G, Fischer M, Nendel M (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 621.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ama>Dianetti J, Ferrari G, Fischer M, Nendel M. &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 621. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<frontiers>Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G., Fischer, M., and Nendel, M. (2019). Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 621, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G., Fischer, M. &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G., Fischer, M., &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 621). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> J. Dianetti, et al., &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 621,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<wels>Dianetti, J.; Ferrari, G.; Fischer, M.; Nendel, M. (2019): Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Dianetti J, Ferrari G, Fischer M, Nendel M (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 621.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dianetti, J., et al., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.621, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dianetti, J., Ferrari, G., Fischer, M., &amp;amp; Nendel, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 621). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Dianetti, G.  Ferrari, M.  Fischer, and M.  Nendel, &lt;em&gt;Submodular Mean Field Games. Existence and Approximation of Solutions&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2936699</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-26T08:53:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>