<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937511</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Timo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Korthals</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">42006529</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4297-7197</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16266121</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rudolph</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hesse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23665617</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9500-3284</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rückert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15438821</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15438710</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Evaluation of robotic experiments requires physical robots as well as position sensing systems. Accurate systems detecting sufficiently all necessary degrees of freedom, like the famous Vicon system, are commonly too expensive. Therefore, we target an economical multi-camera based solution by following these three requirements: Using multiple cameras to track even large laboratory areas, applying fiducial marker trackers for pose identification, and fuse tracking hypothesis resulting from multiple cameras via extended Kalman filter (i.e. ROS's robot\_localization). While the registration of a multi-camera system for collaborative tracking remains a challenging issue, the contribution of this paper is as follows: We introduce the framework of Cognitive Interaction Tracking (CITrack). Then, common fiducial marker tracking systems (ARToolKit, AprilTag, ArUco) are compared with respect to their maintainability. Lastly, a graph-based camera registration approach in SE(3), using the fiducial marker tracking in a multi-camera setup, is presented and evaluated.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Korthals - 2019 - Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937511/2937516/Korthals - 2019 - Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Marker tracking</topic><topic>Marker</topic><topic>Fiducial Marker</topic><topic>publication</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29375116</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-6</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Korthals T, Wolf D, Rudolph D, Hesse M, Rückert U (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019.  1-6.</default>
<mla>Korthals, Timo, Wolf, Daniel, Rudolph, Daniel, Hesse, Marc, and Rückert, Ulrich. “Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform”. &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;. 2019. 1-6.</mla>
<frontiers>Korthals, T., Wolf, D., Rudolph, D., Hesse, M., and Rückert, U. (2019). “Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform” in &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt; 1-6.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, T., Wolf, D., Rudolph, D., Hesse, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2019). Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;, 1-6.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Korthals, T.; Wolf, D.; Rudolph, D.; Hesse, M.; Rückert, U. (2019): Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. In: European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019.  S. 1-6.</wels>
<apa>Korthals, T., Wolf, D., Rudolph, D., Hesse, M., &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2019). Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;, 1-6.</apa>
<ieee> T. Korthals, et al., “Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform”, &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;, 2019,  pp.1-6.</ieee>
<harvard1>Korthals, T., et al., 2019. Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. In &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;. pp. 1-6.</harvard1>
<bio1>Korthals T, Wolf D, Rudolph D, Hesse M, Rückert U (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. &lt;br /&gt;In:  European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019.  1-6.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Korthals, D.  Wolf, D.  Rudolph, M.  Hesse, and U.  Rückert, in &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-6.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, T., Wolf, D., Rudolph, D., Hesse, M. &amp;amp; Rückert, U. (2019). Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-6).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Korthals, T., Wolf, D., Rudolph, D., Hesse, M., Rückert, U.: Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019. p. 1-6. (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Korthals, Timo, Wolf, Daniel, Rudolph, Daniel, Hesse, Marc, and Rückert, Ulrich. 2019. “Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform”. In &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;, 1-6.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Korthals T, Wolf D, Rudolph D, Hesse M, Rückert U. Fiducial Marker based Extrinsic Camera Calibration for a Robot Benchmarking Platform. In:  &lt;em&gt;European Conference on Mobile Robots, ECMR 2019, Prague, CZ, September 4-6, 2019&lt;/em&gt;. 2019: 1-6.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937511</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-09-20T14:17:34Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-17T00:25:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>