<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937238</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Melanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böckmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">165672182</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5909-5508</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sahil</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Warsi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maryam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Noor</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Omara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dogar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Esha Haowa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mustagfira</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fariza</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Firoze</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zahid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Readshaw</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kamran</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Siddiqi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kotz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175761</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Smoking worsens tuberculosis (TB) outcomes. Persons with TB who smoke can benefit from smoking cessation. We report findings of a multi-country qualitative process evaluation assessing barriers and facilitators to implementation of smoking cessation behaviour support in TB clinics in Bangladesh and Pakistan. We conducted semi-structured qualitative interviews at five case study clinics with 35 patients and 8 health workers over a period of 11 months (2017-2018) at different time points during the intervention implementation phase. Interviews were conducted by trained researchers in the native languages, audio-recorded, transcribed into English and analysed using a combined deductive-inductive approach guided by the Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research and Theoretical Domains Framework. All patients report willingness to quit smoking and recent quit attempts. Individuals' main motivations to quit are their health and the need to financially provide for a family. Behavioural regulation such as avoiding exposure to cigarettes and social influences from friends, family and colleagues are main themes of the interviews. Most male patients do not feel shy admitting to smoking, for the sole female patient interviewee stigma was an issue. Health workers report structural characteristics such as high workload and limited time per patient as primary barriers to offering behavioural support. Self-efficacy to discuss tobacco use with women varies by health worker. Systemic barriers to implementation such as staff workload and socio-cultural barriers to cessation like gender relations, stigma or social influences should be dealt with creatively to optimize the behaviour support for sustainability and scale-up. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Boeckmann et al 2019 NPJPCRM.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937238/2937263/Boeckmann et al 2019 NPJPCRM.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>NPJ primary care respiratory medicine</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2055-1010</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31481678</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000483614400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29372381</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1038/s41533-019-0146-6</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>29</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> M. Böckmann, et al., “Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care”, &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 29, 2019, : 34.</ieee>
<apa>Böckmann, M., Warsi, S., Noor, M., Dogar, O., Mustagfira, E. H., Firoze, F., Zahid, R., et al. (2019). Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1), 34. doi:10.1038/s41533-019-0146-6</apa>
<frontiers>Böckmann, M., Warsi, S., Noor, M., Dogar, O., Mustagfira, E. H., Firoze, F., Zahid, R., Readshaw, A., Siddiqi, K., and Kotz, D. (2019). Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt; 29:34.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böckmann, M., Warsi, S., Noor, M., Dogar, O., Mustagfira, E.H., Firoze, F., Zahid, R., Readshaw, A., Siddiqi, K. &amp;amp; Kotz, D. (2019). Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1): 34. Springer Nature. doi:10.1038/s41533-019-0146-6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Böckmann M, Warsi S, Noor M, et al. Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;29(1): 34.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Böckmann, S.  Warsi, M.  Noor, O.  Dogar, E. H.  Mustagfira, F.  Firoze, R.  Zahid, A.  Readshaw, K.  Siddiqi, and D.  Kotz, “Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care”, &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;, : 34.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böckmann, M., Warsi, S., Noor, M., Dogar, O., Mustagfira, E. H., Firoze, F., Zahid, R., et al. (2019). Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1), 34. doi:10.1038/s41533-019-0146-6&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Böckmann M, Warsi S, Noor M, Dogar O, Mustagfira EH, Firoze F, Zahid R, Readshaw A, Siddiqi K, Kotz D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care.&lt;br /&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine 29(1): 34.</bio1>
<harvard1>Böckmann, M., et al., 2019. Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;, 29(1): 34.</harvard1>
<wels>Böckmann, M.; Warsi, S.; Noor, M.; Dogar, O.; Mustagfira, E. H.; Firoze, F.; Zahid, R.; Readshaw, A.; Siddiqi, K.; Kotz, D. (2019): Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt;,29:(1):34</wels>
<default>Böckmann M, Warsi S, Noor M, Dogar O, Mustagfira EH, Firoze F, Zahid R, Readshaw A, Siddiqi K, Kotz D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt; 29(1): 34.</default>
<mla>Böckmann, Melanie, Warsi, Sahil, Noor, Maryam, Dogar, Omara, Mustagfira, Esha Haowa, Firoze, Fariza, Zahid, Raana, Readshaw, Anne, Siddiqi, Kamran, and Kotz, Daniel. “Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care”. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt; 29.1 (2019): 34.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Böckmann, Melanie, Warsi, Sahil, Noor, Maryam, Dogar, Omara, Mustagfira, Esha Haowa, Firoze, Fariza, Zahid, Raana, Readshaw, Anne, Siddiqi, Kamran, and Kotz, Daniel. 2019. “Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care”. &lt;em&gt;NPJ primary care respiratory medicine&lt;/em&gt; 29 (1): 34.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Böckmann, M., Warsi, S., Noor, M., Dogar, O., Mustagfira, E.H., Firoze, F., Zahid, R., Readshaw, A., Siddiqi, K., Kotz, D.: Health worker and patient views on implementation of smoking cessation in routine tuberculosis care. NPJ primary care respiratory medicine. 29, : 34 (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937238</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-09-10T06:02:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>