<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937842</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">accepted</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Babak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hosseini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49514363</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3335-4289</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Convolutional neural networks (CNNs) are deep learning frameworks which are well-known for their notable performance in classification tasks. Hence, many skeleton-based action recognition and segmentation (SBARS) algorithms benefit from them in their designs. However, a shortcoming of such applications is the general lack of spatial relationships between the input features in such data types. Besides, non-uniform temporal scalings is a common issue in skeleton-based data streams which leads to having different input sizes even within one specific action category.
In this work, we propose a novel deep-aligned convolutional neural network (DACNN) to tackle the above challenges for the particular problem of SBARS. Our network is designed by introducing a new type of filters in the context of CNNs which are trained based on their alignments to the local subsequences in the inputs. These filters result in efficient predictions as well as learning interpretable patterns in the data. We empirically evaluate our framework on real-world benchmarks showing that the proposed DACNN algorithm obtains a competitive performance compared to the state-of-the-art while benefiting from a less complicated yet more interpretable model.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="icdm2019-191112153317.pptx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937842/2938828/icdm2019-191112153317.pptx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.presentation</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Beijing</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="arXiv">1911.04969</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29378423</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. Accepted. “Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation”. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hosseini, B., Hammer, B.: Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing (Accepted).</lncs>
<default>Hosseini B, Hammer B (Accepted)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</default>
<mla>Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. “Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation”. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing, Accepted.</mla>
<wels>Hosseini, B.; Hammer, B. (Accepted): Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Hosseini, and B.  Hammer, &lt;strong&gt;Accepted&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hosseini B, Hammer B (Accepted) &lt;br /&gt;Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., Accepted. Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). &lt;em&gt;Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hosseini, B., and Hammer, B. (Accepted).“Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation”. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation. Gehalten auf der 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hosseini B, Hammer B. Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</ama>
<ieee> B. Hosseini and B. Hammer, “Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation”, Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing, Accepted.</ieee>
<apa>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). &lt;em&gt;Deep-Aligned Convolutional Neural Network for Skeleton-based Action Recognition and Segmentation&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), Beijing.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937842</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-11T23:19:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-13T10:26:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>