<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937083</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Torsten Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bollweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">55128610</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0147-6890</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53811697</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1714-4783</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fretian</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">71174999</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Janine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bröder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">57782759</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0399-7649</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olga</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Domanska</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susanne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jordan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Paulo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pinheiro</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">50999128</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ullrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73808</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">7978137</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Up to now, the under-13s have received little attention in research on health literacy (HL). Although some tools assess children’s HL, no validated tool is available that
assesses self-reported HL in a systematic and comparable way. The HLS-EU
questionnaire is a valid and reliable measure of adolescents’ and adults’ self-reported
HL, but has never been adapted for use with children. However, it would be worth
adapting for younger age groups so that self-reported HL could be assessed
continuously.


Objective: To quantitatively test an adapted scale based on the HLS-EU-Q developed
for German-speaking 9- to 10-year-olds.


Methods: An adapted 26-item HLS-EU-Q scale was given in a paper-and-pencil survey
to 907 fourth-grade students in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany. The psychometric
properties of the scale were investigated with item analysis and factor analyses, and
both concurrent and discriminant validity were assessed.


Key Results: Of the 26 tested items, 9 were discarded due to poor performance in
terms of missing values, item difficulty, and dimensionality. This left a 15-item scale
with a high internal consistency (α = .791) that takes only a short time to administer.
The scale had a low correlation with functional health literacy (r = .107, p &lt; .001), and a
moderate correlation with indicators of self-efficacy (ρ = .280–.306, p &lt; .001). The latter
indicates adequate discriminant validity; whereas the former points to a need to further
investigate concurrent validity.


Conclusions: This is the first study in applying an age-adapted version of the HLS-EUQ
to children. Statistical analyses indicated the successful development of a promising
instrument, but further research is needed on its dimensionality and validity. This study
contributes significantly to the comparative assessment of HL across the life course by
providing a promising measurement tool for children aged 9 to 10.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bollweg_2020_Adapting_HLS-EU-Q_Validation_Analysis.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937083/2945012/Bollweg_2020_Adapting_HLS-EU-Q_Validation_Analysis.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Slack Inc.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Health Literacy Research and Practice</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2474-8307</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29370837</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3928/24748307-20200428-01</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">e144-e159</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Bollweg, T. M., Okan, O., Fretian, A., Bröder, J., Domanska, O., Jordan, S., Bruland, D., Pinheiro, P., and Bauer, U. (2020). Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 4, e144-e159.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, T.M., Okan, O., Fretian, A., Bröder, J., Domanska, O., Jordan, S., Bruland, D., Pinheiro, P. &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2020). Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(3), e144-e159. Slack Inc. doi:10.3928/24748307-20200428-01.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bollweg TM, Okan O, Fretian A, et al. Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;4(3):e144-e159.</ama>
<ieee> T.M. Bollweg, et al., “Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 4, 2020,  pp. e144-e159.</ieee>
<apa>Bollweg, T. M., Okan, O., Fretian, A., Bröder, J., Domanska, O., Jordan, S., Bruland, D., et al. (2020). Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(3), e144-e159. doi:10.3928/24748307-20200428-01</apa>
<wels>Bollweg, T. M.; Okan, O.; Fretian, A.; Bröder, J.; Domanska, O.; Jordan, S.; Bruland, D.; Pinheiro, P.; Bauer, U. (2020): Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;,4:(3): e144-e159.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T. M.  Bollweg, O.  Okan, A.  Fretian, J.  Bröder, O.  Domanska, S.  Jordan, D.  Bruland, P.  Pinheiro, and U.  Bauer, “Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis”, &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, e144-e159.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Bollweg, T.M., et al., 2020. Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, 4(3), p e144-e159.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bollweg TM, Okan O, Fretian A, Bröder J, Domanska O, Jordan S, Bruland D, Pinheiro P, Bauer U (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis.&lt;br /&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice 4(3): e144-e159.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, T. M., Okan, O., Fretian, A., Bröder, J., Domanska, O., Jordan, S., Bruland, D., et al. (2020). Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(3), e144-e159. doi:10.3928/24748307-20200428-01&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bollweg, Torsten Michael, Okan, Orkan, Fretian, Alexandra, Bröder, Janine, Domanska, Olga, Jordan, Susanne, Bruland, Dirk, Pinheiro, Paulo, and Bauer, Ullrich. 2020. “Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 4 (3): e144-e159.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bollweg, T.M., Okan, O., Fretian, A., Bröder, J., Domanska, O., Jordan, S., Bruland, D., Pinheiro, P., Bauer, U.: Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis. Health Literacy Research and Practice. 4, e144-e159 (2020).</lncs>
<default>Bollweg TM, Okan O, Fretian A, Bröder J, Domanska O, Jordan S, Bruland D, Pinheiro P, Bauer U (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 4(3): e144-e159.</default>
<mla>Bollweg, Torsten Michael, Okan, Orkan, Fretian, Alexandra, Bröder, Janine, Domanska, Olga, Jordan, Susanne, Bruland, Dirk, Pinheiro, Paulo, and Bauer, Ullrich. “Adapting the European Health Literacy Survey Questionnaire for Fourth-Grade Students in Germany: Validation and Psychometric Analysis”. &lt;em&gt;Health Literacy Research and Practice&lt;/em&gt; 4.3 (2020): e144-e159.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937083</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-08-29T08:54:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-27T10:32:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>