<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937841</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">accepted</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Babak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hosseini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49514363</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3335-4289</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) </namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Prototype-based methods are of the particular interest for domain specialists and practitioners as they summarize a dataset by a small set of representatives. Therefore, in a classification setting, interpretability of the prototypes is as significant as the prediction accuracy of the algorithm. Nevertheless, the state-of-the-art methods make inefficient trade-offs between these concerns by sacrificing one in favor of the other, especially if the given data has a kernel-based (or multiple-kernel) representation. In this paper, we propose a novel interpretable multiple-kernel prototype learning (IMKPL) to construct highly interpretable prototypes in the feature space, which are also efficient for the discriminative representation of the data. Our method focuses on the local discrimination of the classes in the feature space and shaping the prototypes based on condensed class-homogeneous neighborhoods of data. Besides, IMKPL learns a combined embedding in the feature space in which the above objectives are better fulfilled. When the base kernels coincide with the data dimensions, this embedding results in a discriminative features selection. We evaluate IMKPL on several benchmarks from different domains which demonstrate its superiority to the related state-of-the-art methods regarding both interpretability and discriminative representation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="cikm2019-191112150408.pptx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937841/2938827/cikm2019-191112150408.pptx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.presentation</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Beijing</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>prototype learning</topic><topic>interpretation</topic><topic>multiple-kernel</topic><topic>classification</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="arXiv">1911.03949</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29378413</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Hosseini B, Hammer B. Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection. Gehalten auf der The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) .&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hosseini, B., and Hammer, B. (Accepted).“Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection”. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</frontiers>
<apa>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). &lt;em&gt;Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</apa>
<ieee> B. Hosseini and B. Hammer, “Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection”, Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing, Accepted.</ieee>
<wels>Hosseini, B.; Hammer, B. (Accepted): Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection.</wels>
<bio1>Hosseini B, Hammer B (Accepted) &lt;br /&gt;Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</bio1>
<harvard1>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., Accepted. Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (Accepted). &lt;em&gt;Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Hosseini, and B.  Hammer, &lt;strong&gt;Accepted&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Hosseini, B., Hammer, B.: Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing (Accepted).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. Accepted. “Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection”. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. “Interpretable Multiple-Kernel Prototype Learning for Discriminative Representation and Feature Selection”. Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing, Accepted.</mla>
<default>Hosseini B, Hammer B (Accepted)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the The 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM) , Beijing.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937841</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-11T23:07:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-13T10:25:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>