<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937756</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marco</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Piccirilli</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maren Diane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84348951</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tiziano</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vargiolu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we introduce an additive two-factor model for electricity futures
prices based on Normal Inverse Gaussian Lévy processes, that fulfills
a no-overlapping-arbitrage (NOA) condition. We compute European option
prices by Fourier transform methods, introduce a specific calibration procedure
that takes into account no-arbitrage constraints and fit the model to power option
settlement prices of the European Energy Exchange (EEX). We show that
our model is able to reproduce the different levels and shapes of the implied
volatility (IV) profiles displayed by options with a variety of delivery periods.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_625.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937756/2937757/IMW_working_paper_625.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Volatility Smile</topic><topic>Overlapping Delivery Periods</topic><topic>Arbitrage</topic><topic>Additive Models</topic><topic>Power Options</topic><topic>FFT</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29377564</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>625</number></detail><extent unit="pages">34</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> M. Piccirilli, M.D. Schmeck, and T. Vargiolu, &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 625,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M.D., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.625, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M. D., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 625). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<wels>Piccirilli, M.; Schmeck, M. D.; Vargiolu, T. (2019): Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M. D., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 625). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M. D., and Vargiolu, T. (2019). Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 625, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Piccirilli, Marco, Schmeck, Maren Diane, and Vargiolu, Tiziano. &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 625.</mla>
<default>Piccirilli M, Schmeck MD, Vargiolu T (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 625.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ama>Piccirilli M, Schmeck MD, Vargiolu T. &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 625. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Piccirilli, Marco, Schmeck, Maren Diane, and Vargiolu, Tiziano. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 625. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M.D., Vargiolu, T.: Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 625. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Piccirilli, M., Schmeck, M.D. &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Piccirilli M, Schmeck MD, Vargiolu T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 625.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Piccirilli, M. D.  Schmeck, and T.  Vargiolu, &lt;em&gt;Capturing the power options smile by an additive two-factor model for overlapping futures prices&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937756</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-07T12:33:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>