<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2937839</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Babak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hosseini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">49514363</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3335-4289</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hammer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">18302458</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10037</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML)</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Dimensionality reduction (DR) on the manifold includes effective methods which project the data from an implicit relational space onto a vectorial space. Regardless of the achievements in this area, these algorithms suffer from the lack of interpretation of the projection dimensions. Therefore, it is often difficult to explain the physical meaning behind the embedding dimensions. In this research, we propose the interpretable kernel DR algorithm (I-KDR) as a new algorithm which maps the data from the feature space to a lower dimensional space where the classes are more condensed with less overlapping. Besides, the algorithm creates the dimensions upon local contributions of the data samples, which makes it easier to interpret them by class labels. Additionally, we efficiently fuse the DR with feature selection task to select the most relevant features of the original space to the discriminative objective. Based on the empirical evidence, I-KDR provides better interpretations for embedding dimensions as well as higher discriminative performance in the embedded space compared to the state-of-the-art and popular DR algorithms.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ECML2019.pptx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2937839/2937840/ECML2019.pptx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.presentation</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Würzburg</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>multiple kernel learning</topic><topic>dimensionality reduction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="arXiv">1909.09218</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29378397</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B., 2019. Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Hosseini and B. Hammer, “Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold”, Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B., &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. “Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold”. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg, 2019.</mla>
<frontiers>Hosseini, B., and Hammer, B. (2019).“Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold”. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</frontiers>
<wels>Hosseini, B.; Hammer, B. (2019): Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold.</wels>
<default>Hosseini B, Hammer B (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</default>
<ama>Hosseini B, Hammer B. Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</ama>
<lncs> Hosseini, B., Hammer, B.: Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, Babak, and Hammer, Barbara. 2019. “Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold”. Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hosseini, B. &amp;amp; Hammer, B. (2019). Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold. Gehalten auf der 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Hosseini, and B.  Hammer, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hosseini B, Hammer B (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Interpretable Discriminative Dimensionality Reduction and Feature Selection on the Manifold. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the 2019 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML), Würzburg.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2937839</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-11T23:00:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-14T11:55:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>