<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2938492</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">71001871</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Norbert</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Sewald</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17977</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Surface sterilisation of plant material from various host species and tissue types, collected 
from  different  habitats,  with  subsequent cultivation of  the arising fungal  mycelia as axenic 
cultures  resulted  in  the  isolation  of  55  fungal  endophytes.  The  strains  were  identified  via 
nrITS-DNA  (ITS-barcoding).  A  broad  taxonomical  distribution  within  these  strains  was  ob-
served with a focus on ascomycotous fungi and an emphasis on members of the Sordari-
omycetes und Dothideomycetes classes. Some of the cultivated fungal strains showed low 
sequence identity to the reference species in the databases. Therefore they were recognized 
as potential new or underexplored species. &lt;br /&gt;
Antibacterial  and  cytotoxic activities  were  observed  in  crude  extracts of  ethyl  acetate  after 
cultivation through solid-state-fermentation on rice. Due to phylogenetic considerations and 
bioactive properties five strains, were chosen for a detailed mycochemical investigation, _Pur-
pureocillium lilacinum_ (T26B), _Xylaria cubensis_ (TS7), _Daldinia_ sp. (SG1), Didymosphaeriaceae sp. (SG8c, cf. _Tremateia_ sp.), _Biscogniauxia_ sp. (SG25). &lt;br /&gt;
These mycochemical investigation of endophytic fungal crude extracts resulted in the isola-
tion, identification and characterisation of nine new, previously undescribed and 55 already 
literature  known  compounds.  The new described  molecules  were comprised of  three dep-
sidones (Tremateiasidon A - C), one depside (Tremateiasid A), one pyranocoumarin (Trema-
teiajulin A)  with  an  unusual  molecular  scaffold,  one  monosulfated  diketopiperazine 
( 3_S_-Norgliovictin),  one  quinone  (Tremaquin A)  und  one  isochromane  (Tremachroman),  as 
well  as  a  butenolide  (Lilacinolid A).  Some  of  the  new  molecules  show  strong  antibacterial 
activity, comparable or exceeding the potency of the reference drug (Gentamicin). The previ-
ously published metabolites, some of which were ascertained in their respective fungal spe-
cies or genera for the first time, represent different compound classes (depsidones, isocou-
marines,  cytochalasines,  linear,  non-ribosomal  peptides,  cyclic  depsipeptides,  butenolides, 
lipids, etc.), which underlined the biosynthetic potential of endophytic fungi. In addition, vari-
ous fractions and pure isolated compounds showed bioactive properties. These mycochemi-
cal investigations were able to prove that endophytic fungi are a good source for new and 
bioactive natural products.  </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation Sebastian Maschke (geb. Gohlke).pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2938492/2938658/Dissertation Sebastian Maschke (geb. Gohlke).pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29384922</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2938492</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2019-09-27</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Maschke, S. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2938492" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2938492&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Maschke, S., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Maschke, &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</ieee>
<default>Maschke S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Maschke, Sebastian. &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Maschke, S. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2938492" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2938492&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Maschke, S. (2019). Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<wels>Maschke, S. (2019): Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Maschke, Sebastian. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Maschke, S.: Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<ama>Maschke S. &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2019.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Maschke, &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Maschke S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Maschke, S. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Naturstoffe aus endophytischen Pilzen&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2938492.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2938492</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-30T14:18:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-26T11:28:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>