<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2938811</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Torben</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">63940079</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tiziano</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vargiolu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We consider a price-maker company which generates electricity and sells it in
the spot market. The company can increase its level of installed power by irreversible installations
of solar panels. In absence of the company's economic activities, the spot electricity
price evolves as an Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process, and therefore it has a mean-reverting behavior.
The current level of the company's installed power has a permanent impact on the
electricity price and affects its mean-reversion level. The company aims at maximizing the
total expected profits from selling electricity in the market, net of the total expected proportional
costs of installation. This problem is modeled as a *two-dimensional degenerate singular
stochastic control problem* in which the installation strategy is identified as the company's
control variable. We follow a *guess-and-verify approach* to solve the problem. We find that
the optimal installation strategy is triggered by a curve which separates the *waiting region*,
where it is not optimal to install additional panels, and the *installation region*, where it is.
Such a curve depends on the current level of the company's installed power, and is the unique
strictly increasing function which solves a first-order ordinary differential equation (ODE).
Finally, our study is complemented by a numerical analysis of the dependency of the optimal
installation strategy on the model's parameters.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">MSC2010 subject classification: 93E20; 49L20; 91B70; 60G99</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_627.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2938811/2938815/IMW_working_paper_627.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>irreversible investment</topic><topic>variational inequality</topic><topic>Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process</topic><topic>market impact</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29388119</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>627</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Koch, T.; Vargiolu, T. (2019): Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koch, T. &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koch, T., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 627). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Koch, T., and Vargiolu, T. (2019). Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 627, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Koch, Torben, and Vargiolu, Tiziano. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 627.</mla>
<default>Koch T, Vargiolu T (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 627.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Koch, and T.  Vargiolu, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Koch T, Vargiolu T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 627.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Koch, T., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.627, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> T. Koch and T. Vargiolu, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 627,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<ama>Koch T, Vargiolu T. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 627. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<apa>Koch, T., &amp;amp; Vargiolu, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 627). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Koch, Torben, and Vargiolu, Tiziano. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 627. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Koch, T., Vargiolu, T.: Optimal Installation of Solar Panels with Price Impact: a Solvable Singular Stochastic Control Problem. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 627. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2938811</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-13T09:24:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>