<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2938204</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Victoria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barham</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ghislain-Herman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Demeze-Jouatsa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53496285</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4368-0504</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Roland</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pongou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study the effect of strategic and partisan voting on electoral outcomes, and on the
relative popularity of the victor. Voters are randomly assigned to be partisan or strategic.
When all voters are strategic in a plurality election, any equilibrium manipulation of the
outcome elects a popular leader. Voting populations with a large proportion of partisan voters
are more at risk of electing an unpopular leader: in elections with three candidates, if only
one-third of the population is partisan, then the winner of the election may be unpopular
with two-thirds of voters. We derive exact bounds for the proportion of the population
that benefits from manipulation of the election outcome by strategic voters, for arbitrary
numbers of voters, candidates, partisans and strategic voters. The analysis also shows that
the unpopularity of the election winner differs between partisan and strategic voters. When
most voters are partisan, they may be the vast majority of those who gain from strategic
voting.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_626.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2938204/2938205/IMW_working_paper_626.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Morality and Politics</topic><topic>Partisan Voting</topic><topic>Winner Unpopularity</topic><topic>Plurality</topic><topic>Impact Heterogeneity</topic><topic>Randomization</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29382043</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>626</number></detail><extent unit="pages">32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Barham, V.; Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H.; Pongou, R. (2019): Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H. &amp;amp; Pongou, R. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H., and Pongou, R. (2019). Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 626, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H., &amp;amp; Pongou, R. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 626). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Barham, Victoria, Demeze-Jouatsa, Ghislain-Herman, and Pongou, Roland. &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 626.</mla>
<default>Barham V, Demeze-Jouatsa G-H, Pongou R (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 626.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Barham, G. - H.  Demeze-Jouatsa, and R.  Pongou, &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Barham V, Demeze-Jouatsa G-H, Pongou R (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 626.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H., &amp;amp; Pongou, R., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.626, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> V. Barham, G.-H. Demeze-Jouatsa, and R. Pongou, &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 626,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<ama>Barham V, Demeze-Jouatsa G-H, Pongou R. &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 626. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<apa>Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G. - H., &amp;amp; Pongou, R. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 626). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<lncs> Barham, V., Demeze-Jouatsa, G.-H., Pongou, R.: Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 626. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Barham, Victoria, Demeze-Jouatsa, Ghislain-Herman, and Pongou, Roland. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Did Partisan Voters Spoil the Country? A Randomized-thought Experiment&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 626. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2938204</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-23T08:14:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>