<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2938327</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:360</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jonas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rees</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26385901</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4966-2649</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yann</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rees</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">100641389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3205-0777</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jens H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zick</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">112507</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Since 2015, far right parties drawing heavily on radical anti-refugee rhetoric gained electoral support in Germany while the number of political hate crimes targeting refugees rose. Both phenomena – far right electoral support and prevalence of right-wing hate crimes – have theoretically and empirically been linked with socio-structural and contextual variables. However, systematic empirical research on these links is scattered and scarce at best. We combine official statistics on political hate crimes targeting refugees in Germany and far right electoral support of the far right party “Alternative für Deutschland” (AfD) in the German national elections 2017 with socio-structural variables (proportion of foreigners and unemployment rate) and survey data collected in a representative survey (N = 1,506) in 2016. We aggregate and combine data for all German municipalities except Berlin which were the level of analysis for the current study. In path analyses, we find socio-structural variables to be unrelated with each other but significantly correlated with both criterion variables in a systematic fashion: proportion of foreigners was negatively while unemployment rate was positively linked with far right electoral support. Right-wing crime was linked positively with unemployment rate across Germany and positively with proportion of foreigners only in East Germany while proportion of foreigners was unrelated to right-wing crime in West Germany. When including survey measures into the model, they were linked with socio-structural variables in the predicted fashion – intergroup contact correlated positively with proportion of foreigners, collective deprivation correlated positively with unemployment rates, and both predicted extreme right-wing attitudes. However, their contribution to the explained variance in outcome variables above and beyond socio-structural variables was neglectable. We argue that both far right-wing electoral support and right-wing hate crime can be conceptualized as behavioral forms of political extremism shaped through socio-structural and contextual factors and discuss implications for preventing political extremism.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpsyg-10-02328.rees.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2938327/2939541/fpsyg-10-02328.rees.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Research Foundation</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31681118</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000494289600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29383274</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02328</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Rees J, Rees Y, Hellmann JH, Zick A. Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;10: 2328.</ama>
<lncs> Rees, J., Rees, Y., Hellmann, J.H., Zick, A.: Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. Frontiers in Psychology. 10, : 2328 (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rees, Jonas, Rees, Yann, Hellmann, Jens H., and Zick, Andreas. 2019. “Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 10: 2328.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rees, J., Rees, Y., Hellmann, J.H. &amp;amp; Zick, A. (2019). Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;: 2328. Frontiers Research Foundation. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02328.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Rees, Y.  Rees, J. H.  Hellmann, and A.  Zick, “Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 2328.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Rees J, Rees Y, Hellmann JH, Zick A (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Psychology 10: 2328.</bio1>
<harvard1>Rees, J., et al., 2019. Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 10: 2328.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Rees, et al., “Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2019, : 2328.</ieee>
<apa>Rees, J., Rees, Y., Hellmann, J. H., &amp;amp; Zick, A. (2019). Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 2328. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02328</apa>
<mla>Rees, Jonas, Rees, Yann, Hellmann, Jens H., and Zick, Andreas. “Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 10 (2019): 2328.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Rees, J., Rees, Y., Hellmann, J. H., &amp;amp; Zick, A. (2019). Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 2328. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02328&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Rees, J., Rees, Y., Hellmann, J. H., and Zick, A. (2019). Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 10:2328.</frontiers>
<wels>Rees, J.; Rees, Y.; Hellmann, J. H.; Zick, A. (2019): Climate of Hate: Similar Correlates of Far Right Electoral Support and Right-Wing Hate Crimes in Germany &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,10:2328</wels>
<default>Rees J, Rees Y, Hellmann JH, Zick A (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 10: 2328.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2938327</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-10-25T13:39:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:47:33Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>