<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939756</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:360</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kayvan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bozorgmehr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">166226004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1411-1209</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Louise</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Biddle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rohleder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Soorej</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Puthoopparambil </namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rosa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jahn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="9789289054423-eng.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939756/2939757/9789289054423-eng.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2227-4316</identifier>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-92-890-5442-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29397569</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>66</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bozorgmehr, L.  Biddle, S.  Rohleder, S.  Puthoopparambil, and R.  Jahn, &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;, World Health Organization. Regional Office For Europe, Copenhagen, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bozorgmehr K, Biddle L, Rohleder S, Puthoopparambil  S, Jahn R (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;. Health Evidence Network synthesis report; 66.&lt;br /&gt;Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bozorgmehr, K., et al., 2019. &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;, Health Evidence Network synthesis report, no.66, Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, K., Biddle, L., Rohleder, S., Puthoopparambil , S., &amp;amp; Jahn, R. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt; (Health Evidence Network synthesis report, 66). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Bozorgmehr, K.; Biddle, L.; Rohleder, S.; Puthoopparambil , S.; Jahn, R. (2019): What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</wels>
<ieee> K. Bozorgmehr, et al., &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;, Health Evidence Network synthesis report, vol. 66,  Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Bozorgmehr, K., Biddle, L., Rohleder, S., Puthoopparambil , S., &amp;amp; Jahn, R. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt; (Health Evidence Network synthesis report, 66). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, K., Biddle, L., Rohleder, S., Puthoopparambil , S. &amp;amp; Jahn, R. (2019). &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt; (Health Evidence Network synthesis report). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bozorgmehr, K., Biddle, L., Rohleder, S., Puthoopparambil , S., and Jahn, R. (2019). What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region? &lt;em&gt;Health Evidence Network synthesis report&lt;/em&gt;, 66, Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</frontiers>
<ama>Bozorgmehr K, Biddle L, Rohleder S, Puthoopparambil  S, Jahn R. &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;. Health Evidence Network synthesis report. Vol 66. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe; 2019.</ama>
<default>Bozorgmehr K, Biddle L, Rohleder S, Puthoopparambil  S, Jahn R (2019)  Health Evidence Network synthesis report; 66.&lt;br /&gt;Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</default>
<mla>Bozorgmehr, Kayvan, Biddle, Louise, Rohleder, Sven, Puthoopparambil , Soorej, and Jahn, Rosa. &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, 2019. Health Evidence Network synthesis report. 66.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, Kayvan, Biddle, Louise, Rohleder, Sven, Puthoopparambil , Soorej, and Jahn, Rosa. 2019. &lt;em&gt;What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 66. Health Evidence Network synthesis report. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bozorgmehr, K., Biddle, L., Rohleder, S., Puthoopparambil , S., Jahn, R.: What is the evidence on availability and integration of refugee and migrant health data in health information systems in the WHO European Region? Health Evidence Network synthesis report, 66. World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, Copenhagen (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939756</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-04T00:42:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T14:51:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>