<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939657</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lisa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sansen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">35624827</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Laura</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Saupe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62957855</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Annika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steidl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörg M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fegert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoffmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neuner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9438235</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33704</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Although trauma-focused interventions are the first-line therapies for patients with posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD), they are not frequently used in clinical practice. Factors preventing therapists from applying trauma-focused methods include a lack of training and negative attitudes towards trauma-focused therapy. The aim of the present study was to investigate which factors predict willingness to carry out trauma-focused therapy and to examine whether a web-based training is able to reduce negative attitudes and reservations about these interventions. In a wait-list controlled evaluation study, therapists (N = 499) were randomized into an intervention or a wait-list control group. Results show that trauma-treatment specific competencies and overcoming pre-existing concerns towards trauma-focused therapy significantly predict therapists’ willingness to utilize trauma-focused interventions. Thus, the content alignment of the web-based course is appropriate for improving therapists’ willingness to conduct trauma-focused therapy. A retrospective examination of therapists after the training and a comparison of fears and reservations before and after the training demonstrate a significant reduction of fears and reservations. In terms of perceived contraindications, no effects of the web-based training were found. The present study provides compelling evidence that web-based training in evidence-based PTSD therapy is able to reduce reservations that may prevent therapists from applying evidence-based trauma-focused interventions.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Daring to process the trauma.illies.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939657/2939658/Daring to process the trauma.illies.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Posttraumatic stress disorder</topic><topic>PTSD</topic><topic>trauma-focused therapy</topic><topic>web-based training</topic><topic>evidence-based trauma therapy</topic><topic>e-learning</topic><topic>online course</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>European Journal of Psychotraumatology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2000-8198</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31853333</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000506388800001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29396578</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1080/20008198.2019.1696590</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sansen, Lisa, Saupe, Laura, Steidl, Annika, Fegert, Jörg M., Hoffmann, Ulrike, and Neuner, Frank. 2019. “Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt; 10 (1): 1696590.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Sansen, L., Saupe, L., Steidl, A., Fegert, J.M., Hoffmann, U., Neuner, F.: Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. European Journal of Psychotraumatology. 10, : 1696590 (2019).</lncs>
<default>Sansen L, Saupe L, Steidl A, Fegert JM, Hoffmann U, Neuner F (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt; 10(1): 1696590.</default>
<mla>Sansen, Lisa, Saupe, Laura, Steidl, Annika, Fegert, Jörg M., Hoffmann, Ulrike, and Neuner, Frank. “Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt; 10.1 (2019): 1696590.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sansen, L., Saupe, L., Steidl, A., Fegert, J.M., Hoffmann, U. &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2019). Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1): 1696590. Taylor &amp;amp; Francis. doi:10.1080/20008198.2019.1696590.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Sansen, L., Saupe, L., Steidl, A., Fegert, J. M., Hoffmann, U., and Neuner, F. (2019). Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt; 10:1696590.</frontiers>
<ama>Sansen L, Saupe L, Steidl A, Fegert JM, Hoffmann U, Neuner F. Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;10(1): 1696590.</ama>
<ieee> L. Sansen, et al., “Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2019, : 1696590.</ieee>
<apa>Sansen, L., Saupe, L., Steidl, A., Fegert, J. M., Hoffmann, U., &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2019). Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1696590. doi:10.1080/20008198.2019.1696590</apa>
<wels>Sansen, L.; Saupe, L.; Steidl, A.; Fegert, J. M.; Hoffmann, U.; Neuner, F. (2019): Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;,10:(1):1696590</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Sansen, L.  Saupe, A.  Steidl, J. M.  Fegert, U.  Hoffmann, and F.  Neuner, “Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 1696590.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Sansen L, Saupe L, Steidl A, Fegert JM, Hoffmann U, Neuner F (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy.&lt;br /&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology 10(1): 1696590.</bio1>
<harvard1>Sansen, L., et al., 2019. Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;, 10(1): 1696590.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sansen, L., Saupe, L., Steidl, A., Fegert, J. M., Hoffmann, U., &amp;amp; Neuner, F. (2019). Daring to process the trauma: using a web-based training to reduce psychotherapists’ fears and reservations around implementing trauma-focused therapy. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Psychotraumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1696590. doi:10.1080/20008198.2019.1696590&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939657</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-19T07:16:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-20T12:48:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>