<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939681</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philip</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bergmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46832732</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper investigates the effects of total factor productivity and energy price
shocks in a real business cycle (RBC) model with heterogeneous agents. It extends
standard RBC models by including the distinction between durable goods and
non-durable goods but also including energy in production of non-durable goods.
Furthermore, we combine two sources of heterogeneity using idiosyncratic shocks in
labor supply and limited asset market participation by a fixed proportion of agents.
We study to what degree the empirically observed inequality in income and wealth
can be explained by the provided framework. The model can predict the evolution
of inequality in income and wealth, unlike traditional homogeneous macroeconomic
models with a representative agent. We show that the distinction between nondurable
and durable goods leads to a significant improvement in predicting most of
the moments close to the one in observational data from Germany. Furthermore,
we find that energy price shocks lead to decreasing inequalities, with respect to
both income and wealth. In a brief policy analysis, we give an outlook about the
effects of redistribution of income between classes of agents.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_13_2019.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939681/2939682/wpaper_13_2019.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29396815</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2939681</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13-2019</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, Philip. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 13-2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bergmann, P.: Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2019. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<ama>Bergmann P. &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 13-2019. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2019.</ama>
<bio1>Bergmann P (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  Bergmann, &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, P. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939681.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Bergmann, P. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939681</apa>
<ieee> P. Bergmann, &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 13-2019,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bergmann, P., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.13-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<default>Bergmann P (2019)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Bergmann, Philip. &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 13-2019.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bergmann, P. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939681&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bergmann, P. (2019). Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 13-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Bergmann, P. (2019): Heterogeneity in an RBC Model with Durable Goods and Energy. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939681</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-20T08:38:14Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-20T08:38:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>