<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939561</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jelena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brankovic</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84392295</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0485-9096</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Leopold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ringel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">83181896</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tobias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werron</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11287848</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">93309060</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we lay down a comparative framework for theorizing university rankings. In so do-ing, we wish to contextualize the analysis of university rankings within a broader sociology of rankings. We employ analogical theorizing to bring insights from the arts and sports fields into the study of university rankings. We identify two dimensions along which such theorizing could be done: (a) systematic, referring to the comparison of university rankings with rankings in other fields and focusing on how university rankings can be informed by insights from other em-pirical settings; and (b) historical, which concerns long-term trajectories, rather than just the last few years. This approach, we argue, can benefit both our understanding of university rank-ings and rankings more generally</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Der Artikel entwickelt eine vergleichende Perspektive auf Universitätsrankings. Unser Ziel ist, die Analyse von Universitätsrankings in eine allgemeine Soziologie der Rankings einzubetten und Er-kenntnisse über Rankings in anderen Feldern – hier Sport und Kunst – für die Erforschung von Universitätsrankings fruchtbar zu machen. Zu diesem Zweck unterscheiden wir zwei Vergleichs-perspektiven: (a) eine systematisch vergleichende Perspektive, die Universitätsrankings mit ähnlichen Vergleichspraktiken in anderen Feldern vergleicht; (b) eine historisch vergleichende Perspektive, die Rankings und ähnliche Vergleichspraktiken über längere Zeitverläufe miteinan-der vergleicht. Ein beide Perspektiven verknüpfender Ansatz, so unsere These, schärft nicht nur unseren Blick auf Universitätsrankings, sondern auch auf Rankings im Allgemeinen.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">**Ergänzender Hinweis zu den Creative Commons Lizenzen**&lt;br /&gt;"Creative Commons license terms for re-use do not apply to any content (such as graphs, figures, photos, excerpts, etc.) not original to the Open Access publication and further permission may be required from the rights holder. The obligation to research and clear permission lies solely with the party re-using the material."</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WorkingPaper2_SFB1288.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939561/2939599/WorkingPaper2_SFB1288.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2628-7722</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29395610</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2939561</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">23</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Brankovic J, Ringel L, Werron T. &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. Vol 2. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288; 2019.</ama>
<lncs> Brankovic, J., Ringel, L., Werron, T.: Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 2. Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brankovic, Jelena, Ringel, Leopold, and Werron, Tobias. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 2. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brankovic, J., Ringel, L. &amp;amp; Werron, T. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939561.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Brankovic J, Ringel L, Werron T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Brankovic, L.  Ringel, and T.  Werron, &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Sfb 1288, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> J. Brankovic, L. Ringel, and T. Werron, &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, vol. 2,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Brankovic, J., Ringel, L., &amp;amp; Werron, T., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, no.2, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</harvard1>
<apa>Brankovic, J., Ringel, L., &amp;amp; Werron, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 2). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939561</apa>
<wels>Brankovic, J.; Ringel, L.; Werron, T. (2019): Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brankovic, J., Ringel, L., &amp;amp; Werron, T. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 2). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939561&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Brankovic, J., Ringel, L., and Werron, T. (2019). Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective. &lt;em&gt;Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288&lt;/em&gt;, 2, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</frontiers>
<mla>Brankovic, Jelena, Ringel, Leopold, and Werron, Tobias. &lt;em&gt;Theorizing University Rankings. A Comparative Research Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, 2019. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. 2.</mla>
<default>Brankovic J, Ringel L, Werron T (2019)  Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288; 2.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939561</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-13T14:58:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-17T10:11:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>