<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939601</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nikolai Malkolm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brandt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33304519</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dennis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heitmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7612223</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In a horizontal differentiated duopoly we compare Nash and Stackelberg
equilibria in which the firms endogeneously choose to behave as a price or
quantity setter. Using the utility function introduced by Dixit (1979) we
generalize the model of Boyer and Moreaux (1987) and show that it is always
more profitable to strategically set the price (quantity) if the goods
are complements (substitutes). For every degree of product differentiation,
consumer surplus and total welfare are maximal in the standard Bertrand
equilibrium, followed by the price Stackelberg, the quantity Stackelberg and
the Cournot equilibrium. In contrast to Boyer and Moreaux we show that
there is no unique ranking of prices, quantities and profits of the leader and
follower depending on the degree of product differentiation and the type of
competition. Furthermore, we show that the price (quantity) Stackelberg
equilibrium is bounded by the Bertrand and the mixed Nash equilibrium in
which firm 1 sets the price (quantity) and firm 2 the quantity (price).</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_12_2019.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939601/2939603/wpaper_12_2019.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Stackelberg equilibrium</topic><topic>Cournot</topic><topic>Bertrand</topic><topic>strategy space</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29396019</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2939601</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12-2019</number></detail><extent unit="pages">24</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Brandt, N. M., &amp;amp; Heitmann, D. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939601</apa>
<ieee> N.M. Brandt and D. Heitmann, &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 12-2019,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<ama>Brandt NM, Heitmann D. &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 12-2019. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2019.</ama>
<frontiers>Brandt, N. M., and Heitmann, D. (2019). Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 12-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandt, N.M. &amp;amp; Heitmann, D. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939601.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandt, N. M., &amp;amp; Heitmann, D. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939601&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Brandt NM, Heitmann D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Brandt, N.M., &amp;amp; Heitmann, D., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.12-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>N. M.  Brandt, and D.  Heitmann, &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Brandt, N. M.; Heitmann, D. (2019): Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<mla>Brandt, Nikolai Malkolm, and Heitmann, Dennis. &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 12-2019.</mla>
<default>Brandt NM, Heitmann D (2019)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<lncs> Brandt, N.M., Heitmann, D.: Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2019. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brandt, Nikolai Malkolm, and Heitmann, Dennis. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Endogeneous strategy spaces: Simultaneous move vs. sequential move games&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12-2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939601</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-17T13:11:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-17T14:13:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>