<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939849</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabienne Lara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dascher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">100593456</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper our objective is to analyze sustainable debt policy rules and economic growth
using a model of endogenous economic growth theory. For the government it is possible to run
into debt, but, the primary surplus is a positive linear function of the debt-to-GDP ratio which
guarantees that public debt is sustainable. We analyze different sustainable debt policies in
this small open economy model of endogenous growth with public capital accumulation, as
well we take transitions into account. We investigate the characteristics and stability of the
steady state and we analyze the effects on welfare for the different debt policies.
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_14_2019.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939849/2939851/wpaper_14_2019.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Public Debt</topic><topic>Fiscal Sustainability</topic><topic>Economic Growth</topic><topic>Small Open Economy Model</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29398497</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2939849</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>14-2019</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher, Fabienne Lara. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 14-2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dascher, F.L.: Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile? Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 14-2019. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<default>Dascher FL (2019)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 14-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Dascher, Fabienne Lara. &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 14-2019.</mla>
<wels>Dascher, F. L. (2019): Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F. L.  Dascher, &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dascher FL (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 14-2019.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dascher, F.L., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.14-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher, F. L. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 14-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939849&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Dascher, F. L. (2019). Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile? &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 14-2019, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher, F.L. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939849.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Dascher FL. &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 14-2019. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2019.</ama>
<ieee> F.L. Dascher, &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 14-2019,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Dascher, F. L. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Debt Policy Rules and Growth in a Small Open Economy Model: Is a balanced government budget worthwhile?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 14-2019). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939849</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939849</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-07T14:17:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-07T14:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>