<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939844</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bright Opoku</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Junior</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eugene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Budu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hormenu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joseph Kwame</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mintah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Francis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sambah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Pregnancy among girls 10–19 years remains a challenge that requires critical resolution all over the world. Despite this worrying sexual phenomenon, research pertaining to prevention information and related services in Sub-Saharan nations like Ghana is sparse. This study sought to determine the influence of access to pregnancy prevention information and services on adolescent pregnancy in the Komenda-Edina-Eguafo-Abrem Municipality in the Central Region of Ghana.

Methods and Results: Adopting a matched case-control research design with a 1:1 mapping, female adolescents aged between 15 and 19 years in the KEEA Municipality were selected using a facility based sampling technique. Results from both bivariate and multivariate analyses revealed that non-pregnant adolescents were about two times more likely to have access to pregnancy prevention information from health workers compared to pregnant adolescents [OR = 0.57, 95% CI = (0.33–0.96), p = 0.036]. Likewise, pregnant adolescents were five times more likely to have access to pregnancy prevention information from media compared to non-pregnant adolescents [OR = 5.44, 95% CI = (2.64–11.23), p = 0.000]. Additionally, non-pregnant adolescents were two times more likely to receive information on pregnancy prevention from school compared to pregnant adolescents [OR = 0.48, 95% CI = (0.28–0.81), p = 0.006].

Conclusion: Sexuality and reproductive health (SRH) programme organizers should target specific intervention programmes that focus on training health workers and/or other analogous staff to enhance their awareness, attitudes, and skills to more effectively meet with the specific needs of adolescents. Specific health workers training and redesign of health facilities to foster more adolescent user friendly working environment (e.g., extension in operational times, reduction in fees of SRH services, transforming physical design to promote privacy or confidentiality) ought to be encouraged. Different media outreach programmes should also combine other community level events [e.g., informative methods through schools (e.g., focus group discussions, participatory learning), assisting connections to health services, community information network (e.g., use of sirens)] to provide well–tailored advocacy that would help modify SRH and sociocultural norms that hinder positive sexual behaviors among young people.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpubh-07-00382.hagan.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939844/2940685/fpubh-07-00382.hagan.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Research Foundation</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2296-2565</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2296-2565</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31921747</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000504734600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29398449</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2019.00382</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1-11</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> B.O. Ahinkorah, et al., “Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 7, 2019,  pp. 1-11.</ieee>
<apa>Ahinkorah, B. O., Hagan Junior, J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Budu, E., Hormenu, T., Mintah, J. K., Sambah, F., et al. (2019). Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1-11. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00382</apa>
<frontiers>Ahinkorah, B. O., Hagan Junior, J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Budu, E., Hormenu, T., Mintah, J. K., Sambah, F., and Schack, T. (2019). Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7, 1-11.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, B.O., Hagan Junior, J.E., Seidu, A.-A., Budu, E., Hormenu, T., Mintah, J.K., Sambah, F. &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2019). Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1-11. Frontiers Research Foundation. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00382.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ahinkorah BO, Hagan Junior JE, Seidu A-A, et al. Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2019;7:1-11.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>B. O.  Ahinkorah, J. E.  Hagan Junior, A. - A.  Seidu, E.  Budu, T.  Hormenu, J. K.  Mintah, F.  Sambah, and T.  Schack, “Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1-11.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, B. O., Hagan Junior, J. E., Seidu, A. - A., Budu, E., Hormenu, T., Mintah, J. K., Sambah, F., et al. (2019). Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 1-11. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2019.00382&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Ahinkorah BO, Hagan Junior JE, Seidu A-A, Budu E, Hormenu T, Mintah JK, Sambah F, Schack T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Public Health 7: 1-11.</bio1>
<harvard1>Ahinkorah, B.O., et al., 2019. Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 7, p 1-11.</harvard1>
<wels>Ahinkorah, B. O.; Hagan Junior, J. E.; Seidu, A. - A.; Budu, E.; Hormenu, T.; Mintah, J. K.; Sambah, F.; Schack, T. (2019): Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,7: 1-11.</wels>
<default>Ahinkorah BO, Hagan Junior JE, Seidu A-A, Budu E, Hormenu T, Mintah JK, Sambah F, Schack T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1-11.</default>
<mla>Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Budu, Eugene, Hormenu, Thomas, Mintah, Joseph Kwame, Sambah, Francis, and Schack, Thomas. “Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7 (2019): 1-11.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Budu, Eugene, Hormenu, Thomas, Mintah, Joseph Kwame, Sambah, Francis, and Schack, Thomas. 2019. “Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1-11.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ahinkorah, B.O., Hagan Junior, J.E., Seidu, A.-A., Budu, E., Hormenu, T., Mintah, J.K., Sambah, F., Schack, T.: Access to Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Information and Services in Ghana: A Community-Based Case-Control Study. Frontiers in Public Health. 7, 1-11 (2019).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939844</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-07T11:13:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-13T05:58:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>