<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939156</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tamino</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huxohl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">96181372</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8865-2895</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pohling</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27545250</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Birte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Carlmeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46832369</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0957-2406</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Britta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10380</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>









<name type="conference">
  <namePart> International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The use of Personal Voice Assistants (PVAs) such as Alexa and the Google Assistant is rising steadily, but there is a lack of research investigating common issues and requests of PVAs in the context of smart home control. We address this research question with an online survey (n = 65), using a qualitative evaluation of users’ problems and improvement requests. Our analysis leads to a partly hierarchic clustering of issues &amp; recommendations for interaction capabilities of PVAs into seven basic categories, allowing us in turn to derive implications and to condense them into design guidelines for future Human-Agent Interaction (HAI) with PVAs. Specifically, we formulate and elaborate the concepts Authentication &amp; Authorization, Activity-Based Interaction, Situated Dialogue, and Explainability &amp; Transparency as key topics for making progress towards smooth interaction with smart homes.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="preprint.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939156/2939157/preprint.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Timișoara</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>personal voice assistants</topic><topic>smart home</topic><topic>interaction guidelines</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29391562</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1109/SPED.2019.8906642</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">1-10</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Huxohl, T.; Pohling, M.; Carlmeyer, B.; Wrede, B.; Hermann, T. (2019): Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. In: 2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD). Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.  S. 1-10.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Huxohl, M.  Pohling, B.  Carlmeyer, B.  Wrede, and T.  Hermann, in &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, Piscataway, NJ, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1-10.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Huxohl T, Pohling M, Carlmeyer B, Wrede B, Hermann T (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. &lt;br /&gt;In:  2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD).  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  1-10.</bio1>
<harvard1>Huxohl, T., et al., 2019. Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. In &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;.  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, pp. 1-10.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huxohl, T., Pohling, M., Carlmeyer, B., Wrede, B., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2019). Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/SPED.2019.8906642&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Huxohl, T., Pohling, M., Carlmeyer, B., Wrede, B., and Hermann, T. (2019). “Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes” in &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt; (Piscataway, NJ: IEEE), 1-10.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huxohl, T., Pohling, M., Carlmeyer, B., Wrede, B. &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2019). Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1-10). Gehalten auf der  International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue, Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/SPED.2019.8906642.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Huxohl T, Pohling M, Carlmeyer B, Wrede B, Hermann T. Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. In:  &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE;  2019: 1-10.</ama>
<ieee> T. Huxohl, et al., “Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes”, &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;,  Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2019,  pp.1-10.</ieee>
<apa>Huxohl, T., Pohling, M., Carlmeyer, B., Wrede, B., &amp;amp; Hermann, T. (2019). Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. doi:10.1109/SPED.2019.8906642</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huxohl, Tamino, Pohling, Marian, Carlmeyer, Birte, Wrede, Britta, and Hermann, Thomas. 2019. “Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes”. In &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1-10. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Huxohl, T., Pohling, M., Carlmeyer, B., Wrede, B., Hermann, T.: Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes. 2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD). p. 1-10. IEEE, Piscataway, NJ (2019).</lncs>
<default>Huxohl T, Pohling M, Carlmeyer B, Wrede B, Hermann T (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD). Piscataway, NJ: IEEE:  1-10.</default>
<mla>Huxohl, Tamino, Pohling, Marian, Carlmeyer, Birte, Wrede, Britta, and Hermann, Thomas. “Interaction Guidelines for Personal Voice Assistants in Smart Homes”. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: IEEE, 2019. 1-10.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939156</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-25T08:02:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-27T13:12:41Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>