<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939741</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aleksas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mazeliauskas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Aleksi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kurkela</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jean-Francois</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paquet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sören</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlichting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">135644554</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3713-2325</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Derek</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Teaney</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum (Confinement2018)</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Confinement2018_152.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939741/2955450/Confinement2018_152.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Proceedings of Science (PoS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Maynooth, Ireland</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="INSPIRE">1757175</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29397419</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.22323/1.336.0152</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>336</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> A. Mazeliauskas, et al., “Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of Science, vol. 336, Proceedings of Science (PoS), 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Mazeliauskas, A., et al., 2019. Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of Science. no.336  Proceedings of Science (PoS).</harvard1>
<apa>Mazeliauskas, A., Kurkela, A., Paquet, J. - F., Schlichting, S., &amp;amp; Teaney, D. (2019). Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of Science, &lt;em&gt;336&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of Science (PoS). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.22323/1.336.0152" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.22323/1.336.0152&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Mazeliauskas, A.; Kurkela, A.; Paquet, J. - F.; Schlichting, S.; Teaney, D. (2019): Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. In: Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018. Proceedings of Science (PoS). (Proceedings of Science, 336).</wels>
<mla>Mazeliauskas, Aleksas, Kurkela, Aleksi, Paquet, Jean-Francois, Schlichting, Sören, and Teaney, Derek. “Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of Science (PoS), 2019.Vol. 336. Proceedings of Science.</mla>
<frontiers>Mazeliauskas, A., Kurkela, A., Paquet, J. - F., Schlichting, S., and Teaney, D. (2019). “Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of Science, vol. 336, (Proceedings of Science (PoS).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mazeliauskas, A., Kurkela, A., Paquet, J. - F., Schlichting, S., &amp;amp; Teaney, D. (2019). Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of Science, &lt;em&gt;336&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of Science (PoS). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.22323/1.336.0152" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.22323/1.336.0152&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Mazeliauskas A, Kurkela A, Paquet J-F, Schlichting S, Teaney D (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018. Proceedings of Science, 336.  Proceedings of Science (PoS).</default>
<ama>Mazeliauskas A, Kurkela A, Paquet J-F, Schlichting S, Teaney D. Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of Science. Vol 336. Proceedings of Science (PoS);  2019.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mazeliauskas, Aleksas, Kurkela, Aleksi, Paquet, Jean-Francois, Schlichting, Sören, and Teaney, Derek. 2019. “Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 336. Proceedings of Science. Proceedings of Science (PoS): 152.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Mazeliauskas, A., Kurkela, A., Paquet, J.-F., Schlichting, S., Teaney, D.: Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018. Proceedings of Science. 336,  Proceedings of Science (PoS) (2019).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Mazeliauskas, A., Kurkela, A., Paquet, J.-F., Schlichting, S. &amp;amp; Teaney, D. (2019). Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory (Proceedings of Science). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum (Confinement2018), Proceedings of Science (PoS). doi:10.22323/1.336.0152.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Mazeliauskas A, Kurkela A, Paquet J-F, Schlichting S, Teaney D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Matching the non-equilibrium initial stage of heavy ion collisions to hydrodynamics with QCD kinetic theory. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018.  Proceedings of Science, 336. Proceedings of Science (PoS).</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Mazeliauskas, A.  Kurkela, J. - F.  Paquet, S.  Schlichting, and D.  Teaney, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of XIII Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum - Confinement 2018&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings Of Science (Pos), &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939741</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-03T13:09:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-09T05:26:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>