<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939597</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:100</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">inpress</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marek </namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tamm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Zoltán Boldizsár</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Simon</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">47424226</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8763-7415</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jouni-Matti</namePart><namePart type="family">Kuukkanen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10023</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Tamm &amp; Simon Draft More-than-Human History.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939597/2941755/Tamm &amp; Simon Draft More-than-Human History.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bloomsbury</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn"> 9781350111844 </identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29395978</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tamm, Marek, and Simon, Zoltán Boldizsár. In Press. “More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene”. In &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Jouni-Matti Kuukkanen. London: Bloomsbury.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Tamm, M., Simon, Z.B.: More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In: Kuukkanen, J.-M. (ed.) Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives.  Bloomsbury, London (In Press).</lncs>
<default>Tamm M, Simon ZB (In Press)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives. Kuukkanen J-M (Ed);  London: Bloomsbury.</default>
<mla>Tamm, Marek, and Simon, Zoltán Boldizsár. “More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene”. &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Jouni-Matti Kuukkanen. London: Bloomsbury, In Press.</mla>
<frontiers>Tamm, M., and Simon, Z. B. (In Press). “More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene” in &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Kuukkanen, J. - M. ed. (London: Bloomsbury).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tamm, M. &amp;amp; Simon, Z.B. (In Press). More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In J.-M. Kuukkanen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. London: Bloomsbury.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Tamm M, Simon ZB. More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In: Kuukkanen J-M, ed. &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. London: Bloomsbury;  In Press.</ama>
<ieee> M.  Tamm and Z.B. Simon, “More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene”, &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, J.-M. Kuukkanen, ed.,  London: Bloomsbury, In Press.</ieee>
<apa>Tamm, M., &amp;amp; Simon, Z. B. (In Press). More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In J. - M.  Kuukkanen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; London: Bloomsbury.</apa>
<wels>Tamm, M.; Simon, Z. B. (In Press): More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In: Jouni-Matti Kuukkanen (Hrsg.):  Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives. London: Bloomsbury.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.   Tamm, and Z. B.  Simon, in &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: J.-M. Kuukkanen), Bloomsbury, London, &lt;strong&gt;In Press&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Tamm M, Simon ZB (In Press) &lt;br /&gt;More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives. Kuukkanen J-M (Ed); London: Bloomsbury.</bio1>
<harvard1>Tamm, M., &amp;amp; Simon, Z.B., In Press. More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In J. - M.  Kuukkanen, ed. &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;.  London: Bloomsbury.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Tamm, M., &amp;amp; Simon, Z. B. (In Press). More-than-Human History: Philosophy of History at the Time of the Anthropocene. In J. - M.  Kuukkanen (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of History. Twenty-First-Century Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; London: Bloomsbury.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939597</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-17T10:31:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-10T10:26:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>