<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939511</id><setSpec>report</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:report</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>reportFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>report</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tessa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulenkorf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Niklas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nutsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nadolny</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Änne-Dörte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Latteck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175759</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Today, low levels of physical activity are a major health problem for society and are associated with an increased risk for chronic diseases especially by people with intellectual disability. To our knowledge, target group concepts to promote physical activity addressing daily life are rarely. For this, the aim of our research project is to develop, test and validate a multi-modal target-group-oriented intervention. This intervention will promote a physically active lifestyle by promoting health-related literacy, Physical activity-related health competence and self-efficacy. The first step of the project is to review the current state of interventions promoting physical activity in people with intellectual disability with a focus on daily life activities. This article describes the approach and the findings of the conducted scoping review.
In general, 33 articles could be included. They were sorted by overviews, systematic reviews, studies, and curriculum. For a good overlook and comparision data were mapped for each category, except the single curriculum. Likewise, for all categories the results were summarized via a qualitative thematic analysis in a narrative format. For this, we identify relevant statements in the articles according to our research questions: a) How is motivation of the participants discussed? b) How are the needs of participants integrated in the intervention? c) Are competencies/physical requirements for physical activity of users analyzed and if so, how? d) How are the interventions evaluated? We added categories if we think that they are important for our own intervention development.
This report has three goals:
a) It is a tool-box (pool of ideas) mainly with basic concepts and tested strategies for our own development but also with other information about e.g. barriers and facilitator.
b) Above that, with the detailed results presentation, we would like to achieve good transparency on which data basis our intervention will be developed.
c) We like to share our results with interested.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Bruland et al Interventions to improve physical activity .pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939511/2939980/Bruland et al Interventions to improve physical activity .pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Attachment No 1_ all studies without duplicates.xlsx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939511/2939513/Attachment No 1_ all studies without duplicates.xlsx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Attachment No 2_ excluded articles with reasons.xlsx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939511/2939514/Attachment No 2_ excluded articles with reasons.xlsx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Attachment No 3 data_mapping.xlsx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939511/2939515/Attachment No 3 data_mapping.xlsx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29395110</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2939511</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">53</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2945982</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Bruland, D., Schulenkorf, T., Nutsch, N., Nadolny, S., &amp;amp; Latteck, Ä. - D. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939511</apa>
<ieee> D. Bruland, et al., &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Bruland, D., et al., 2019. &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<default>Bruland D, Schulenkorf T, Nutsch N, Nadolny S, Latteck Ä-D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<wels>Bruland, D.; Schulenkorf, T.; Nutsch, N.; Nadolny, S.; Latteck, Ä. - D. (2019): Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bruland, D., Schulenkorf, T., Nutsch, N., Nadolny, S., &amp;amp; Latteck, Ä. - D. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939511&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bruland, Dirk, Schulenkorf, Tessa, Nutsch, Niklas, Nadolny, Stephan, and Latteck, Änne-Dörte. &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2019.</mla>
<frontiers>Bruland, D., Schulenkorf, T., Nutsch, N., Nadolny, S., and Latteck, Ä. - D. (2019). Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<lncs> Bruland, D., Schulenkorf, T., Nutsch, N., Nadolny, S., Latteck, Ä.-D.: Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bruland, Dirk, Schulenkorf, Tessa, Nutsch, Niklas, Nadolny, Stephan, and Latteck, Änne-Dörte. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Bruland D, Schulenkorf T, Nutsch N, Nadolny S, Latteck Ä-D. &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2019.</ama>
<bio1>Bruland D, Schulenkorf T, Nutsch N, Nadolny S, Latteck Ä-D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Bruland, T.  Schulenkorf, N.  Nutsch, S.  Nadolny, and Ä. - D.  Latteck, &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bruland, D., Schulenkorf, T., Nutsch, N., Nadolny, S. &amp;amp; Latteck, Ä.-D. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Interventions to improve physical activity in daily life of people with intellectual disabilities. Detailed results presentation of a Scoping Review&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2939511.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939511</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-12-10T15:35:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-22T12:24:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>