<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939988</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olivia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sanchez Graillet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">128228680</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3483-265X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Birgit</namePart><namePart type="family">Gersbeck-Schierholz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Shada</namePart><namePart type="family">Alsalamah</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>4th Conference HEALTHINFO 2019</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="healthinfo_2019_1_10_80025.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939988/2939991/healthinfo_2019_1_10_80025.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IARIA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Valencia, Spain</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29399885</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Sanchez Graillet O, Cimiano P (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing. Gersbeck-Schierholz B, Alsalamah S (Eds);  Wilmington: IARIA.</default>
<mla>Sanchez Graillet, Olivia, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations”. &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Birgit Gersbeck-Schierholz and Shada Alsalamah. Wilmington: IARIA, 2019.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sanchez Graillet, Olivia, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2019. “Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations”. In &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Birgit Gersbeck-Schierholz and Shada Alsalamah. Wilmington: IARIA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Sanchez Graillet, O., Cimiano, P.: Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In: Gersbeck-Schierholz, B. and Alsalamah, S. (eds.) HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing.  IARIA, Wilmington (2019).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Sanchez Graillet, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: B. Gersbeck-Schierholz, S. Alsalamah), Iaria, Wilmington, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sanchez Graillet, O., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2019). Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In B.  Gersbeck-Schierholz &amp;amp; S.  Alsalamah (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt; Wilmington: IARIA.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Sanchez Graillet, O., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2019. Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In B.  Gersbeck-Schierholz &amp;amp; S.  Alsalamah, eds. &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;.  Wilmington: IARIA.</harvard1>
<bio1>Sanchez Graillet O, Cimiano P (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. &lt;br /&gt;In:  HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing. Gersbeck-Schierholz B, Alsalamah S (Eds); Wilmington: IARIA.</bio1>
<wels>Sanchez Graillet, O.; Cimiano, P. (2019): Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In: Birgit Gersbeck-Schierholz; Shada Alsalamah (Hrsg.):  HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing. Wilmington: IARIA.</wels>
<ieee> O. Sanchez Graillet and P. Cimiano, “Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations”, &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;, B. Gersbeck-Schierholz and S. Alsalamah, eds.,  Wilmington: IARIA, 2019.</ieee>
<apa>Sanchez Graillet, O., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2019). Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In B.  Gersbeck-Schierholz &amp;amp; S.  Alsalamah (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt; Wilmington: IARIA.</apa>
<frontiers>Sanchez Graillet, O., and Cimiano, P. (2019). “Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations” in &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;, Gersbeck-Schierholz, B., and Alsalamah, S. eds. (Wilmington: IARIA).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Sanchez Graillet, O. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2019). Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In B. Gersbeck-Schierholz &amp;amp; S. Alsalamah (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 4th Conference HEALTHINFO 2019, Wilmington: IARIA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Sanchez Graillet O, Cimiano P. Argumentation Schemes for Clinical Interventions. Towards an Evidence-Aggregation System for Medical Recommendations. In: Gersbeck-Schierholz B, Alsalamah S, eds. &lt;em&gt;HEALTHINFO 2019. The Fourth International Conference on Informatics and Assistive Technologies for Health-Care, Medical Support and Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt;. Wilmington: IARIA;  2019.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939988</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-14T15:10:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-15T09:15:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>