<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939265</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Max</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nendel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">127338064</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The aim of this work is to give an overview on nonlinear expectation
and to relate them to other concepts that describe model uncertainty
or imprecision in a probabilistic framework. We discuss imprecise versions
of stochastic processes with a particular interest in imprecise Markov chains.
First, we focus on basic properties and representations of nonlinear expectations
with additional structural assumptions such as translation invariance or
convexity. In a second step, we discuss how stochastic processes under nonlinear
expectations can be constructed via primal and dual representations. We
illustrate the concepts by means of imprecise Markov chains with a countable
state space, and show how families of Markov chains give rise to imprecise
versions of Markov chains. We discuss dual representations and differential
equations related to the latter.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">AMS 2010 Subject Classification: 28E05; 60G20; 60J27; 60J35</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_628.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939265/2939266/IMW_working_paper_628.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Nonlinear expectation</topic><topic>imprecise probability</topic><topic>Choquet capacity</topic><topic>imprecise Markov chain</topic><topic>nonlinear transition probability</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29392658</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>628</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Nendel, Max. &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 628.</mla>
<default>Nendel M (2019)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 628.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<lncs> Nendel, M.: On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 628. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, Max. 2019. &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 628. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Nendel, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 628). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> M. Nendel, &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 628,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2019.</ieee>
<ama>Nendel M. &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 628. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2019.</ama>
<frontiers>Nendel, M. (2019). On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 628, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, M. (2019). &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Nendel M (2019) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 628.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Nendel, M., 2019. &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.628, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, M. (2019).  &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 628). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Nendel, &lt;em&gt;On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Nendel, M. (2019): On Nonlinear Expectations and Markov Chains under Model Uncertainty. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939265</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-11-29T10:56:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>