<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2939758</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:360</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kayvan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bozorgmehr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">166226004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1411-1209</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Razum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">134970</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Santino</namePart><namePart type="family">Severoni</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Monika</namePart><namePart type="family">Kosinska</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Palmira</namePart><namePart type="family">Immordini</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Mihaly</namePart><namePart type="family">Kökény </namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michaela</namePart><namePart type="family">Told</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WHO_HEALTH_DIPLOMACY_spotlight on refugees and migrants_FINALpublished.zip">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2939758/2939759/WHO_HEALTH_DIPLOMACY_spotlight on refugees and migrants_FINALpublished.zip</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/x-zip-compressed</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-92-890-5433-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29397583</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">269-80</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, Kayvan, and Razum, Oliver. 2019. “Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany”. In &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Santino Severoni, Monika Kosinska, Palmira Immordini, Mihaly Kökény, Michaela Told, and World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe, 269-80. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bozorgmehr, K., Razum, O.: Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In: Severoni, S., Kosinska, M., Immordini, P., Kökény , M., Told, M., and World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (eds.) Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants. p. 269-80. World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, Copenhagen (2019).</lncs>
<default>Bozorgmehr K, Razum O (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants. Severoni S, Kosinska M, Immordini P, Kökény  M, Told M, World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Eds);  Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe:  269-80.</default>
<mla>Bozorgmehr, Kayvan, and Razum, Oliver. “Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany”. &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Santino Severoni, Monika Kosinska, Palmira Immordini, Mihaly Kökény, Michaela Told, and World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, 2019. 269-80.</mla>
<frontiers>Bozorgmehr, K., and Razum, O. (2019). “Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany” in &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;, Severoni, S., Kosinska, M., Immordini, P., Kökény , M., Told, M., and World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe eds. (Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe), 269-80.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, K. &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2019). Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In S. Severoni, M. Kosinska, P. Immordini, M. Kökény, M. Told &amp;amp; World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt; (S. 269-80). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bozorgmehr K, Razum O. Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In: Severoni S, Kosinska M, Immordini P, Kökény  M, Told M, World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe, eds. &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe;  2019: 269-80.</ama>
<ieee> K. Bozorgmehr and O. Razum, “Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany”, &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;, S. Severoni, et al., eds.,  Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, 2019,  pp.269-80.</ieee>
<apa>Bozorgmehr, K., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2019). Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In S.  Severoni, M.  Kosinska, P.  Immordini, M.  Kökény, M.  Told, &amp;amp; World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 269-80). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.</apa>
<wels>Bozorgmehr, K.; Razum, O. (2019): Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In: Santino Severoni; Monika Kosinska; Palmira Immordini; Mihaly Kökény; Michaela Told; World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Hrsg.):  Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants. Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.  S. 269-80.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Bozorgmehr, and O.  Razum, in &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Severoni, M. Kosinska, P. Immordini, M. Kökény, M. Told, World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe), World Health Organization. Regional Office For Europe, Copenhagen, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 269-80.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bozorgmehr, K., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2019). Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In S.  Severoni, M.  Kosinska, P.  Immordini, M.  Kökény, M.  Told, &amp;amp; World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 269-80). Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Bozorgmehr K, Razum O (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants. Severoni S, Kosinska M, Immordini P, Kökény  M, Told M, World Health Organization - Regional Office for Europe (Eds); Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe:  269-80.</bio1>
<harvard1>Bozorgmehr, K., &amp;amp; Razum, O., 2019. Negotiating access to health care for asylum seekers in Germany. In S.  Severoni, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Health diplomacy: spotlight on refugees and migrants&lt;/em&gt;.  Copenhagen: World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe, pp. 269-80.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2939758</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-04T00:49:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-06T14:45:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>