<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2940183</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53811697</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1714-4783</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart><namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ullrich</namePart><namePart type="family">Bauer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Diane</namePart><namePart type="family">Levin-Zamir</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paulo</namePart><namePart type="family">Pinheiro</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Kristine</namePart><namePart type="family">Sørensen </namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">7978137</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="International Handbook Health Literacy-2019-Chapter 2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2940183/2940184/International Handbook Health Literacy-2019-Chapter 2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Policy Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4473-4451-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29401836</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">21 - 38</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Okan, Orkan. “From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy”. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Paulo Pinheiro, and Kristine Sørensen. Bristol, UK: Policy Press, 2019. 21-38.</mla>
<apa>Okan, O. (2019). From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, P.  Pinheiro, &amp;amp; K.  Sørensen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 21-38). Bristol, UK: Policy Press.</apa>
<ieee> O. Okan, “From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy”, &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, O. Okan, et al., eds.,  Bristol, UK: Policy Press, 2019,  pp.21-38.</ieee>
<default>Okan O (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen  K (Eds);  Bristol, UK: Policy Press:  21-38.</default>
<ama>Okan O. From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In: Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen  K, eds. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bristol, UK: Policy Press;  2019: 21-38.</ama>
<lncs> Okan, O.: From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In: Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Pinheiro, P., and Sørensen , K. (eds.) International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. p. 21-38. Policy Press, Bristol, UK (2019).</lncs>
<frontiers>Okan, O. (2019). “From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy” in &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Pinheiro, P., and Sørensen , K. eds. (Bristol, UK: Policy Press), 21-38.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Okan, O. (2019). From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, P. Pinheiro &amp;amp; K. Sørensen (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (S. 21-38). Bristol, UK: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Okan, Orkan. 2019. “From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy”. In &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Paulo Pinheiro, and Kristine Sørensen, 21-38. Bristol, UK: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Okan, O., 2019. From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In O.  Okan, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;.  Bristol, UK: Policy Press, pp. 21-38.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Okan, O. (2019). From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, P.  Pinheiro, &amp;amp; K.  Sørensen (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 21-38). Bristol, UK: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Okan O (2019) &lt;br /&gt;From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Pinheiro P, Sørensen  K (Eds); Bristol, UK: Policy Press:  21-38.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Okan, in &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, P. Pinheiro, K. Sørensen), Policy Press, Bristol, UK, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 21-38.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Okan, O. (2019): From Saranac Lake to Shanghai: A brief history of health literacy. In: Orkan Okan; Ullrich Bauer; Diane Levin-Zamir; Paulo Pinheiro; Kristine Sørensen (Hrsg.):  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Bristol, UK: Policy Press.  S. 21-38.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2940183</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-21T14:23:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-22T10:57:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>