<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2940232</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Saboga-Nunes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uwe H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bittlingmayer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53811697</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1714-4783</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Orkan</namePart><namePart type="family">Okan</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ullrich</namePart><namePart type="family">Bauer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Diane</namePart><namePart type="family">Levin-Zamir</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Krstine</namePart><namePart type="family">Sørensen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paulo</namePart><namePart type="family">Pinheiro</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">7978137</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="International Handbook Health Literacy-2019-Chapter 42.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2940232/2940237/International Handbook Health Literacy-2019-Chapter 42.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Policy Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-4473-4451-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29402323</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">649–664</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Saboga-Nunes L, Bittlingmayer UH, Okan O (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Sørensen K, Pinheiro P (Eds);  Bristol: Policy Press:  649–664.</default>
<mla>Saboga-Nunes, Luis, Bittlingmayer, Uwe H., and Okan, Orkan. “Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!”. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Krstine Sørensen, and Paulo Pinheiro. Bristol: Policy Press, 2019. 649–664.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saboga-Nunes, Luis, Bittlingmayer, Uwe H., and Okan, Orkan. 2019. “Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!”. In &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Orkan Okan, Ullrich Bauer, Diane Levin-Zamir, Krstine Sørensen, and Paulo Pinheiro, 649–664. Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U.H., Okan, O.: Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In: Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Sørensen, K., and Pinheiro, P. (eds.) International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. p. 649–664. Policy Press, Bristol (2019).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Saboga-Nunes, U. H.  Bittlingmayer, and O.  Okan, in &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, K. Sørensen, P. Pinheiro), Policy Press, Bristol, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 649–664.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Saboga-Nunes L, Bittlingmayer UH, Okan O (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Sørensen K, Pinheiro P (Eds); Bristol: Policy Press:  649–664.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U. H., &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, K.  Sørensen, &amp;amp; P.  Pinheiro (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (p. 649–664). Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U.H., &amp;amp; Okan, O., 2019. Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In O.  Okan, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;.  Bristol: Policy Press, pp. 649–664.</harvard1>
<wels>Saboga-Nunes, L.; Bittlingmayer, U. H.; Okan, O. (2019): Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In: Orkan Okan; Ullrich Bauer; Diane Levin-Zamir; Krstine Sørensen; Paulo Pinheiro (Hrsg.):  International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan. Bristol: Policy Press.  S. 649–664.</wels>
<ieee> L. Saboga-Nunes, U.H. Bittlingmayer, and O. Okan, “Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!”, &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, O. Okan, et al., eds.,  Bristol: Policy Press, 2019,  pp.649–664.</ieee>
<apa>Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U. H., &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In O.  Okan, U.  Bauer, D.  Levin-Zamir, K.  Sørensen, &amp;amp; P.  Pinheiro (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (p. 649–664). Bristol: Policy Press.</apa>
<frontiers>Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U. H., and Okan, O. (2019). “Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!” in &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;, Okan, O., Bauer, U., Levin-Zamir, D., Sørensen, K., and Pinheiro, P. eds. (Bristol: Policy Press), 649–664.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Saboga-Nunes, L., Bittlingmayer, U.H. &amp;amp; Okan, O. (2019). Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In O. Okan, U. Bauer, D. Levin-Zamir, K. Sørensen &amp;amp; P. Pinheiro (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt; (S. 649–664). Bristol: Policy Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Saboga-Nunes L, Bittlingmayer UH, Okan O. Health Literacy and Salutogenesis: the health promotion simplex!. In: Okan O, Bauer U, Levin-Zamir D, Sørensen K, Pinheiro P, eds. &lt;em&gt;International Handbook of Health Literacy. Research, Practice and Policy across the Lifespan&lt;/em&gt;. Bristol: Policy Press;  2019: 649–664.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2940232</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-21T16:50:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-01-23T15:55:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>