<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2941833</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:320</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Knecht</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">168448331</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Robert W.</namePart><namePart type="family">Corell</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jong Deog</namePart><namePart type="family">Kim</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Yoon Hyung</namePart><namePart type="family">Kim</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Arild</namePart><namePart type="family">Moe</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Charles E.</namePart><namePart type="family">Morrison</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">David L.</namePart><namePart type="family">VanderZwaag</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Oran R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Young</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656050</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Knecht 2019_The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2941833/2949374/Knecht 2019_The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">979-11-89964-67-2</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29418336</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">385-394</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Knecht, S. (2019). The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In R. W.  Corell, J. D.  Kim, Y. H.  Kim, A.  Moe, C. E.  Morrison, D. L.  VanderZwaag, O. R.  Young, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 385-394). Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center.</apa>
<lncs> Knecht, S.: The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In: Corell, R.W., Kim, J.D., Kim, Y.H., Moe, A., Morrison, C.E., VanderZwaag, D.L., Young, O.R., and Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center (eds.) The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs . p. 385-394. Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center, Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knecht, Sebastian. 2019. “The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow”. In &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Robert W. Corell, Jong Deog Kim, Yoon Hyung Kim, Arild Moe, Charles E. Morrison, David L. VanderZwaag, Oran R. Young, and Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center, 385-394. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs . Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> S. Knecht, “The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow”, &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, R.W. Corell, et al., eds., KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs ,  Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center, 2019,  pp.385-394.</ieee>
<harvard1>Knecht, S., 2019. The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In R. W.  Corell, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs .  Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center, pp. 385-394.</harvard1>
<ama>Knecht S. The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In: Corell RW, Kim JD, Kim YH, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs . Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center;  2019: 385-394.</ama>
<default>Knecht S (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings. Corell RW, Kim JD, Kim YH, Moe A, Morrison CE, VanderZwaag DL, Young OR, Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center (Eds);  KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs .  Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center:  385-394.</default>
<bio1>Knecht S (2019) &lt;br /&gt;The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings. Corell RW, Kim JD, Kim YH, Moe A, Morrison CE, VanderZwaag DL, Young OR, Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center (Eds); KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs ,  Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center:  385-394.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Knecht, in &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: R.W. Corell, J.D. Kim, Y.H. Kim, A. Moe, C.E. Morrison, D.L. VanderZwaag, O.R. Young, Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center), Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center, Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 385-394.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Knecht, S. (2019): The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In: Robert W. Corell; Jong Deog Kim; Yoon Hyung Kim; Arild Moe; Charles E. Morrison; David L. VanderZwaag; Oran R. Young; Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center (Hrsg.):  The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings. Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center. (KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs , ).  S. 385-394.</wels>
<mla>Knecht, Sebastian. “The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow”. &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Robert W. Corell, Jong Deog Kim, Yoon Hyung Kim, Arild Moe, Charles E. Morrison, David L. VanderZwaag, Oran R. Young, and Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center. Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center, 2019. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs . 385-394.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knecht, S. (2019). The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow. In R. W.  Corell, J. D.  Kim, Y. H.  Kim, A.  Moe, C. E.  Morrison, D. L.  VanderZwaag, O. R.  Young, et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 385-394). Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Knecht, S. (2019). “The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow” in &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;, Corell, R. W., Kim, J. D., Kim, Y. H., Moe, A., Morrison, C. E., VanderZwaag, D. L., Young, O. R., and Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center eds. KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs  (Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center), 385-394.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Knecht, S. (2019). The Roles of Non-Arctic States in the Arctic: A Perspective from an NPAC Fellow (KMI/EWC series on The Arctic in World Affairs ). In R.W. Corell, J.D. Kim, Y.H. Kim, A. Moe, C.E. Morrison, D.L. VanderZwaag, O.R. Young &amp;amp; Korea Maritime Institute (KMI) and East-West Center (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The Arctic in World Affairs: A North Pacific Dialogue on Global-Arctic Interactions: The Arctic Moves from Periphery to Center. 2019 North Pacific Arctic Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; (S. 385-394). Busan, Korea ; Honolulu, HI: Korea Maritime Institute ; East-West Center.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2941833</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-12T11:01:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-11T09:13:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>