<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2941457</id><setSpec>research_data</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:ResearchData</setSpec><setSpec>research_dataFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>database</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fritz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trillmich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21949</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4816-1156</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Reproduction is one of the costliest processes in the life of an animal. Life history theory assumes that when resources are limiting allocation to reproduction will reduce allocation to other essential processes thereby inducing costs of reproduction. The immune system is vital for survival. If reproduction reduces investment in immune function, this could increase the risk of disease, morbidity and mortality. We here test in the guinea pig, if even under ad libitum food conditions, pregnancy and lactation reduce the activity of the adaptive and innate immune system compared to the reaction of non-reproducing animals. In response to a challenge with keyhole limpet haemocyanin the antibody-mediated adaptive immunity during (pregnancy and) lactation was reduced. Pregnant and lactating females showed higher levels of bacterial killing activity, an integrated measure of innate immunity, than non-reproducing females. However, two major effectors of the innate immunity, the natural antibody and the complement of pregnant and lactating females showed lower levels than in non-reproducing females. Pregnant and lactating females did not differ significantly in the expressed levels of innate immunity. Our results indicate that changes in the immune response during reproduction are physiological adjustments to predictable allocation problems, because they happen even under ad libitum food availability.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Data on Exp I and II.xlsx">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2941457/2941458/Data on Exp I and II.xlsx</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>

<subject><topic>adaptive and innate immunity</topic><topic>trade-off</topic><topic>pregnancy</topic><topic>lactation</topic><topic>physiological regulation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2941457</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2942010</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Trillmich, F., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University.</harvard1>
<ieee> F. Trillmich, &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, 2020.</ieee>
<apa>Trillmich, F. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2941457</apa>
<frontiers>Trillmich, F. (2020). Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food. Bielefeld University.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trillmich, F. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2941457&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Trillmich, Fritz. &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University, 2020.</mla>
<wels>Trillmich, F. (2020): Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food. Bielefeld University.</wels>
<default>Trillmich F (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</default>
<ama>Trillmich F. &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University; 2020.</ama>
<lncs> Trillmich, F.: Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food. Bielefeld University (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trillmich, Fritz. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Trillmich, F. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld University. doi:10.4119/unibi/2941457.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Trillmich, &lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Trillmich F (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reproduction affects immune defenses in the guinea pig even under ad libitum food&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld University.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2941457</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-02-24T09:18:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-06T11:20:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>