<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2942886</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Miriam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Santel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beblo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">166148</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neuner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9438235</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michaela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Berg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kristina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hennig-Fast</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">David A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jobes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Driessen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33704</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

The Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) is a therapeutic framework that has been shown to reduce suicidal ideation and overall symptom distress. CAMS has not been previously evaluated in a standard acute inpatient mental health care setting with only short treatment times for suicidal patients. In this randomized controlled trial (RCT) we are investigating whether CAMS is more effective than Enhanced-Treatment as Usual (E-TAU) in reducing suicidal thoughts as primary outcome variable. We are also investigating depressive symptoms, general symptom relief, and the quality of the therapeutic alliance as secondary outcomes.
Methods/Design

This RCT is designed as a single-center, two-armed, parallel group observer-blinded clinical effectiveness investigation. We are recruiting and randomizing 60 participants with different diagnoses, who are admitted as inpatients because of acute suicidal thoughts or behaviors into the Clinic for Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Ev. Hospital Bethel in Bielefeld, Germany. The duration of treatment will vary depending on patients’ needs and clinical assessments ranging between 10 and 40 days. Patients are assessed four times, at admission, discharge, 1 month, and 5 months post-discharge. The primary outcome measure is the Beck Scale for Suicide Ideation. Other outcome measures are administered as assessment timepoints including severity of psychiatric symptoms, depression, reasons for living, and therapeutic relationship.
Discussion

This effectiveness study is being conducted on an acute ward in a psychiatric clinic where patients have multiple problems and diagnoses. Treatment is somewhat limited, and therapists have a large caseloads. The results of this study can thus be generalizable to a typical inpatient psychiatric hospital settings.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s12888-020-02589-x.santel.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2942886/2942887/s12888-020-02589-x.santel.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Psychiatry and Mental health</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Psychiatry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1471-244X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32321477</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000530275500004</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29428864</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12888-020-02589-x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>20</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Santel, M.; Beblo, T.; Neuner, F.; Berg, M.; Hennig-Fast, K.; Jobes, D. A.; Driessen, M. (2020): Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,20:(1):183</wels>
<harvard1>Santel, M., et al., 2020. Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, 20(1): 183.</harvard1>
<bio1>Santel M, Beblo T, Neuner F, Berg M, Hennig-Fast K, Jobes DA, Driessen M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Psychiatry 20(1): 183.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Santel, M., Beblo, T., Neuner, F., Berg, M., Hennig-Fast, K., Jobes, D. A., &amp;amp; Driessen, M. (2020). Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;(1), 183. doi:10.1186/s12888-020-02589-x&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Santel, T.  Beblo, F.  Neuner, M.  Berg, K.  Hennig-Fast, D. A.  Jobes, and M.  Driessen, “Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;, : 183.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Santel M, Beblo T, Neuner F, et al. Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;20(1): 183.</ama>
<frontiers>Santel, M., Beblo, T., Neuner, F., Berg, M., Hennig-Fast, K., Jobes, D. A., and Driessen, M. (2020). Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 20:183.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Santel, M., Beblo, T., Neuner, F., Berg, M., Hennig-Fast, K., Jobes, D.A. &amp;amp; Driessen, M. (2020). Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;(1): 183. Springer Science and Business Media LLC. doi:10.1186/s12888-020-02589-x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Santel, M., Beblo, T., Neuner, F., Berg, M., Hennig-Fast, K., Jobes, D. A., &amp;amp; Driessen, M. (2020). Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;(1), 183. doi:10.1186/s12888-020-02589-x</apa>
<ieee> M. Santel, et al., “Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 20, 2020, : 183.</ieee>
<lncs> Santel, M., Beblo, T., Neuner, F., Berg, M., Hennig-Fast, K., Jobes, D.A., Driessen, M.: Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 20, : 183 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Santel, Miriam, Beblo, Thomas, Neuner, Frank, Berg, Michaela, Hennig-Fast, Kristina, Jobes, David A., and Driessen, Martin. 2020. “Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 20 (1): 183.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Santel, Miriam, Beblo, Thomas, Neuner, Frank, Berg, Michaela, Hennig-Fast, Kristina, Jobes, David A., and Driessen, Martin. “Collaborative Assessment and Management of Suicidality (CAMS) compared to enhanced treatment as usual (E-TAU) for suicidal patients in an inpatient setting: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 20.1 (2020): 183.</mla>
<default>Santel M, Beblo T, Neuner F, Berg M, Hennig-Fast K, Jobes DA, Driessen M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 20(1): 183.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2942886</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-27T07:09:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-06T11:20:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>