<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2942465</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kieninger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oscar N.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ventura</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tilman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kottke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">185295</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8080-9579</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17981</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Flavin cofactors, like flavin adenine dinucleotide (FAD), are important electron shuttles in living systems. They catalyze a wide range of one- or two-electron redox reactions. Experimental investigations include UV-vis as well as infrared spectroscopy. FAD in aqueous solution exhibits a significantly shorter excited state lifetime than its analog, the flavin mononucleotide. This finding is explained by the presence of a “stacked” FAD conformation, in which isoalloxazine and adenine moieties form a π-complex. Stacking of the isoalloxazine and adenine rings should have an influence on the frequency of the vibrational modes. Density functional theory (DFT) studies of the closed form of FAD in microsolvation (explicit water) were used to reproduce the experimental infrared spectra, substantiating the prevalence of the stacked geometry of FAD in aqueous surroundings. It could be shown that the existence of the closed structure in FAD can be narrowed down to the presence of only a single water molecule between the third hydroxyl group (of the ribityl chain) and the N7 in the adenine ring of FAD.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="biomolecules-10-00573-v2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2942465/2943355/biomolecules-10-00573-v2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>stacked flavin adenine dinucleotide (FAD) in microsolvation</topic><topic>vibrational spectra</topic><topic>supramolecular orbitals</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biomolecules</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2218-273X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32283685</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000539492400079</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29424652</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/biom10040573</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>4</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Kieninger, M.; Ventura, O. N.; Kottke, T. (2020): Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;,10:(4):573</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Kieninger, O. N.  Ventura, and T.  Kottke, “Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer”, &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 573.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Kieninger, M., Ventura, O.N., &amp;amp; Kottke, T., 2020. Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;, 10(4): 573.</harvard1>
<bio1>Kieninger M, Ventura ON, Kottke T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer.&lt;br /&gt;Biomolecules 10(4): 573.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kieninger, M., Ventura, O. N., &amp;amp; Kottke, T. (2020). Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4), 573. doi:10.3390/biom10040573&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kieninger, M., Ventura, O.N. &amp;amp; Kottke, T. (2020). Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4): 573. MDPI. doi:10.3390/biom10040573.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Kieninger, M., Ventura, O. N., and Kottke, T. (2020). Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt; 10:573.</frontiers>
<ama>Kieninger M, Ventura ON, Kottke T. Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;10(4): 573.</ama>
<ieee> M. Kieninger, O.N. Ventura, and T. Kottke, “Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer”, &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2020, : 573.</ieee>
<apa>Kieninger, M., Ventura, O. N., &amp;amp; Kottke, T. (2020). Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(4), 573. doi:10.3390/biom10040573</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kieninger, Martina, Ventura, Oscar N., and Kottke, Tilman. 2020. “Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer”. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt; 10 (4): 573.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Kieninger, M., Ventura, O.N., Kottke, T.: Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer. Biomolecules. 10, : 573 (2020).</lncs>
<default>Kieninger M, Ventura ON, Kottke T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt; 10(4): 573.</default>
<mla>Kieninger, Martina, Ventura, Oscar N., and Kottke, Tilman. “Calculation of the Geometries and Infrared Spectra of the Stacked Cofactor Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide (FAD) as the Prerequisite for Studies of Light-Triggered Proton and Electron Transfer”. &lt;em&gt;Biomolecules&lt;/em&gt; 10.4 (2020): 573.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2942465</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-10T13:51:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-30T06:51:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>