<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2942044</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Uliana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kostareva</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cheryl L.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albright</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eva-Maria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Berens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">22797466</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Diane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Levin-Zamir</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Altyn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aringazina</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maria</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lopatina</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luba L.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ivanov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tetine L.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sentell</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175759</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Among the world’s 272 million international migrants, more than 25 million are from the former Soviet Union (FSU), yet there is a paucity of literature available about FSU immigrants’ health literacy. Besides linguistic and cultural differences, FSU immigrants often come from a distinct healthcare system affecting their ability to find, evaluate, process, and use health information in the host countries. In this scoping review and commentary, we describe the health literacy issues of FSU immigrants and provide an overview of FSU immigrants’ health literacy based on the integrated health literacy model. We purposefully consider the three most common locations where FSU immigrants have settled: the USA, Germany, and Israel. For context, we describe the healthcare systems of the three host countries and the two post-Soviet countries to illustrate the contribution of system-level factors on FSU immigrants’ health literacy. We identify research gaps and set a future research agenda to help understand FSU immigrants’ health literacy across countries. Amidst the ongoing global population changes related to international migration, this article contributes to a broad-scope understanding of health literacy among FSU immigrants related to the system-level factors that may also apply to other immigrants, migrants, and refugees.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijerph-17-02155.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2942044/2943229/ijerph-17-02155.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32213891</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000529342300345</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29420449</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph17062155</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>17</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Kostareva, U.; Albright, C. L.; Berens, E. - M.; Levin-Zamir, D.; Aringazina, A.; Lopatina, M.; Ivanov, L. L.; Sentell, T. L. (2020): International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,17:(6):2155</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kostareva, U., Albright, C. L., Berens, E. - M., Levin-Zamir, D., Aringazina, A., Lopatina, M., Ivanov, L. L., et al. (2020). International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(6), 2155. doi:10.3390/ijerph17062155&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kostareva, U., Albright, C. L., Berens, E. - M., Levin-Zamir, D., Aringazina, A., Lopatina, M., Ivanov, L. L., and Sentell, T. L. (2020). International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17:2155.</frontiers>
<mla>Kostareva, Uliana, Albright, Cheryl L., Berens, Eva-Maria, Levin-Zamir, Diane, Aringazina, Altyn, Lopatina, Maria, Ivanov, Luba L., and Sentell, Tetine L. “International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17.6 (2020): 2155.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kostareva, U., Albright, C.L., Berens, E.-M., Levin-Zamir, D., Aringazina, A., Lopatina, M., Ivanov, L.L. &amp;amp; Sentell, T.L. (2020). International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(6): 2155. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph17062155.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Kostareva U, Albright CL, Berens E-M, Levin-Zamir D, Aringazina A, Lopatina M, Ivanov LL, Sentell TL (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17(6): 2155.</default>
<bio1>Kostareva U, Albright CL, Berens E-M, Levin-Zamir D, Aringazina A, Lopatina M, Ivanov LL, Sentell TL (2020) &lt;br /&gt;International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17(6): 2155.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Kostareva, C. L.  Albright, E. - M.  Berens, D.  Levin-Zamir, A.  Aringazina, M.  Lopatina, L. L.  Ivanov, and T. L.  Sentell, “International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;, : 2155.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> U. Kostareva, et al., “International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 17, 2020, : 2155.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kostareva, U., et al., 2020. International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 17(6): 2155.</harvard1>
<ama>Kostareva U, Albright CL, Berens E-M, et al. International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;17(6): 2155.</ama>
<apa>Kostareva, U., Albright, C. L., Berens, E. - M., Levin-Zamir, D., Aringazina, A., Lopatina, M., Ivanov, L. L., et al. (2020). International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(6), 2155. doi:10.3390/ijerph17062155</apa>
<lncs> Kostareva, U., Albright, C.L., Berens, E.-M., Levin-Zamir, D., Aringazina, A., Lopatina, M., Ivanov, L.L., Sentell, T.L.: International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 17, : 2155 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kostareva, Uliana, Albright, Cheryl L., Berens, Eva-Maria, Levin-Zamir, Diane, Aringazina, Altyn, Lopatina, Maria, Ivanov, Luba L., and Sentell, Tetine L. 2020. “International Perspective on Health Literacy and Health Equity: Factors That Influence the Former Soviet Union Immigrants”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17 (6): 2155.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2942044</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-03-26T06:55:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-06-22T08:12:11Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>