<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2943700</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">epub_ahead</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20254</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17975</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The development of the current knowledge of the gas-phase chemistry of protonated methylbenzenes, such as toluenium, xylenium and mesitylenium ions, their higher congeners as well as of their mostly cyclo-olefinic isomers by mass spectrometric methodology is presented. Starting from the observation of the characteristic expulsion of dihydrogen from metastable C7 H9 + ions, which is associated with the release of large amounts of kinetic energy, and the composite C- and H-scrambling prior to the loss of methane, in particular, insights into the isomerization scenario of various isomeric C7 H9 + , C8 H11 + , and C9 H13 + ions, based on a large variety of independent techniques, are discussed. Besides isotope labeling and metastable ion methodology, these include flowing afterglow mass spectrometry, gas-phase titration and infrared spectroscopy of mass-selected ions. The particularly complex energy hypersurface of isomerizing and fragmenting toluenium ions, which has been elaborated in various reports over the years, is presented in a combined way to assess the role of protonated cycloheptatriene, norbornadiene, and 6-methylfulvene as well as a number of further C7 H9 + isomers. The formation and nature of C7 H9 + ions generated by fragmentation of various hydrocarbon precursors, such as monoterpenes and adamantane, is also addressed. The contribution of infrared multiphoton dissociation spectroscopy (IRMPD)and tagged-ion infrared photodissociation (IRPD) of the gaseous C7 H9 + ions as compared to the wealth of previous understanding of their chemistry is commented on as well. Finally, remarkable parallels of the gas-phase chemistry of methylbenzenium ions and the role of such species within the cavities of acidic zeolite catalysts in the course of the industrially important methanol-to-hydrocarbon reaction are discussed. © 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd. Mass Spec Rev. © 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="mas.21631.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2943700/2953500/mas.21631.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Mass Spectrometry Reviews</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1098-2787</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32468717</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000535948400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29437005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/mas.21631</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Kuck, D., 2020. Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Kuck, “Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins”, &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;, 2020.</ieee>
<apa>Kuck, D. (2020). Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/mas.21631" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/mas.21631&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Kuck, D. (2020): Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, D. (2020). Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/mas.21631" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/mas.21631&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kuck, D. (2020). Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<mla>Kuck, Dietmar. “Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins”. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt; (2020).</mla>
<default>Kuck D (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;.</default>
<ama>Kuck D. Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;. 2020.</ama>
<lncs> Kuck, D.: Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. Mass Spectrometry Reviews. (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, Dietmar. 2020. “Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins”. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kuck, D. (2020). Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins. &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;. Wiley. doi:10.1002/mas.21631.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Kuck, “Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins”, &lt;em&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Kuck D (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Toluenium and other Gaseous Methylbenzenium Ions: Complex Interplay of Protonated Arenes and Cyclo-Olefins.&lt;br /&gt;Mass Spectrometry Reviews.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2943700</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-06-02T06:30:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-01T09:18:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>