<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2943950</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jasmina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arifovic</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mariam</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nanumyan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">110102629</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we explore the role of social influence for the coordination of
effort choice in a game with strategic complementarities. Players are repeatedly randomly partitioned in groups to play a minimum effort game and choose their effort based on their beliefs about the minimal effort
among the other members of their group. Individual expectations about
this minimal effort is influenced by own experience as well as by communication of beliefs within a social network. We show that increasing the
importance of social influence in the expectation formation process has
positive effects on the emerging (long run) effort level, thereby improving the efficiency of the outcome. Furthermore, a more centralized social
network leads to higher average efficiency, but also to increased variance
of outcomes. Finally, communication of actual minimum effort cannot
replace the communication of beliefs as a device fostering the emergence
of high long run effort.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_01_2020.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2943950/2943951/wpaper_01_2020.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Minimum Effort Game</topic><topic>Expectation Formation</topic><topic>Social Influence</topic><topic>Belief Communication</topic><topic>etace_WP</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29439502</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2943950</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>01-2020</number></detail><extent unit="pages">53</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Arifovic, J.; Dawid, H.; Nanumyan, M. (2020): Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arifovic, J., Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Nanumyan, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2020). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943950&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Arifovic J, Dawid H, Nanumyan M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Arifovic, J., Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Nanumyan, M., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.01-2020, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Arifovic, H.  Dawid, and M.  Nanumyan, &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Arifovic, J., Dawid, H., Nanumyan, M.: Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2020. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<ama>Arifovic J, Dawid H, Nanumyan M. &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 01-2020. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2020.</ama>
<frontiers>Arifovic, J., Dawid, H., and Nanumyan, M. (2020). Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 01-2020, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arifovic, J., Dawid, H. &amp;amp; Nanumyan, M. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943950.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arifovic, Jasmina, Dawid, Herbert, and Nanumyan, Mariam. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 01-2020. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Arifovic, J., Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Nanumyan, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2020). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943950</apa>
<mla>Arifovic, Jasmina, Dawid, Herbert, and Nanumyan, Mariam. &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2020. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 01-2020.</mla>
<default>Arifovic J, Dawid H, Nanumyan M (2020)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ieee> J. Arifovic, H. Dawid, and M. Nanumyan, &lt;em&gt;Efficiency Gains through Social Influence in a Minimum Effort Game&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 01-2020,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2020.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2943950</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-06-18T07:18:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-20T10:06:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>