<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2943566</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Melanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eulitz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60158951</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The transition from studying to a doctorate can also be understood as a transition from students to scholars. The paper explores the question of how this transition can be designed in universities and what measures are helpful for the prospective doctoral researchers. The interlinking of financial and academic support is reflected on the Shortcuts programme of the Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS). The decision to do a doctorate is understood as a process that requires both information and reflection. What is also decisive is the exchange within the group, which is discussed by the example of the programme module “peer coaching”.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Der Übergang vom Studium zur Promotion lässt sich zugleich als Übergang von Studierenden zu Wissenschaftler*innen verstehen. Das Paper geht der Frage nach, wie dieser Übergang in Hochschulen gestaltet werden kann und welche Maßnahmen dabei für die angehenden Promovierenden hilfreich sind. Anhand des Shortcuts-Programms der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) wird die Verzahnung von finanzieller und inhaltlicher Unterstützung reflektiert. Dabei wird die Entscheidung zur Promotion als Prozess verstanden, der sowohl Information als auch Reflexion benötigt. Maßgeblich ist zudem der Austausch in der Gruppe, was anhand des Programmbausteins des Peer-Coachings diskutiert wird.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BGHS_WP_05_Eulitz.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2943566/2943612/BGHS_WP_05_Eulitz.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Promotion</topic><topic>Übergang</topic><topic>Gruppe</topic><topic>Entscheidung</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2512-8051</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29435660</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">18</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eulitz, Melanie. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 5. BGHS Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Eulitz, M.: Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung. BGHS Working Paper Series, 5. Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS), Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<default>Eulitz M (2020)  BGHS Working Paper Series; 5.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</default>
<mla>Eulitz, Melanie. &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS), 2020. BGHS Working Paper Series. 5.</mla>
<frontiers>Eulitz, M. (2020). Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung. &lt;em&gt;BGHS Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 5, Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eulitz, M. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Eulitz M. &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;. BGHS Working Paper Series. Vol 5. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS); 2020.</ama>
<ieee> M. Eulitz, &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;, BGHS Working Paper Series, vol. 5,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS), 2020.</ieee>
<apa>Eulitz, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series, 5). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</apa>
<wels>Eulitz, M. (2020): Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung. Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Eulitz, &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld Graduate School In History And Sociology (Bghs), Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Eulitz M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;. BGHS Working Paper Series; 5.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</bio1>
<harvard1>Eulitz, M., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt;, BGHS Working Paper Series, no.5, Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eulitz, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Übergang zur Promotion. Das Shortcuts-Programm der Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS) als Instrument zur Karriereplanung&lt;/em&gt; (BGHS Working Paper Series, 5). Bielefeld: Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology (BGHS).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2943566</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-25T08:45:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-25T12:43:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>