<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2943299</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haneke-Reinders</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">93903609</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna-Paulina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mazur</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oleksandr</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zyma</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Steven A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ramm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">29115088</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7786-7364</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reinhold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">133426</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685497</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Shared behavioural traits result from the interaction of two or more individuals, making it difficult to discern which individual is in control of the behaviour of interest. Especially in the case of shared reproductive traits such as mating duration or mate guarding duration is this an important issue to resolve, because these are potentially closely connected to fitness and are likely to exhibit sexual conflict. Here, we sought to disentangle which sex controls mate guarding duration in the tropical house cricket Gryllodes sigillatus, a species in which mate guarding and nuptial feeding by the male have been proposed to prevent premature removal of the transferred spermatophore by the female. To do so, we performed a series of mating experiments in a paired design, in which the first mating dyad was allowed to start mating some time before the second dyad. Once both dyads were in the mate guarding phase, we then interrupted them and exchanged partners, enabling us to determine whether the remaining guarding duration depended more on the duration of guarding already performed by the male in the new dyad (implying male control) or on the guarding already received by the female (implying female control). We found that the time a female was guarded overall was significantly affected by how long the exchanged male had already engaged in mate guarding with the previous female, but conversely, the total time males guarded both females was unaffected by the duration of guarding that the exchanged female had previously received. Our data thus clearly demonstrate that males rather than females control mate guarding duration and adjust the duration according to females' weight.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Haneke-Reinders2020_Article_DisentanglingASharedTraitMaleC.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2943299/2944595/Haneke-Reinders2020_Article_DisentanglingASharedTraitMaleC.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Interaction phenotypes</topic><topic>Mate guarding</topic><topic>Mate exchange</topic><topic>Sexual conflict</topic><topic>Mating behaviour</topic><topic>Gryllodes</topic><topic>Cricket</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Behavioral ecology and sociobiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0340-5443</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-0762</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000526246100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29432990</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s00265-020-02832-1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>74</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Haneke-Reinders, M., Mazur, A.-P., Zyma, O., Ramm, S.A., Reinhold, K.: Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. Behavioral ecology and sociobiology. 74, : 54 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haneke-Reinders, Michael, Mazur, Anna-Paulina, Zyma, Oleksandr, Ramm, Steven A., and Reinhold, Klaus. 2020. “Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment”. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt; 74 (5): 54.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Haneke-Reinders, Michael, Mazur, Anna-Paulina, Zyma, Oleksandr, Ramm, Steven A., and Reinhold, Klaus. “Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment”. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt; 74.5 (2020): 54.</mla>
<default>Haneke-Reinders M, Mazur A-P, Zyma O, Ramm SA, Reinhold K (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt; 74(5): 54.</default>
<ama>Haneke-Reinders M, Mazur A-P, Zyma O, Ramm SA, Reinhold K. Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;74(5): 54.</ama>
<frontiers>Haneke-Reinders, M., Mazur, A. - P., Zyma, O., Ramm, S. A., and Reinhold, K. (2020). Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt; 74:54.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haneke-Reinders, M., Mazur, A.-P., Zyma, O., Ramm, S.A. &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (2020). Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;74&lt;/em&gt;(5): 54. Springer Nature. doi:10.1007/s00265-020-02832-1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Haneke-Reinders, M., Mazur, A. - P., Zyma, O., Ramm, S. A., &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (2020). Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;74&lt;/em&gt;(5), 54. doi:10.1007/s00265-020-02832-1</apa>
<ieee> M. Haneke-Reinders, et al., “Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment”, &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 74, 2020, : 54.</ieee>
<wels>Haneke-Reinders, M.; Mazur, A. - P.; Zyma, O.; Ramm, S. A.; Reinhold, K. (2020): Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;,74:(5):54</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haneke-Reinders, M., Mazur, A. - P., Zyma, O., Ramm, S. A., &amp;amp; Reinhold, K. (2020). Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;74&lt;/em&gt;(5), 54. doi:10.1007/s00265-020-02832-1&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Haneke-Reinders, M., et al., 2020. Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;, 74(5): 54.</harvard1>
<bio1>Haneke-Reinders M, Mazur A-P, Zyma O, Ramm SA, Reinhold K (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment.&lt;br /&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology 74(5): 54.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Haneke-Reinders, A. - P.  Mazur, O.  Zyma, S. A.  Ramm, and K.  Reinhold, “Disentangling a shared trait: male control over mate guarding duration revealed by a mate exchange experiment”, &lt;em&gt;Behavioral ecology and sociobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;74&lt;/em&gt;, : 54.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2943299</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-05-11T08:47:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-11-28T19:19:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>