<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2943008</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Klaus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weinhauer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">123884</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">93309060</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper elaborates steps towards an approach which can bring about new insights about the
racially coded street violence of July/August 1919 and about related problems in Chicago. Three
interrelated perspectives are integrated: the social construction of race and racism based on racial
projects, the triangular setting (perpetrator-victim-audience/third parties) of social conflict
(including race/racism) and violence, and the study of practices of comparing. In 1919 there was a
widely shared assumption of similarity (‘Gleichartigkeitsannahme’) which naturalized the difference
between two distinct races (‘white’ and ‘negro’). The racial projects studied in this paper
addressed different third parties/audiences. The press was no passive audience but an active third
party which communicated the often localized patterns of racism to translocal audiences. The
racial projects of the report of the Chicago Commission on Race Relations (CCRR) were shaped by
progressive comparisons which focused on urban-based social-political progress and on advanced
masculine rationality. The racial projects in Chicago were massively shaped by practices of comparing
which tried to bring order and stability to a society whose white members felt themselves
threatened through massive war-induced social change.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Das Arbeitspapier entwickelt erste Schritte für einen Ansatz, der neue Einsichten vermitteln kann
über die rassisch kodierte Straßengewalt in Chicago im Juli/August 1919 sowie über damit verbundene
Problemfelder. Verknüpft werden drei Perspektiven: die soziale Konstruktion von „race“ und
Rassismus durch dezentrale „racial projects“, das triadische Setting Täter-Opfer-Dritte/Publikum
sowie Vergleichspraktiken. 1919 gab es eine weithin geteilte Gleichartigkeitsannahme, durch die
Unterschiede zwischen zwei klar unterscheidbaren „Rassen“ (Weiße und Schwarze) naturalisiert
wurden. Die in vielen Gesellschaftsbereichen verankerten dezentralen „racial projects“ adressierten
ein weites Spektrum von lokalen bis hin zu translokalen Dritten/Publika. Die Presse, ein wichtiger
und aktiver Dritter, kein passives Publikum, kommunizierte und ergänzte die oft lokal begrenzten
rassistischen Muster an translokale Publika. Die im Bericht der Chicago Commission on
Race Relations (CCRR) formulierten „racial projects“ nutzten progressive Vergleiche, ausgerichtet
auf urban geprägten sozialen und politischen Fortschritt sowie auf fortschrittliche männliche Rationalität.
Die „racial projects“ in Chicago waren untrennbar verbunden mit Vergleichspraktiken.
Letztere sollten Ordnung und Stabilität in eine weiße städtische Gesellschaft bringen, die sich bedroht
fühlte durch weltkriegsinduzierten sozialen Wandel.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">**Ergänzender Hinweis zu den Creative Commons Lizenzen**&lt;br /&gt;"Creative Commons license terms for re-use do not apply to any content (such as graphs, figures, photos, excerpts, etc.) not original to the Open Access publication and further permission may be required from the rights holder. The obligation to research and clear permission lies solely with the party re-using the material."</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="WorkingPaper5_SFB1288.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2943008/2943382/WorkingPaper5_SFB1288.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2628-7722</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29430083</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2943008</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">28</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Weinhauer K (2020)  Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288; 5.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</default>
<bio1>Weinhauer K (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288; 5.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Weinhauer, &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Sfb 1288, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Weinhauer, K. (2020): Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</wels>
<frontiers>Weinhauer, K. (2020). Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919. &lt;em&gt;Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288&lt;/em&gt;, 5, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weinhauer, K. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 5). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943008&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Weinhauer, Klaus. &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, 2020. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. 5.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weinhauer, K. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943008.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Weinhauer, K. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt; (Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 5). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288. doi:10.4119/unibi/2943008</apa>
<lncs> Weinhauer, K.: Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, 5. Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Weinhauer, Klaus. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 5. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> K. Weinhauer, &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;, Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, vol. 5,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288, 2020.</ieee>
<harvard1>Weinhauer, K., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;, Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288, no.5, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288.</harvard1>
<ama>Weinhauer K. &lt;em&gt;Urban Order and Rationality: Racially Coded Street Violence, Racial Projects and Practices of Comparing in Chicago 1919&lt;/em&gt;. Practices of Comparing. Working Paper SFB 1288. Vol 5. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, SFB 1288; 2020.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2943008</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-04-29T11:00:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-17T10:05:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>