<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2944321</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Viola</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gräfe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">37120364</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Steffen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moritz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">152704</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21335</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">BACKGROUND: Depressive disorders often remain undiagnosed or are treated inadequately. Online-based programs may reduce the present treatment gap for depressive disorders and reduce disease-related costs. This study aimed to examine the potential of the internet intervention "deprexis" to reduce the total costs of statutory health insurance. Changes in depression severity, health-related quality of life and impairment in functioning were also examined.; METHOD: A total of 3805 participants with, at minimum, mild depressive symptoms were randomized to either a 12-week online intervention (deprexis) or a control condition. The primary outcome measure was statutory health insurance costs, estimated using health insurers' administrative data. Secondary outcomes were: depression severity, health-related quality of life, and impairment in functioning; assessed on patient's self-report at baseline, post-treatment, and three-months' and nine-months' follow-up.; RESULTS: In both groups, total costs of statutory health insurance decreased during the study period, but changes from baseline differed significantly. In the intervention group total costs decreased by 32% from 3139 per year at baseline to 2119 in the study year (vs. a mean reduction in total costs of 13% in the control group). In comparison to the control group, the intervention group also showed a significantly greater reduction in depression severity, and impairment in functioning and a significantly greater increase in health-related quality of life.; CONCLUSION: The study underlines the potential of innovative internet intervention programs in treating depressive disorders. The results suggest that the use of deprexis over a period of 12weeks leads to a significant improvement in symptoms with a simultaneous reduction in the costs of statutory health insurance. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s13561-020-00273-0.graefe.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2944321/2944355/s13561-020-00273-0.graefe.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>S</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Health economics review</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2191-1991</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32548724</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000540513600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29443214</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Gräfe, V., Moritz, S., &amp;amp; Greiner, W., 2020. Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;, 10: 19.</harvard1>
<ieee> V. Gräfe, S. Moritz, and W. Greiner, “Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.”, &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2020, : 19.</ieee>
<apa>Gräfe, V., Moritz, S., &amp;amp; Greiner, W. (2020). Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 19. doi:10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</apa>
<wels>Gräfe, V.; Moritz, S.; Greiner, W. (2020): Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;,10:19</wels>
<mla>Gräfe, Viola, Moritz, Steffen, and Greiner, Wolfgang. “Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.”. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt; 10 (2020): 19.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gräfe, V., Moritz, S., &amp;amp; Greiner, W. (2020). Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 19. doi:10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Gräfe, V., Moritz, S., and Greiner, W. (2020). Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt; 10:19.</frontiers>
<default>Gräfe V, Moritz S, Greiner W (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt; 10: 19.</default>
<ama>Gräfe V, Moritz S, Greiner W. Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;10: 19.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gräfe, Viola, Moritz, Steffen, and Greiner, Wolfgang. 2020. “Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.”. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt; 10: 19.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gräfe, V., Moritz, S., Greiner, W.: Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. Health economics review. 10, : 19 (2020).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gräfe, V., Moritz, S. &amp;amp; Greiner, W. (2020). Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;: 19. S. doi:10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Gräfe, S.  Moritz, and W.  Greiner, “Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.”, &lt;em&gt;Health economics review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 19.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Gräfe V, Moritz S, Greiner W (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.&lt;br /&gt;Health economics review 10: 19.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2944321</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-06-29T06:38:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-06T11:20:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>