<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2944679</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klegrewe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">145149323</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Unger</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Lattice methods are the essential tool to study QCD in its non-perturbative framework. At ﬁnite baryon densities, Monte Carlo simulations are most severely hindered by the sign problem. Thus, a ﬁnite density analysis of thermodynamic observables is limited, and the exploration of the QCD phase diagram via lattice QCD requires new ideas to tackle the sign problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Within the strong coupling limit of lattice QCD (SC-LQCD), a dual formulation is known which suﬀers only from a mild sign problem, allowing studies at ﬁnite baryon densities. Moreover, the continuous time framework is employed, which exhibits many assets compared to standard discrete time analysis such as a faster sampling of conﬁgurations, the avoidance of extrapolations in N τ as well as a smoother treatment of observables on anisotropic lattices. On top of that, its feature of having static baryons removes the sign problem completely.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The measurement of the critical temperature T c at µ B = 0 or the determination of physical quantities such as the pion decay constant F π directly in the continuous time limit signiﬁcantly removes uncertainties due to extrapolations in discrete time studies. The featured continuous time algorithm allows for a straightforward study of temporal correlators at zero and ﬁnite baryon density. Pole masses are extracted using correlated ﬁts and the temperature dependence is analyzed. A Taylor expansion in the pressure allows to compare the ﬁnite density phase transition with the radius of convergence. The temperature dependence of Taylor coeﬃcients is inspected and the pressure from ﬁnite density Monte Carlo simulations is reconstructed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The continuous time limit within the SC-LQCD framework turns out to be highly promising for future projects such as studies with multiple ﬂavors, at ﬁnite quark masses as well as at ﬁnite gauge coupling. Within the scope of this thesis, evidence is provided that the continuous time limit is well deﬁned and suited to study QCD thermodynamics. This is illustrated with various applications.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Thesis_MarcKlegrewe.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2944679/2944680/Thesis_MarcKlegrewe.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29446792</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2944679</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">165</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2020-07-09</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Klegrewe M. &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2020.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klegrewe, Marc. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Klegrewe, M.: Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klegrewe, M. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2944679.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Klegrewe M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Klegrewe, &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ieee> M. Klegrewe, &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2020.</ieee>
<harvard1>Klegrewe, M., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<apa>Klegrewe, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2944679</apa>
<wels>Klegrewe, M. (2020): Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Klegrewe, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2944679&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Klegrewe, M. (2020). Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<mla>Klegrewe, Marc. &lt;em&gt;Strong Coupling Lattice QCD in the Continuous Time Limit&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2020.</mla>
<default>Klegrewe M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2944679</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-14T22:29:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-27T08:53:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>