<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2944537</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kress</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">112667245</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Razum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">134970</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kim Alexandra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zolitschka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84388063</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Breckenkamp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">124680</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Odile</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sauzet</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">28472139</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21333</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background

Neighbourhood has risen as a relevant determinant of health. While there is substantial evidence that environmental factors affect health, far less evidence of the role of social mechanisms in the causal chain between neighbourhood characteristics and health is available.
Method

To evaluate the role of social cohesion as a mediator between four different neighbourhood characteristics and health using data from German Socio-Economic-Panel (SOEP), a longitudinal mediation analysis was performed. Multilevel linear regression models adjusted for socio-economic variables involved three time points and two measures of physical and mental health (physical and mental component scores (PCS and MCS) of the SF12 Questionnaire. Participants were followed-up for 4 and 10 year starting in 2004.
Results

A total of 15,518 measures of MCS and PCS on 10,013 participants living in 4985 households were included. After adjusting for values of MCS and PCS at baseline and demographic/socio-economic variables, social cohesion was a significant positive predictor of both MCS and PCS (β-coefficient MCS: 1.57 (0.27); PCS: 1.50 (0.24)). Interaction between social cohesion and follow-up were significant for PCS. The effect of environmental and built characteristics on health was consistently mediated by social cohesion with proportion varying between 10 and 23%.
Discussion

We show that social cohesion is part of the causal chain between environmental and built characteristics of a neighbourhood and health, with increasing mediation effect over time for physical health. Social mechanisms should be considered when studying the effect of neighbourhood characteristics on health inequalities making social cohesion as a legitimate target of public health interventions at neighbourhood level.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="s12889-020-09149-8.sauzet.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2944537/2944538/s12889-020-09149-8.sauzet.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Public Health</topic><topic>Environmental and Occupational Health</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1471-2458</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32611338</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000549938000002</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29445374</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-09149-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>20</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kress, S., Razum, O., Zolitschka, K.A., Breckenkamp, J. &amp;amp; Sauzet, O. (2020). Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;: 1043. Springer Nature. doi:10.1186/s12889-020-09149-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kress S, Razum O, Zolitschka KA, Breckenkamp J, Sauzet O (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Public Health 20: 1043.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kress, O.  Razum, K. A.  Zolitschka, J.  Breckenkamp, and O.  Sauzet, “Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;, : 1043.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Kress S, Razum O, Zolitschka KA, Breckenkamp J, Sauzet O. Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;20: 1043.</ama>
<lncs> Kress, S., Razum, O., Zolitschka, K.A., Breckenkamp, J., Sauzet, O.: Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. BMC Public Health. 20, : 1043 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kress, Sara, Razum, Oliver, Zolitschka, Kim Alexandra, Breckenkamp, Jürgen, and Sauzet, Odile. 2020. “Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 20: 1043.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Kress, S.; Razum, O.; Zolitschka, K. A.; Breckenkamp, J.; Sauzet, O. (2020): Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,20:1043</wels>
<frontiers>Kress, S., Razum, O., Zolitschka, K. A., Breckenkamp, J., and Sauzet, O. (2020). Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 20:1043.</frontiers>
<mla>Kress, Sara, Razum, Oliver, Zolitschka, Kim Alexandra, Breckenkamp, Jürgen, and Sauzet, Odile. “Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 20 (2020): 1043.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Kress, S., Razum, O., Zolitschka, K. A., Breckenkamp, J., &amp;amp; Sauzet, O. (2020). Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;, 1043. doi:10.1186/s12889-020-09149-8&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Kress S, Razum O, Zolitschka KA, Breckenkamp J, Sauzet O (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 20: 1043.</default>
<ieee> S. Kress, et al., “Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 20, 2020, : 1043.</ieee>
<harvard1>Kress, S., et al., 2020. Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 20: 1043.</harvard1>
<apa>Kress, S., Razum, O., Zolitschka, K. A., Breckenkamp, J., &amp;amp; Sauzet, O. (2020). Does social cohesion mediate neighbourhood effects on mental and physical health? Longitudinal analysis using German Socio-Economic Panel data. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt;, 1043. doi:10.1186/s12889-020-09149-8</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2944537</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-07T08:55:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-06T11:20:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>