<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945081</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Max</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nendel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">127338064</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maren Diane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84348951</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riedel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4244291</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4291-6610</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we provide an axiomatic approach to general premium
principles giving rise to a decomposition into risk, as a generalization of the expected
value, and deviation, as a generalization of the variance. We show that, for every premium
principle, there exists a maximal risk measure capturing all risky components
covered by the insurance prices. In a second step, we consider dual representations of
convex risk measures consistent with the premium principle. In particular, we show
that the convex conjugate of the aforementioned maximal risk measure coincides with
the convex conjugate of the premium principle on the set of all finitely additive probability
measures. In a last step, we consider insurance prices in the presence of a
not neccesarily frictionless market, where insurance claims are traded. In this setup,
we discuss premium principles that are consistent with hedging using securization
products that are traded in the market.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">AMS 2010 Subject Classification: 91B30; 91G20; 46A20</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_638_neu.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945081/2945082/IMW_working_paper_638_neu.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Principle of premium calculation</topic><topic>risk measure</topic><topic>deviation measure</topic><topic>convex duality</topic><topic>superhedging</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29450810</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>638</number></detail><extent unit="pages">18</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Nendel M, Schmeck MD, Riedel F. &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 638 aktual. Version July 2020. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2020.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, M., Schmeck, M.D. &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers) (aktual. Version July 2020.). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Nendel, M., Schmeck, M. D., and Riedel, F. (2020). Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 638, aktual. Version July 2020. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Nendel, M., Schmeck, M. D., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 638) aktual. Version July 2020. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> M. Nendel, M.D. Schmeck, and F. Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 638, aktual. Version July 2020.,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2020.</ieee>
<wels>Nendel, M.; Schmeck, M. D.; Riedel, F. (2020): Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation. aktual. Version July 2020.  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, M., Schmeck, M. D., &amp;amp; Riedel, F. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 638) aktual. Version July 2020. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Nendel M, Schmeck MD, Riedel F (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 638, aktual. Version July 2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Nendel, M., Schmeck, M.D., &amp;amp; Riedel, F., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.638, aktual. Version July 2020., Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Nendel, M. D.  Schmeck, and F.  Riedel, &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Nendel, M., Schmeck, M.D., Riedel, F.: Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 638, aktual. Version July 2020. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Nendel, Max, Schmeck, Maren Diane, and Riedel, Frank. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;. aktual. Version July 2020. Vol. 638. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Nendel, Max, Schmeck, Maren Diane, and Riedel, Frank. &lt;em&gt;Decomposition of General Premium Principles into Risk and Deviation&lt;/em&gt;. aktual. Version July 2020. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2020. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 638.</mla>
<default>Nendel M, Schmeck MD, Riedel F (2020)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 638, aktual. Version July 2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945081</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-31T08:56:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>