<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945969</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Chloe Charlotte</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schröder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hasselhorn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jean-Baptist</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">du Prel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Breckenkamp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">124680</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21333</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study was to investigate the subjective employment perspective in higher working age for different employee groups with migrant background (EMB) and without (non-EMB), meaning willing, being able, and planning to work until the individual state pension age (iSPA).; METHODS: A representative sample of socially insured employees born in 1959 or 1965 was surveyed in 2011, 2014, and 2018 with computer-assisted personal interviews. The current cross-sectional analysis is based on data from the third study wave (n=3286) of the lidA cohort study. EMB were differentiated via generation (first generation, G1, vs second generation, G2) or nationality (German vs foreign). Applying bivariate statistics with the tests of independence and block-wise logistic regressions, group differences were investigated. Sex, age, educational level, net household income, health, and work factors were considered as covariates.; RESULTS: When comparing subgroups of EMB, significant differences appeared in bivariate analyses for willing and planning to work. G1 were to a higher degree planning to work longer than G2 and those with foreign nationality were more willing and planning than those with German nationality. Multivariate analyses revealed significant differences of G1 and non-EMB for planning, being significant in the fully adjusted model, but not for willing.; CONCLUSION: The findings underline the need for differentiation of migrant groups in social research and policy. When it comes to extended working lives, the first-generation migrant group, as well as foreigners may constitute risk groups and require increased attention from a work, health, and economic point of view. © 2020 The Authors. Journal of Occupational Health published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of The Japan Society for Occupational Health.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="JOH2_JOH212166.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945969/2949644/JOH2_JOH212166.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Occupational Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1348-9585</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32906224</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000590193500049</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29459699</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/1348-9585.12166</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>62</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Schröder, C.C., Hasselhorn, H.M., du Prel, J.-B., Breckenkamp, J.: Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. Journal of Occupational Health. 62, : e12166 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schröder, Chloe Charlotte, Hasselhorn, Hans Martin, du Prel, Jean-Baptist, and Breckenkamp, Jürgen. 2020. “Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt; 62 (1): e12166.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Schröder CC, Hasselhorn HM, du Prel J-B, Breckenkamp J. Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;62(1): e12166.</ama>
<bio1>Schröder CC, Hasselhorn HM, du Prel J-B, Breckenkamp J (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Occupational Health 62(1): e12166.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C. C.  Schröder, H. M.  Hasselhorn, J. - B.  du Prel, and J.  Breckenkamp, “Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;, : e12166.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schröder, C.C., Hasselhorn, H.M., du Prel, J.-B. &amp;amp; Breckenkamp, J. (2020). Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;(1): e12166. Wiley. doi:10.1002/1348-9585.12166.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Schröder, C. C., Hasselhorn, H. M., du Prel, J. - B., &amp;amp; Breckenkamp, J. (2020). Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;(1), e12166. doi:10.1002/1348-9585.12166</apa>
<ieee> C.C. Schröder, et al., “Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 62, 2020, : e12166.</ieee>
<harvard1>Schröder, C.C., et al., 2020. Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;, 62(1): e12166.</harvard1>
<default>Schröder CC, Hasselhorn HM, du Prel J-B, Breckenkamp J (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt; 62(1): e12166.</default>
<wels>Schröder, C. C.; Hasselhorn, H. M.; du Prel, J. - B.; Breckenkamp, J. (2020): Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;,62:(1):e12166</wels>
<mla>Schröder, Chloe Charlotte, Hasselhorn, Hans Martin, du Prel, Jean-Baptist, and Breckenkamp, Jürgen. “Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt; 62.1 (2020): e12166.</mla>
<frontiers>Schröder, C. C., Hasselhorn, H. M., du Prel, J. - B., and Breckenkamp, J. (2020). Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt; 62:e12166.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schröder, C. C., Hasselhorn, H. M., du Prel, J. - B., &amp;amp; Breckenkamp, J. (2020). Subjective employment perspective among older workers with and without migrant background in Germany-Results of the lidA cohort study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Occupational Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;(1), e12166. doi:10.1002/1348-9585.12166&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945969</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-21T09:52:25Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-22T15:36:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>