<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945542</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>From Geometries to Contact Graphs</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6564614</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">33056</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5842-9991</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">91130</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Igor</namePart><namePart type="family">Farkas</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Paolo</namePart><namePart type="family">Masulli</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart><namePart type="family">Wermter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10038</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">When a robot perceives its environment, it is not only important to know what kind of objects are present in it, but also
how they relate to each other. For example in a cleanup task in a cluttered environment, a sensible 
strategy is to pick the objects with the least contacts to other objects first, to minimize the chance of unwanted
movements not related to the current picking action. Estimating object contacts
in cluttered scenes only based on passive observation is a complex problem.
To tackle this problem, we present a deep neural network that learns physically stable object relations directly
from geometric features. The learned relations are encoded as contact graphs between the objects. To facilitate
training of the network, we generated a rich, publicly available dataset consisting of more than 25000 unique contact scenes,
by utilizing a physics simulation. Different deep architectures have been evaluated and the final
architecture, which shows good results in reconstructing contact graphs, is evaluated quantitatively and qualitatively.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="icann2020.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945542/2950675/icann2020.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Bratislava, Slovakia</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-030-61615-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29455427</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-61616-8_44</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12397</number></detail><extent unit="pages">546-555</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Meier, M., Haschke, R., Ritter, H.: From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In: Farkas, I., Masulli, P., and Wermter, S. (eds.) Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 12397, p. 546-555. Springer, Cham (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, Martin, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. 2020. “From Geometries to Contact Graphs”. In &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Igor Farkas, Paolo Masulli, and Stefan Wermter, 12397:546-555. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Meier, Martin, Haschke, Robert, and Ritter, Helge. “From Geometries to Contact Graphs”. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Igor Farkas, Paolo Masulli, and Stefan Wermter. Cham: Springer, 2020.Vol. 12397. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. 546-555.</mla>
<default>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H (2020)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II. Farkas I, Masulli P, Wermter S (Eds);  Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 12397.  Cham: Springer:  546-555.</default>
<ama>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H. From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In: Farkas I, Masulli P, Wermter S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Vol 12397. Cham: Springer;  2020: 546-555.</ama>
<frontiers>Meier, M., Haschke, R., and Ritter, H. (2020). “From Geometries to Contact Graphs” in &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;, Farkas, I., Masulli, P., and Wermter, S. eds. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 12397, (Cham: Springer), 546-555.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, M., Haschke, R. &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2020). From Geometries to Contact Graphs (Lecture Notes in Computer Science). In I. Farkas, P. Masulli &amp;amp; S. Wermter (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt; (S. 546-555). Gehalten auf der International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks, Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-61616-8_44.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2020). From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In I.  Farkas, P.  Masulli, &amp;amp; S.  Wermter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 12397&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 546-555). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-61616-8_44</apa>
<ieee> M. Meier, R. Haschke, and H. Ritter, “From Geometries to Contact Graphs”, &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;, I. Farkas, P. Masulli, and S. Wermter, eds., Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 12397,  Cham: Springer, 2020,  pp.546-555.</ieee>
<wels>Meier, M.; Haschke, R.; Ritter, H. (2020): From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In: Igor Farkas; Paolo Masulli; Stefan Wermter (Hrsg.):  Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II. Cham: Springer. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 12397).  S. 546-555.</wels>
<harvard1>Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H., 2020. From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In I.  Farkas, P.  Masulli, &amp;amp; S.  Wermter, eds. &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt;. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. no.12397  Cham: Springer, pp. 546-555.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Meier, M., Haschke, R., &amp;amp; Ritter, H. (2020). From Geometries to Contact Graphs. In I.  Farkas, P.  Masulli, &amp;amp; S.  Wermter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Vol. 12397&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 546-555). Cham: Springer. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-61616-8_44&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Meier M, Haschke R, Ritter H (2020) &lt;br /&gt;From Geometries to Contact Graphs. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II. Farkas I, Masulli P, Wermter S (Eds); Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 12397. Cham: Springer:  546-555.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Meier, R.  Haschke, and H.  Ritter, in &lt;em&gt;Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2020. Proceedings. Part II&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Farkas, P. Masulli, S. Wermter), Springer, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 546-555.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945542</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-08-24T13:34:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-02T08:57:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>