<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945874</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Judith</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huget</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">808248e5-8187-495b-9b15-e33c4b309720</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9678-8562</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Peter-Koop</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23032347</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Uffe Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Jankvist</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marja</namePart><namePart type="family">van den Heuvel-Panhuizen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michiel</namePart><namePart type="family">Veldhuis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>11th Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="TWG19_14.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945874/2945875/TWG19_14.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Freudenthal Group &amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Utrecht, Netherlands</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Teacher Learning</topic><topic>Teacher Attention</topic><topic>Teacher Knowledge</topic><topic>Mixed Methods</topic><topic>International Comparison</topic><topic>Mathematics Lessons</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-90-73346-75-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29458747</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Huget, J., &amp;amp; Peter-Koop, A. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, Judith, and Peter-Koop, Andrea. 2019. “Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Uffe Thomas Jankvist, Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and Michiel Veldhuis. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Huget, J., Peter-Koop, A.: Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In: Jankvist, U.T., van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M., and Veldhuis, M. (eds.) Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11).  Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., Utrecht (2019).</lncs>
<harvard1>Huget, J., &amp;amp; Peter-Koop, A., 2019. Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;.  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Huget and A. Peter-Koop, “Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and M. Veldhuis, eds.,  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., 2019.</ieee>
<ama>Huget J, Peter-Koop A. Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In: Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.;  2019.</ama>
<default>Huget J, Peter-Koop A (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M (Eds);  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Huget, and A.  Peter-Koop, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M. Veldhuis), Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University And Erme., Utrecht, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Huget J, Peter-Koop A (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M (Eds); Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</bio1>
<wels>Huget, J.; Peter-Koop, A. (2019): Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In: Uffe Thomas Jankvist; Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen; Michiel Veldhuis (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J. &amp;amp; Peter-Koop, A. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen &amp;amp; M. Veldhuis (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 11th Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education, Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J., &amp;amp; Peter-Koop, A. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study. In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Huget, J., and Peter-Koop, A. (2019). “Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, Jankvist, U. T., van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M., and Veldhuis, M. eds. (Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.).</frontiers>
<mla>Huget, Judith, and Peter-Koop, Andrea. “Learning from Lessons: A study on structure and construction of mathematics teacher knowledge – First results of case study”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Uffe Thomas Jankvist, Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and Michiel Veldhuis. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., 2019.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945874</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-15T12:53:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-21T10:17:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>