<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945867</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education </title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Judith</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huget</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">808248e5-8187-495b-9b15-e33c4b309720</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9678-8562</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Uffe Thomas</namePart><namePart type="family">Jankvist</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Marja</namePart><namePart type="family">van den Heuvel-Panhuizen</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Michiel</namePart><namePart type="family">Veldhuis</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>11th Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The importance of probability increased in German teacher education in the last decades. However, research about the professional knowledge of (prospective) teachers focused on other content such as number theory and functions rather than probability. The project “The development of professional knowledge of prospective teachers in probability” aims at developing a test in order to measure teacher knowledge in probability. In order to measure content knowledge and pedagogical knowledge in this domain, one has to identify categories, concepts and ideas and connections between. This paper shows the development of a domain map, which indicates categories, concepts and ideas. The theoretical framework, the procedure of developing and an outlook is given.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="TWG05_16.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945867/2945868/TWG05_16.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Freudenthal Group &amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Utrecht, Netherlands</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Mathematics education</topic><topic>mathematics teachers</topic><topic>teacher competencies</topic><topic>teacher competency test</topic><topic>probability</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-90-73346-75-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29458671</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Huget J (2019) &lt;br /&gt;The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M (Eds); Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Huget, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M. Veldhuis), Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University And Erme., Utrecht, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Huget J (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M (Eds);  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J. (2019). The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Huget, J. (2019). “The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education ” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, Jankvist, U. T., van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M., and Veldhuis, M. eds. (Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.).</frontiers>
<mla>Huget, Judith. “The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education ”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Uffe Thomas Jankvist, Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and Michiel Veldhuis. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., 2019.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J. (2019). The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen &amp;amp; M. Veldhuis (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Gehalten auf der 11th Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education, Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Huget, J. (2019): The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In: Uffe Thomas Jankvist; Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen; Michiel Veldhuis (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11). Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</wels>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, Judith. 2019. “The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education ”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Uffe Thomas Jankvist, Marja van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and Michiel Veldhuis. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Huget, J.: The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In: Jankvist, U.T., van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, M., and Veldhuis, M. (eds.) Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11).  Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., Utrecht (2019).</lncs>
<apa>Huget, J. (2019). The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt; Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</apa>
<ama>Huget J. The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In: Jankvist UT, van den Heuvel-Panhuizen M, Veldhuis M, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;. Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.;  2019.</ama>
<ieee> J. Huget, “The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education ”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;, U.T. Jankvist, M. van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, and M. Veldhuis, eds.,  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME., 2019.</ieee>
<harvard1>Huget, J., 2019. The development of a domain map in probability for teacher education . In U. T.  Jankvist, M.  van den Heuvel-Panhuizen, &amp;amp; M.  Veldhuis, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Eleventh Congress of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME11)&lt;/em&gt;.  Utrecht: Freudenthal Group &amp;amp; Freudenthal Institute, Utrecht University and ERME.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945867</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-15T11:56:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-21T10:18:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>