<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2945026</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadja Alina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Henke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">62867163</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sophie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Austermeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabell L.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grothaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Susanne</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Götker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5152649</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcus</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Persicke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">177004</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Peters-Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15371738</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Carotenoid biosynthesis in Corynebacteriumglutamicum is controlled by the MarR-type regulator CrtR, which represses transcription of the promoter of the crt operon (PcrtE) and of its own gene (PcrtR). Geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate (GGPP), and to a lesser extent other isoprenoid pyrophosphates, interfere with the binding of CrtR to its target DNA in vitro, suggesting they act as inducers of carotenoid biosynthesis. CrtR homologs are encoded in the genomes of many other actinobacteria. In order to determine if and to what extent the function of CrtR, as a metabolite-dependent transcriptional repressor of carotenoid biosynthesis genes responding to GGPP, is conserved among actinobacteria, five CrtR orthologs were characterized in more detail. EMSA assays showed that the CrtR orthologs from Corynebacteriumcallunae, Acidipropionibacteriumjensenii, Paenarthrobacternicotinovorans, Micrococcusluteus and Pseudarthrobacterchlorophenolicus bound to the intergenic region between their own gene and the divergently oriented gene, and that GGPP inhibited these interactions. In turn, the CrtR protein from C. glutamicum bound to DNA regions upstream of the orthologous crtR genes that contained a 15 bp DNA sequence motif conserved between the tested bacteria. Moreover, the CrtR orthologs functioned in C. glutamicum in vivo at least partially, as they complemented the defects in the pigmentation and expression of a PcrtE_gfpuv transcriptional fusion that were observed in a crtR deletion mutant to varying degrees. Subsequently, the utility of the PcrtE_gfpuv transcriptional fusion and chromosomally encoded CrtR from C. glutamicum as genetically encoded biosensor for GGPP was studied. Combined FACS and LC-MS analysis demonstrated a correlation between the sensor fluorescent signal and the intracellular GGPP concentration, and allowed us to monitor intracellular GGPP concentrations during growth and differentiate between strains engineered to accumulate GGPP at different concentrations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijms-21-05482.wendisch.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2945026/2945220/ijms-21-05482.wendisch.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>C. glutamicum</topic><topic>regulation of carotenogenesis</topic><topic>GGPP</topic><topic>biosensor</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Molecular Sciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1422-0067</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32751941</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000559124400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29450267</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijms21155482</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>21</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>15</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henke, Nadja Alina, Austermeier, Sophie, Grothaus, Isabell L., Götker, Susanne, Persicke, Marcus, Peters-Wendisch, Petra, and Wendisch, Volker F. 2020. “Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 21 (15): 5482.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Henke, N.A., Austermeier, S., Grothaus, I.L., Götker, S., Persicke, M., Peters-Wendisch, P., Wendisch, V.F.: Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 21, : 5482 (2020).</lncs>
<default>Henke NA, Austermeier S, Grothaus IL, Götker S, Persicke M, Peters-Wendisch P, Wendisch VF (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 21(15): 5482.</default>
<mla>Henke, Nadja Alina, Austermeier, Sophie, Grothaus, Isabell L., Götker, Susanne, Persicke, Marcus, Peters-Wendisch, Petra, and Wendisch, Volker F. “Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 21.15 (2020): 5482.</mla>
<frontiers>Henke, N. A., Austermeier, S., Grothaus, I. L., Götker, S., Persicke, M., Peters-Wendisch, P., and Wendisch, V. F. (2020). Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 21:5482.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henke, N.A., Austermeier, S., Grothaus, I.L., Götker, S., Persicke, M., Peters-Wendisch, P. &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F. (2020). Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(15): 5482. MDPI. doi:10.3390/ijms21155482.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Henke NA, Austermeier S, Grothaus IL, et al. Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;21(15): 5482.</ama>
<ieee> N.A. Henke, et al., “Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 21, 2020, : 5482.</ieee>
<apa>Henke, N. A., Austermeier, S., Grothaus, I. L., Götker, S., Persicke, M., Peters-Wendisch, P., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2020). Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(15), 5482. doi:10.3390/ijms21155482</apa>
<wels>Henke, N. A.; Austermeier, S.; Grothaus, I. L.; Götker, S.; Persicke, M.; Peters-Wendisch, P.; Wendisch, V. F. (2020): Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,21:(15):5482</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>N. A.  Henke, S.  Austermeier, I. L.  Grothaus, S.  Götker, M.  Persicke, P.  Peters-Wendisch, and V. F.  Wendisch, “Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;, : 5482.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Henke NA, Austermeier S, Grothaus IL, Götker S, Persicke M, Peters-Wendisch P, Wendisch VF (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences 21(15): 5482.</bio1>
<harvard1>Henke, N.A., et al., 2020. Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 21(15): 5482.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henke, N. A., Austermeier, S., Grothaus, I. L., Götker, S., Persicke, M., Peters-Wendisch, P., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2020). Corynebacterium glutamicum CrtR and its orthologs in actinobacteria: conserved function and application as genetically encoded biosensor for detection of geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(15), 5482. doi:10.3390/ijms21155482&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2945026</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-07-29T05:20:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-18T13:57:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>