<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2946063</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:900</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz-Josef</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arlinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">171789</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alessandro</namePart><namePart type="family">Arcangeli</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jörg</namePart><namePart type="family">Rogge</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Hannu</namePart><namePart type="family">Salmi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791087</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">During the centuries we focus on here, people communicated in very refined and highly differentiated ways. Therefore the chapter not only tries to focus on literacy, orality, messengers and rituals, but also attempts to shed light on how a combination of these elements in a given situation worked. The objective is to modify the motion that rituals are irrational and literacy means rationalization. Rituals are increasingly seen as an expression of clever political moves, and charters, books and the reading of texts portrayed as ritualized performances. While dichotomies seem to vanish and teleological narrative is discredited, despite long and intense research efforts, the relationship between rituals, literacy and medieval society is still a story ending with ‘to be continued’.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Arlinghaus_Practices_of_communication.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2946063/2954595/Arlinghaus_Practices_of_communication.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Routledge</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>ritual</topic><topic>literacy</topic><topic>orality</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-138-64946-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29460636</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4324/9781003080206</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">96-110</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> F.-J. Arlinghaus, “Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication”, &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;, A. Arcangeli, J. Rogge, and H. Salmi, eds.,  London: Routledge, 2020,  pp.96-110.</ieee>
<apa>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2020). Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In A.  Arcangeli, J.  Rogge, &amp;amp; H.  Salmi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 96-110). London: Routledge. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003080206" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003080206&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<frontiers>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2020). “Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication” in &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;, Arcangeli, A., Rogge, J., and Salmi, H. eds. (London: Routledge), 96-110.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F.-J. (2020). Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In A. Arcangeli, J. Rogge &amp;amp; H. Salmi (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt; (S. 96-110). London: Routledge. doi:10.4324/9781003080206.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Arlinghaus F-J. Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In: Arcangeli A, Rogge J, Salmi H, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;. London: Routledge;  2020: 96-110.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>F. - J.  Arlinghaus, in &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: A. Arcangeli, J. Rogge, H. Salmi), Routledge, London, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 96-110.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Arlinghaus F-J (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World. Arcangeli A, Rogge J, Salmi H (Eds); London: Routledge:  96-110.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2020). Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In A.  Arcangeli, J.  Rogge, &amp;amp; H.  Salmi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 96-110). London: Routledge. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003080206" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003080206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Arlinghaus, F.-J., 2020. Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In A.  Arcangeli, J.  Rogge, &amp;amp; H.  Salmi, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;.  London: Routledge, pp. 96-110.</harvard1>
<wels>Arlinghaus, F. - J. (2020): Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In: Alessandro Arcangeli; Jörg Rogge; Hannu Salmi (Hrsg.):  The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World. London: Routledge.  S. 96-110.</wels>
<default>Arlinghaus F-J (2020)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World. Arcangeli A, Rogge J, Salmi H (Eds);  London: Routledge:  96-110.</default>
<mla>Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. “Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication”. &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Alessandro Arcangeli, Jörg Rogge, and Hannu Salmi. London: Routledge, 2020. 96-110.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Arlinghaus, Franz-Josef. 2020. “Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication”. In &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Alessandro Arcangeli, Jörg Rogge, and Hannu Salmi, 96-110. London: Routledge.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Arlinghaus, F.-J.: Practices Of Communication. Literacy, gestures and words: research on late medieval communication. In: Arcangeli, A., Rogge, J., and Salmi, H. (eds.) The Routledge Companion to Cultural History in the Western World. p. 96-110. Routledge, London (2020).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2946063</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-09-24T10:40:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-06T17:51:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>