<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2946275</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nora Dalia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gottlieb</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">234956215</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9199-2321</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Conny</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Püschmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stenzinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koelber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Laurette</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rasch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Martha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koppelow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Razan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Al Munjid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: LGBTIQ asylum-seekers face multiple health risks. Yet, little is known about their healthcare needs. In 2016, Berlin opened the only major shelter for LGBTIQ asylum-seekers in Germany. This preliminary study describes health and healthcare utilization by asylum-seekers living in Berlin’s LGBTIQ shelter. To identify particular healthcare needs, we compared our results to asylum-seekers from other shelters.&lt;br&gt;
 
Methods: We surveyed residents of the LGBTIQ shelter and 21 randomly selected shelters in Berlin, using a validated questionnaire in nine languages (n = 309 respondents, including 32 respondents from the LGBTIQ shelter). Bivariate tests and generalized linear mixed models were applied to examine differences in health and healthcare utilization between the two groups. &lt;br&gt;

Results: Residents of the LGBTIQ shelter show high rates of chronic and mental illness. They use ambulatory and mental health services more frequently than asylum-seekers from other shelters, including a significantly higher chance of obtaining psychotherapy/psychiatric care in case of need. Emergency room utilization is also higher in the LGBTIQ group. &lt;br&gt;

Conclusions: Asylum-seekers from the LGBTIQ shelter face high chronic and mental health burdens. Tailored services in the LGBTIQ shelter help obtain adequate healthcare; they should be scaled up to maximize their potential. Yet, unmet needs remain and warrant further research.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Gottlieb et al_Health and healthcare LGBTIQ asylum-seekers Berlin.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2946275/2946276/Gottlieb et al_Health and healthcare LGBTIQ asylum-seekers Berlin.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>asylum-seekers</topic><topic>refugees</topic><topic>LGBTIQ</topic><topic>healthcare utilization</topic><topic>Germany</topic><topic>mental health</topic><topic>chronic illness</topic><topic>intersectionality</topic><topic>cross-sectional survey</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">32585992</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000554698800001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29462753</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph17124514</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>17</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gottlieb, N.D., Püschmann, C., Stenzinger, F., Koelber, J., Rasch, L., Koppelow, M. &amp;amp; Al Munjid, R. (2020). Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(12): 4514. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph17124514.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>N. D.  Gottlieb, C.  Püschmann, F.  Stenzinger, J.  Koelber, L.  Rasch, M.  Koppelow, and R.  Al Munjid, “Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;, : 4514.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Gottlieb ND, Püschmann C, Stenzinger F, Koelber J, Rasch L, Koppelow M, Al Munjid R (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17(12): 4514.</bio1>
<ama>Gottlieb ND, Püschmann C, Stenzinger F, et al. Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;17(12): 4514.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gottlieb, Nora Dalia, Püschmann, Conny, Stenzinger, Fabian, Koelber, Julia, Rasch, Laurette, Koppelow, Martha, and Al Munjid, Razan. 2020. “Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17 (12): 4514.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gottlieb, N.D., Püschmann, C., Stenzinger, F., Koelber, J., Rasch, L., Koppelow, M., Al Munjid, R.: Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 17, : 4514 (2020).</lncs>
<mla>Gottlieb, Nora Dalia, Püschmann, Conny, Stenzinger, Fabian, Koelber, Julia, Rasch, Laurette, Koppelow, Martha, and Al Munjid, Razan. “Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17.12 (2020): 4514.</mla>
<frontiers>Gottlieb, N. D., Püschmann, C., Stenzinger, F., Koelber, J., Rasch, L., Koppelow, M., and Al Munjid, R. (2020). Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17:4514.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gottlieb, N. D., Püschmann, C., Stenzinger, F., Koelber, J., Rasch, L., Koppelow, M., &amp;amp; Al Munjid, R. (2020). Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(12), 4514. doi:10.3390/ijerph17124514&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Gottlieb, N. D.; Püschmann, C.; Stenzinger, F.; Koelber, J.; Rasch, L.; Koppelow, M.; Al Munjid, R. (2020): Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,17:(12):4514</wels>
<default>Gottlieb ND, Püschmann C, Stenzinger F, Koelber J, Rasch L, Koppelow M, Al Munjid R (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 17(12): 4514.</default>
<harvard1>Gottlieb, N.D., et al., 2020. Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 17(12): 4514.</harvard1>
<ieee> N.D. Gottlieb, et al., “Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 17, 2020, : 4514.</ieee>
<apa>Gottlieb, N. D., Püschmann, C., Stenzinger, F., Koelber, J., Rasch, L., Koppelow, M., &amp;amp; Al Munjid, R. (2020). Health and Healthcare Utilization among Asylum-Seekers from Berlin’s LGBTIQ Shelter: Preliminary Results of a Survey. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(12), 4514. doi:10.3390/ijerph17124514</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2946275</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-01T10:40:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-10-05T10:52:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>