<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2949317</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">epub_ahead</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Abitaev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Yaseen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Qawasmi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Atanasova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dargel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bill</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">19511146</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2394-5846</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sottmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17981</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The manifold applications of porous materials, such as in storage, separation, and catalysis, have led to an enormous interest in their cost-efficient preparation. A promising strategy to obtain porous materials with adjustable pore size and morphology is to use templates exhibiting the appropriate nanostructure. In this study, close-packed polystyrene (PS) nanoparticles, synthesized by emulsion polymerization, were used to produce porous PS and ZnO inverse opals. The size and distribution of the polystyrene nanoparticles, characterized by dynamic light scattering (DLS), small-angle neutron scattering (SANS), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), were controlled via the concentration of sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS). Systematic measurements of the water/styrene-interfacial tension show that the critical micelle concentration (CMC) of the ternary water–styrene–SDS system, which determines whether monodisperse or polydisperse PS particles are obtained, is considerably lower than that of the binary water–SDS system. The assemblies of close-packed PS nanoparticles obtained via drying were then studied by small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) and SEM. Both techniques prove that PS nanoparticles synthesized above the CMC result in a significantly unordered but denser packing of the particles. The polystyrene particles were subsequently used to produce porous polystyrene and ZnO inverse opals. While the former consists of micrometer-sized spherical pores surrounded by extended open-cellular regions of mesopores (Rpore ≈ 25 nm), the latter are made of ZnO-nanoparticles forming a structure of well-aligned interconnected pores.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Abitaev2020_Article_AdjustablePolystyreneNanoparti.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2949317/2949318/Abitaev2020_Article_AdjustablePolystyreneNanoparti.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Colloid and Polymer Science</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0303-402X</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1435-1536</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000599042600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29493175</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s00396-020-04791-5</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Abitaev K, Qawasmi Y, Atanasova P, Dargel C, Bill J, Hellweg T, Sottmann T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;.</default>
<wels>Abitaev, K.; Qawasmi, Y.; Atanasova, P.; Dargel, C.; Bill, J.; Hellweg, T.; Sottmann, T. (2020): Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;</wels>
<mla>Abitaev, Karina, Qawasmi, Yaseen, Atanasova, Petia, Dargel, Carina, Bill, Joachim, Hellweg, Thomas, and Sottmann, Thomas. “Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals”. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt; (2020).</mla>
<frontiers>Abitaev, K., Qawasmi, Y., Atanasova, P., Dargel, C., Bill, J., Hellweg, T., and Sottmann, T. (2020). Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abitaev, K., Qawasmi, Y., Atanasova, P., Dargel, C., Bill, J., Hellweg, T., &amp;amp; Sottmann, T. (2020). Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1007/s00396-020-04791-5&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Abitaev, K., Qawasmi, Y., Atanasova, P., Dargel, C., Bill, J., Hellweg, T., &amp;amp; Sottmann, T. (2020). Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1007/s00396-020-04791-5</apa>
<ieee> K. Abitaev, et al., “Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals”, &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;, 2020.</ieee>
<harvard1>Abitaev, K., et al., 2020. Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<bio1>Abitaev K, Qawasmi Y, Atanasova P, Dargel C, Bill J, Hellweg T, Sottmann T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals.&lt;br /&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Abitaev, Y.  Qawasmi, P.  Atanasova, C.  Dargel, J.  Bill, T.  Hellweg, and T.  Sottmann, “Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals”, &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abitaev, K., Qawasmi, Y., Atanasova, P., Dargel, C., Bill, J., Hellweg, T. &amp;amp; Sottmann, T. (2020). Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;. Springer. doi:10.1007/s00396-020-04791-5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Abitaev, K., Qawasmi, Y., Atanasova, P., Dargel, C., Bill, J., Hellweg, T., Sottmann, T.: Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. Colloid and Polymer Science. (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Abitaev, Karina, Qawasmi, Yaseen, Atanasova, Petia, Dargel, Carina, Bill, Joachim, Hellweg, Thomas, and Sottmann, Thomas. 2020. “Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals”. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Abitaev K, Qawasmi Y, Atanasova P, et al. Adjustable polystyrene nanoparticle templatesfor the production of mesoporous foams and ZnO inverse opals. &lt;em&gt;Colloid and Polymer Science&lt;/em&gt;. 2020.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2949317</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-10T10:12:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-11T12:24:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>