<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2949117</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:796</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Strenge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">63941258</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1789-6977</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koester</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11021779</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3940-8559</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">The interdisciplinary research area Cognitive Interaction Technology (CIT) aims to understand and support interactions between human users and other elements of socio-technical systems. Important reasons for the new interest in understanding CIT in sport psychology are the impressive development of cognitive robotics and advanced technologies such as virtual or augmented reality systems, cognitive glasses or neurotechnology settings. The present article outlines this area of research, addresses ethical issues, and presents an empirical study in the context of a new measurement and assessment system for training in karate. Recent advances in the field of cognitive assistance systems enabled largely automatized assessments of individual mental representation structures for action sequences, such as choreographed movement patterns in dance or martial arts. Empirical investigations with karate practitioners of different skill levels demonstrate that advanced software-based survey and algorithmic analysis procedures based on cognitive models generate individualized performance predictions for a movement sequence from the Kanku-dai kata (a pre-defined karate movement sequence), which correlated significantly not only with formal expertise (kyu/dan rank) but also with the actual likelihood of mistakes in action execution. This information could prospectively be used to define individual training goals for deliberate practice and incorporated into cognitive interaction technology to provide appropriate feedback. We argue that the development of cognitive interaction systems for sport should explicitly take ethical issues into consideration and present a particular developed engineering approach. The potential benefits of such an assistance system for intermediate and advanced practitioners include more effective and flexible practice, as well as supportive effects, and more flexible training schedules. Furthermore, we argue that researchers from the field of sport psychology can benefit from advances in technological systems that enhance the understanding of mental and motor control in skilled voluntary action.
1. Introduction</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpsyg-11-597913.strenge.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2949117/2949808/fpsyg-11-597913.strenge.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33408668</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000604295400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29491174</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Strenge B, Koester D, Schack T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 3641.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Strenge, B., Koester, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2020). Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 3641. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Strenge, Benjamin, Koester, Dirk, and Schack, Thomas. “Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 11 (2020): 3641.</mla>
<frontiers>Strenge, B., Koester, D., and Schack, T. (2020). Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 11:3641.</frontiers>
<wels>Strenge, B.; Koester, D.; Schack, T. (2020): Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,11:3641</wels>
<apa>Strenge, B., Koester, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2020). Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 3641. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Strenge, B., Koester, D., &amp;amp; Schack, T., 2020. Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 11: 3641.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Strenge, D. Koester, and T. Schack, “Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2020, : 3641.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Strenge, D.  Koester, and T.  Schack, “Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, : 3641.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Strenge B, Koester D, Schack T (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Psychology 11: 3641.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Strenge, B., Koester, D. &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2020). Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;: 3641. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2020.597913.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Strenge, B., Koester, D., Schack, T.: Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. Frontiers in Psychology. 11, : 3641 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Strenge, Benjamin, Koester, Dirk, and Schack, Thomas. 2020. “Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 3641.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Strenge B, Koester D, Schack T. Cognitive Interaction Technology in Sport - Improving Performance by Individualized Diagnostics and Error Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;11: 3641.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2949117</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-01T14:48:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-05T11:02:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>