<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2949200</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Beeinflusst die Mediennutzung vor dem Zubettgehen den Schlaf bei Patienten der psychosomatischen Rehabilitation?</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jasmin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Faber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">61231459</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Indra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steinbrecher-Hocke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bommersbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Angelika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlarb</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">46110571</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33700</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objective

Media use can affect sleep. However, research regarding various populations is sparse. The objective of this study was to examine the relationship between media use directly before bedtime and various sleep parameters in patients of a psychosomatic rehabilitation clinic.
Methods

Patients from a German psychosomatic rehabilitation clinic were tested regarding subjective sleep quality and insomnia symptoms based on questionnaires such as the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI). Eligible patients also completed an additional sleep log over a period of 1 week. A total of 347 insomnia patients were enrolled, with a mean age of 49.77 years (range 22–64 years; median = 52 years). 57.5% of the patients were 50 years or older.
Results

Analysis showed that media use and various sleep diary parameters such as total sleep time (r = −0.386, p = 0.042; rTST2 = 0.149) and sleep efficiency (r = −0.507, p = 0.006; rSE2 = 0.257) were significantly associated. In detail, more media consumption was associated with less total sleep time and a lower sleep efficiency. The same result was found for media use and sleep efficiency on weekdays (r = −0.544, p = 0.002; rSE2 = 0.296), but not for other sleep parameters. However, media use time and subjective sleep quality were not significantly correlated, r = −0.055, p = 0.768.
Conclusion

This study, which is the first to examine the relation between media use and sleep in patients of a psychosomatic rehabilitation clinic, suggests a significant association between media use and sleep duration as well as sleep efficiency. However, more research is needed to investigate the relationship between media use and sleep in more detail, to increase patients’ quality of life and to incorporate these findings into the daily life of clinicians and therapists as well as into sleep hygiene education and sleep trainings.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Zusammenfassung
Ziel

Medienkonsum kann Schlaf beeinträchtigen. Jedoch gibt es wenige Forschungsergebnisse hinsichtlich unterschiedlicher Patientengruppen. Ziel dieser Studie war es, den Zusammenhang zwischen dem Medienkonsum vor dem Zubettgehen und Schlaf bei Patienten und Patientinnen einer psychosomatischen Rehabilitationsklinik zu untersuchen.
Methoden

Patienten einer psychosomatischen Rehabilitationsklinik wurden bei der Aufnahme hinsichtlich ihrer Schlafqualität und Insomniekriterien befragt. Patienten, die über eine schlechte Schlafqualität berichteten und die Insomniekriterien erfüllten, wurden in die Studie aufgenommen und füllten ein einwöchiges Schlaftagebuch aus. Insgesamt wurden die Daten von 347 Patienten mit einem Durchschnittsalter von 49,77 Jahren (Spannbreite: 22–64 Jahre; Median: 52 Jahre) berücksichtigt. Von den Patienten waren 57,5 % über 50 Jahre alt.
Ergebnisse

Mit der Mediennutzung korrelierten die Schlafdauer (r = −0,386; p = 0,042; rTST2 = 0,149) und die Schlafeffizienz (r = −0,507; p = 0,006; rSE2 = 0,257), gemessen mit dem Schlaftagebuch. Je mehr Medien direkt vor dem Schlafen genutzt wurden, desto geringer waren die Schlafdauer und die Schlafeffizienz. Dies galt ebenfalls für die Mediennutzung und die Schlafeffizienz an Wochentagen (r = −0,544; p = 0,002; rSE2 = 0,296), jedoch nicht für andere Schlafparameter. Zwischen der Mediennutzung vor dem Zubettgehen und der subjektiven Schlafqualität wurde hingegen kein signifikanter Zusammenhang gefunden, r = −0,055; p = 0,768.
Schlussfolgerung

Die vorliegende Studie ist eine der ersten, die den Zusammenhang von Mediennutzung und Schlaf bei Patienten einer psychosomatischen Rehabilitation untersuchte. Die Ergebnisse zeigen, dass dieser Zusammenhang zumindest für die Schlafdauer und -effizienz signifikant ist. Zukünftige Forschung sollte dies jedoch detaillierter untersuchen, um die Lebensqualität der Patienten zu erhöhen und die Integration in den Therapiealltag sowie in Anleitungen zur Schlafhygiene und in das Schlaftraining zu erleichtern.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Article_DoesMediaUseBeforeBedtimeAffec.schlarb.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2949200/2949795/Article_DoesMediaUseBeforeBedtimeAffec.schlarb.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Sleep quality</topic><topic>Sleep efficiency</topic><topic>Total sleep time</topic><topic>Insomnia</topic><topic>Rehabilitation patients</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Somnologie</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1432-9123</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1439-054X</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000588215800001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29492002</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s11818-020-00282-5</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>24</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">253-258</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Faber, J., Steinbrecher-Hocke, I., Bommersbach, P., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2020). Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;(4), 253-258. doi:10.1007/s11818-020-00282-5</apa>
<harvard1>Faber, J., et al., 2020. Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;, 24(4), p 253-258.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Faber, et al., “Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?”, &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 24, 2020,  pp. 253-258.</ieee>
<default>Faber J, Steinbrecher-Hocke I, Bommersbach P, Schlarb A (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt; 24(4): 253-258.</default>
<mla>Faber, Jasmin, Steinbrecher-Hocke, Indra, Bommersbach, Peter, and Schlarb, Angelika. “Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?”. &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt; 24.4 (2020): 253-258.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faber, J., Steinbrecher-Hocke, I., Bommersbach, P., &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2020). Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;(4), 253-258. doi:10.1007/s11818-020-00282-5&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Faber, J., Steinbrecher-Hocke, I., Bommersbach, P., and Schlarb, A. (2020). Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt; 24, 253-258.</frontiers>
<wels>Faber, J.; Steinbrecher-Hocke, I.; Bommersbach, P.; Schlarb, A. (2020): Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;,24:(4): 253-258.</wels>
<lncs> Faber, J., Steinbrecher-Hocke, I., Bommersbach, P., Schlarb, A.: Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? Somnologie. 24, 253-258 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faber, Jasmin, Steinbrecher-Hocke, Indra, Bommersbach, Peter, and Schlarb, Angelika. 2020. “Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?”. &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt; 24 (4): 253-258.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Faber J, Steinbrecher-Hocke I, Bommersbach P, Schlarb A. Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;24(4):253-258.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Faber, I.  Steinbrecher-Hocke, P.  Bommersbach, and A.  Schlarb, “Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?”, &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;, 253-258.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Faber J, Steinbrecher-Hocke I, Bommersbach P, Schlarb A (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients?&lt;br /&gt;Somnologie 24(4): 253-258.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Faber, J., Steinbrecher-Hocke, I., Bommersbach, P. &amp;amp; Schlarb, A. (2020). Does media use before bedtime affect the sleep of psychosomatic rehabilitation patients? &lt;em&gt;Somnologie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;(4), 253-258. Springer Nature. doi:10.1007/s11818-020-00282-5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2949200</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-07T12:33:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-06T07:04:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>