<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2949405</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mattia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Guerini</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6471004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8865-7466</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mauro</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Napoletano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We develop a model to study the impact of corporate governance on firm investment decisions
and industry competition. In the model, governance structure affects the distribution of shares
among short- and long-term oriented investors, the robustness of the management regarding possible
stockholder interference, and the managerial remuneration scheme. A bargaining process
between firm’s stakeholders determines the optimal allocation of financial resources between real
investments in R&amp;D and financial investments in shares buybacks. We characterize the relation
between corporate governance and firm’s optimal investment strategy and we study how different
governance structures shape technical progress and the degree of competition over the industrial
life cycle. Numerical simulations of a calibrated set-up of the model show that pooling together
industries characterized by heterogeneous governance structures generate the well-documented
inverted-U shaped relation between competition and innovation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_07_2020.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2949405/2949406/wpaper_07_2020.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>governance structure</topic><topic>industry dynamics</topic><topic>competition</topic><topic>technical change</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29494055</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2949405</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>07-2020</number></detail><extent unit="pages">32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2950277</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Guerini, M., Harting, P., Napoletano, M.: Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2020. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Guerini, Mattia, Harting, Philipp, and Napoletano, Mauro. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 07-2020. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Guerini, Mattia, Harting, Philipp, and Napoletano, Mauro. &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2020. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 07-2020.</mla>
<default>Guerini M, Harting P, Napoletano M (2020)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 07-2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<wels>Guerini, M.; Harting, P.; Napoletano, M. (2020): Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<harvard1>Guerini, M., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Napoletano, M., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.07-2020, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Guerini M, Harting P, Napoletano M (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 07-2020.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Guerini, M., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Napoletano, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2020). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2949405&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Guerini, P.  Harting, and M.  Napoletano, &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Guerini M, Harting P, Napoletano M. &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 07-2020. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2020.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Guerini, M., Harting, P. &amp;amp; Napoletano, M. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2949405.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Guerini, M., Harting, P., and Napoletano, M. (2020). Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 07-2020, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Guerini, M., Harting, P., &amp;amp; Napoletano, M. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2020). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2949405</apa>
<ieee> M. Guerini, P. Harting, and M. Napoletano, &lt;em&gt;Governance structure, technical change, and industry competition&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 07-2020,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2020.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2949405</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-14T08:14:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-19T10:39:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>