<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2949664</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Carina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Prell</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">162856138</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arthur</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Burgardt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">162855797</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">182373532</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8349-1153</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Volker F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15282606</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3473-0012</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685319</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33070705</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">L-2-hydroxyglutarate (L-2HG) is a trifunctional building block and highly attractive for the chemical and pharmaceutical industries. The natural L-lysine biosynthesis pathway of the amino acid producer Corynebacterium glutamicum was extended for the fermentative production of L-2HG. Since L-2HG is not native to the metabolism of C. glutamicum metabolic engineering of a genome-streamlined L-lysine overproducing strain was required to enable the conversion of L-lysine to L-2HG in a six-step synthetic pathway. To this end, L-lysine decarboxylase was cascaded with two transamination reactions, two NAD(P)-dependent oxidation reactions and the terminal 2-oxoglutarate-dependent glutarate hydroxylase. Of three sources for glutarate hydroxylase the metalloenzyme CsiD from Pseudomonas putida supported L-2HG production to the highest titers. Genetic experiments suggested a role of succinate exporter SucE for export of L-2HG and improving expression of its gene by chromosomal exchange of its native promoter improved L-2HG production. The availability of Fe2+ as cofactor of CsiD was identified as a major bottleneck in the conversion of glutarate to L-2HG. As consequence of strain engineering and media adaptation product titers of 34 ± 0 mM were obtained in a microcultivation system. The glucose-based process was stable in 2 L bioreactor cultivations and a L-2HG titer of 3.5 g L−1 was obtained at the higher of two tested aeration levels. Production of L-2HG from a sidestream of the starch industry as renewable substrate was demonstrated. To the best of our knowledge, this study is the first description of fermentative production of L-2HG, a monomeric precursor used in electrochromic polyamides, to cross-link polyamides or to increase their biodegradability.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Prell_2021_Front-Bioeng-Biotechnol-8-630476_L-2-hydroxyglutarate.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2949664/2950579/Prell_2021_Front-Bioeng-Biotechnol-8-630476_L-2-hydroxyglutarate.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2296-4185</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33585425</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000616510800001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29496647</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Prell, Carina, Burgardt, Arthur, Meyer, Florian, and Wendisch, Volker F. “Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt; 8 (2021): 630476.</mla>
<default>Prell C, Burgardt A, Meyer F, Wendisch VF (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt; 8: 630476.</default>
<lncs> Prell, C., Burgardt, A., Meyer, F., Wendisch, V.F.: Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology. 8, : 630476 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prell, Carina, Burgardt, Arthur, Meyer, Florian, and Wendisch, Volker F. 2021. “Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt; 8: 630476.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Prell, C., Burgardt, A., Meyer, F., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2021). Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 630476. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> C. Prell, et al., “Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2021, : 630476.</ieee>
<ama>Prell C, Burgardt A, Meyer F, Wendisch VF. Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;8: 630476.</ama>
<frontiers>Prell, C., Burgardt, A., Meyer, F., and Wendisch, V. F. (2021). Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt; 8:630476.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prell, C., Burgardt, A., Meyer, F. &amp;amp; Wendisch, V.F. (2021). Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;: 630476. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Prell, C., Burgardt, A., Meyer, F., &amp;amp; Wendisch, V. F. (2021). Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 630476. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2020.630476&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Prell, C., et al., 2021. Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, 8: 630476.</harvard1>
<bio1>Prell C, Burgardt A, Meyer F, Wendisch VF (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology 8: 630476.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Prell, A.  Burgardt, F.  Meyer, and V. F.  Wendisch, “Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, : 630476.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Prell, C.; Burgardt, A.; Meyer, F.; Wendisch, V. F. (2021): Fermentative production of ʟ-2-hydroxyglutarate by engineered Corynebacterium glutamicum via pathway extension of ʟ-lysine biosynthesis &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;,8:630476</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2949664</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-12-24T09:09:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-17T15:12:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>