<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2950562</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sevak</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Alaverdyan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">On the one hand, in expansions it is relatively easier for workers to find jobs, so they rely less strongly on their social networks, which means that hiring through referrals should be less frequent in expansions. On the other hand, firms have difficulties to fill their open positions in expansions and rely more strongly on their social networks, which means that referral hiring may be dominating in expansions. Empirical analysis of the IAB Job Vacancy Survey data of the years from 2000 to 2013 and GSOEP data from 2000 to 2014 show that in the long run there is a positive correlation between the GDP and the proportion of workers hired through their social networks. In order to explain the effect of the productivity change on the search and matching strategies of firms and workers, this paper presents a search and matching model with several search channels. The firm chooses advertisement effort through formal search channels to maximize the asset value of an open vacancy. The workers choose their search intensity through formal channels to maximize the asset value of being unem- ployed. Calibration results of the model show that during expansions formal advertisement is not gainful for the firms because of competition. As a result, the firms advertise less, so the proportion of referral hiring should increase. While when the productivity increases, employment becomes more gainful, so the workers exert more effort in search through formal channels. As a result, the proportion of referral hiring should decrease. Both the estimation and the calibration results indicate that the firm-side effect dominates.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_03_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2950562/2950563/wpaper_03_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>social contacts</topic><topic>referrals</topic><topic>search effort</topic><topic>advertisement effort</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29505621</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2950562</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Alaverdyan S. &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 03-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<ieee> S. Alaverdyan, &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 03-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<harvard1>Alaverdyan, S., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.03-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alaverdyan, Sevak. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Alaverdyan, S.: Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<apa>Alaverdyan, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950562</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alaverdyan, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950562&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Alaverdyan, Sevak. &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 03-2021.</mla>
<frontiers>Alaverdyan, S. (2021). Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 03-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Alaverdyan, S. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950562.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<wels>Alaverdyan, S. (2021): Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Alaverdyan S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Alaverdyan, &lt;em&gt;Search Channels of Workers and Firms over the Business Cycle&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<default>Alaverdyan S (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2950562</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-27T09:19:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-27T09:23:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>