<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2950351</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jasper</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hepp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">250140590</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4989-8881</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper explores the impact of technological change on industry concentration and
the underlying firm dynamics. In the agent-based model EURACE@Unibi I implement a
paradigm shift in the technological frontier – a shift from a slow to a fast growing regime.
The analysis shows that the acceleration in technological change causes a strong increase in
market concentration. The reallocation of market shares towards a few large firms is driven
by diverging productivities and skills across firms. An ex-post analysis reveals that after
the paradigm shift small, but undervalued firms become the large dominating ones in the
long-run. Their success gets initiated by a fortunate outcome on the labor market, which
increases their skill level. With the faster technological change, their high skilled workforce
incentivizes them to invest at the frontier and to build up the most productive capital stock.
A virtuous cycle between their decisions on the labor and capital market further increases
the productivity gap towards competitors enabling their rise.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_02_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2950351/2950354/wpaper_02_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Market Concentration</topic><topic>Technological Paradigm Shift</topic><topic>Path Dependency</topic><topic>Firm Determinants</topic><topic>Agent-Based Model</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29503516</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2950351</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>02-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">44</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hepp, J. (2021): Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Hepp, J. (2021). Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 02-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hepp, J. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950351&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hepp, Jasper. &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 02-2021.</mla>
<default>Hepp J (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Hepp, J., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.02-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Hepp, &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 02-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Hepp, J. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950351</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hepp, J. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950351.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Hepp, &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hepp J (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 02-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Hepp J. &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 02-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hepp, Jasper. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 02-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hepp, J.: Being small at the right moment: Path dependence after a shift in the technological regime. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 02-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2950351</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-22T08:54:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-01-22T08:56:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>