<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2950974</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Owusu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper assesses the fiscal sustainability hypothesis for 10 Eastern and Central European countries (CEEC) between 1997 and 2019. The study adopts very recent panel econometric techniques which accounts for issues of structural breaks and cross-sectional dependence in the data generating process to examine the cointegration between government revenue and expenditures. Preliminary results show that revenues and expenditures do not have a long-run relationship and hence a rejection of the sustainability hypothesis. As a next step, we discriminate between structural and cyclical components of revenues and expenditures in order to place emphasis on the structural component. We argue that the structural component of fiscal variables represents the actual long term behaviour of the policymaker. Further results indicate that structural revenues and expenditures have a long-run relationship however with a slope coefficient less than unity which implies sustainability in the weaker sense. At that point, expenditures exceed revenues and if this continues for a long time the government may find it difficult to market its debts in the long run. This result suggests that the fiscal authorities in CEEC must therefore do more by taking long term actions to counteract the rising fiscal deficit problems.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_04_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2950974/2951000/wpaper_04_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Fiscal Sustainability</topic><topic>Cointegration</topic><topic>Government Revenue</topic><topic>Government Expenditure</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29509743</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2950974</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>04-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">50</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Owusu, B.: Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 04-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, Benjamin. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 04-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Owusu, Benjamin. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 04-2021.</mla>
<default>Owusu B (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 04-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ama>Owusu B. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 04-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Owusu, B. (2021). Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 04-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, B. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950974.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Owusu, B. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 04-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950974</apa>
<ieee> B. Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 04-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<wels>Owusu, B. (2021): Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Owusu B (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 04-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Owusu, B., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.04-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, B. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 04-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2950974&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sustainability Hypothesis Test in Central and Eastern Europe: A Panel Data Perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2950974</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-04T14:10:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-05T14:56:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>