<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2951007</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Caspar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lückenbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">52167041</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1293-6175</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eduard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klukas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">336600562</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Phillip Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84479989</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gerlinger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">16956277</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21331</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This series of reports is one of the research results of the Mc-COVID-19 project, “MC-COVID19: Coordination mechanisms in Coronavirus management between different levels of government and public policy sectors in 15 European countries”, funded by the Spanish National Research Council (CSIC) within the CSIC-COVID-19 programme, as well as of the GoWPER project, “Restructuring the Governance of the Welfare State: Political Determinants and Implications for the (De)Commodification of Risks”, CSO2017-85598-R Plan Estatal de Investigación Científica y Técnica y de Innovación.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="210204 CSIC_covid_ALEMANIA.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2951007/2961533/210204 CSIC_covid_ALEMANIA.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Spanish National Research Council (CSIC)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29510072</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number> 06/2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">40</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Lückenbach C, Klukas E, Schmidt PF, Gerlinger T (2021)  MC COVID-19 working paper;  06/2021.&lt;br /&gt;Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).</default>
<wels>Lückenbach, C.; Klukas, E.; Schmidt, P. F.; Gerlinger, T. (2021): Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany. Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).</wels>
<mla>Lückenbach, Caspar, Klukas, Eduard, Schmidt, Phillip Florian, and Gerlinger, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), 2021. MC COVID-19 working paper.  06/2021.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lückenbach, C., Klukas, E., Schmidt, P. F., &amp;amp; Gerlinger, T. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt; (MC COVID-19 working paper,  06/2021). Spanish National Research Council (CSIC). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Lückenbach, C., Klukas, E., Schmidt, P. F., and Gerlinger, T. (2021). Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany. &lt;em&gt;MC COVID-19 working paper&lt;/em&gt;,  06/2021, Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).</frontiers>
<apa>Lückenbach, C., Klukas, E., Schmidt, P. F., &amp;amp; Gerlinger, T. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt; (MC COVID-19 working paper,  06/2021). Spanish National Research Council (CSIC). &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Lückenbach, C., et al., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;, MC COVID-19 working paper, no. 06/2021, Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).</harvard1>
<ieee> C. Lückenbach, et al., &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;, MC COVID-19 working paper, vol.  06/2021, Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), 2021.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Lückenbach, E.  Klukas, P. F.  Schmidt, and T.  Gerlinger, &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Spanish National Research Council (Csic), &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lückenbach C, Klukas E, Schmidt PF, Gerlinger T (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;. MC COVID-19 working paper;  06/2021.&lt;br /&gt;Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lückenbach, C., Klukas, E., Schmidt, P.F. &amp;amp; Gerlinger, T. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt; (MC COVID-19 working paper). Spanish National Research Council (CSIC). doi:10.20350/digitalCSIC/13694.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lückenbach, Caspar, Klukas, Eduard, Schmidt, Phillip Florian, and Gerlinger, Thomas. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;. Vol.  06/2021. MC COVID-19 working paper. Spanish National Research Council (CSIC).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lückenbach, C., Klukas, E., Schmidt, P.F., Gerlinger, T.: Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany. MC COVID-19 working paper,  06/2021. Spanish National Research Council (CSIC) (2021).</lncs>
<ama>Lückenbach C, Klukas E, Schmidt PF, Gerlinger T. &lt;em&gt;Governmental response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Long-Term Care residences for older people: preparedness, responses and challenges for the future: Germany&lt;/em&gt;. MC COVID-19 working paper. Vol  06/2021. Spanish National Research Council (CSIC); 2021.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2951007</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-06T12:10:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-03T09:32:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>