<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2951595</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Truc Sophia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dinh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ana Isabel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">González-González</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas D.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kym I. E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Snell</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Henrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rudolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maria-Sophie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brueckle</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jeanet W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Blom</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thiem</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trampisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra J. M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Elders</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Donner-Banzhoff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ferdinand M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gerlach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marjan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van den Akker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Paul P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Glasziou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haefeli</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Muth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">241685401</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">241685249</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Cumulative anticholinergic exposure, also known as anticholinergic burden, is associated with a variety of adverse outcomes. However, studies show that anticholinergic effects tend to be underestimated by prescribers, and anticholinergics are the most frequently prescribed potentially inappropriate medication in older patients. The grading systems and drugs included in existing scales to quantify anticholinergic burden differ considerably and do not adequately account for patients’ susceptibility to medications. Furthermore, their ability to link anticholinergic burden with adverse outcomes such as falls is unclear. This study aims to develop a prognostic model that predicts falls in older general practice patients, to assess the performance of several anticholinergic burden scales, and to quantify the added predictive value of anticholinergic symptoms in this context.

Methods: Data from two cluster-randomized controlled trials investigating medication optimization in older general practice patients in Germany will be used. One trial (RIME, n = 1,197) will be used for the model development and the other trial (PRIMUM, n = 502) will be used to externally validate the model. A priori, candidate predictors will be selected based on a literature search, predictor availability, and clinical reasoning. Candidate predictors will include socio-demographics (e.g. age, sex), morbidity (e.g. single conditions), medication (e.g. polypharmacy, anticholinergic burden as defined by scales), and well-being (e.g. quality of life, physical function). A prognostic model including sociodemographic and lifestyle-related factors, as well as variables on morbidity, medication, health status, and well-being, will be developed, whereby the prognostic value of extending the model to include additional patient-reported symptoms will be also assessed. Logistic regression will be used for the binary outcome, which will be defined as “no falls” vs. “≥1 fall” within six months of baseline, as reported in patient interviews.

Discussion: As the ability of different anticholinergic burden scales to predict falls in older patients is unclear, this study may provide insights into their relative importance as well as into the overall contribution of anticholinergic symptoms and other patient characteristics. The results may support general practitioners in their clinical decision-making and in prescribing fewer medications with anticholinergic properties.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fphar-11-577747.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2951595/2951596/fphar-11-577747.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Pharmacology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1663-9812</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33519441</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000612797600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29515956</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fphar.2020.577747</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dinh, T.S., González-González, A.I., Meid, A.D., Snell, K.I.E., Rudolf, H., Brueckle, M.-S., Blom, J.W., Thiem, U., Trampisch, H.-J., Elders, P.J.M., Donner-Banzhoff, N., Gerlach, F.M., Harder, S., van den Akker, M., Glasziou, P.P., Haefeli, W.E. &amp;amp; Muth, C. (2021). Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;: 577747. Frontiers Media SA. doi:10.3389/fphar.2020.577747.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>T. S.  Dinh, A. I.  González-González, A. D.  Meid, K. I. E.  Snell, H.  Rudolf, M. - S.  Brueckle, J. W.  Blom, U.  Thiem, H. - J.  Trampisch, P. J. M.  Elders, et al., “Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, : 577747.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dinh TS, González-González AI, Meid AD, Snell KIE, Rudolf H, Brueckle M-S, Blom JW, Thiem U, Trampisch H-J, Elders PJM, Donner-Banzhoff N, Gerlach FM, Harder S, van den Akker M, Glasziou PP, Haefeli WE, Muth C (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology 11: 577747.</bio1>
<ama>Dinh TS, González-González AI, Meid AD, et al. Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;11: 577747.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dinh, Truc Sophia, González-González, Ana Isabel, Meid, Andreas D., Snell, Kym I. E., Rudolf, Henrik, Brueckle, Maria-Sophie, Blom, Jeanet W., et al. 2021. “Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 577747.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dinh, T.S., González-González, A.I., Meid, A.D., Snell, K.I.E., Rudolf, H., Brueckle, M.-S., Blom, J.W., Thiem, U., Trampisch, H.-J., Elders, P.J.M., Donner-Banzhoff, N., Gerlach, F.M., Harder, S., van den Akker, M., Glasziou, P.P., Haefeli, W.E., Muth, C.: Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. Frontiers in Pharmacology. 11, : 577747 (2021).</lncs>
<wels>Dinh, T. S.; González-González, A. I.; Meid, A. D.; Snell, K. I. E.; Rudolf, H.; Brueckle, M. - S.; Blom, J. W.; Thiem, U.; Trampisch, H. - J.; Elders, P. J. M.; Donner-Banzhoff, N.; Gerlach, F. M.; Harder, S.; van den Akker, M.; Glasziou, P. P.; Haefeli, W. E.; Muth, C. (2021): Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;,11:577747</wels>
<mla>Dinh, Truc Sophia, González-González, Ana Isabel, Meid, Andreas D., Snell, Kym I. E., Rudolf, Henrik, Brueckle, Maria-Sophie, Blom, Jeanet W., Thiem, Ulrich, Trampisch, Hans-Joachim, Elders, Petra J. M., Donner-Banzhoff, Norbert, Gerlach, Ferdinand M., Harder, Sebastian, van den Akker, Marjan, Glasziou, Paul P., Haefeli, Walter E., and Muth, Christiane. “Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt; 11 (2021): 577747.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dinh, T. S., González-González, A. I., Meid, A. D., Snell, K. I. E., Rudolf, H., Brueckle, M. - S., Blom, J. W., et al. (2021). Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 577747. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.577747" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.577747&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Dinh, T. S., González-González, A. I., Meid, A. D., Snell, K. I. E., Rudolf, H., Brueckle, M. - S., Blom, J. W., Thiem, U., Trampisch, H. - J., Elders, P. J. M., et al. (2021). Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt; 11:577747.</frontiers>
<default>Dinh TS, González-González AI, Meid AD, Snell KIE, Rudolf H, Brueckle M-S, Blom JW, Thiem U, Trampisch H-J, Elders PJM, Donner-Banzhoff N, et al. (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 577747.</default>
<harvard1>Dinh, T.S., et al., 2021. Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;, 11: 577747.</harvard1>
<ieee> T.S. Dinh, et al., “Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2021, : 577747.</ieee>
<apa>Dinh, T. S., González-González, A. I., Meid, A. D., Snell, K. I. E., Rudolf, H., Brueckle, M. - S., Blom, J. W., et al. (2021). Are Anticholinergic Symptoms a Risk Factor for Falls in Older General Practice Patients With Polypharmacy? Study Protocol for the Development and Validation of a Prognostic Model. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 577747. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.577747" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2020.577747&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2951595</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-23T14:40:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-09T17:47:39Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>