<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2951757</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7346775</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8778-1273</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart><namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Cord</namePart><namePart type="family">Wiljes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10085</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Conquaire: Conquaire</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">In this chapter, we briefly describe the Git-based infrastructure that has been implemented as a result of the Conquaire project to support analytical reproducibility. The infrastructure implemented relies on principles of continuous integration as used in software engineering projects. Importantly, we rely on a distributed version control system (DVCS) to store computational artifacts that are key to reproducing the analytical results of an experiment. Using a
DVCS has the benefit that artifacts can be versioned and each version can be uniquely addressed via a revision number. The DVCS implementation we rely on is Git, extended by GitLab as a web interface and collaboration platform.
The heart of the infrastructure implemented in the Conquaire project is the so called Conquaire server. We assume that each research project deposits relevant data and code in a Git repository. In the background, a GitLab CI Runner
on the Conquaire server is triggered by Git push events on the local GitLab server and executes a number of tests on the data and runs the code or script to reproduce a particular result. By this, we ensure that results can be reproduced
independently of the original researchers on a separate machine. In this chapter, we briefly describe the infrastructure implemented and how tests are automatically executed when updates are committed to the Git repository.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="conquaire-book _chapter-2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2951757/2953785/conquaire-book _chapter-2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-943363-06-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29517575</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">17-27</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2942780</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Hermann, F.; Pietsch, C.; Cimiano, P. (2021): Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In: Philipp Cimiano; Christian Pietsch; Cord Wiljes; Bielefeld University (Hrsg.):  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Bielefeld.  S. 17-27.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Hermann, C.  Pietsch, and P.  Cimiano, in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, C. Wiljes, Bielefeld University), Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 17-27.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Hermann, F., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P., 2021. Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In P.  Cimiano, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld, pp. 17-27.</harvard1>
<bio1>Hermann F, Pietsch C, Cimiano P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C, Bielefeld University (Eds); Bielefeld:  17-27.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, F., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2021). Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, C.  Wiljes, &amp;amp; Bielefeld University (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 17-27). Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, F., Pietsch, C. &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2021). Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, C. Wiljes &amp;amp; Bielefeld University (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (S. 17-27). Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Hermann, F., Pietsch, C., and Cimiano, P. (2021). “Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control” in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., Wiljes, C., and Bielefeld University eds. (Bielefeld), 17-27.</frontiers>
<ama>Hermann F, Pietsch C, Cimiano P. Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In: Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C, Bielefeld University, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld;  2021: 17-27.</ama>
<ieee> F. Hermann, C. Pietsch, and P. Cimiano, “Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control”, &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, P. Cimiano, et al., eds.,  Bielefeld: 2021,  pp.17-27.</ieee>
<apa>Hermann, F., Pietsch, C., &amp;amp; Cimiano, P. (2021). Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, C.  Wiljes, &amp;amp; Bielefeld University (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 17-27). Bielefeld.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hermann, Fabian, Pietsch, Christian, and Cimiano, Philipp. 2021. “Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control”. In &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, Cord Wiljes, and Bielefeld University, 17-27. Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hermann, F., Pietsch, C., Cimiano, P.: Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control. In: Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., Wiljes, C., and Bielefeld University (eds.) Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. p. 17-27. Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<default>Hermann F, Pietsch C, Cimiano P (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C, Bielefeld University (Eds);  Bielefeld:  17-27.</default>
<mla>Hermann, Fabian, Pietsch, Christian, and Cimiano, Philipp. “Conquaire Infrastructure for Continuous Quality Control”. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, Cord Wiljes, and Bielefeld University. Bielefeld, 2021. 17-27.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2951757</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-25T20:15:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T13:06:39Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>