<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2951661</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bott</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">184569824</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Natasha</namePart><namePart type="family">Abner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Jason</namePart><namePart type="family">Bishop</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4961795</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="paper1817.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2951661/2951662/paper1817.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Cascadilla Proceedings Project</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-1-57473-428-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29516611</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">63-71</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Bott, O.: Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In: Abner, N. and Bishop, J. (eds.) Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics. p. 63-71. Cascadilla Proceedings Project, Somerville, MA (2008).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bott, Oliver. 2008. “Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Natasha Abner and Jason Bishop, 63-71. Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Bott O. Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In: Abner N, Bishop J, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project;  2008: 63-71.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Bott, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: N. Abner, J. Bishop), Cascadilla Proceedings Project, Somerville, MA, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 63-71.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bott O (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics. Abner N, Bishop J (Eds); Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project:  63-71.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bott, O. (2008). Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In N. Abner &amp;amp; J. Bishop (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (S. 63-71). Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Bott, O. (2008). Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In N.  Abner &amp;amp; J.  Bishop (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-71). Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project.</apa>
<harvard1>Bott, O., 2008. Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In N.  Abner &amp;amp; J.  Bishop, eds. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;.  Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project, pp. 63-71.</harvard1>
<ieee> O. Bott, “Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, N. Abner and J. Bishop, eds.,  Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project, 2008,  pp.63-71.</ieee>
<default>Bott O (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics. Abner N, Bishop J (Eds);  Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project:  63-71.</default>
<mla>Bott, Oliver. “Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Natasha Abner and Jason Bishop. Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project, 2008. 63-71.</mla>
<frontiers>Bott, O. (2008). “Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, Abner, N., and Bishop, J. eds. (Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project), 63-71.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bott, O. (2008). Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In N.  Abner &amp;amp; J.  Bishop (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 63-71). Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Bott, O. (2008): Doing It Again and Again May Be Difficult, But It Depends on What You Are Doing. In: Natasha Abner; Jason Bishop (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the 27th West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics. Somerville, MA: Cascadilla Proceedings Project.  S. 63-71.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2951661</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-25T10:46:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-01T09:47:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>