<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2951246</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lennart</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dabelow</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">120398118</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Reimann</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Understanding how the macroscopically observable behavior of systems with many degrees of freedom emerges from the laws governing their microscopic constituents is an intriguing fundamental problem. We approach this issue by investigating how the dynamics of many-body quantum systems is affected by weak-to-moderate perturbations in three different nonequilibrium setups. First, we study the relaxation towards equilibrium under the influence of time-independent perturbations. Second, we consider so-called echo protocols, where the system relaxes for a certain time followed by an effective time reversal during another period of equal duration, spoiled by small inaccuracies in the state at the point of reversal or in the dynamical laws. Third, we analyze the response to external driving in the form of a time-dependent coupling strength for perturbations of a similar kind as in the first setup. These settings cover a large variety of different phenomena and applications such as the relaxation of system-bath compounds, prethermalization, magnetic resonance imaging, quantum quenches, and periodically modulated external fields. Adopting typicality arguments, we derive analytical predictions for the observable dynamics in all three scenarios. Furthermore, we analyze these predictions and verify them by comparison with numerical and experimental data for several different models and observables. 

</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">Wie sich das makroskopisch beobachtbare Verhalten von Systemen mit vielen Freiheitsgraden aus den Gesetzmäßigkeiten ergibt, die deren mikroskopische Bestandteile beschreiben, ist eine faszinierende grundlegende Fragestellung. Dieser nähern wir uns hier, indem wir in drei verschiedenen Nichtgleichgewichts-Szenarien ergründen, wie sich die Dynamik von Quanten-Vielteilchen-Systemen unter dem Einfluss schwacher Störungen ändert. Erstens untersuchen wir den Effekt von zeitunabhängigen Störungen auf die Relaxation ins Gleichgewicht. Zweitens betrachten wir sogenannte Echo-Protokolle, bei denen ein System für eine gewisse Zeit relaxiert, worauf eine Phase gleicher Länge folgt, während der es sich effektiv in umgekehrter Zeitrichtung entwickelt, wobei jedoch kleine Ungenauigkeiten im Zustand am Umkehrzeitpunkt oder in den dynamischen Eigenschaften auftreten können. Drittens analysieren wir, wie ein gegebenes System auf Störungen ähnlich wie im ersten Fall, jedoch mit zeitlich variabler Intensität reagiert. Diese Szenarien decken eine Vielzahl verschiedener Phänomene und Anwendungen ab, zum Beispiel die Relaxation von zusammengesetzten Systemen mit Wärmebad, Präthermalisierung, Magnetresonanztomografie, schnelle Parameteränderungen (engl."quenches") oder periodisch modulierte externe Felder. Unter Ausnutzung von Typikalitätsargumenten leiten wir in allen drei Fällen analytische Vorhersagen für die beobachtbare Dynamik her. Darüber hinaus analysieren wir diese Vorhersagen und vergleichen sie mit numerischen und experimentellen Daten für verschiedene Modellsysteme und Observablen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Dissertation-Dabelow_Lennart.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2951246/2951247/Dissertation-Dabelow_Lennart.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29512464</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2951246</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2021-01-29</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> L. Dabelow, &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Dabelow, L. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2951246" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2951246&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dabelow, L. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2951246.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Dabelow, L. (2021). Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<ama>Dabelow L. &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2021.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Dabelow, &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dabelow L (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dabelow, L. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2951246" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2951246&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Dabelow, L., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<wels>Dabelow, L. (2021): Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<default>Dabelow L (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<mla>Dabelow, Lennart. &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dabelow, Lennart. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dabelow, L.: Predicting quantum many-body dynamics out of equilibrium. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2951246</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-11T14:43:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-02-18T14:26:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>