<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952125</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:790</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bright Opoku</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Richard Gyan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aboagye</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Francis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Arthur-Holmes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Junior</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joshua</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okyere</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eugene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Budu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert Kokou</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dowou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Collins</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Adu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">(1) Background: Among the health problems affecting adolescents, anxiety disorders are considered among the health-compromising or debilitating outcomes that affect adolescents’ mental health. We examined the prevalence and factors associated with anxiety-induced sleep disturbance among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA). (2) Methods: This study involved a cross-sectional analysis of data from the Global School-Based Health Survey (GSHS). We analyzed data on 25,454 in-school adolescents from eleven (11) countries in SSA with a dataset between 2010 and 2017. Two multivariable logistic regression models were built to determine the strength of the association between anxiety-induced sleep disturbance and the explanatory variables. The results of the regression analyses were presented using adjusted odds ratios (aOR) and their respective 95% confidence intervals (CIs). Statistical significance was set at p-value &lt; 0.05. (3) Results: The overall prevalence of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance among in-school adolescents in SSA was 12.2%. The prevalence ranged from 5.1% in Tanzania to 20.5% in Benin. The odds of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance was higher among adolescents aged 15 and above [aOR = 1.26, 95% CI = 1.15, 1.39] compared to those aged 14 or younger. Additionally, the odds of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance was higher among adolescents who were bullied [aOR = 1.54, 95% CI = 1.42, 1.67], those that felt lonely [aOR = 3.85, 95% CI = 3.52, 4.22], those who had suicidal ideations [aOR = 1.70, 95% CI = 1.52, 1.90], those who had suicidal plan [aOR = 1.26, 95% CI = 1.13, 1.41], those who have had suicidal attempt [aOR = 1.21, 95% CI = 1.08, 1.35], those who used marijuana [aOR = 1.27, 95% CI = 1.06, 1.52], and those who were truant at school [aOR = 1.33, 95% CI = 1.22, 1.46]. However, male adolescents had lower odds of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance [aOR = 0.88, 95% CI = 0.81, 0.95], compared to their female counterparts. (4) Conclusions: We found a relatively high prevalence of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance among in-school adolescents in SSA. Higher age, being female, being bullied, loneliness, having suicidal ideations/plan/attempt, use of marijuana and truancy were risk factors for anxiety-induced sleep disturbance. The findings, therefore, highlight the urgency for policies (e.g., early school-based screening) and interventions (e.g., Rational Emotive Behavioral Education (REBE), Social Emotional Learning (SEL) that target in-school adolescents within the most at-risk populations of anxiety-induced sleep disturbance in SSA.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="healthcare-09-00234-v2.hagan.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952125/2952554/healthcare-09-00234-v2.hagan.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>anxiety-induced sleep disturbance</topic><topic>in-school adolescents</topic><topic>mental health</topic><topic>rational emotive behavioral education</topic><topic>social emotional learning</topic><topic>sub-Saharan Africa</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Healthcare</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2227-9032</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33671775</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000622569700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29521259</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/healthcare9020234</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Ahinkorah, B. O.; Aboagye, R. G.; Arthur-Holmes, F.; Hagan Junior, J. E.; Okyere, J.; Budu, E.; Dowou, R. K.; Adu, C.; Seidu, A. - A. (2021): A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;,9:(2):234</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B. O.  Ahinkorah, R. G.  Aboagye, F.  Arthur-Holmes, J. E.  Hagan Junior, J.  Okyere, E.  Budu, R. K.  Dowou, C.  Adu, and A. - A.  Seidu, “A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey”, &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, : 234.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, B. O., Aboagye, R. G., Arthur-Holmes, F., Hagan Junior, J. E., Okyere, J., Budu, E., Dowou, R. K., et al. (2021). A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 234. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9020234" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9020234&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Ahinkorah BO, Aboagye RG, Arthur-Holmes F, Hagan Junior JE, Okyere J, Budu E, Dowou RK, Adu C, Seidu A-A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey.&lt;br /&gt;Healthcare 9(2): 234.</bio1>
<harvard1>Ahinkorah, B.O., et al., 2021. A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;, 9(2): 234.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Ahinkorah, B. O., Aboagye, R. G., Arthur-Holmes, F., Hagan Junior, J. E., Okyere, J., Budu, E., Dowou, R. K., Adu, C., and Seidu, A. - A. (2021). A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt; 9:234.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, B.O., Aboagye, R.G., Arthur-Holmes, F., Hagan Junior, J.E., Okyere, J., Budu, E., Dowou, R.K., Adu, C. &amp;amp; Seidu, A.-A. (2021). A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2): 234. MDPI . doi:10.3390/healthcare9020234.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ahinkorah BO, Aboagye RG, Arthur-Holmes F, et al. A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;9(2): 234.</ama>
<ieee> B.O. Ahinkorah, et al., “A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey”, &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2021, : 234.</ieee>
<apa>Ahinkorah, B. O., Aboagye, R. G., Arthur-Holmes, F., Hagan Junior, J. E., Okyere, J., Budu, E., Dowou, R. K., et al. (2021). A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 234. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9020234" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9020234&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Aboagye, Richard Gyan, Arthur-Holmes, Francis, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Okyere, Joshua, Budu, Eugene, Dowou, Robert Kokou, Adu, Collins, and Seidu, Abdul-Aziz. 2021. “A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey”. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt; 9 (2): 234.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ahinkorah, B.O., Aboagye, R.G., Arthur-Holmes, F., Hagan Junior, J.E., Okyere, J., Budu, E., Dowou, R.K., Adu, C., Seidu, A.-A.: A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey. Healthcare. 9, : 234 (2021).</lncs>
<default>Ahinkorah BO, Aboagye RG, Arthur-Holmes F, Hagan Junior JE, Okyere J, Budu E, Dowou RK, Adu C, Seidu A-A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt; 9(2): 234.</default>
<mla>Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Aboagye, Richard Gyan, Arthur-Holmes, Francis, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Okyere, Joshua, Budu, Eugene, Dowou, Robert Kokou, Adu, Collins, and Seidu, Abdul-Aziz. “A Multi-Country Analysis of Prevalence of Anxiety-Induced Sleep Disturbance and Its Associated Factors among In-School Adolescents in Sub-Saharan Africa Using the Global School-Based Health Survey”. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare&lt;/em&gt; 9.2 (2021): 234.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952125</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-01T07:29:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-18T16:22:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>