<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952182</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Salvatore</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Federico</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Neofytos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rodosthenous</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study the problem of optimally managing an inventory with unknown demand trend. Our
formulation leads to a stochastic control problem under partial observation, in which a Brownian motion
with non-observable drift can be singularly controlled in both an upward and downward direction. We
first derive the equivalent separated problem under full information, with state-space components given
by the Brownian motion and the filtering estimate of its unknown drift, and we then completely solve
this latter problem. Our approach uses the transition amongst three different but equivalent problem
formulations, links between two-dimensional bounded-variation stochastic control problems and games
of optimal stopping, and probabilistic methods in combination with refined viscosity theory arguments.
We show substantial regularity of (a transformed version of) the value function, we construct an optimal
control rule, and we show that the free boundaries delineating (transformed) action and inaction regions
are bounded globally Lipschitz continuous functions. To our knowledge this is the first time that such
a problem has been solved in the literature.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">MSC2020 subject classifications: Primary 93E20, 93E11, 91A55, 49J40, 90B05.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_643.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952182/2952187/IMW_working_paper_643.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>bounded-variation stochastic control</topic><topic>partial observation</topic><topic>inventory management</topic><topic>Dynkin games</topic><topic>free boundaries</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29521821</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>643</number></detail><extent unit="pages">32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Federico S, Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N (2021)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 643.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<frontiers>Federico, S., Ferrari, G., and Rodosthenous, N. (2021). Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 643, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, S., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 643). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Federico, Salvatore, Ferrari, Giorgio, and Rodosthenous, Neofytos. &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 643.</mla>
<wels>Federico, S.; Ferrari, G.; Rodosthenous, N. (2021): Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa>Federico, S., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 643). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<harvard1>Federico, S., Ferrari, G., &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.643, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> S. Federico, G. Ferrari, and N. Rodosthenous, &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 643,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Federico, G.  Ferrari, and N.  Rodosthenous, &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Federico S, Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 643.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, S., Ferrari, G. &amp;amp; Rodosthenous, N. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Federico, S., Ferrari, G., Rodosthenous, N.: Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 643. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Federico, Salvatore, Ferrari, Giorgio, and Rodosthenous, Neofytos. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 643. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Federico S, Ferrari G, Rodosthenous N. &lt;em&gt;Two-Sided Singular Control of an Inventory with Unknown Demand Trend&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 643. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2021.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952182</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-01T12:27:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>