<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952178</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Owusu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The European Union has set up a fund in order to compensate countries for damages
resulting from Covid-19 that hit the economies in an asymmetric way. We argue
that payments should be based only on relative damages, expressed as losses relative
to GDP, and any distribution mechanism implying that damages in the countries
are treated differently is discriminatory. Hence, we compute the compensation payments
if the resources of the fund are spent according to the relative loss in GDP.
Finally, we compare the compensations relative to the losses in GDP, resulting from
the application of that principle, with those obtained by distributing the funds as
suggested by the Council of the European Union. Our results provide evidence of
discrimination by the EU Covid-19 compensation package.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_05-2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952178/2952181/wpaper_05-2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Covid-19</topic><topic>European Union</topic><topic>transfers</topic><topic>discrimination</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29521781</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2952178</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>05-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">14</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Greiner A, Owusu B (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<bio1>Greiner A, Owusu B (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 05-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, and B.  Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Greiner, A.; Owusu, B. (2021): Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<frontiers>Greiner, A., and Owusu, B. (2021). Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 05-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952178" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred, and Owusu, Benjamin. &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 05-2021.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2952178.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952178" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952178&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred, and Owusu, Benjamin. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 05-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Greiner, A., Owusu, B.: Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 05-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<ieee> A. Greiner and B. Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 05-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.05-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ama>Greiner A, Owusu B. &lt;em&gt;Who is discriminated most in the EU? An analysis of the Covid-19 compensation fund&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 05-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952178</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-01T12:18:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-18T15:40:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>