<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952428</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alessandro</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Basurto</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8f888d0e-df7b-4c7f-86dc-d9aee37b45b0</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Harting</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">6471004</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8865-7466</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jasper</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hepp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">250140590</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4989-8881</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dirk</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kohlweyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">53462453</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We analyze the impact of different designs of COVID-19 related lockdown policies on
economic loss and mortality using a micro-level simulation model, which combines a multisectoral
closed economy with an epidemic transmission model. In particular, the model
captures explicitly the (stochastic) effect of interactions between heterogeneous agents during
different economic activities on virus transmissions. The empirical validity of the model is
established using data on economic and pandemic dynamics in Germany in the first six
months after the COVID-19 outbreak. We show that a policy inducing switches between a
strict lockdown and a full opening-up of economic activity is strictly dominated by alternative
policies, which implement either a much more cautious opening at the end of the lockdown
or a more or less continuous light lockdown with only minor restrictions of economic activity.
Furthermore, also the ex-ante variance of the economic loss suffered during the pandemic
is substantially lower under these policies. Keeping the other policy parameters fixed, a
variation of the consumption restrictions during the lockdown induces a trade-off between
GDP loss and mortality. Finally, we study the robustness of these findings with respect to
the occurrence of a more infectious virus mutation.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_06_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952428/2952429/wpaper_06_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>COVID-19</topic><topic>economic loss</topic><topic>containment policy</topic><topic>variance of policy effects</topic><topic>agentbased modeling</topic><topic>etace_WP</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29524281</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2952428</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>06-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">61</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Basurto, A., Dawid, H., Harting, P., Hepp, J., &amp;amp; Kohlweyer, D. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 06-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952428" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952428&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> A. Basurto, et al., &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 06-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<harvard1>Basurto, A., et al., 2021. &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.06-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<default>Basurto A, Dawid H, Harting P, Hepp J, Kohlweyer D (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 06-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Basurto, A., Dawid, H., Harting, P., Hepp, J., &amp;amp; Kohlweyer, D. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 06-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952428" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952428&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Basurto, Alessandro, Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, Hepp, Jasper, and Kohlweyer, Dirk. &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 06-2021.</mla>
<frontiers>Basurto, A., Dawid, H., Harting, P., Hepp, J., and Kohlweyer, D. (2021). How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 06-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<wels>Basurto, A.; Dawid, H.; Harting, P.; Hepp, J.; Kohlweyer, D. (2021): How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<lncs> Basurto, A., Dawid, H., Harting, P., Hepp, J., Kohlweyer, D.: How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 06-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Basurto, Alessandro, Dawid, Herbert, Harting, Philipp, Hepp, Jasper, and Kohlweyer, Dirk. 2021. &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 06-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Basurto A, Dawid H, Harting P, Hepp J, Kohlweyer D. &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 06-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<bio1>Basurto A, Dawid H, Harting P, Hepp J, Kohlweyer D (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 06-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Basurto, H.  Dawid, P.  Harting, J.  Hepp, and D.  Kohlweyer, &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Basurto, A., Dawid, H., Harting, P., Hepp, J. &amp;amp; Kohlweyer, D. (2021). &lt;em&gt;How to design virus containment polices? A joint analysis of economic and epidemic dynamics under the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2952428.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952428</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-05T13:24:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-05T13:43:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>