<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952430</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Herbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dawid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">81472</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-8536-9960</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Serhat</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gezer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">39565958</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we study Markov-perfect equilibria (MPE) of two-player multimode
dierential games with controlled state dynamics, where one player controls
the transition between modes. Different types of MPE are characterized distinguishing
between delay equilbria, inducing for some initial conditions mode switches
after a positive finite delay, and now or never equilbria, under which, depending on
the initial condition, a mode switch occurs immediately or never. These results are
applied to analyze the MPE of a game capturing the dynamic interaction between
two incumbent firms among which one has to decide when to extend its product
range by introducing a new product. The market appeal of the new product can
be (positively or negatively) in
uenced over time by the competing firms through
costly investments. It is shown that under a wide range of market introduction costs
a now or never equilibrium co-exists with a continuum of delay equilibria, with each
of them inducing a different time of product introduction.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_07_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952430/2952431/wpaper_07_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>multi-mode differential games</topic><topic>Markov-perfect-equilibrium</topic><topic>product innovation</topic><topic>optimal timing</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29524307</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2952430</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>07-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Gezer, S., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.07-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> H. Dawid and S. Gezer, &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 07-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Gezer, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952430" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952430&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H., &amp;amp; Gezer, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952430" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952430&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Dawid, H., and Gezer, S. (2021). Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 07-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<mla>Dawid, Herbert, and Gezer, Serhat. &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 07-2021.</mla>
<wels>Dawid, H.; Gezer, S. (2021): Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Dawid H, Gezer S (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 07-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ama>Dawid H, Gezer S. &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 07-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, Herbert, and Gezer, Serhat. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 07-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Dawid, H., Gezer, S.: Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 07-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dawid, H. &amp;amp; Gezer, S. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2952430.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Dawid, and S.  Gezer, &lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dawid H, Gezer S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markov perfect equilibria in multi-mode differential games with endogenous timing of mode transitions&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 07-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952430</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-05T13:39:53Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-18T15:36:25Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>