<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952700</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bogdan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ludusan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">173323916</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Petra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9723026</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6662-3612</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart><namePart type="family">Hillmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart><namePart type="family">Weiss</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Thilo</namePart><namePart type="family">Michael</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart><namePart type="family">Möller</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">18015556</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">We present here an investigation into the use of social laughter in human-machine interaction. We employed an overhearer study, in which the interaction between a virtual real-estate agent and a client visiting an apartment was evaluated. Two conditions were considered, without and with laughter, the only difference between the two cases being the inclusion of laughter, at appropriate locations in the agent's speech, in the latter case. A large pool of participants listened to the recording corresponding to one of the two conditions, while watching a slideshow of the visited apartment. They were asked to judge the interaction of the agent, based on the following dimensions: professionalism, communication, pleasantness, formality and spontaneity, as well as expressing the likelihood of recommending the apartment and the agent to acquaintances. The results showed that the scores of the five dimensions decreased while the apartment and the agent ratings increased, in the laughter case, but only the formality difference reached significance. Nevertheless, a linear regression analysis showed that condition had an effect on the ratings, mainly through interactions with other factors. We discuss these findings and propose further directions of research to be followed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ESSV2021___laughter_virtual_agent.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952700/2952701/ESSV2021___laughter_virtual_agent.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>TUDpress, 2021</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Berlin</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-95908-227-3</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29527004</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>99</number></detail><extent unit="pages">281-288</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Ludusan B, Wagner P (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz. Hillmann S, Weiss B, Michael T, Möller S (Eds);  Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation , 99.  Dresden: TUDpress, 2021:  281-288.</default>
<mla>Ludusan, Bogdan, and Wagner, Petra. “Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent”. &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; Ed. Stefan Hillmann, Benjamin Weiss, Thilo Michael, and Sebastian Möller. Dresden: TUDpress, 2021, 2021.Vol. 99. Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation . 281-288.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ludusan, B., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2021). Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In S.  Hillmann, B.  Weiss, T.  Michael, &amp;amp; S.  Möller (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation : Vol. 99&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 281-288). Dresden: TUDpress, 2021.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Ludusan, B., and Wagner, P. (2021). “Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent” in &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt;, Hillmann, S., Weiss, B., Michael, T., and Möller, S. eds. Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation , vol. 99, (Dresden: TUDpress, 2021), 281-288.</frontiers>
<wels>Ludusan, B.; Wagner, P. (2021): Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In: Stefan Hillmann; Benjamin Weiss; Thilo Michael; Sebastian Möller (Hrsg.):  Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.. Dresden: TUDpress, 2021. (Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation , 99).  S. 281-288.</wels>
<apa>Ludusan, B., &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2021). Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In S.  Hillmann, B.  Weiss, T.  Michael, &amp;amp; S.  Möller (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation : Vol. 99&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 281-288). Dresden: TUDpress, 2021.</apa>
<ieee> B. Ludusan and P. Wagner, “Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent”, &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt;, S. Hillmann, et al., eds., Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation , vol. 99,  Dresden: TUDpress, 2021, 2021,  pp.281-288.</ieee>
<harvard1>Ludusan, B., &amp;amp; Wagner, P., 2021. Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In S.  Hillmann, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation . no.99  Dresden: TUDpress, 2021, pp. 281-288.</harvard1>
<bio1>Ludusan B, Wagner P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz. Hillmann S, Weiss B, Michael T, Möller S (Eds); Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation , 99. Dresden: TUDpress, 2021:  281-288.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Ludusan, and P.  Wagner, in &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: S. Hillmann, B. Weiss, T. Michael, S. Möller), Tudpress, 2021, Dresden, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 281-288.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ludusan, B. &amp;amp; Wagner, P. (2021). Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent (Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation ). In S. Hillmann, B. Weiss, T. Michael &amp;amp; S. Möller (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; (S. 281-288). Gehalten auf der Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021, Dresden: TUDpress, 2021.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Ludusan, Bogdan, and Wagner, Petra. 2021. “Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent”. In &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Stefan Hillmann, Benjamin Weiss, Thilo Michael, and Sebastian Möller, 99:281-288. Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation . Dresden: TUDpress, 2021.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Ludusan, B., Wagner, P.: Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In: Hillmann, S., Weiss, B., Michael, T., and Möller, S. (eds.) Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz. Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation . 99, p. 281-288. TUDpress, 2021, Dresden (2021).</lncs>
<ama>Ludusan B, Wagner P. Knock-Knock! Who's There? The Laughter-Enhanced Virtual Real-Estate Agent. In: Hillmann S, Weiss B, Michael T, Möller S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Elektronische Sprachsignalverarbeitung 2021. Tagungsband der 32. Konferenz.&lt;/em&gt; Studientexte zur Sprachkommunikation . Vol 99. Dresden: TUDpress, 2021;  2021: 281-288.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952700</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-12T18:43:35Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-01T15:43:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>