<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952676</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>

<targetAudience>general</targetAudience>


<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Diana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schüler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Madeleine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gänge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Prinz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kamil J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrona</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">69327627</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-6834-4075</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175763</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The  ongoing  digital  transformation  is  having  an  increasing  impact  on  the economy and society, and the current Covid-19 pandemic seems to accelerate this process. In this paper, we take a look at the implications of the digital transformation in the areas of the health care system, the working  world  and  education  in  Germany  and  South  Korea.  First,  we  introduce the terminology and emphasize the importance of the digital transformation for the economy and society. Then the paper deals with the opportunities and challenges of the digital transformation in each area  in  both  countries.  Overall,  we  conclude  that  the  opportunities  of  the digital transformation can only be exploited if a nation-wide, state-of-the-art digital infrastructure is in place. In the healthcare sector, there is a need for more research, but especially a shift towards higher public acceptance  of  digital  healthcare  seems  necessary.  In  the  workplace,  the  digital  transformation  leads  to  more  telework,  which  needs  to  be  accompanied by training and a legal framework. In education, the use of digital technologies in classrooms should be promoted more strongly and digital skills/digital literacy should become part of the curriculum. In addition to the numerous opportunities, both countries face several challenges that have to be overcome. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Thesenpapier Digitalsierung Final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952676/2960053/Thesenpapier Digitalsierung Final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29526762</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2952676</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">40</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Schüler D, Gänge M, Prinz M, Wrona KJ. &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. Vol 2 1st ed.; 2020.</ama>
<harvard1>Schüler, D., et al., 2020. &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;, Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, no.2, 1st ed.,</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Schüler, et al., &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;, Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, vol. 2, 1st ed., 2020.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schüler, Diana, Gänge, Madeleine, Prinz, Michael, and Wrona, Kamil J. 2020. &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;. 1st ed. Vol. 2. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schüler, D., Gänge, M., Prinz, M., Wrona, K.J.: Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 2, 1st ed. (2020).</lncs>
<apa>Schüler, D., Gänge, M., Prinz, M., &amp;amp; Wrona, K. J. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 2) 1st ed. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952676" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952676&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schüler, D., Gänge, M., Prinz, M. &amp;amp; Wrona, K.J. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea). doi:10.4119/unibi/2952676.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schüler, D., Gänge, M., Prinz, M., &amp;amp; Wrona, K. J. (2020).  &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 2) 1st ed. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952676" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2952676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Schüler, D., Gänge, M., Prinz, M., and Wrona, K. J. (2020). Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea. &lt;em&gt;Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 1st ed.</frontiers>
<mla>Schüler, Diana, Gänge, Madeleine, Prinz, Michael, and Wrona, Kamil J. &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;. 1st ed. 2020. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. 2.</mla>
<wels>Schüler, D.; Gänge, M.; Prinz, M.; Wrona, K. J. (2020): Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea. 1. </wels>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Schüler, M.  Gänge, M.  Prinz, and K. J.  Wrona, &lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Schüler D, Gänge M, Prinz M, Wrona KJ (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zur digitalen Transformation in Deutschland und Südkorea&lt;/em&gt;. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea; 2, 1st ed.</bio1>
<default>Schüler D, Gänge M, Prinz M, Wrona KJ (2020)  Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea; 2, 1st ed.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952676</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-12T12:53:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-05T11:17:29Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>