<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2952526</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:790</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Junior</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Given that elite athletes experience a wide range of different emotions (e.g., anxiety, anger, dejection, excitement) toward upcoming sporting environments, it is surprising that researchers have given limited attention to the linkages between varied emotional experiences and diverse coping (unaccustomed) among athletes from diverse backgrounds. This study investigated the impact of religious coping, as opposed to conventional psychological skills, to ascertain whether these coping options influence elite student-athletes’ emotional reactions across gender, competitive status, and religion. Using a descriptive cross-sectional survey design, self-reported discrete emotions and religious coping were measured with the Sport Emotion Questionnaire (SEQ) and Brief-Religious Coping Scale (Brief RCOPE) after 300 selected athletes were conveniently chosen. A factorial multivariate analysis of covariance (MANCOVA) after controlling for age revealed no significant interactions for between-subject factors (gender, status, religion) across all the discrete emotions and religious coping dimensions. However, significant main effects were realized for competitive status and religion on only anger, anxiety, dejection, and negative religious coping. A follow-up multiple regression analysis identified religion as the most significant predictor of anger, anxiety, and dejection, whereas competitive status was the most associated variable for negative religious coping. Current findings suggest that athletes’ unpleasant or negative emotions were linked to negative religious coping, a maladaptive coping mechanism that may hinder attaining optimal emotional state prior to competition. Therefore, these athletes need purposeful strategies (e.g., positive religious coping, motivational strategies) that may improve weakened beliefs based on their struggles before competition. The development of appropriate psychological intervention framework that maintains respect for athletes’ religious identities for improved psychological well-being is also warranted</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="religions-12-00149-v2.hagan.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2952526/2952594/religions-12-00149-v2.hagan.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>anger</topic><topic>anxiety</topic><topic>dejection</topic><topic>discrete emotions</topic><topic>negative religious coping</topic><topic>student-athletes</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Religions</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2077-1444</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000634197700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29525265</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/rel12030149</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Hagan Junior JE (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt; 12(3): 149.</default>
<mla>Hagan Junior, John Elvis. “Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice”. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt; 12.3 (2021): 149.</mla>
<frontiers>Hagan Junior, J. E. (2021). Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt; 12:149.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Junior, J. E. (2021). Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(3), 149. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/rel12030149" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/rel12030149&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Hagan Junior, J. E. (2021): Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;,12:(3):149</wels>
<apa>Hagan Junior, J. E. (2021). Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(3), 149. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/rel12030149" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/rel12030149&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Hagan Junior, J.E., 2021. Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;, 12(3): 149.</harvard1>
<ieee> J.E. Hagan Junior, “Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice”, &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2021, : 149.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>J. E.  Hagan Junior, “Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice”, &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : 149.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hagan Junior JE (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice.&lt;br /&gt;Religions 12(3): 149.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Junior, J.E. (2021). Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(3): 149. MDPI . doi:10.3390/rel12030149.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Junior, John Elvis. 2021. “Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice”. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt; 12 (3): 149.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Hagan Junior, J.E.: Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. Religions. 12, : 149 (2021).</lncs>
<ama>Hagan Junior JE. Investigating Pre-Competition-Related Discrete Emotions and Unaccustomed Religious Coping among Elite Student-Athletes: Implications for Reflexive Practice. &lt;em&gt;Religions&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;12(3): 149.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2952526</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-09T08:51:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-22T06:43:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>