<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953796</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">17147389</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9251-1075</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meyer zu Borgsen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">50802023</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0887-5672</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sven</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10378</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jasmin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bernotat</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">38373076</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2448-9467</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friederike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eyssel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">140331</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4978-8922</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Goldstone</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Selma</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sebanovic</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart><namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Cord</namePart><namePart type="family">Wiljes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21484764</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">23136503</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Conquaire: Conquaire</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">Studies in human-robot interaction (HRI) typically involve computational artifacts, i.e. the robotic system, as the subject of investigation. Thus, the reproducibility of any result in HRI studies directly relates to the reproducibility of this computational artifact in the first place. This has certain consequences for appropriate workflows that will be discussed in this chapter. We argue for a higher awareness, improved standards, and further automation of tool chains used to conduct robotic experiments. We identify this as a research topic in its own right, especially in cases where robotic systems are used in interdisciplinary research. This inherently includes that technically complex robotic experiments should also be reproducible by scientists with a non-technical background. We analyze and discuss a dedicated study by the CITEC Central Lab Facilities and an international team demonstrating that it is possible to replicate a relatively complex HRI experiment in two different laboratories across the globe by a research assistant with no experience in robotics at all. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="conquaire-book _chapter-10.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953796/2953807/conquaire-book _chapter-10.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Human-Robot Interaction</topic><topic>Reproducibility</topic><topic>Robotic experiments</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-943363-06-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29537967</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">129-144</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2942780</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Wachsmuth, S., Bernotat, J., Eyssel, F., Goldstone, R. &amp;amp; Sebanovic, S. (2021). Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch &amp;amp; C. Wiljes (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (S. 129-144). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Wachsmuth, S., Bernotat, J., Eyssel, F., Goldstone, R., and Sebanovic, S. (2021). “Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study” in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., and Wiljes, C. eds. (Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld), 129-144.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Wachsmuth, S., Bernotat, J., Eyssel, F., Goldstone, R., &amp;amp; Sebanovic, S. (2021). Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-144). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Lier, Florian, Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Wachsmuth, Sven, Bernotat, Jasmin, Eyssel, Friederike, Goldstone, Robert, and Sebanovic, Selma. “Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study”. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, and Cord Wiljes. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021. 129-144.</mla>
<wels>Lier, F.; Meyer zu Borgsen, S.; Wachsmuth, S.; Bernotat, J.; Eyssel, F.; Goldstone, R.; Sebanovic, S. (2021): Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In: Philipp Cimiano; Christian Pietsch; Cord Wiljes (Hrsg.):  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.  S. 129-144.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Lier, S.  Meyer zu Borgsen, S.  Wachsmuth, J.  Bernotat, F.  Eyssel, R.  Goldstone, and S.  Sebanovic, in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, C. Wiljes), Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 129-144.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lier F, Meyer zu Borgsen S, Wachsmuth S, Bernotat J, Eyssel F, Goldstone R, Sebanovic S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C (Eds); Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld:  129-144.</bio1>
<default>Lier F, Meyer zu Borgsen S, Wachsmuth S, Bernotat J, Eyssel F, Goldstone R, Sebanovic S (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C (Eds);  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld:  129-144.</default>
<ama>Lier F, Meyer zu Borgsen S, Wachsmuth S, et al. Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In: Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld;  2021: 129-144.</ama>
<harvard1>Lier, F., et al., 2021. Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, pp. 129-144.</harvard1>
<ieee> F. Lier, et al., “Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study”, &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, and C. Wiljes, eds.,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021,  pp.129-144.</ieee>
<lncs> Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Wachsmuth, S., Bernotat, J., Eyssel, F., Goldstone, R., Sebanovic, S.: Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In: Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., and Wiljes, C. (eds.) Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. p. 129-144. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lier, Florian, Meyer zu Borgsen, Sebastian, Wachsmuth, Sven, Bernotat, Jasmin, Eyssel, Friederike, Goldstone, Robert, and Sebanovic, Selma. 2021. “Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study”. In &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, and Cord Wiljes, 129-144. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Lier, F., Meyer zu Borgsen, S., Wachsmuth, S., Bernotat, J., Eyssel, F., Goldstone, R., &amp;amp; Sebanovic, S. (2021). Reproducibility in Human-Robot Interaction Research: A Case Study. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129-144). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953796</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-10T20:18:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T13:06:41Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>