<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953594</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eugene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Budu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bright Opoku</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wonder</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Agbemavi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James Boadu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frimpong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Collins</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Adu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kwamena Sekyi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dickson</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sanni</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Yaya</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Child marriage has a variety of undesirable consequences at the peril of women’s health and autonomy. In this study, we examined the association between child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in sub-Saharan Africa. We utilised data from the most recent Demographic and Health Surveys conducted in 31 countries in sub-Saharan Africa between 2010 and 2019. A total of 218,578 women aged 20–49 were included in this study. Multivariable binary logistic regression models were used to show the association between child marriage and sexual autonomy. Crude odds ratio (cOR) and adjusted odds ratio (aOR) were used in presenting the results. The prevalence of child marriage and sexual autonomy was 44.51% and 83.35%, respectively. Compared to women who married at 18 years or above, those who married at less than 18 were less likely to have sexual autonomy, and this persisted after controlling for important covariates. In terms of the country-specific results, women who experienced child marriage were less likely to have sexual autonomy in Burundi, Congo DR, Nigeria, and Niger. With the covariates, lower odds of sexual autonomy were found among women with no formal education, those whose partners had no formal education, those who were not exposed to media, and non-working women. Child marriage was found to be associated with sexual autonomy. There is a need to strengthen policies and programmes such as compulsory basic education, poverty alleviation, and an increase in access to media that aim at reducing child marriage. These interventions will help to improve sexual autonomy among women, especially in this 21st century where individuals and organisations incessantly advocate for gender equality.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Hagan202104.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953594/2953637/Hagan202104.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>child marriage</topic><topic>intimate partner violence</topic><topic>public health</topic><topic>sexual autonomy</topic><topic>SSA</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33916845</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000638489700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29535949</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph18073754</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>7</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Budu, E.; Ahinkorah, B. O.; Seidu, A. - A.; Hagan Jr., J. E.; Agbemavi, W.; Frimpong, J. B.; Adu, C.; Dickson, K. S.; Yaya, S. (2021): Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,18:(7):3754</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Budu, B. O.  Ahinkorah, A. - A.  Seidu, J. E.  Hagan Jr., W.  Agbemavi, J. B.  Frimpong, C.  Adu, K. S.  Dickson, and S.  Yaya, “Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 3754.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Budu, E., et al., 2021. Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 18(7): 3754.</harvard1>
<bio1>Budu E, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu A-A, Hagan Jr. JE, Agbemavi W, Frimpong JB, Adu C, Dickson KS, Yaya S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 18(7): 3754.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budu, E., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Agbemavi, W., Frimpong, J. B., Adu, C., et al. (2021). Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(7), 3754. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18073754" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18073754&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budu, E., Ahinkorah, B.O., Seidu, A.-A., Hagan Jr., J.E., Agbemavi, W., Frimpong, J.B., Adu, C., Dickson, K.S. &amp;amp; Yaya, S. (2021). Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(7): 3754. MDPI . doi:10.3390/ijerph18073754.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Budu, E., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Agbemavi, W., Frimpong, J. B., Adu, C., Dickson, K. S., and Yaya, S. (2021). Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18:3754.</frontiers>
<ama>Budu E, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu A-A, et al. Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;18(7): 3754.</ama>
<ieee> E. Budu, et al., “Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2021, : 3754.</ieee>
<apa>Budu, E., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Agbemavi, W., Frimpong, J. B., Adu, C., et al. (2021). Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(7), 3754. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18073754" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18073754&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budu, Eugene, Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Agbemavi, Wonder, Frimpong, James Boadu, Adu, Collins, Dickson, Kwamena Sekyi, and Yaya, Sanni. 2021. “Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18 (7): 3754.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Budu, E., Ahinkorah, B.O., Seidu, A.-A., Hagan Jr., J.E., Agbemavi, W., Frimpong, J.B., Adu, C., Dickson, K.S., Yaya, S.: Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 18, : 3754 (2021).</lncs>
<default>Budu E, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu A-A, Hagan Jr. JE, Agbemavi W, Frimpong JB, Adu C, Dickson KS, Yaya S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18(7): 3754.</default>
<mla>Budu, Eugene, Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Agbemavi, Wonder, Frimpong, James Boadu, Adu, Collins, Dickson, Kwamena Sekyi, and Yaya, Sanni. “Child marriage and sexual autonomy among women in Sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from 31 demographic and health surveys”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18.7 (2021): 3754.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953594</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-06T07:50:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-10-22T14:23:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>