<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953580</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:660.6</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">epub_ahead</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Budde</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gian-Luca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Noll</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">163841</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0748-3423</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jurkiewicz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10045</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The presence of leachables in biopharmaceutical processes using single-use technologies (SUT) is well known. For the detection and quantification of the latter, extractable studies of SUT are very common nowadays. Although a mixture of compounds is regularly found in extractable studies, research has only been carried out regarding the effect of individual compounds on cell culture and the cumulative effect of a mix of leachables has not been investigated yet. In this study, a set of leachable model compounds (LMCs) was chosen and the effect of the LMCs on a Chinese hamster ovary DG44 cell line producing an IgG antibody was investigated concerning cell growth, cell cycle distribution and productivity. It was shown that even if worst-case concentrations were used, the LMCs solely impact cell growth. Additionally, interaction studies revealed that the inhibiting effect of the mix is lower than the expected cumulative effect. A strong antagonism between the antioxidant butylated hydroxytoluene and the plasticizer Tris(2-ethylhexyl)trimellitate was found using an isobologram analysis. © 2021 The Authors. Biotechnology Progress published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Institute of Chemical Engineers.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="btpr.3150.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953580/2956324/btpr.3150.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biotechnology Progress</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1520-6033</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">33773066</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000635599400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29535805</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/btpr.3150</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Budde D, Albano G-L, Noll T, Jurkiewicz E (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;: e3150.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budde, D., Albano, G. - L., Noll, T., &amp;amp; Jurkiewicz, E. (2021). Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;, e3150. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3150" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3150&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Budde, D., Albano, G. - L., Noll, T., and Jurkiewicz, E. (2021). Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;:e3150.</frontiers>
<mla>Budde, Dana, Albano, Gian-Luca, Noll, Thomas, and Jurkiewicz, Elke. “Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt; (2021): e3150.</mla>
<wels>Budde, D.; Albano, G. - L.; Noll, T.; Jurkiewicz, E. (2021): Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;,e3150</wels>
<apa>Budde, D., Albano, G. - L., Noll, T., &amp;amp; Jurkiewicz, E. (2021). Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;, e3150. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3150" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3150&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Budde, D., et al., 2021. Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;, : e3150.</harvard1>
<ieee> D. Budde, et al., “Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;, 2021, : e3150.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Budde, G. - L.  Albano, T.  Noll, and E.  Jurkiewicz, “Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation”, &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, : e3150.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Budde D, Albano G-L, Noll T, Jurkiewicz E (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation.&lt;br /&gt;Biotechnology Progress: e3150.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budde, D., Albano, G.-L., Noll, T. &amp;amp; Jurkiewicz, E. (2021). Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;: e3150. Wiley-Blackwell. doi:10.1002/btpr.3150.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Budde, D., Albano, G.-L., Noll, T., Jurkiewicz, E.: Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. Biotechnology Progress. : e3150 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Budde, Dana, Albano, Gian-Luca, Noll, Thomas, and Jurkiewicz, Elke. 2021. “Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation”. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;: e3150.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Budde D, Albano G-L, Noll T, Jurkiewicz E. Interaction of leachable model compounds and their impact on Chinese hamster ovary cell cultivation. &lt;em&gt;Biotechnology Progress&lt;/em&gt;. 2021: e3150.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953580</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-06T07:37:57Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-19T14:47:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>