<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953603</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eisenberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lukas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fabrykowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maren Diane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84348951</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper, we consider a company that wishes to determine the optimal reinsurance
strategy minimising the total expected discounted amount of capital injections
needed to prevent the ruin. The company's surplus process is assumed to follow a
Brownian motion with drift, and the reinsurance price is modelled by a continuous-time
Markov chain with two states. The presence of regime-switching complicates
substantially the optimal reinsurance problem, as the surplus-independent strategies
turn out to be suboptimal. We develop a recursive approach that allows to
represent a solution to the corresponding Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman equation and
the corresponding reinsurance strategy as the unique limits of the sequence of
solutions to ordinary differential equations and their first and second order derivatives.
Via Ito's formula we prove the constructed function to be the value function.
Two examples illustrate the recursive procedure along with a numerical approach
yielding the direct solution to the HJB equation.</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">Classification: 60K10; 91B30; 60J65; 49K15</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_648.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953603/2953606/IMW_working_paper_648.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Reinsurance</topic><topic>Regime-switching</topic><topic>Brownian motion</topic><topic>Markov chain</topic><topic>Optimal control</topic><topic>HJB equation</topic><topic>Ordinary differential equations</topic><topic>Boundary value problem</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29536033</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>648</number></detail><extent unit="pages">36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2954953</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L. &amp;amp; Schmeck, M.D. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Eisenberg J, Fabrykowski L, Schmeck MD (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 648.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Eisenberg, L.  Fabrykowski, and M. D.  Schmeck, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Eisenberg J, Fabrykowski L, Schmeck MD. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 648. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2021.</ama>
<lncs> Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L., Schmeck, M.D.: Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 648. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eisenberg, Julia, Fabrykowski, Lukas, and Schmeck, Maren Diane. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 648. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Eisenberg, J.; Fabrykowski, L.; Schmeck, M. D. (2021): Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L., &amp;amp; Schmeck, M. D. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 648). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Eisenberg, Julia, Fabrykowski, Lukas, and Schmeck, Maren Diane. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 648.</mla>
<frontiers>Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L., and Schmeck, M. D. (2021). Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 648, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<default>Eisenberg J, Fabrykowski L, Schmeck MD (2021)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 648.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ieee> J. Eisenberg, L. Fabrykowski, and M.D. Schmeck, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 648,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<harvard1>Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L., &amp;amp; Schmeck, M.D., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.648, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa>Eisenberg, J., Fabrykowski, L., &amp;amp; Schmeck, M. D. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Surplus-dependent Reinsurance under Regime-Switching in a Brownian Risk Model&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 648). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953603</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-06T12:21:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>