<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953795</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rebecca M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Foerster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">10428544</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4632-1382</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">15020699</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4771-441X</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Werner X.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schneider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">8139667</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Philipp</namePart><namePart type="family">Cimiano</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Christian</namePart><namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Cord</namePart><namePart type="family">Wiljes</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">15019923</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33694</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>





<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Conquaire: Conquaire</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">project</roleTerm></role>
</name>



<abstract lang="eng">This chapter describes a case study in reproducing work conducted by the neuro-cognitive psychology research group at Bielefeld University in the area of sequential visual processing. In particular, we describe our effort to independently reproduce the results obtained via the experiment conducted in the paper ‘Expectation violations in sensorimotor sequences: shifting from LTM-based attentional selection to visual search’ [1]. The research of the group focuses on the area of visual attention, eye movements, working memory, transsaccadic learning, and sensorimotor learning. The group works on understanding visual processing in humans via controlled behavioral experiments in laboratory environments alongside real-world studies. The main result of the article mentioned above was the finding that expectation violations in a well-learned sensorimotor sequence in humans caused a regression from LTM-based attentional selection to visual search. We describe in this paper our efforts to independently reproduce these results. We conclude that this case is a case of limited analytical reproducibility in that results are reproducible by relying on SPSS as in the original data analysis or by adapting analysis codes to open-source software packages such as R. The data and scripts for this project are available at https: //gitlab.ub.uni-bielefeld.de/conquaire/neurocognitive_psychology. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="conquaire-book _chapter-9.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953795/2953806/conquaire-book _chapter-9.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>attention</topic><topic>eye movements</topic><topic>long-term memory (LTM)</topic><topic>visual search</topic><topic>sensorimotor action</topic><topic>expectation discrepancy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-943363-06-7</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29537954</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">113-127</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2942780</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Foerster, R.M., Cimiano, P., Schneider, W.X.: Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In: Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., and Wiljes, C. (eds.) Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. p. 113-127. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Foerster, Rebecca M., Cimiano, Philipp, and Schneider, Werner X. 2021. “Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing”. In &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, and Cord Wiljes, 113-127. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Foerster, Rebecca M., Cimiano, Philipp, and Schneider, Werner X. “Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing”. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Philipp Cimiano, Christian Pietsch, and Cord Wiljes. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021. 113-127.</mla>
<default>Foerster RM, Cimiano P, Schneider WX (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C (Eds);  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld:  113-127.</default>
<ama>Foerster RM, Cimiano P, Schneider WX. Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In: Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld;  2021: 113-127.</ama>
<frontiers>Foerster, R. M., Cimiano, P., and Schneider, W. X. (2021). “Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing” in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, Cimiano, P., Pietsch, C., and Wiljes, C. eds. (Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld), 113-127.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Foerster, R.M., Cimiano, P. &amp;amp; Schneider, W.X. (2021). Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch &amp;amp; C. Wiljes (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (S. 113-127). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Foerster, R. M., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Schneider, W. X. (2021). Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 113-127). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</apa>
<ieee> R.M. Foerster, P. Cimiano, and W.X. Schneider, “Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing”, &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;, P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, and C. Wiljes, eds.,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021,  pp.113-127.</ieee>
<wels>Foerster, R. M.; Cimiano, P.; Schneider, W. X. (2021): Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In: Philipp Cimiano; Christian Pietsch; Cord Wiljes (Hrsg.):  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.  S. 113-127.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Foerster, R. M., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Schneider, W. X. (2021). Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 113-127). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Foerster RM, Cimiano P, Schneider WX (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project. Cimiano P, Pietsch C, Wiljes C (Eds); Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld:  113-127.</bio1>
<harvard1>Foerster, R.M., Cimiano, P., &amp;amp; Schneider, W.X., 2021. Reproducing the analysis of an experiment in sequential visual processing. In P.  Cimiano, C.  Pietsch, &amp;amp; C.  Wiljes, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, pp. 113-127.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>R. M.  Foerster, P.  Cimiano, and W. X.  Schneider, in &lt;em&gt;Studies in Analytical Reproducibility: the Conquaire Project&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: P. Cimiano, C. Pietsch, C. Wiljes), Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 113-127.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953795</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-10T20:17:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-10T13:06:40Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>