<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953421</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nandeeta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Samad</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pranta</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Das</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bright Opoku</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James Boadu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frimpong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joshua</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Okyere</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Junior</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mohammad Hayatun</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nabi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mohammad Delwer Hossain</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hawlader</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Intimate partner violence has been associated with numerous consequences for women, including pregnancy termination. This study examined the association between predictive capacity of intimate partner violence and pregnancy termination among women in Armenia. The study analyzed the 2015–16 Armenia Demographic and Health Survey (ADHS) data on women aged 15–49 (Mean: 31.49; Standard Deviation, SD: 9.51). Marital control exercised by husbands, ever experienced physical violence, sexual violence, and emotional violence by husbands were the four indicators of intimate partner violence used in this study. To assess the association between intimate partner violence and pregnancy termination, a binary logistic regression model was fitted. After controlling for confounders, we found that women whose husbands exercised marital control were 26% more likely to experience pregnancy termination, compared to women whose husbands did not exercise marital control (adjusted odds ratio (aOR): 1.26, 95% Confidence interval (CI): 1.03–1.53). Women who ever experienced sexual violence were about 10 times likely to experience pregnancy termination than women who did not experience sexual violence (aOR: 9.76, 95% CI: 1.91–49.96). Both ever experienced physical violence and emotional violence did not have any significant associations with pregnancy termination. Forms of intimate partner violence are associated with pregnancy termination. The findings of this study provide evidence for government and policymakers to formulate, modify, and implement policies and program that target both men and women regarding the prevailing intimate partner violence and its consequences. Strengthening the policy implementation will ensure that women are empowered to make decisions about their reproductive health. Making husbands and their family members aware of the basics and consequences of intimate partner violence and focusing on child cognitive development which can be hampered due to the prevalence violence in families are recommended.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Hagan_2021_ejihpe-11-00022-v2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953421/2953452/Hagan_2021_ejihpe-11-00022-v2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Armenia</topic><topic>emotional violence</topic><topic>intimate partner violence</topic><topic>physical violence</topic><topic>pregnancytermination</topic><topic>sexual violence</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2254-9625</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34708813</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000665123700001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29534214</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ejihpe11020022</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">294-303</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Samad, N.; Das, P.; Ahinkorah, B. O.; Seidu, A. - A.; Frimpong, J. B.; Okyere, J.; Hagan Junior, J. E.; Nabi, M. H.; Hawlader, M. D. H. (2021): Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;,11:(2): 294-303.</wels>
<bio1>Samad N, Das P, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu A-A, Frimpong JB, Okyere J, Hagan Junior JE, Nabi MH, Hawlader MDH (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data.&lt;br /&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education 11(2): 294-303.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Samad, N., Das, P., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Frimpong, J. B., Okyere, J., Hagan Junior, J. E., et al. (2021). Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(2), 294-303. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ejihpe11020022" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ejihpe11020022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Samad, N., et al., 2021. Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;, 11(2), p 294-303.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Samad, P.  Das, B. O.  Ahinkorah, A. - A.  Seidu, J. B.  Frimpong, J.  Okyere, J. E.  Hagan Junior, M. H.  Nabi, and M. D. H.  Hawlader, “Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 294-303.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Samad N, Das P, Ahinkorah BO, et al. Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;11(2):294-303.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Samad, N., Das, P., Ahinkorah, B.O., Seidu, A.-A., Frimpong, J.B., Okyere, J., Hagan Junior, J.E., Nabi, M.H. &amp;amp; Hawlader, M.D.H. (2021). Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(2), 294-303. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ejihpe11020022.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Samad, N., Das, P., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Frimpong, J. B., Okyere, J., Hagan Junior, J. E., Nabi, M. H., and Hawlader, M. D. H. (2021). Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt; 11, 294-303.</frontiers>
<apa>Samad, N., Das, P., Ahinkorah, B. O., Seidu, A. - A., Frimpong, J. B., Okyere, J., Hagan Junior, J. E., et al. (2021). Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(2), 294-303. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ejihpe11020022" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ejihpe11020022&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> N. Samad, et al., “Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2021,  pp. 294-303.</ieee>
<lncs> Samad, N., Das, P., Ahinkorah, B.O., Seidu, A.-A., Frimpong, J.B., Okyere, J., Hagan Junior, J.E., Nabi, M.H., Hawlader, M.D.H.: Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data. European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education. 11, 294-303 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Samad, Nandeeta, Das, Pranta, Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Frimpong, James Boadu, Okyere, Joshua, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Nabi, Mohammad Hayatun, and Hawlader, Mohammad Delwer Hossain. 2021. “Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt; 11 (2): 294-303.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Samad, Nandeeta, Das, Pranta, Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Frimpong, James Boadu, Okyere, Joshua, Hagan Junior, John Elvis, Nabi, Mohammad Hayatun, and Hawlader, Mohammad Delwer Hossain. “Intimate Partner Violence and Pregnancy Termination in Armenia: Evidence from Nationally-Representative Survey Data”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt; 11.2 (2021): 294-303.</mla>
<default>Samad N, Das P, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu A-A, Frimpong JB, Okyere J, Hagan Junior JE, Nabi MH, Hawlader MDH (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology and Education&lt;/em&gt; 11(2): 294-303.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953421</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-29T10:50:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-02T10:30:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>