<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953430</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Verena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Penning</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">200293595</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oliver</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Razum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">134970</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>PH-LENS research group - Refugee Migration to Germany: a magnifying glass for broader Public Health challenges</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">research group</roleTerm></role>
</name>




<abstract lang="eng">Housing is considered an important social determinant of health. In the context of refugee
migration, living in one’s own apartment is a key indicator of successful integration. The type
of housing in which refugees are accommodated, however, varies widely. Empirically,
measuring health-related attributes of accommodation is challenging. The (international)
refugee camp context has been focused on from various fields of research, often drawing on
particular theoretical concepts. In this article, these theoretical concepts – mainly based on the
work of Hannah Arendt, Erving Goffman, Michel Foucault and Giorgio Agamben – form the
basis for developing a broad analytical framework of refugee accommodation. Housing in the
context of refugee accommodation must be understood from four dimensions, including the
broader political context, the immediate surroundings of the accommodation and its’ physical
and social boundaries, and the structures and processes inside the accommodation that may
establish means of social control. As the conditions on each of these three dimensions can
affect individuals differently, a fourth, individual dimension complements this analytical
framework by a subjective evaluation of the overall living situation. The framework provides a
multidimensional approach to assess the context of refugee accommodation which then can
be used to systematically analyse health associations. The relevance the dimensions and
contextual factors of this framework have on health is supported by empirical evidence as well
as conceptual approaches.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PH-LENS_WP_No1_PenningRazum2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953430/2953451/PH-LENS_WP_No1_PenningRazum2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2702-2676</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29534308</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2953430</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Penning, Verena, and Razum, Oliver. &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021. PH-LENS Working Paper Series. 1.</mla>
<default>Penning V, Razum O (2021)  PH-LENS Working Paper Series; 1.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<lncs> Penning, V., Razum, O.: An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective. PH-LENS Working Paper Series, 1. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Penning, Verena, and Razum, Oliver. 2021. &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 1. PH-LENS Working Paper Series. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Penning, V., &amp;amp; Razum, O., 2021. &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;, PH-LENS Working Paper Series, no.1, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Penning, V., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt; (PH-LENS Working Paper Series, 1). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953430" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953430&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Penning V, Razum O (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;. PH-LENS Working Paper Series; 1.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Penning, and O.  Razum, &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Penning, V.; Razum, O. (2021): An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<apa>Penning, V., &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt; (PH-LENS Working Paper Series, 1). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953430" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953430&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> V. Penning and O. Razum, &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;, PH-LENS Working Paper Series, vol. 1,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021.</ieee>
<ama>Penning V, Razum O. &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt;. PH-LENS Working Paper Series. Vol 1. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Penning, V., and Razum, O. (2021). An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective. &lt;em&gt;PH-LENS Working Paper Series&lt;/em&gt;, 1, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Penning, V. &amp;amp; Razum, O. (2021). &lt;em&gt;An analytical framework for assessing types of refugee accommodation from a public health perspective&lt;/em&gt; (PH-LENS Working Paper Series). Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2953430.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953430</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-29T14:33:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-31T06:55:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>