<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2953460</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>

<targetAudience>general</targetAudience>


<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ariane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Odendahl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Madeleine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gänge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nicolas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Raschke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Kamil J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wrona</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">69327627</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-6834-4075</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175763</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">When discussing the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on public health, it is important to consider not only the direct consequences, but also the indirect effects. In addition to aspects such as the Post-Covid-Syndrome (Long-Covid) or the PIMS-Syndrome (especially affecting children), there are serious effects on mental health as well. Children and adolescents tend to be the most affected. Necessary restrictions in social life have far-reaching  effects  on  the  developmental  processes  of  young  people.  In  addition, the COVID-19 pandemic exposes existing economic or social inequalities  in  our  society.  For  example,  the  multi-layered  demands  and  overburdens  of  the  crisis  on  parents  and  guardians  increase  the  risk of physical and emotional abuse among children and adolescents. As a result, mental and psychosomatic disorders are increasing among the younger generation. Furthermore, social inequalities are widening. Thus, young women and children from poverty-stricken families are most likely to suffer the negative consequences of the pandemic. Moreover, the social relationships of those who need them the most for their own personal development suffer. And alternative communication via social media is no substitute for „real“ interpersonal relationships. A society-wide  approach  is  needed  to  reduce  mental  burdens  and,  if  possible,  to counteract them preventively. To achieve this, more importance has to be assigned to the mental health of young people, especially at the political level. However, in order to finally develop adequate solutions and take appropriate measures, the participation of all stakeholders in the health care system is required.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Thesenpapier-Covid Psyche Final.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2953460/2960055/Thesenpapier-Covid Psyche Final.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>COVID-19</topic><topic>Mental Health</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29534607</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2953460</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">29</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Odendahl, Ariane, Gänge, Madeleine, Raschke, Nicolas, and Wrona, Kamil J. &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;. 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 2021. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. 3.</mla>
<default>Odendahl A, Gänge M, Raschke N, Wrona KJ (2021)  Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea; 3, 1st ed.&lt;br /&gt;Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.</default>
<lncs> Odendahl, A., Gänge, M., Raschke, N., Wrona, K.J.: COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 3, 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Odendahl, Ariane, Gänge, Madeleine, Raschke, Nicolas, and Wrona, Kamil J. 2021. &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;. 1st ed. Vol. 3. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Odendahl A, Gänge M, Raschke N, Wrona KJ (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea; 3, 1st ed.&lt;br /&gt;Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.</bio1>
<harvard1>Odendahl, A., et al., 2021. &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;, Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, no.3, 1st ed., Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Odendahl, A., Gänge, M., Raschke, N., &amp;amp; Wrona, K. J. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 3) 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953460" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Odendahl, M.  Gänge, N.  Raschke, and K. J.  Wrona, &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;, Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Odendahl, A.; Gänge, M.; Raschke, N.; Wrona, K. J. (2021): COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen. 1.  Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.</wels>
<apa>Odendahl, A., Gänge, M., Raschke, N., &amp;amp; Wrona, K. J. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 3) 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953460" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2953460&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> A. Odendahl, et al., &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;, Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, vol. 3, 1st ed., Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea, 2021.</ieee>
<ama>Odendahl A, Gänge M, Raschke N, Wrona KJ. &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt;. Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. Vol 3 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Odendahl, A., Gänge, M., Raschke, N., and Wrona, K. J. (2021). COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen. &lt;em&gt;Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea&lt;/em&gt;, 3, 1st ed. Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Odendahl, A., Gänge, M., Raschke, N. &amp;amp; Wrona, K.J. (2021). &lt;em&gt;COVID-19 und die Psyche: Auswirkungen der Pandemie auf die mentale Gesundheit der jungen Generationen&lt;/em&gt; (Thesenpapiere Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea). Netzwerk Junge Generation Deutschland-Korea. doi:10.4119/unibi/2953460.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2953460</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-03-30T18:35:18Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-06T22:05:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>