<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2954817</id><setSpec>conference_abstract</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:other</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conference_abstractFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jochen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schirrwagen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7323749</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0458-1004</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cord</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wiljes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27436085</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2528-5391</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pietsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7346775</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-8778-1273</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nils</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hachmeister</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">23232875</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5400-1522</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Czerniak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">136739224</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3883-4169</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>Open Science Conference 2020</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">&lt;p&gt;We understand the digital transformation of science as a socio-technical process in which digital tools&lt;br&gt;
and infrastructure go hand in hand with a (social) opening of essential phases of publicly funded&lt;br&gt;
research and teaching, taking into account subject-specific cultures. One can mandate this process from&lt;br&gt;
the top down, but in our experience a bottom up approach by researchers for researchers with the&lt;br&gt;
support of central facilities on the campus such as computing centre and library is more promising for&lt;br&gt;
the practice of an open scientific culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our opinion, the home institutions of the researchers have to play an important role in this&lt;br&gt;
transformative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Policies on Open Access, on the management of research data and an Open Science Manifesto also&lt;br&gt;
provide the institutional framework at our institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this transformation process has only gained momentum with the establishment of an Open Access&lt;br&gt;
Task Force, now renamed into the Open Science Task Force, which brings together active members of&lt;br&gt;
various faculties and university institutions for almost ten years. This think tank meets regularly every&lt;br&gt;
two weeks and develops new ideas to support Open Science transformation up to its implementation in&lt;br&gt;
research projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group is an important driving force for the entire university which has to provide an infrastructure&lt;br&gt;
of services and tools for data publishing integrated seamlessly in the research process, efficient support&lt;br&gt;
to minimize the additional workload for researchers, policy and communication to raise awareness, and&lt;br&gt;
incentives to motivate data publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, our university has consistently expanded its activities to include Open Science. Services for&lt;br&gt;
researchers include an institutional repository for publishing data, a GitLab installation that can&lt;br&gt;
perform automated data quality checks, and virtual research environments designed specifically for&lt;br&gt;
research projects. Particular attention was paid to integrating data management and open science into&lt;br&gt;
student education. A full-semester seminar has been offered for seven consecutive years and is included&lt;br&gt;
as an elective module in several degree programs. This is complemented by sharing of successful&lt;br&gt;
solutions with other universities and the adoption of promising approaches by others. We plan to&lt;br&gt;
present our overall approach to Open Science and the solutions developed so far, all of which are ready&lt;br&gt;
for reuse.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="OSC2020_13-1_Poster.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2954817/2954818/OSC2020_13-1_Poster.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Berlin, Germany</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Service Infrastructure</topic><topic>Policy</topic><topic>Training and Support</topic><topic>Working Group</topic><topic>Community Building</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29548174</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3776793</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Schirrwagen, J., Wiljes, C., Pietsch, C., Hachmeister, N., &amp;amp; Czerniak, A. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3776793" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3776793&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> J. Schirrwagen, et al., “Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy”, Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany, 2020.</ieee>
<ama>Schirrwagen J, Wiljes C, Pietsch C, Hachmeister N, Czerniak A. Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany.</ama>
<frontiers>Schirrwagen, J., Wiljes, C., Pietsch, C., Hachmeister, N., and Czerniak, A. (2020).“Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy”. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schirrwagen, J., Wiljes, C., Pietsch, C., Hachmeister, N. &amp;amp; Czerniak, A. (2020). Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy. Gehalten auf der Open Science Conference 2020. doi:10.5281/zenodo.3776793.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Schirrwagen, J., et al., 2020. Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schirrwagen, J., Wiljes, C., Pietsch, C., Hachmeister, N., &amp;amp; Czerniak, A. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3776793" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3776793&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Schirrwagen J, Wiljes C, Pietsch C, Hachmeister N, Czerniak A (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy. &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Schirrwagen, C.  Wiljes, C.  Pietsch, N.  Hachmeister, and A.  Czerniak, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Schirrwagen, J.; Wiljes, C.; Pietsch, C.; Hachmeister, N.; Czerniak, A. (2020): Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy.</wels>
<mla>Schirrwagen, Jochen, Wiljes, Cord, Pietsch, Christian, Hachmeister, Nils, and Czerniak, Andreas. “Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy”. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany, 2020.</mla>
<default>Schirrwagen J, Wiljes C, Pietsch C, Hachmeister N, Czerniak A (2020)  &lt;br /&gt;Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany.</default>
<lncs> Schirrwagen, J., Wiljes, C., Pietsch, C., Hachmeister, N., Czerniak, A.: Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Schirrwagen, Jochen, Wiljes, Cord, Pietsch, Christian, Hachmeister, Nils, and Czerniak, Andreas. 2020. “Catalyzing the Open Science Transformation by an Institutional Strategy”. Presented at the Open Science Conference 2020, Berlin, Germany .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2954817</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-15T23:43:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-15T23:47:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>