<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2954607</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marjan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Haghighi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Caradee</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wright</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ayer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Urban</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Minh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pham</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Melanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Böckmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">165672182</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-5909-5508</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ashtyn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Areal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bianca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wernecke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Callum</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Swift</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthew</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Robinson</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Robyn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hetem</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthew</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chersich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175761</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Links between heat exposure and congenital anomalies have not been explored in detail despite animal data and other strands of evidence that indicate such links are likely. We reviewed articles on heat and congenital anomalies from PubMed and Web of Science, screening 14,880 titles and abstracts in duplicate for articles on environmental heat exposure during pregnancy and congenital anomalies. Thirteen studies were included. Most studies were in North America (8) or the Middle East (3). Methodological diversity was considerable, including in temperature measurement, gestational windows of exposure, and range of defects studied. Associations were detected between heat exposure and congenital cardiac anomalies in three of six studies, with point estimates highest for atrial septal defects. Two studies with null findings used self-reported temperature exposures. Hypospadias, congenital cataracts, renal agenesis/hypoplasia, spina bifida, and craniofacial defects were also linked with heat exposure. Effects generally increased with duration and intensity of heat exposure. However, some neural tube defects, gastroschisis, anopthalmia/microphthalmia and congenital hypothyroidism were less frequent at higher temperatures. While findings are heterogenous, the evidence raises important concerns about heat exposure and birth defects. Some heterogeneity may be explained by biases in reproductive epidemiology. Pooled analyses of heat impacts using registers of congenital anomalies are a high priority.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijerph-18-04910-v2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2954607/2955556/ijerph-18-04910-v2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34063033</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000650264900001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29546079</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph18094910</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>9</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Haghighi, C.  Wright, J.  Ayer, M.  Urban, M.  Pham, M.  Böckmann, A.  Areal, B.  Wernecke, C.  Swift, M.  Robinson, et al., “Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 4910.</angewandte-chemie>
<harvard1>Haghighi, M., et al., 2021. Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 18(9): 4910.</harvard1>
<bio1>Haghighi M, Wright C, Ayer J, Urban M, Pham M, Böckmann M, Areal A, Wernecke B, Swift C, Robinson M, Hetem R, Chersich M (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 18(9): 4910.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haghighi, M., Wright, C., Ayer, J., Urban, M., Pham, M., Böckmann, M., Areal, A., et al. (2021). Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(9), 4910. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094910" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094910&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Haghighi, M.; Wright, C.; Ayer, J.; Urban, M.; Pham, M.; Böckmann, M.; Areal, A.; Wernecke, B.; Swift, C.; Robinson, M.; Hetem, R.; Chersich, M. (2021): Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,18:(9):4910</wels>
<ieee> M. Haghighi, et al., “Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2021, : 4910.</ieee>
<apa>Haghighi, M., Wright, C., Ayer, J., Urban, M., Pham, M., Böckmann, M., Areal, A., et al. (2021). Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(9), 4910. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094910" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094910&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haghighi, M., Wright, C., Ayer, J., Urban, M., Pham, M., Böckmann, M., Areal, A., Wernecke, B., Swift, C., Robinson, M., Hetem, R. &amp;amp; Chersich, M. (2021). Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(9): 4910. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph18094910.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Haghighi, M., Wright, C., Ayer, J., Urban, M., Pham, M., Böckmann, M., Areal, A., Wernecke, B., Swift, C., Robinson, M., et al. (2021). Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18:4910.</frontiers>
<ama>Haghighi M, Wright C, Ayer J, et al. Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;18(9): 4910.</ama>
<default>Haghighi M, Wright C, Ayer J, Urban M, Pham M, Böckmann M, Areal A, Wernecke B, Swift C, Robinson M, Hetem R, et al. (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18(9): 4910.</default>
<mla>Haghighi, Marjan, Wright, Caradee, Ayer, Julian, Urban, Michael, Pham, Minh, Böckmann, Melanie, Areal, Ashtyn, Wernecke, Bianca, Swift, Callum, Robinson, Matthew, Hetem, Robyn, and Chersich, Matthew. “Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18.9 (2021): 4910.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Haghighi, Marjan, Wright, Caradee, Ayer, Julian, Urban, Michael, Pham, Minh, Böckmann, Melanie, Areal, Ashtyn, et al. 2021. “Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18 (9): 4910.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Haghighi, M., Wright, C., Ayer, J., Urban, M., Pham, M., Böckmann, M., Areal, A., Wernecke, B., Swift, C., Robinson, M., Hetem, R., Chersich, M.: Impacts of High Environmental Temperatures on Congenital Anomalies: A Systematic Review. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 18, : 4910 (2021).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2954607</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-07T15:50:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-14T16:33:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>