<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2954087</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:796</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mario</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wendtlandt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pamela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wicker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">183572443</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977996</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This study examined the effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on the subjective well-being of working-age adults (18-64). Specifically, it analyzes the effects of different types of sport activities, including nature-based, natural resource-using, and nature-neutral sport activities and different types of environmentally sustainable behaviors such as recycling, ecological consumption, energy-saving, and mobility on subjective well-being. The study conducts comparisons between the period before the COVID-19 pandemic and during the first lockdown in Germany. Quantitative survey data were collected using a convenience sampling approach (n=412). Sport activities were captured with the number of hours spent on nature-based, natural resource-using, and nature-neutral activities. Environmentally sustainable behaviors were measured across four areas, including recycling, ecological consumption, energy-saving, and mobility. Subjective well-being was measured using the scale of the World Health Organization (WHO-5). Differences between the periods before and during COVID-19 were analyzed using t-tests. A set of multivariate regression models was estimated with subjective well-being as the dependent variable and sport activities, environmentally sustainable behaviors, and socio-demographics as independent variables. The results show that nature-based and nature-neutral sport activities significantly decreased during the first COVID-19 lockdown, while environmentally sustainable behaviors increased. The regression analyzes reveal that nature-based and nature-neutral sport activities as well as ecological consumption significantly added to individuals’ well-being in the pre- and during-COVID-19-period. A decrease in nature-based and nature-neutral sport activities significantly predicted a decrease in individuals’ subjective well-being. The findings of this study might help people understand the role and importance of active living for psychosocial outcomes during the COVID-19 pandemic. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="PUB-ok_Wickerfspor-03-659837.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2954087/2955132/PUB-ok_Wickerfspor-03-659837.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>environment</topic><topic>nature</topic><topic>sport participation</topic><topic>sustainability</topic><topic>Well-being</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Sports and Active Living</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2624-9367</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34109311</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29540870</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 </identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>3</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Wendtlandt M, Wicker P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt; 3: 659837.</default>
<bio1>Wendtlandt M, Wicker P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living 3: 659837.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Wendtlandt, and P.  Wicker, “The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, : 659837.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Wendtlandt, M.; Wicker, P. (2021): The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19 &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;,3:659837</wels>
<frontiers>Wendtlandt, M., and Wicker, P. (2021). The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt; 3:659837.</frontiers>
<mla>Wendtlandt, Mario, and Wicker, Pamela. “The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt; 3 (2021): 659837.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wendtlandt, M., &amp;amp; Wicker, P. (2021). The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 659837. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 " target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wendtlandt, M. &amp;amp; Wicker, P. (2021). The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;: 659837. Frontiers. doi:10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 .&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Wendtlandt, M., &amp;amp; Wicker, P. (2021). The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 659837. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 " target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.659837 &lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<lncs> Wendtlandt, M., Wicker, P.: The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. Frontiers in Sports and Active Living. 3, : 659837 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Wendtlandt, Mario, and Wicker, Pamela. 2021. “The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt; 3: 659837.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> M. Wendtlandt and P. Wicker, “The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 3, 2021, : 659837.</ieee>
<harvard1>Wendtlandt, M., &amp;amp; Wicker, P., 2021. The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;, 3: 659837.</harvard1>
<ama>Wendtlandt M, Wicker P. The effects of sport activities and environmentally sustainable behaviors on subjective well-being: A comparison before and during COVID-19. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Sports and Active Living&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;3: 659837.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2954087</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-04-20T09:57:44Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-14T14:35:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>