<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2954860</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Owusu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bökemeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5537351</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper empirically studies public debt sustainability with the penalized panel
splines approach for 25 EU economies from 2000 to 2019 by estimating the response
of the primary surplus to lagged debt relative to GDP, respectively. A positive
coecient on average indicates sustainable policies, which is supported by all our
results. Moreover, we show that this relationship is not homogeneous across the
distribution of the debt ratios, but, varies with the magnitude of public debt to
GDP. The estimations reveal a strongly increasing reaction for small and high debt
ratios while it is rather flat for intermediate levels. This holds for normal times, too,
whereas during years of economic crises a monotonously increasing response can be
observed. Additionally, for a cluster consisting of smaller EU economies, there is
indication of 'fiscal fatigue', meaning that the effort of active fiscal counter-steering
peters out for high ratios of public debt to GDP. The same effect can be observed for
the whole sample and for a sample including the large EU economies, once Greece
is removed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_10_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2954860/2954861/wpaper_10_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Debt sustainability</topic><topic>fiscal response function</topic><topic>panel spline estimation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29548606</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2954860</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">27</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B., Greiner, A.: Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, Benjamin, Bökemeier, Bettina, and Greiner, Alfred. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 10-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Owusu, Benjamin, Bökemeier, Bettina, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 10-2021.</mla>
<default>Owusu B, Bökemeier B, Greiner A (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<ama>Owusu B, Bökemeier B, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 10-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2954860.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B., and Greiner, A. (2021). Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 10-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2954860" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2954860&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> B. Owusu, B. Bökemeier, and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 10-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<wels>Owusu, B.; Bökemeier, B.; Greiner, A. (2021): Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Owusu B, Bökemeier B, Greiner A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 10-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.10-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Owusu, B., Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 10-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2954860" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2954860&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Owusu, B.  Bökemeier, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Assessing non-linearities and heterogeneity in debt sustainability analysis: A panel spline approach&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2954860</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-05-18T09:17:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-18T15:08:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>