<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2955537</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Isabel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Brand</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Leonard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gilberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merce</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wieser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tabea M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jonathan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frese</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mohamed I M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahmed</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raquel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Rubio-Acero</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jessica M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Guggenbuehl Noller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Noemi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Castelletti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jana</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Diekmannshemke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">516c5573-ceca-4ee9-bdf3-ed6ac83e59af</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sophie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thiesbrummel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Duc</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huynh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Simon</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Inge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kroidl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fuchs</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">122077231</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3565-8315</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hoelscher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Roider</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kobold</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pritsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christof</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Geldmacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">123191762</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Adaptive immune responses to structural proteins of the virion play a crucial role in protection against coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). We therefore studied T cell responses against multiple SARS-CoV-2 structural proteins in a large cohort using a simple, fast, and high-throughput approach.; Methods: An automated interferon gamma release assay (IGRA) for the Nucleocapsid (NC)-, Membrane (M)-, Spike-C-terminus (SCT)-, and N-terminus-protein (SNT)-specific T cell responses was performed using fresh whole blood from study subjects with convalescent, confirmed COVID-19 (n = 177, more than 200 days post infection), exposed household members (n = 145), and unexposed controls (n = 85). SARS-CoV-2-specific antibodies were assessed using ElecsysAnti-SARS-CoV-2 (Ro-N-Ig) and Anti-SARS-CoV-2-ELISA (IgG) (EI-S1-IgG).; Results: 156 of 177 (88%) previously PCR confirmed cases were still positive by Ro-N-Ig more than 200 days after infection. In T cells, most frequently the M-protein was targeted by 88% seropositive, PCR confirmed cases, followed by SCT (85%), NC (82%), and SNT (73%), whereas each of these antigens was recognized by less than 14% of non-exposed control subjects. Broad targeting of these structural virion proteins was characteristic of convalescent SARS-CoV-2 infection; 68% of all seropositive individuals targeted all four tested antigens. Indeed, anti-NC antibody titer correlated loosely, but significantly with the magnitude and breadth of the SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell response. Age, sex, and body mass index were comparable between the different groups.; Conclusion: SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity correlates with broad T cell reactivity of the structural virus proteins at 200 days after infection and beyond. The SARS-CoV-2-IGRA can facilitate large scale determination of SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell responses with high accuracy against multiple targets. Copyright © 2021 Brand, Gilberg, Bruger, Gari, Wieser, Eser, Frese, Ahmed, Rubio-Acero, Guggenbuehl Noller, Castelletti, Diekmannshemke, Thiesbrummel, Huynh, Winter, Kroidl, Fuchs, Hoelscher, Roider, Kobold, Pritsch and Geldmacher.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fimmu-12-688436.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2955537/2955549/fimmu-12-688436.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Immunology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-3224</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34093595</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000657293400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29555375</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brand, Isabel, Gilberg, Leonard, Bruger, Jan, Gari, Merce, Wieser, Andreas, Eser, Tabea M, Frese, Jonathan, et al. 2021. “Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 688436.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Brand, I., Gilberg, L., Bruger, J., Gari, M., Wieser, A., Eser, T.M., Frese, J., Ahmed, M.I.M., Rubio-Acero, R., Guggenbuehl Noller, J.M., Castelletti, N., Diekmannshemke, J., Thiesbrummel, S., Huynh, D., Winter, S., Kroidl, I., Fuchs, C., Hoelscher, M., Roider, J., Kobold, S., Pritsch, M., Geldmacher, C.: Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. Frontiers in Immunology. 12, : 688436 (2021).</lncs>
<default>Brand I, Gilberg L, Bruger J, Gari M, Wieser A, Eser TM, Frese J, Ahmed MIM, Rubio-Acero R, Guggenbuehl Noller JM, Castelletti N, et al. (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 688436.</default>
<mla>Brand, Isabel, Gilberg, Leonard, Bruger, Jan, Gari, Merce, Wieser, Andreas, Eser, Tabea M, Frese, Jonathan, Ahmed, Mohamed I M, Rubio-Acero, Raquel, Guggenbuehl Noller, Jessica M, Castelletti, Noemi, Diekmannshemke, Jana, Thiesbrummel, Sophie, Huynh, Duc, Winter, Simon, Kroidl, Inge, Fuchs, Christiane, Hoelscher, Michael, Roider, Julia, Kobold, Sebastian, Pritsch, Michael, and Geldmacher, Christof. “Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt; 12 (2021): 688436.</mla>
<frontiers>Brand, I., Gilberg, L., Bruger, J., Gari, M., Wieser, A., Eser, T. M., Frese, J., Ahmed, M. I. M., Rubio-Acero, R., Guggenbuehl Noller, J. M., et al. (2021). Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt; 12:688436.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brand, I., Gilberg, L., Bruger, J., Gari, M., Wieser, A., Eser, T.M., Frese, J., Ahmed, M.I.M., Rubio-Acero, R., Guggenbuehl Noller, J.M., Castelletti, N., Diekmannshemke, J., Thiesbrummel, S., Huynh, D., Winter, S., Kroidl, I., Fuchs, C., Hoelscher, M., Roider, J., Kobold, S., Pritsch, M. &amp;amp; Geldmacher, C. (2021). Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;: 688436. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Brand I, Gilberg L, Bruger J, et al. Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;12: 688436.</ama>
<ieee> I. Brand, et al., “Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2021, : 688436.</ieee>
<apa>Brand, I., Gilberg, L., Bruger, J., Gari, M., Wieser, A., Eser, T. M., Frese, J., et al. (2021). Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 688436. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Brand, I.; Gilberg, L.; Bruger, J.; Gari, M.; Wieser, A.; Eser, T. M.; Frese, J.; Ahmed, M. I. M.; Rubio-Acero, R.; Guggenbuehl Noller, J. M.; Castelletti, N.; Diekmannshemke, J.; Thiesbrummel, S.; Huynh, D.; Winter, S.; Kroidl, I.; Fuchs, C.; Hoelscher, M.; Roider, J.; Kobold, S.; Pritsch, M.; Geldmacher, C. (2021): Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;,12:688436</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Brand, L.  Gilberg, J.  Bruger, M.  Gari, A.  Wieser, T. M.  Eser, J.  Frese, M. I. M.  Ahmed, R.  Rubio-Acero, J. M.  Guggenbuehl Noller, et al., “Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : 688436.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Brand, I., Gilberg, L., Bruger, J., Gari, M., Wieser, A., Eser, T. M., Frese, J., et al. (2021). Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 688436. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.688436&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Brand I, Gilberg L, Bruger J, Gari M, Wieser A, Eser TM, Frese J, Ahmed MIM, Rubio-Acero R, Guggenbuehl Noller JM, Castelletti N, Diekmannshemke J, Thiesbrummel S, Huynh D, Winter S, Kroidl I, Fuchs C, Hoelscher M, Roider J, Kobold S, Pritsch M, Geldmacher C (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Immunology 12: 688436.</bio1>
<harvard1>Brand, I., et al., 2021. Broad T Cell Targeting of Structural Proteins After SARS-CoV-2 Infection: High Throughput Assessment of T Cell Reactivity Using an Automated Interferon Gamma Release Assay. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Immunology&lt;/em&gt;, 12: 688436.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2955537</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-14T07:51:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-27T14:18:27Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>