<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2955304</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:410</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frederic</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zähres</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">70569599</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-6570-7128</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ISLE 6 - Evolving English and the Digital Era</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">Over the last couple of years, Namibia has been receiving increased attention by World Englishes (WE) researchers (cf. Buschfeld &amp; Kautzsch 2014; Stell 2016; Steigertahl 2019; Schröder fc.2021) and Namibian Englishes (NamEs) are slowly emerging from South Africa’s shadow. Namibia constitutes an interesting case in the WE context as its status as post-colonial variety of English is debatable or very atypical, to say the least, and, thus, presents a challenge for WE models (cf. Buschfeld &amp; Kautzsch 2017; Schröder &amp; Zähres 2020). Recent studies have also shown that NamEs should not simply be understood as being “of a South African type” (Trudgill &amp; Hannah 2017: 127) since uniquely Namibian features appear to exist on the levels of lexicon and morpho-syntax (cf. Kautzsch 2019), pragmatics (cf. Schröder &amp; Schneider 2018) as well as regarding phonetic and phonological variation (cf. Kautzsch &amp; Schröder 2016). Also, NamE is not a monolithic entity and subject to intranational variation as suggested by recent phonetic and phonological studies (cf. Stell &amp; Fuchs 2019; Schröder et al. 2020; Schröder et al. fc.2021). At this point, the question of norms remains, however – i.e. which variety of NamE is regarded as the nation’s norm variety and how much exo- or endonormative influence is present in Namibia?

The video sharing platform YouTube has received even less attention than NamE in the WE context despite its world-wide omnipresence and wealth of multimodal data. While it can be tricky to navigate for researchers (cf. Schneider 2016), YouTube offers a variety of data types that can differ immensely from data found in traditional mass media or elicited via
(socio-)linguistic methods and, thus, complement existing approaches to paint a more complex picture for inquiries in variational linguistics and WE research in particular (cf. e.g. Lee 2017; Rüdiger 2020; Zähres fc.2021).

This study investigates phonological norms of NamE by analyzing speakers’ vowel spaces in two different types of YouTube data via acoustic phonetic means: a) formal news reports by the Namibian Broadcasting Corporation and b) informal vlogs by Namibian YouTubers. Both types of data shed light on the performance of (endo-)normative realizations of NamE, which especially highlight the similarities and contrasts to South African Englishes as well as previous studies on ethnic varieties of NamE.

References
Buschfeld, Sarah &amp; Alexander Kautzsch. 2014. English in Namibia: A first approach. English World-Wide 35(2). 121-160.
Buschfeld, Sarah &amp; Alexander Kautzsch. 2017. Towards an integrated approach to postcolonial and non-postcolonial Englishes. World Englishes 36(1). 104-126.
Kautzsch, Alexander. 2019. Namibian English on the web: Lexical and morphosyntactic features in a Corpus of Namibian Online Newspapers (CNamON). In Esimaje, Alexandra U., Ulrike Gut &amp; Bassey E. Antia (eds.), Corpus linguistics and African Englishes, 232-258. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.
Kautzsch, Alexander &amp; Anne Schröder. 2016. English in multilingual and multiethnic Namibia: Some evidence on language attitudes and on the pronunciation of vowels. In Ehland, Christoph, Ilka Mindt, &amp; Merle Tönnies (eds.), Anglistentag 2015 Paderborn: Proceedings, 277-288. Trier: Wissenschaftlicher Verlag Trier.
Lee, Sarah. 2017. Style-shifting in vlogging: An acoustic analysis of “YouTube voice.” Lifespans and Styles 3(1). 28-39.
Rüdiger, Sofia. 2020. Dinner for one: The use of language in eating shows on YouTube. In Rüdiger, Sofia &amp; Susanne Mühleisen (eds.), Talking about food: The social and the global in eating communities, 145-165. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.
Schneider, Edgar W. 2016. World Englishes on YouTube: Treasure trove or nightmare? In Seoane, Elena &amp; Cristina Suárez-Gómez (eds.), World Englishes: New theoretical and methodological considerations, 253-282. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.
Schröder, Anne (ed.). fc.2021. The dynamics of English in Namibia. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.
Schröder, Anne &amp; Klaus P. Schneider. 2018. Variational pragmatics, responses to thanks, and the specificity of English in Namibia. English World-Wide 39(3). 338-363.
Schröder, Anne &amp; Frederic Zähres. 2020. English in Namibia: Multilingualism and ethnic variation in the Extra- and Intra-territorial Forces Model. In Buschfeld, Sarah &amp; Alexander Kautzsch (eds.), Modelling World Englishes A joint approach to postcolonial and non-postcolonial varieties, 38-62. Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press.
Schröder, Anne, Frederic Zähres &amp; Alexander Kautzsch. 2020. Ethnic variation in the phonology of Namibian English: A first approach to Baster English. English World-Wide 41(2). 193-224.
Schröder, Anne, Frederic Zähres &amp; Alexander Kautzsch. fc.2021. The phonetics of Namibian English: Investigating vowels as local features in a global context. In Anne Schröder (ed.), The dynamics of English in Namibia. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.
Steigertahl, Helene. 2019. English(es) in post-independence Namibia: An investigation of variety status and its implications for English language teaching. Bern: Peter Lang D.
Stell, Gerald. 2016. Trends in linguistic diversity in post-independence Windhoek: A qualitative appraisal. Language Matters 47. 326-348.
Stell, Gerald &amp; Robert Fuchs. 2019. Intergroup dynamics and variation in postcolonial ESL varieties: A preliminary view of Namibian English vowel systems. English World-Wide 40(2). 143-168.
Trudgill, Peter, &amp; Jean Hannah. 2017. International English: A guide to varieties of English around the world, 6th edn. London: Routledge.
Zähres, Frederic. fc.2021. Broadcasting your variety: Namibian English(es) on YouTube. In Anne Schröder (ed.), The dynamics of English in Namibia. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ISLE6_Slides_NamE_YT_FZ.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2955304/2955307/ISLE6_Slides_NamE_YT_FZ.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">University of Eastern Finland, Joensuu</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Namibia</topic><topic>Namibian English</topic><topic>YouTube</topic><topic>World Englishes</topic><topic>Sociophonetics</topic><topic>Phonetics</topic><topic>Phonology</topic><topic>Southern Africa</topic><topic>Southern African English</topic><topic>FAVE</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29553043</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Zähres, Frederic. “Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube”. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt; (2021).</mla>
<default>Zähres F (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;.</default>
<lncs> Zähres, F.: Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media. (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zähres, Frederic. 2021. “Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube”, Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media, .&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Zähres, F. (2021). Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> F. Zähres, “Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube”, &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;, 2021.</ieee>
<ama>Zähres F. Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;. 2021.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zähres, F. (2021). Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube (Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media). Gehalten auf der ISLE 6 - Evolving English and the Digital Era. doi:10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Zähres, F. (2021). Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Zähres, F. (2021). Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17112.01283&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Zähres F (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube.&lt;br /&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media.</bio1>
<harvard1>Zähres, F., 2021. Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube. &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Zähres, “Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube”, &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Zähres, F. (2021): Emerging Norms? Namibian English(es) on YouTube &lt;em&gt;Workshop: Lesser-Known and Expanding Circle Varieties of English on Social Media&lt;/em&gt;</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2955304</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-02T08:36:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-28T14:45:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>