<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2955492</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alessandro</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Calvia</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper deals with a nonlinear filtering problem in which a multi-dimensional signal process is additively affected by a process $\nu$ whose components have paths of bounded variation. The presence of the process $\nu$ prevents from directly applying classical results and novel estimates need to be derived. By making use of the so-called reference probability measure approach, we derive the Zakai equation satisfied by the unnormalized filtering process, and then we deduce the corresponding Kushner-Stratonovich equation. Under the condition that the jump times of the process $\nu$ do not accumulate over the considered time horizon, we show that the unnormalized filtering process is the unique solution to the Zakai equation, in the class of measure-valued processes having a square-integrable density. Our analysis paves the way to the study of stochastic control problems where a decision maker can exert singular controls in order to adjust the dynamics of an unobservable Itô-process. </abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">AMS 2020: 93E11, 60H15; 60J25, 60J76
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_651.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2955492/2955493/IMW_working_paper_651.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Stochastic filtering</topic><topic>singularly controlled systems</topic><topic>reference probability measure</topic><topic>Zakai equation</topic><topic>Kushner-Stratonovich equation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29554928</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>651</number></detail><extent unit="pages">26</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Calvia, A., Ferrari, G.: Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 651. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Calvia, Alessandro, and Ferrari, Giorgio. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 651. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Calvia, Alessandro, and Ferrari, Giorgio. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 651.</mla>
<default>Calvia A, Ferrari G (2021)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 651.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
<ama>Calvia A, Ferrari G. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 651. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Calvia, A., and Ferrari, G. (2021). Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 651, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Calvia, A. &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Calvia, A., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 651). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> A. Calvia and G. Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 651,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<wels>Calvia, A.; Ferrari, G. (2021): Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<harvard1>Calvia, A., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.651, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Calvia, A., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 651). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Calvia A, Ferrari G (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 651.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Calvia, and G.  Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Filtering of Partially Observed Systems Arising in Singular Stochastic Optimal Control&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2955492</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-06-10T13:53:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>