<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956892</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gläser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">78885607</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9523-0105</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Efficient solid waste management is one of the most relevant issues for urban communities.
With regard to the service type of household waste collection, there are two approaches in
practice: When collecting household waste via a door-to-door system, the collection vehicles
drive down all the streets to empty the garbage cans on the curb. Using a bring system,
waste is accumulated at central collection sites with a larger capacity. While residents do
have to travel an additional distance to dispose of their waste at these central collection sites,
a bring system can reduce the distance to be covered by collection vehicles because they
no longer have to drive down all the streets. To combine the advantages of both systems,
in this article the service type decision is introduced. The corresponding waste collection
problem with service type option (WCPSTO) is modeled as a new variant of a periodic location
routing problem and an adaptive large neighborhood search-based solution approach
is proposed. This solution approach not only solves the newly presented problem, but also
outperforms a solution algorithm for a related waste collection problem seen in the literature,
which can be seen as a special case of the WCPSTO.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_13_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956892/2956927/wpaper_13_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Combinatorial optimization</topic><topic>Waste collection</topic><topic>Vehicle routing</topic><topic>ALNS</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29568928</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2956892</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>13-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">41</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> S. Gläser, &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 13-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Gläser, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956892" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956892&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gläser, S. (2021). &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2956892.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Gläser, S. (2021). A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 13-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Gläser S. &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 13-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Gläser, &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gläser, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956892" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Gläser, S., 2021. &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.13-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Gläser S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<wels>Gläser, S. (2021): A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Gläser S (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 13-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Gläser, Sina. &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 13-2021.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Gläser, Sina. 2021. &lt;em&gt;A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 13-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Gläser, S.: A Waste Collection Problem with Service Type Option. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 13-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956892</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-23T10:00:27Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-23T10:18:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>