<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956310</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:370</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Judith</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Huget</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">808248e5-8187-495b-9b15-e33c4b309720</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9678-8562</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Barton</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">78762025</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">G. </namePart><namePart type="family">Hine</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">S. </namePart><namePart type="family">Blackley</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">A. </namePart><namePart type="family">Cooke</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia</namePart>
</name>







<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SC_Barton_Huget.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956310/2956311/SC_Barton_Huget.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Perth, Australien</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29563103</identifier>
<part><detail type="issue"><number>42</number></detail><extent unit="pages">795</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Huget J, Barton D (2019)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia). Hine G, Blackley S, Cooke A (Eds);  MERGA Conference Proceedings(42).  Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia:  795.</default>
<mla>Huget, Judith, and Barton, Daniel. “Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies”. &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. G.  Hine, S.  Blackley, and A.  Cooke. Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia, 2019. MERGA Conference Proceedings. 795.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J., &amp;amp; Barton, D. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In G.   Hine, S.   Blackley, &amp;amp; A.   Cooke (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;MERGA Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt; (p. 795). Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Huget, J., and Barton, D. (2019). “Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies” in &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;, Hine, G., Blackley, S., and Cooke, A. eds. MERGA Conference Proceedings (Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia), 795.</frontiers>
<wels>Huget, J.; Barton, D. (2019): Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In: G.  Hine; S.  Blackley; A.  Cooke (Hrsg.):  Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia). Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia. (MERGA Conference Proceedings, ).  S. 795.</wels>
<apa>Huget, J., &amp;amp; Barton, D. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In G.   Hine, S.   Blackley, &amp;amp; A.   Cooke (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;MERGA Conference Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt; (p. 795). Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia.</apa>
<harvard1>Huget, J., &amp;amp; Barton, D., 2019. Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In G.   Hine, S.   Blackley, &amp;amp; A.   Cooke, eds. &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;. MERGA Conference Proceedings.  Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia, pp. 795.</harvard1>
<ieee> J. Huget and D. Barton, “Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies”, &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;, G.  Hine, S.  Blackley, and A.  Cooke, eds., MERGA Conference Proceedings, Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia, 2019,  pp.795.</ieee>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Huget, and D.  Barton, in &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: G.  Hine, S.  Blackley, A.  Cooke), Mathematics Education Research Group Of Australasia, &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 795.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Huget J, Barton D (2019) &lt;br /&gt;Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia). Hine G, Blackley S, Cooke A (Eds); MERGA Conference Proceedings,  Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia:  795.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, J. &amp;amp; Barton, D. (2019). Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies (MERGA Conference Proceedings). In G.  Hine, S.  Blackley &amp;amp; A.  Cooke (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 795). Gehalten auf der 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia, Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<lncs> Huget, J., Barton, D.: Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In: Hine, G., Blackley, S., and Cooke, A. (eds.) Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia). MERGA Conference Proceedings. p. 795. Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia (2019).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Huget, Judith, and Barton, Daniel. 2019. “Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies”. In &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. G.  Hine, S.  Blackley, and A.  Cooke, 795. MERGA Conference Proceedings. Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Huget J, Barton D. Learning from Lessons: A Study on Structure and Construction of Mathematics Teacher Knowledge - First Results of German Case Studies. In: Hine G, Blackley S, Cooke A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Mathematics Education Research: Impacting Practice (Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia)&lt;/em&gt;. MERGA Conference Proceedings. Mathematics Education Research Group of Australasia;  2019: 795.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956310</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-19T09:25:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-02T09:27:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>