<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956220</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Berens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">203794331</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lasha</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Chochua</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">102150048</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Willmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26488631</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study the stability of trade policy arrangements under two regulatory scenarios, with/without
PTAs. Unlike previous papers, we consider an extensive set of trade policy constellations and allow for
unlimited farsightedness of negotiating parties. We find global free trade (GFT) to be uniquely stable under
symmetry, with/without PTAs. When two countries are smaller(larger) than the third, availability of PTAs
decreases (increases) the stability of GFT. Away from symmetry, GFT is not attainable, and without PTAs
the non-cooperative MFN regime is the only stable outcome. The effect of (dis-)allowing PTAs thus depends
on the size asymmetry of countries.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_11_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956220/2956221/wpaper_11_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Trade Policy Arrangements</topic><topic>Stability</topic><topic>Unlimited Farsightedness</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29562204</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2956220</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">47</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>     <url>https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/record/2915628</url>  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Berens, S., Chochua, L., and Willmann, G. (2021). The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 11-2021, aktual. Version. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, S., Chochua, L. &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2021). &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management) (aktual. Version.). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2956220.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Berens S, Chochua L, Willmann G. &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 11-2021 aktual. Version. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<ieee> S. Berens, L. Chochua, and G. Willmann, &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 11-2021, aktual. Version.,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Berens, S., Chochua, L., &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2021) aktual. Version. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956220" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956220&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Berens, S.; Chochua, L.; Willmann, G. (2021): The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements. aktual. Version.  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Berens, L.  Chochua, and G.  Willmann, &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Berens S, Chochua L, Willmann G (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 11-2021, aktual. Version.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Berens, S., Chochua, L., &amp;amp; Willmann, G., 2021. &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.11-2021, aktual. Version., Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, S., Chochua, L., &amp;amp; Willmann, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2021) aktual. Version. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956220" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956220&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Berens, Stefan, Chochua, Lasha, and Willmann, Gerald. 2021. &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;. aktual. Version. Vol. 11-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Berens, S., Chochua, L., Willmann, G.: The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 11-2021, aktual. Version. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<default>Berens S, Chochua L, Willmann G (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 11-2021, aktual. Version.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Berens, Stefan, Chochua, Lasha, and Willmann, Gerald. &lt;em&gt;The Farsighted Stability of Global Trade Policy Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;. aktual. Version. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 11-2021.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956220</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-14T11:45:19Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-23T10:16:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>