<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956152</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Richard Gyan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aboagye</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Abdul-Aziz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James Boadu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frimpong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eugene</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Budu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Collins</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Adu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Raymond K</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ayilu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bright Opoku</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahinkorah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">BACKGROUND: Over the past few years, there has been growing public and research interest in adolescents' experiences with various forms of bullying victimisation because of their psychological, emotional, and/ or physical consequences. The present study examined the prevalence of bullying victimisation and its associated factors among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa.; METHODS: Using data fromthe Global School-based Health Survey (GSHS) from 2010 to 2017 of eleven sub-Saharan Africancountries, a sample of 25,454 in-school adolescents was used for analysis. Statistical analyses included frequencies, percentages, Pearson chi-square and multivariable logistic regression. Results were presented as adjusted odds ratios(aOR) at 95% confidence intervals (CIs).; RESULTS: The overall prevalence of bullying victimisation among the respondents was 38.8%. The prevalence was lowest in Mauritius (22.2%) and highest in Sierra Leone (54.6%). Adolescents who felt lonely [aOR=1.66, 95% CI=1.53, 1.80], had history of anxiety [aOR=1.53, 95% CI=1.41, 1.66], suicidal ideation [aOR=1.28, 95% CI=1.17, 1.39], suicidal attempt [aOR=1.86, 95% CI=1.72, 2.02], current users of marijuana [aOR=1.59, 95% CI=1.38, 1.84], and truants at [aOR=1.43, 95% CI=1.34, 1.52] were more likely to be victims of bullying. Conversely, adolescents who had peer support were less likely to be victims of bullying [aOR=0.78, 95% CI=0.73, 0.82].Adolescents aged 15years or older had lower odds of experiencing bullying victimization compared to their counterparts aged 14years or younger [aOR=0.74, 95% CI=0.69, 0.78].; CONCLUSION: Our findings suggest that age, loneliness, anxiety, suicidal ideation, suicidal attempt,and current use of marijuana are associated with increased risk of bullying victimisation. School-wide preventative interventions (e.g., positive behavioural strategies- Rational Emotive Behavioral Education, [REBE], peer educator network systems, face-face counseling sessions, substance use cessation therapy) are essential in promoting a positive school climate and reduce students' bullying victimisation behaviours. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="SN_gOA_Hagan_s12888-021-03337-5.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956152/2960352/SN_gOA_Hagan_s12888-021-03337-5.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>BioMed Central</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Abuse</topic><topic>Bullying</topic><topic>In-school adolescents</topic><topic>Physical harm</topic><topic>Sub-Saharan Africa</topic><topic>Victimisation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC psychiatry</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1471-244X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34210264</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000671796600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29561523</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>21</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aboagye, R.G., Seidu, A.-A., Hagan Jr., J.E., Frimpong, J.B., Budu, E., Adu, C., Ayilu, R.K. &amp;amp; Ahinkorah, B.O. (2021). A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(1): 325. BioMed Central. doi:10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Aboagye RG, Seidu A-A, Hagan Jr. JE, Frimpong JB, Budu E, Adu C, Ayilu RK, Ahinkorah BO (2021) &lt;br /&gt;A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey.&lt;br /&gt;BMC psychiatry 21(1): 325.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>R. G.  Aboagye, A. - A.  Seidu, J. E.  Hagan Jr., J. B.  Frimpong, E.  Budu, C.  Adu, R. K.  Ayilu, and B. O.  Ahinkorah, “A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey”, &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;, : 325.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Aboagye RG, Seidu A-A, Hagan Jr. JE, et al. A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;21(1): 325.</ama>
<lncs> Aboagye, R.G., Seidu, A.-A., Hagan Jr., J.E., Frimpong, J.B., Budu, E., Adu, C., Ayilu, R.K., Ahinkorah, B.O.: A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. BMC psychiatry. 21, : 325 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aboagye, Richard Gyan, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Frimpong, James Boadu, Budu, Eugene, Adu, Collins, Ayilu, Raymond K, and Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku. 2021. “A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey”. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 21 (1): 325.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Aboagye, R. G., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Frimpong, J. B., Budu, E., Adu, C., Ayilu, R. K., and Ahinkorah, B. O. (2021). A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 21:325.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Aboagye, R. G., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Frimpong, J. B., Budu, E., Adu, C., Ayilu, R. K., et al. (2021). A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(1), 325. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Aboagye, Richard Gyan, Seidu, Abdul-Aziz, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Frimpong, James Boadu, Budu, Eugene, Adu, Collins, Ayilu, Raymond K, and Ahinkorah, Bright Opoku. “A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey”. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 21.1 (2021): 325.</mla>
<wels>Aboagye, R. G.; Seidu, A. - A.; Hagan Jr., J. E.; Frimpong, J. B.; Budu, E.; Adu, C.; Ayilu, R. K.; Ahinkorah, B. O. (2021): A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,21:(1):325</wels>
<default>Aboagye RG, Seidu A-A, Hagan Jr. JE, Frimpong JB, Budu E, Adu C, Ayilu RK, Ahinkorah BO (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 21(1): 325.</default>
<ieee> R.G. Aboagye, et al., “A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey”, &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 21, 2021, : 325.</ieee>
<harvard1>Aboagye, R.G., et al., 2021. A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, 21(1): 325.</harvard1>
<apa>Aboagye, R. G., Seidu, A. - A., Hagan Jr., J. E., Frimpong, J. B., Budu, E., Adu, C., Ayilu, R. K., et al. (2021). A multi-country analysis of the prevalence and factors associated with bullying victimisation among in-school adolescents in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the global school-based health survey. &lt;em&gt;BMC psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(1), 325. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-021-03337-5&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956152</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-12T08:29:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-06T08:49:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>