<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956786</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Caspers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5514336</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4380-0476</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Reinaldo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Marfull</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dannenhaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Komdeur</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Korsten</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">51082875</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0814-9099</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">202491419</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">**Abstract**&lt;br&gt;
Acoustic and visual signals are well known to play important roles in social communication in birds. Growing evidence suggests that many bird species, including species of songbirds, additionally have a well-developed sense of smell. However, we are still at the beginning of understanding the potential importance of chemical communication in the social lives of birds, for example in mate choice. The secretion of the preen gland may be an important contributor to the chemical phenotype of birds. Here, we report on a first characterisation of the chemical composition of the preen gland secretion of the Blue Tit (&lt;em&gt;Cyanistes caeruleus&lt;/em&gt;), a common songbird which is an often used model species in animal behaviour and ecology, in particular also in studies of sexual selection and (extra-pair) mate choice. We found sex differences in the composition of the preen gland secretion in breeding Blue Tits. Females further tended to have a larger number of putative compounds in their secretions compared to males. We briefly discuss the possible implications of these findings and speculate that the chemical composition of the preen gland secretion may be a sexually selected trait in Blue Tits. Our preliminary findings warrant follow-up research into the patterns of within- and among individual variation in the chemical composition of the preen gland secretion as well as the identification of the main chemical compounds involved.</abstract>
<abstract lang="ger">**Zusammenfassung**&lt;br&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Chemische Analyse zeigt Geschlechtsunterschiede im Bürzeldrüsensekret brütender Blaumeisen&lt;/bold&gt;Singvögel sind vor allem für ihren Gesang und ihre Gefiedermerkmale, die bei der sozialen  Kommunikation eine bedeutende Rolle spielen, bekannt. Immer mehr Hinweise deuten aber darauf hin, dass viele Vogelarten, darunter auch Singvogelarten, zusätzlich einen gut entwickelten Geruchssinn haben. Welche Bedeutung die geruchliche Kommunikation im sozialen Leben der Vögel, zum Beispiel bei der Partnerwahl, spielt ist allerdings weitgehend noch unbekannt. Das Bürzeldrüsensekret könnte in diesem Zusammenhang einen wichtigen Beitrag zum chemischen Phänotyp der Vögel leisten. In unserer Studie haben wir uns die chemische Zusammensetzung des Bürzeldrüsensekrets der Blaumeise (&lt;em&gt;Cyanistes caeruleus&lt;/em&gt;) in der Brutzeit angeschaut. Blaumeisen sind eine viel genutzte Modellart in der Verhaltensforschung und Verhaltensökologie, insbesondere auch in Studien zur sexuellen Selektion und (außerpaarigen) Partnerwahl. Anhand von chemischen Analysen mittels Gas-Chromatographie fanden wir heraus, dass es bei brütenden Blaumeisen einen Geschlechtsunterschied in der Zusammensetzung des Bürzeldrüsensekrets gibt. Weibchen neigen außerdem dazu, eine größere Anzahl von vermeintlichen Substanzen in ihren Sekreten zu haben als Männchen. Wir diskutieren hier kurz die möglichen Implikationen dieser Ergebnisse und spekulieren, dass die chemische Zusammensetzung des Bürzeldrüsensekrets ein sexuell selektiertes Merkmal bei Blaumeisen sein könnte. Unsere vorläufigen Ergebnisse rechtfertigen Folgeuntersuchungen, in denen die Identifikation der wichtigsten chemischen Verbindungen des Bürzeldrüsensekrets und die Variation innerhalb und zwischen Individuen in der chemischen Zusammensetzung des Drüsensekrets im Fokus stehen.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Caspers2021_Article_ChemicalAnalysisRevealsSexDiff.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956786/2960279/Caspers2021_Article_ChemicalAnalysisRevealsSexDiff.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Uropygial gland</topic><topic>VOCs</topic><topic>Avian olfaction</topic><topic>Sexual selection</topic><topic>Cyanistes caeruleus</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Ornithology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2193-7192</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2193-7206</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000684073900001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29567868</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>163</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">191–198</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Caspers, Barbara, Marfull, Reinaldo, Dannenhaus, Tim, Komdeur, Jan, and Korsten, Peter. 2021. “Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt; 163 (1): 191–198.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Caspers, B., Marfull, R., Dannenhaus, T., Komdeur, J., Korsten, P.: Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. Journal of Ornithology. 163, 191–198 (2021).</lncs>
<default>Caspers B, Marfull R, Dannenhaus T, Komdeur J, Korsten P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt; 163(1): 191–198.</default>
<mla>Caspers, Barbara, Marfull, Reinaldo, Dannenhaus, Tim, Komdeur, Jan, and Korsten, Peter. “Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt; 163.1 (2021): 191–198.</mla>
<wels>Caspers, B.; Marfull, R.; Dannenhaus, T.; Komdeur, J.; Korsten, P. (2021): Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;,163:(1): 191–198.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Caspers, R.  Marfull, T.  Dannenhaus, J.  Komdeur, and P.  Korsten, “Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;163&lt;/em&gt;, 191–198.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Caspers B, Marfull R, Dannenhaus T, Komdeur J, Korsten P (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits.&lt;br /&gt;Journal of Ornithology 163(1): 191–198.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Caspers, B., Marfull, R., Dannenhaus, T., Komdeur, J., &amp;amp; Korsten, P. (2021). Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;163&lt;/em&gt;(1), 191–198. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Caspers, B., et al., 2021. Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;, 163(1), p 191–198.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Caspers, B., Marfull, R., Dannenhaus, T., Komdeur, J. &amp;amp; Korsten, P. (2021). Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;163&lt;/em&gt;(1), 191–198. Springer . doi:10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Caspers, B., Marfull, R., Dannenhaus, T., Komdeur, J., and Korsten, P. (2021). Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt; 163, 191–198.</frontiers>
<ama>Caspers B, Marfull R, Dannenhaus T, Komdeur J, Korsten P. Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;163(1):191–198.</ama>
<ieee> B. Caspers, et al., “Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 163, 2021,  pp. 191–198.</ieee>
<apa>Caspers, B., Marfull, R., Dannenhaus, T., Komdeur, J., &amp;amp; Korsten, P. (2021). Chemical analysis reveals sex differences in the preen gland secretion of breeding Blue Tits. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ornithology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;163&lt;/em&gt;(1), 191–198. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10336-021-01921-w&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956786</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-17T11:46:56Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-14T16:42:01Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>