<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956845</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stapels</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">151642847</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1347-9607</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friederike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eyssel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">140331</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4978-8922</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">21484764</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">**Abstract**&lt;br&gt;
Attitudes towards robots are not always unequivocally positive or negative: when attitudes encompass both strong positive and strong negative evaluations about an attitude object, people experience an unpleasant state of evaluative conflict, called ambivalence. To shed light on ambivalence towards robots, we conducted a mixed-methods experiment with&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;= 163 German university students that investigated the influence of robot autonomy on robot-related attitudes. With technological progress, robots become increasingly autonomous. We hypothesized that high levels of robot autonomy would increase both positive and negative robot-related evaluations, resulting in more attitudinal ambivalence. We experimentally manipulated robot autonomy through text vignettes and assessed objective ambivalence (i.e., the amount of reported conflicting thoughts and feelings) and subjective ambivalence (i.e., self-reported experienced conflict) towards the robot ‘VIVA’ using qualitative and quantitative measures. Autonomy did not impact objective ambivalence. However, subjective ambivalence was higher towards the robot high versus low in autonomy. Interestingly, this effect turned non-significant when controlling for individual differences in technology commitment. Qualitative results were categorized by two independent raters into assets (e.g., assistance, companionship) and risks (e.g., privacy/data security, social isolation). Taken together, the present research demonstrated that attitudes towards robots are indeed ambivalent and that this ambivalence might influence behavioral intentions towards robots. Moreover, the findings highlight the important role of technology commitment. Finally, qualitative results shed light on potential users’ concerns and aspirations. This way, these data provide useful insights into factors that facilitate human–robot research.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="robocalypse data.sav">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956845/2956846/robocalypse data.sav</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/octet-stream</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="robocalypse syntax.sps">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956845/2956847/robocalypse syntax.sps</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/octet-stream</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Stapels-Eyssel2021_Article_RobocalypseYesPleaseTheRoleOfR.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956845/2960280/Stapels-Eyssel2021_Article_RobocalypseYesPleaseTheRoleOfR.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Social Robotics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1875-4791</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1875-4805</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34413912</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000684804100001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29568450</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Stapels, Julia, and Eyssel, Friederike. “Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt; (2021).</mla>
<default>Stapels J, Eyssel F (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;.</default>
<lncs> Stapels, J., Eyssel, F.: Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. International Journal of Social Robotics. (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stapels, Julia, and Eyssel, Friederike. 2021. “Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Stapels J, Eyssel F (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Stapels, J., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F., 2021. Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stapels, J., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F. (2021). Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Stapels, and F.  Eyssel, “Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Stapels, J.; Eyssel, F. (2021): Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;</wels>
<apa>Stapels, J., &amp;amp; Eyssel, F. (2021). Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> J. Stapels and F. Eyssel, “Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;, 2021.</ieee>
<ama>Stapels J, Eyssel F. Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. 2021.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Stapels, J. &amp;amp; Eyssel, F. (2021). Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;. Springer . doi:10.1007/s12369-021-00817-2.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Stapels, J., and Eyssel, F. (2021). Robocalypse? Yes, Please! The Role of Robot Autonomy in the Development of Ambivalent Attitudes Towards Robots. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Social Robotics&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956845</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-19T12:47:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-14T16:46:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>