<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956649</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:540</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gabin Thierry</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bitchagno Mbahbou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">216335122</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jean Garba</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Koffi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ingrid Konga</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Simo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Donald Ulrich K.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kagho</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Augustin Silvere</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ngouela</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bruno Ndjakou</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lenta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Norbert</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sewald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">20281</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0309-2655</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">17977</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A total of nine sesquiterpenoid lactones together with phenolic compounds and other terpenes were identified from the crude methanol extract of Elephantopus mollis Kunth. Compounds were isolated using different chromatographic techniques and their structures were determined by NMR and IR spectroscopy as well as mass spectrometry. The structures of some detected compounds were assigned based on LC-ToF-ESI-MS screening of main fractions/subfractions from flash chromatography and comparison with isolated analogues as standards. The findings revealed not only the in-source loss of water as the base peak in hirsutinolides but also the in-source loss of corresponding alcohol when the oxygen at position 1 is alkylated. The present study also draws up a complement of data with respect to hirsutinolide-like sesquiterpene lactones whose LC-MS characteristics are not available in the literature. The chemophenetic significance is also discussed. Some of the isolated compounds were reported for the first time to be found in the species, the genus as well as the plant family. The medium-polar fractions of the crude extract, also containing the larger amount of sesquiterpenoid lactones, exhibited activity both against a cancer cell line and bacterial strains. Isolated lactones were also active against the cancer cell line, while the chlorogenic derivatives also valuable in Elephantopus genus showed potent radical scavenging activity. This is the first report of cytotoxic and antibacterial activities of our samples against the tested strains and cell line. The present study follows the ongoing research project dealing with the characterization of taxa with antibacterial and antiparasitic activities from Cameroonian pharmacopeia.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="molecules-26-04810.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956649/2956782/molecules-26-04810.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>LC–MS</topic><topic>Asteraceae</topic><topic>sesquiterpenoids</topic><topic>lactones</topic><topic>cytotoxicity</topic><topic>antimicrobial activity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Molecules</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1420-3049</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34443397</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000689959500001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29566495</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/molecules26164810</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>26</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>16</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Bitchagno Mbahbou, G.T., et al., 2021. LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;, 26(16): 4810.</harvard1>
<ieee> G.T. Bitchagno Mbahbou, et al., “LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents”, &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 26, 2021, : 4810.</ieee>
<apa>Bitchagno Mbahbou, G. T., Koffi, J. G., Simo, I. K., Kagho, D. U. K., Ngouela, A. S., Lenta, B. N., &amp;amp; Sewald, N. (2021). LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(16), 4810. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26164810" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26164810&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Bitchagno Mbahbou, G. T.; Koffi, J. G.; Simo, I. K.; Kagho, D. U. K.; Ngouela, A. S.; Lenta, B. N.; Sewald, N. (2021): LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;,26:(16):4810</wels>
<frontiers>Bitchagno Mbahbou, G. T., Koffi, J. G., Simo, I. K., Kagho, D. U. K., Ngouela, A. S., Lenta, B. N., and Sewald, N. (2021). LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt; 26:4810.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bitchagno Mbahbou, G. T., Koffi, J. G., Simo, I. K., Kagho, D. U. K., Ngouela, A. S., Lenta, B. N., &amp;amp; Sewald, N. (2021). LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(16), 4810. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26164810" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26164810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bitchagno Mbahbou, Gabin Thierry, Koffi, Jean Garba, Simo, Ingrid Konga, Kagho, Donald Ulrich K., Ngouela, Augustin Silvere, Lenta, Bruno Ndjakou, and Sewald, Norbert. “LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents”. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt; 26.16 (2021): 4810.</mla>
<default>Bitchagno Mbahbou GT, Koffi JG, Simo IK, Kagho DUK, Ngouela AS, Lenta BN, Sewald N (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt; 26(16): 4810.</default>
<ama>Bitchagno Mbahbou GT, Koffi JG, Simo IK, et al. LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;26(16): 4810.</ama>
<lncs> Bitchagno Mbahbou, G.T., Koffi, J.G., Simo, I.K., Kagho, D.U.K., Ngouela, A.S., Lenta, B.N., Sewald, N.: LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. Molecules. 26, : 4810 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bitchagno Mbahbou, Gabin Thierry, Koffi, Jean Garba, Simo, Ingrid Konga, Kagho, Donald Ulrich K., Ngouela, Augustin Silvere, Lenta, Bruno Ndjakou, and Sewald, Norbert. 2021. “LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents”. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt; 26 (16): 4810.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bitchagno Mbahbou, G.T., Koffi, J.G., Simo, I.K., Kagho, D.U.K., Ngouela, A.S., Lenta, B.N. &amp;amp; Sewald, N. (2021). LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents. &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(16): 4810. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/molecules26164810.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>G. T.  Bitchagno Mbahbou, J. G.  Koffi, I. K.  Simo, D. U. K.  Kagho, A. S.  Ngouela, B. N.  Lenta, and N.  Sewald, “LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents”, &lt;em&gt;Molecules&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;, : 4810.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bitchagno Mbahbou GT, Koffi JG, Simo IK, Kagho DUK, Ngouela AS, Lenta BN, Sewald N (2021) &lt;br /&gt;LC-ToF-ESI-MS Patterns of Hirsutinolide-like Sesquiterpenoids Present in the Elephantopus mollis Kunth Extract and Chemophenetic Significance of Its Chemical Constituents.&lt;br /&gt;Molecules 26(16): 4810.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956649</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-09T15:43:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-12T13:00:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>