<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956407</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eileen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Peters</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">73257726</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Relational Inequality Theory (RIT) argues that relational claims-making- the process of employer-employee exchange relationships explicitly regarding negotiations over resources and rewards- is the central mechanism that produces social inequalities at work. Yet, the COVID-19 pandemic has significantly affected employees and employers, possibly altering their behavior in relational claims-making. Hence, this paper aims to explore if long-standing gender inequalities in employer-employee exchange relationships have reproduced or changed during the COVID-19 pandemic. It is examined (1) whether women and men differ in their response to the pandemic regarding expected employer support with further training to work from home (WFH) and (2) whether employers’ decisions on adequate support depend on employees’ gender. The hypotheses were tested using a linked employer-employee dataset (LEEP-B3) with information on German employees’ working conditions before and during COVID-19. OLS regression models predicted no gender differences in training expectations. However, women are more likely to be provided with less training than they expect from their employers. Thus, employers’ decision-making has not been altered, but gender remains an important determinant in relational claims-making, thereby reproducing gender inequalities. Finally, the workforces’ pre-COVID-19 gender ideologies predicted whether mechanisms are mitigated or enhanced. Hence, these findings underline the crucial role of the workplace context in which employer-employee exchange relationships are embedded.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="socsci-10-00281.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956407/2956408/socsci-10-00281.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>gender inequality</topic><topic>employer-employee exchange relationships</topic><topic>working from home</topic><topic>workplaces</topic><topic>gender ideologies</topic><topic>COVID-19</topic><topic>Germany</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Social Sciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2076-0760</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000691260300001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29564078</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/socsci10080281</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Peters, Eileen. “What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic”. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 10.8 (2021): 281.</mla>
<default>Peters E (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 10(8): 281.</default>
<lncs> Peters, E.: What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. Social Sciences. 10, : 281 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peters, Eileen. 2021. “What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic”. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 10 (8): 281.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Peters, E., 2021. What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 10(8): 281.</harvard1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peters, E. (2021). What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), 281. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci10080281" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci10080281&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Peters E (2021) &lt;br /&gt;What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic.&lt;br /&gt;Social Sciences 10(8): 281.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Peters, “What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic”, &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, : 281.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Peters, E. (2021): What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,10:(8):281</wels>
<apa>Peters, E. (2021). What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8), 281. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci10080281" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci10080281&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> E. Peters, “What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic”, &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 2021, : 281.</ieee>
<ama>Peters E. What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;10(8): 281.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Peters, E. (2021). What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(8): 281. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/socsci10080281.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Peters, E. (2021). What You Want Is Not Always What You Get: Gender Differences in Employer-Employee Exchange Relationships during the COVID-19 Pandemic. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 10:281.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956407</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-07-26T05:48:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-13T09:03:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>