<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2956884</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fabienne Lara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dascher-Preising</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">100593456</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">With this paper our objective is to study the effects of different deficit policies in
an endogenous growth model with publicly funded human capital accumulation and
public debt, where we allow for heterogeneous households. Two types of households
are considered. One household acquires human capital or skills through education
while the other household remains low-skilled. Aggregate production is given by a
function with physical capital and labor as input factors, where total labor input
is modeled by a CES function with high-skilled and low-skilled labor as arguments.
The government can run into debt, but, the primary surplus is a positive function
of public debt which guarantees that public debt is sustainable. We study the
characteristics and stability of the steady state and we investigate the effects of
fiscal policy with regard to long-run growth and the distribution of welfare of the
two households. Further, we analyze growth and welfare effects of switching from
a balanced government budget to permanent public deficits taking into account
transition dynamics.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_12_2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2956884/2956886/wpaper_12_2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Human capital</topic><topic>heterogeneous agents</topic><topic>distribution</topic><topic>endogenous economic growth</topic><topic>fiscal policy</topic><topic>sustainable public debt</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29568842</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2956884</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12-2021</number></detail><extent unit="pages">45</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher-Preising, F.L. &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2956884.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>F. L.  Dascher-Preising, and A.  Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Dascher-Preising FL, Greiner A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<ama>Dascher-Preising FL, Greiner A. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 12-2021. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2021.</ama>
<lncs> Dascher-Preising, F.L., Greiner, A.: Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules? Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2021. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher-Preising, Fabienne Lara, and Greiner, Alfred. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 12-2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Dascher-Preising, Fabienne Lara, and Greiner, Alfred. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 12-2021.</mla>
<frontiers>Dascher-Preising, F. L., and Greiner, A. (2021). Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules? &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 12-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dascher-Preising, F. L., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956884" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956884&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Dascher-Preising, F. L.; Greiner, A. (2021): Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<default>Dascher-Preising FL, Greiner A (2021)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 12-2021.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<harvard1>Dascher-Preising, F.L., &amp;amp; Greiner, A., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.12-2021, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<ieee> F.L. Dascher-Preising and A. Greiner, &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 12-2021,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<apa>Dascher-Preising, F. L., &amp;amp; Greiner, A. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Human capital formation with heterogeneous agents, sustainable debt policies and growth: Who benefits from fiscal policy rules?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 12-2021). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956884" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2956884&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2956884</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-23T09:51:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-08-23T10:27:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>