<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2957607</id><setSpec>bi_dissertation</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:doctoralThesis</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:530</setSpec><setSpec>bi_dissertationFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>thesis</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material</title></titleInfo>





<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sepideh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Izadi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">267075833</identifier></name>





<name type="personal">
  
  <namePart type="given">Gabi</namePart>
  
  
  <namePart type="family">Schierning</namePart>
  
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">supervisor</roleTerm> </role>
</name>



<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Three-dimensional (3D) topological insulators (TI) host surface carriers with extremely high mobility. However, their transport properties are typically dominated by bulk carriers that outnumber the surface carriers by orders of magnitude. We herein present a strategy to overcome the problem of bulk carrier domination by using 3D TI nanoparticles, which were compacted by hot-pressing to macroscopic nanograined bulk samples. Bi2Te3 nanoparticles well known for their excellent thermoelectric and 3D TI properties serve as our model system. As key enabler for this approach, we applied a specific synthesis that creates nanoparticles with a low level of impurities and surface contamination. The compacted nanograined bulk contains a high number of interfaces and grain boundaries. Here we show that these samples exhibit metallic-like electrical transport properties and a distinct weak antilocalization. A downwards trend in the electrical resistivity at temperatures below 5 K was attributed to an increase in the coherence length by applying the Hikami-Larkin-Nagaoka model. THz time-domain spectroscopy revealed a dominance of the surface transport at low frequencies with a mobility of above 〖10〗^3  cm^2 V^(-1) s^(-1) even at room temperature. These findings clearly demonstrate that nanograined bulk Bi2Te3 features surface carrier properties that are of importance for technical applications.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Thesis-Sepideh Izadi.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2957607/2957608/Thesis-Sepideh Izadi.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Universität Bielefeld</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29576074</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2957607</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">113</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<dateOther encoding="w3cdtf" type="defenseDate">2021-02-21</dateOther>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Izadi, S.: Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material. Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Izadi, Sepideh. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Izadi, Sepideh. &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021.</mla>
<default>Izadi S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</default>
<wels>Izadi, S. (2021): Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</wels>
<bio1>Izadi S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Izadi, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2957607" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2957607&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Izadi, S., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Izadi, &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Izadi S. &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Izadi, S. (2021). Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Izadi, S. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. doi:10.4119/unibi/2957607.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Izadi, S. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2957607" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2957607&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> S. Izadi, &lt;em&gt;Thermoelectric and electrical transport properties of Bi2Te3 compacted nanoparticles bulk material&lt;/em&gt;,  Bielefeld: Universität Bielefeld, 2021.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2957607</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-23T11:59:28Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-10-14T09:29:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>