<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2957927</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Gerrit</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bauch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">175079558</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study a signaling game of common interest in which a stochastic noise is perturbing the communication between an informed sender and an uninformed receiver. Despite this inhibiting factor, efficient languages exist. In equilibrium, sender uses a tessellation consisting of convex cells while receiver converts posterior beliefs into Bayesian estimators serving as interpretations. Shannon entropy measures the noise level and describes to which extent communication is possible. A limit case of errors that respect the distance between words leads to concise interpretations in the decoding process. Comparative statics for different levels of noise reveal which grammatical structures are more robust towards noise. For increasing error separation between most distinct types becomes more important than precision about each single one. Furthermore, distinct words are saved for the description of opposite domains of the type space. Evolutionary modeling approaches converge to equilibria, but not every equilibrium is stable.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_655.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2957927/2957930/IMW_working_paper_655.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cheap talk</topic><topic>noisy communication</topic><topic>language formation</topic><topic>Voronoi language</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29579276</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>655</number></detail><extent unit="pages">28</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Bauch, G. (2021): Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<harvard1>Bauch, G., 2021. &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.655, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<bio1>Bauch G (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 655.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bauch, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 655). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>G.  Bauch, &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Bauch G. &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 655. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2021.</ama>
<frontiers>Bauch, G. (2021). Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 655, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bauch, G. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Bauch, G. (2021).  &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 655). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> G. Bauch, &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 655,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021.</ieee>
<lncs> Bauch, G.: Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 655. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bauch, Gerrit. 2021. &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 655. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Bauch, Gerrit. &lt;em&gt;Effects of Noise on the Grammar of Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2021. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 655.</mla>
<default>Bauch G (2021)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 655.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2957927</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-10-05T12:16:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T12:18:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>