<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2957151</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bock von Wülfingen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">255438930</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0073-2274</description></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Karen</namePart><namePart type="family">Kastenhofer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Susan</namePart><namePart type="family">Molyneux-Hodgson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">3791114</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper analyses differences in group perceptions amongst a large international and multi-disciplinary research community. It is a cluster of excellence with the explicit aim of bringing natural sciences and humanities together in joint experiments. Who wins, when disciplinary borders fall? The article discusses the moment of the appearance of the cluster on the grounds of a thorough analysis of the notions of interdisciplinarity, excellence and the recent history of European research policy. This empirical study of the forms of knowledge, practices and behaviours that intersect with differences of cultures, disciplines and gender in this community is part of self-reflexive structures that were installed within the cluster research on research practices. The results show that this new form of structure of ‘big interdisciplinarity’ offers the formation of new (collaborative) identities to those involved. New forms of group minority and majority understandings emerge, which, in contrast to the expectation of the cluster at the beginning don’t seem to advantage usually disadvantaged identities in science.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="BockVonWülfingen2021_Chapter_BigInterdisciplinarityUnsettli.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2957151/2957152/BockVonWülfingen2021_Chapter_BigInterdisciplinarityUnsettli.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-030-61727-1</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29571518</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>31</number></detail><extent unit="pages">263-282</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Bock von Wülfingen, B., 2021. ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In K.  Kastenhofer &amp;amp; S.  Molyneux-Hodgson, eds. &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook. no.31  Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 263-282.</harvard1>
<ieee> B. Bock von Wülfingen, “‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence”, &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;, K. Kastenhofer and S. Molyneux-Hodgson, eds., Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook, vol. 31,  Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2021,  pp.263-282.</ieee>
<ama>Bock von Wülfingen B. ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In: Kastenhofer K, Molyneux-Hodgson S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook. Vol 31. Cham: Springer International Publishing;  2021: 263-282.</ama>
<apa>Bock von Wülfingen, B. (2021). ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In K.  Kastenhofer &amp;amp; S.  Molyneux-Hodgson (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook: Vol. 31&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 263-282). Cham: Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bock von Wülfingen, Bettina. 2021. “‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence”. In &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Karen Kastenhofer and Susan Molyneux-Hodgson, 31:263-282. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook. Cham: Springer International Publishing.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bock von Wülfingen, B.: ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In: Kastenhofer, K. and Molyneux-Hodgson, S. (eds.) Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook. 31, p. 263-282. Springer International Publishing, Cham (2021).</lncs>
<wels>Bock von Wülfingen, B. (2021): ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In: Karen Kastenhofer; Susan Molyneux-Hodgson (Hrsg.):  Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences. Cham: Springer International Publishing. (Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook, 31).  S. 263-282.</wels>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bock von Wülfingen, B. (2021). ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence (Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook). In K. Kastenhofer &amp;amp; S. Molyneux-Hodgson (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt; (S. 263-282). Cham: Springer International Publishing. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bock von Wülfingen, B. (2021). “‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence” in &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;, Kastenhofer, K., and Molyneux-Hodgson, S. eds. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook, vol. 31, (Cham: Springer International Publishing), 263-282.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bock von Wülfingen, B. (2021). ‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. In K.  Kastenhofer &amp;amp; S.  Molyneux-Hodgson (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook: Vol. 31&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 263-282). Cham: Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-61728-8_13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Bock von Wülfingen, Bettina. “‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence”. &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Karen Kastenhofer and Susan Molyneux-Hodgson. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2021.Vol. 31. Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook. 263-282.</mla>
<default>Bock von Wülfingen B (2021)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences. Kastenhofer K, Molyneux-Hodgson S (Eds);  Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook, 31.  Cham: Springer International Publishing:  263-282.</default>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Bock von Wülfingen, in &lt;em&gt;Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: K. Kastenhofer, S. Molyneux-Hodgson), Springer International Publishing, Cham, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 263-282.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bock von Wülfingen B (2021) &lt;br /&gt;‘Big Interdisciplinarity’: Unsettling and Resettling Excellence. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Community and Identity in Contemporary Technosciences. Kastenhofer K, Molyneux-Hodgson S (Eds); Sociology of the Sciences Yearbook, 31. Cham: Springer International Publishing:  263-282.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2957151</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-02T14:31:20Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-09-02T14:40:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>