<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2958713</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Florian H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Almut E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thomas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matteo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Carmignola</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ann-Kathrin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dittrich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eckes</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">31475794</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Großmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">59970828</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-0997-5624</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniela</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Martinek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wilde</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">170225</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-1630-3263</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sonja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bieg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685601</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Self-determination theory assumes that the basic psychological needs for autonomy, competence, and relatedness are associated with motivational regulation. As these basic psychological needs may have been affected by the shift to distance learning, students’ motivational regulation and vitality may have suffered as well. The purpose of this study was to examine the motivational regulation, satisfaction, or frustration of the basic psychological needs and vitality of university students before and after the transition to forced distance learning during the COVID-19 pandemic: Two student samples from Austria and Germany were studied: One was surveyed before the conversion to distance learning (N=1,139) and the other at the beginning of forced distance learning (N=1,835). The instruments used were the Scales for the Measurement of Motivational Regulation for Learning in University Students (SMR-L), the German version of the Basic Psychological Needs Satisfaction and Frustration Scale, a scale developed by the authors to differentiate the assessment of social relatedness, and the German version of the Subjective Vitality Scale. The results show that the satisfaction of basic psychological needs was significantly lower and the frustration thereof substantially higher during the distance learning period than before the pandemic. Intrinsic motivation and identified regulation were significantly lower during the forced distance learning period, and more controlled forms of motivation were higher than before the pandemic. Structural equation models showed that 42% of the students’ vitality can be explained by motivational regulation and the satisfaction and frustration of their basic needs. Motivational regulation styles functioned (differentiated according to the degree of autonomy) as mediating variables between basic needs and vitality. In terms of theoretical implications, the distinction between approach and avoidance components of introjected regulation was shown to be adequate and necessary, as they explain the outcome vitality differently. The support and avoidance of frustration of basic psychological needs should be considered in distance learning to promote the quality of motivation and students’ vitality.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpsyg-12-775804.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2958713/2959941/fpsyg-12-775804.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34899527</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29587136</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Müller, F. H., Thomas, A. E., Carmignola, M., Dittrich, A. - K., Eckes, A., Großmann, N., Martinek, D., et al. (2021). University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 775804. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> F.H. Müller, et al., “University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2021, : 775804.</ieee>
<ama>Müller FH, Thomas AE, Carmignola M, et al. University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;12: 775804.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller, F.H., Thomas, A.E., Carmignola, M., Dittrich, A.-K., Eckes, A., Großmann, N., Martinek, D., Wilde, M. &amp;amp; Bieg, S. (2021). University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;: 775804. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Müller, F. H., Thomas, A. E., Carmignola, M., Dittrich, A. - K., Eckes, A., Großmann, N., Martinek, D., Wilde, M., and Bieg, S. (2021). University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12:775804.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller, F. H., Thomas, A. E., Carmignola, M., Dittrich, A. - K., Eckes, A., Großmann, N., Martinek, D., et al. (2021). University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 775804. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.775804&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Müller FH, Thomas AE, Carmignola M, Dittrich A-K, Eckes A, Großmann N, Martinek D, Wilde M, Bieg S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Psychology 12: 775804.</bio1>
<harvard1>Müller, F.H., et al., 2021. University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 12: 775804.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F. H.  Müller, A. E.  Thomas, M.  Carmignola, A. - K.  Dittrich, A.  Eckes, N.  Großmann, D.  Martinek, M.  Wilde, and S.  Bieg, “University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : 775804.</angewandte-chemie>
<wels>Müller, F. H.; Thomas, A. E.; Carmignola, M.; Dittrich, A. - K.; Eckes, A.; Großmann, N.; Martinek, D.; Wilde, M.; Bieg, S. (2021): University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,12:775804</wels>
<mla>Müller, Florian H., Thomas, Almut E., Carmignola, Matteo, Dittrich, Ann-Kathrin, Eckes, Alexander, Großmann, Nadine, Martinek, Daniela, Wilde, Matthias, and Bieg, Sonja. “University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12 (2021): 775804.</mla>
<default>Müller FH, Thomas AE, Carmignola M, Dittrich A-K, Eckes A, Großmann N, Martinek D, Wilde M, Bieg S (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 775804.</default>
<lncs> Müller, F.H., Thomas, A.E., Carmignola, M., Dittrich, A.-K., Eckes, A., Großmann, N., Martinek, D., Wilde, M., Bieg, S.: University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach. Frontiers in Psychology. 12, : 775804 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Müller, Florian H., Thomas, Almut E., Carmignola, Matteo, Dittrich, Ann-Kathrin, Eckes, Alexander, Großmann, Nadine, Martinek, Daniela, Wilde, Matthias, and Bieg, Sonja. 2021. “University students’ basic psychological needs, motivation, and vitality before and during COVID-19: A self-determination theory approach”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 775804.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2958713</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-02T08:57:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-03T08:26:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>