<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2959948</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Laura</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lindenbaum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">108695459</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-9099-8828</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zehe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">26222947</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Anlauff</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">118704731</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">11596</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0001-7975-4363</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kißler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">27325660</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33695</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">24110126</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Intra-hemispheric interference has been often observed when body parts with neighboring representations within the same hemisphere are stimulated. However, patterns of interference in early and late somatosensory processing stages due to the stimulation of different body parts have not been explored. Here, we explore functional similarities and differences between attention modulation of the somatosensory N140 and P300 elicited at the fingers vs. cheeks. In an active oddball paradigm, 22 participants received vibrotactile intensity deviant stimulation either ipsilateral (within-hemisphere) or contralateral (between-hemisphere) at the fingers or cheeks. The ipsilateral deviant always covered a larger area of skin than the contralateral deviant. Overall, both N140 and P300 amplitudes were higher following stimulation at the cheek and N140 topographies differed between fingers and cheek stimulation. For the N140, results showed higher deviant ERP amplitudes following contralateral than ipsilateral stimulation, regardless of the stimulated body part. N140 peak latency differed between stimulated body parts with shorter latencies for the stimulation at the fingers. Regarding P300 amplitudes, contralateral deviant stimulation at the fingers replicated the N140 pattern, showing higher responses and shorter latencies than ipsilateral stimulation at the fingers. For the stimulation at the cheeks, ipsilateral deviants elicited higher P300 amplitudes and longer latencies than contralateral ones. These findings indicate that at the fingers ipsilateral deviant stimulation leads to intra-hemispheric interference, with significantly smaller ERP amplitudes than in contralateral stimulation, both at early and late processing stages. By contrast, at the cheeks, intra-hemispheric interference is selective for early processing stages. Therefore, the mechanisms of intra-hemispheric processing differ from inter-hemispheric ones and the pattern of intra-hemispheric interference in early and late processing stages is body-part specific.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Lindenbaumetal.2021.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2959948/2959949/Lindenbaumetal.2021.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1662-5161</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34938169</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000732013000001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29599484</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>15</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lindenbaum, Laura, Zehe, Sebastian, Anlauff, Jan, Hermann, Thomas, and Kißler, Johanna. 2021. “Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 15: 781778.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Lindenbaum, L., Zehe, S., Anlauff, J., Hermann, T., Kißler, J.: Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience. 15, : 781778 (2021).</lncs>
<default>Lindenbaum L, Zehe S, Anlauff J, Hermann T, Kißler J (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 15: 781778.</default>
<mla>Lindenbaum, Laura, Zehe, Sebastian, Anlauff, Jan, Hermann, Thomas, and Kißler, Johanna. “Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 15 (2021): 781778.</mla>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lindenbaum, L., Zehe, S., Anlauff, J., Hermann, T. &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2021). Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;: 781778. Frontiers Media. doi:10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Lindenbaum, L., Zehe, S., Anlauff, J., Hermann, T., and Kißler, J. (2021). Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; 15:781778.</frontiers>
<ama>Lindenbaum L, Zehe S, Anlauff J, Hermann T, Kißler J. Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;15: 781778.</ama>
<ieee> L. Lindenbaum, et al., “Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 15, 2021, : 781778.</ieee>
<apa>Lindenbaum, L., Zehe, S., Anlauff, J., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2021). Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;, 781778. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<wels>Lindenbaum, L.; Zehe, S.; Anlauff, J.; Hermann, T.; Kißler, J. (2021): Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;,15:781778</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Lindenbaum, S.  Zehe, J.  Anlauff, T.  Hermann, and J.  Kißler, “Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;, : 781778.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lindenbaum L, Zehe S, Anlauff J, Hermann T, Kißler J (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience 15: 781778.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lindenbaum, L., Zehe, S., Anlauff, J., Hermann, T., &amp;amp; Kißler, J. (2021). Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;, 781778. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2021.781778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Lindenbaum, L., et al., 2021. Different Patterns of Attention Modulation in Early N140 and Late P300 sERPs Following Ipsilateral vs. Contralateral Stimulation at the Fingers and Cheeks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 15: 781778.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2959948</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-14T17:15:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-18T12:58:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>