<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2959954</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:790</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:796</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Medina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Srem-Sai</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Quansah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James Boadu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frimpong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The purpose of this study was to examine the cross-cultural validity of the Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers (OSI-SP) scale by investigating its psychometric properties with Ghanaian footballers. The study particularly sought to assess in the Ghanaian context, 1, the convergence validity and reliability of the OSI-SP scale, 2, the discriminant validity of the OSI-SP scale to understand the applicability of its factor structure, and 3, whether the OSI-SP hypothesized model fits the data collected within the study context. The intensity aspect of the OSI-SP questionnaire was administered to 424 Ghana Premier League (GPL) male footballers who took part in the 2020/2021 season. Quality control strategies were put in place to ensure consistency across interpreters and as well improve the validity of the data. The results from a multi-factor first-order confirmatory factor analysis showed some level of convergence validity of the OSI-SP scale in the Ghanaian context using football players. Out of the 23 items on the original scale, 20 met the factor loadings criterion. In assessing the discriminant validity of the OSI-SP scale using Heterotrait-monotrait (HTMT), 50% of the correlation ratios met the criterion for the original 23-item instrument. Comparing the new model (with the 20-items) with the original model (with 23-items) using the Akaike Information Criterion (AIC) value, the model fit indices for the modified model (20-items) appeared better than the original model with 23-items. Generally, there was minimal support for the applicability of the OSI-SP instrument across the sample of Ghanaian footballers. The implications of these findings are discussed in detail.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="fpsyg-12-772184.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2959954/2960597/fpsyg-12-772184.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Frontiers Media </publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cross-cultural</topic><topic>Ghana</topic><topic>organizational stressor</topic><topic>Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers(OSI-SP)</topic><topic>structural equational modeling (SEM)</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Frontiers in Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1664-1078</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34966331</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000735949600001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29599542</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>12</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Srem-Sai, M., Quansah, F., Frimpong, J. B., Hagan Jr., J. E., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2021). Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 772184. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Srem-Sai, M., et al., 2021. Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 12: 772184.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Srem-Sai, et al., “Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 12, 2021, : 772184.</ieee>
<default>Srem-Sai M, Quansah F, Frimpong JB, Hagan Jr. JE, Schack T (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 772184.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Srem-Sai, M., Quansah, F., Frimpong, J. B., Hagan Jr., J. E., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2021). Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 772184. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Srem-Sai, M., Quansah, F., Frimpong, J. B., Hagan Jr., J. E., and Schack, T. (2021). Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12:772184.</frontiers>
<mla>Srem-Sai, Medina, Quansah, Frank, Frimpong, James Boadu, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, and Schack, Thomas. “Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12 (2021): 772184.</mla>
<wels>Srem-Sai, M.; Quansah, F.; Frimpong, J. B.; Hagan Jr., J. E.; Schack, T. (2021): Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,12:772184</wels>
<lncs> Srem-Sai, M., Quansah, F., Frimpong, J.B., Hagan Jr., J.E., Schack, T.: Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. Frontiers in Psychology. 12, : 772184 (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Srem-Sai, Medina, Quansah, Frank, Frimpong, James Boadu, Hagan Jr., John Elvis, and Schack, Thomas. 2021. “Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach”. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12: 772184.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Srem-Sai M, Quansah F, Frimpong JB, Hagan Jr. JE, Schack T. Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;12: 772184.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Srem-Sai, F.  Quansah, J. B.  Frimpong, J. E.  Hagan Jr., and T.  Schack, “Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach”, &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, : 772184.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Srem-Sai M, Quansah F, Frimpong JB, Hagan Jr. JE, Schack T (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach.&lt;br /&gt;Frontiers in Psychology 12: 772184.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Srem-Sai, M., Quansah, F., Frimpong, J.B., Hagan Jr., J.E. &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2021). Cross-Cultural Applicability of Organizational Stressor Indicator for Sport Performers Questionnaire in Ghana Using Structural Equation Modeling Approach. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;: 772184. Frontiers Media . doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2021.772184.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2959954</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-15T08:02:04Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-14T13:42:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>