<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2959022</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Belau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">84979440</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175763</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Little is known about social determinants among refugees resettled in Germany. This study aims to examine the impact of family separation on refugees’ subjective time pressure and mental health. Data come from the FlueGe Health Study (n = 208), a cross-sectional study administered by Bielefeld University. We used logistic regression analysis to investigate the effect of family separation on (i) being time-stressed and (ii) having a high risk for adverse mental health, considering sociodemographic and postmigration factors. As a result, more than 30% of participants with a spouse or partner and about 18% with a child or children reported separation. Multiple logistic regression showed that family separation was not associated with being time-stressed, but separation from at least one child was associated with adverse mental health (OR = 3.53, 95% CI = [1.23, 10.11]). In conclusion, family separation primarily contributes to adverse mental health among refugees from the Middle East and Africa resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany. Therefore, policies and practices that facilitate family reunification can contribute significantly to the promotion of refugees’ mental health and well-being.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijerph-18-11722-v2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2959022/2959023/ijerph-18-11722-v2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>family separation</topic><topic>time pressure</topic><topic>mental health</topic><topic>health disparities</topic><topic>refugees</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1660-4601</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">34770236</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000718581400001</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29590221</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijerph182111722</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>18</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>21</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Belau, M., Becher, H., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2021). Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(21), 11722. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111722" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111722&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Belau, M., Becher, H., &amp;amp; Krämer, A., 2021. Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, 18(21): 11722.</harvard1>
<ieee> M. Belau, H. Becher, and A. Krämer, “Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 18, 2021, : 11722.</ieee>
<default>Belau M, Becher H, Krämer A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18(21): 11722.</default>
<wels>Belau, M.; Becher, H.; Krämer, A. (2021): Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;,18:(21):11722</wels>
<frontiers>Belau, M., Becher, H., and Krämer, A. (2021). Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18:11722.</frontiers>
<mla>Belau, Matthias, Becher, Heiko, and Krämer, Alexander. “Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18.21 (2021): 11722.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Belau, M., Becher, H., &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2021). Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(21), 11722. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111722" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111722&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Belau, Matthias, Becher, Heiko, and Krämer, Alexander. 2021. “Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt; 18 (21): 11722.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Belau, M., Becher, H., Krämer, A.: Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 18, : 11722 (2021).</lncs>
<ama>Belau M, Becher H, Krämer A. Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2021;18(21): 11722.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Belau, H.  Becher, and A.  Krämer, “Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;, : 11722.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Belau M, Becher H, Krämer A (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 18(21): 11722.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Belau, M., Becher, H. &amp;amp; Krämer, A. (2021). Impact of Family Separation on Subjective Time Pressure and Mental Health in Refugees from the Middle East and Africa Resettled in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany: A Cross-Sectional Study. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(21): 11722. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijerph182111722.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2959022</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-11-15T07:22:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-14T13:18:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>