<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2960155</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">epub_ahead</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Henschel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">286870345</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Iffland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7989113</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-3122-005X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33704</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Fear of failure (FF) is a multidimensional construct encompassing anticipated negative consequences deriving from potential failures in evaluative achievement contexts, such as education or sports. The Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory (PFAI; Conroy et al., 2002 ) assesses five threat appraisals associated with FF and has been validated in various cultures, languages, and contexts. To date, there is no instrument measuring FF in an academic context in German. Thus, this study examined the psychometric properties of a German version of the PFAI in a sample of N = 326 university students. Confirmatory factor analyses supported a correlated five-factor structure that has already been established in previous validation studies as well as a bifactor structure. All dimensions demonstrated satisfactory internal consistencies and construct validity. Within the scope of this study, the German version of the PFAI was found to be a psychometrically sound measure to assess FF in an academic context amongst university students.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2698-1866_a000018.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2960155/2960659/2698-1866_a000018.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Hogrefe Publishing Group</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2021</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Psychological Test Adaptation and Development</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2698-1866</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29601554</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1027/2698-1866/a000018</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> C. Henschel and B. Iffland, “Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory”, &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;, 2021.</ieee>
<harvard1>Henschel, C., &amp;amp; Iffland, B., 2021. Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<ama>Henschel C, Iffland B. Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;. 2021.</ama>
<apa>Henschel, C., &amp;amp; Iffland, B. (2021). Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1027/2698-1866/a000018" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1027/2698-1866/a000018&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<lncs> Henschel, C., Iffland, B.: Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. Psychological Test Adaptation and Development. (2021).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henschel, Christine, and Iffland, Benjamin. 2021. “Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory”. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Henschel, C.; Iffland, B. (2021): Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henschel, C., &amp;amp; Iffland, B. (2021). Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1027/2698-1866/a000018" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1027/2698-1866/a000018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Henschel, Christine, and Iffland, Benjamin. “Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory”. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt; (2021).</mla>
<frontiers>Henschel, C., and Iffland, B. (2021). Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Henschel, C. &amp;amp; Iffland, B. (2021). Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;. Hogrefe Publishing Group. doi:10.1027/2698-1866/a000018.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Henschel C, Iffland B (2021) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;.</default>
<bio1>Henschel C, Iffland B (2021) &lt;br /&gt;Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory.&lt;br /&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Henschel, and B.  Iffland, “Measuring Fear of Failure - Validation of a German Version of the Performance Failure Appraisal Inventory”, &lt;em&gt;Psychological Test Adaptation and Development&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2960155</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-17T15:11:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-18T16:26:14Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>