<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2960096</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:610</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alyson A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van Raalte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Klüsener</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Oksuzyan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">302976228</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4138-5886</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Pavel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grigoriev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">175763</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">**Background**&lt;br&gt;
Subnational regional mortality inequalities are large and appear to be mostly increasing within industrialized countries, although comparative studies across high-income countries are scarce. Germany is an important country to examine because it continues to experience considerable economic disparities between its federal states, in part resulting from its former division.
                  
**Methods**&lt;br&gt;
We analyse state-level mortality in Germany utilizing data from a newly constructed regional database based on the methodology of the Human Mortality Database. We compare time trends (1991–2015) in the German state-level standard deviation in life expectancy to that of other large, wealthy countries and examine the association between mortality and economic inequalities at the regional level. Finally, using contour-decomposition methods, we investigate the degree to which age patterns of mortality are converging across German federal states.
                  
**Results**&lt;br&gt;
Regional inequalities in life expectancy in Germany are comparatively low internationally, particularly among women, despite high state-level inequalities in economic conditions. These low regional mortality inequalities emerged 5–10 years after reunification. Mortality is converging over most ages between the longest- and shortest-living German state populations and across the former East–West political border, with the exception of an emerging East–West divergence in mortality among working-aged men.
                  
**Conclusions**&lt;br&gt;
The German example shows that large regional economic inequalities are not necessarily paralleled with large regional mortality disparities. Future research should investigate the factors that fostered the emergence of this unusual pattern in Germany.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="dyz265.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2960096/2960144/dyz265.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Epidemiology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0300-5771</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1464-3685</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">31977053</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000542052400021</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29600963</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/ije/dyz265</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>49</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">486-496</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="extern">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> van Raalte, A.A., Klüsener, S., Oksuzyan, A., Grigoriev, P.: Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. International Journal of Epidemiology. 49, 486-496 (2020).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Raalte, Alyson A., Klüsener, Sebastian, Oksuzyan, Anna, and Grigoriev, Pavel. 2020. “Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 49 (2): 486-496.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>van Raalte AA, Klüsener S, Oksuzyan A, Grigoriev P. Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;. 2020;49(2):486-496.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>A. A.  van Raalte, S.  Klüsener, A.  Oksuzyan, and P.  Grigoriev, “Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;, 486-496.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>van Raalte AA, Klüsener S, Oksuzyan A, Grigoriev P (2020) &lt;br /&gt;Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology 49(2): 486-496.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Raalte, A.A., Klüsener, S., Oksuzyan, A. &amp;amp; Grigoriev, P. (2020). Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(2), 486-496. Oxford University Press (OUP). doi:10.1093/ije/dyz265.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>van Raalte, A. A., Klüsener, S., Oksuzyan, A., &amp;amp; Grigoriev, P. (2020). Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(2), 486-496. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyz265" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyz265&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>van Raalte, A.A., et al., 2020. Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, 49(2), p 486-496.</harvard1>
<ieee> A.A. van Raalte, et al., “Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 49, 2020,  pp. 486-496.</ieee>
<default>van Raalte AA, Klüsener S, Oksuzyan A, Grigoriev P (2020) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 49(2): 486-496.</default>
<wels>van Raalte, A. A.; Klüsener, S.; Oksuzyan, A.; Grigoriev, P. (2020): Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;,49:(2): 486-496.</wels>
<frontiers>van Raalte, A. A., Klüsener, S., Oksuzyan, A., and Grigoriev, P. (2020). Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 49, 486-496.</frontiers>
<mla>van Raalte, Alyson A., Klüsener, Sebastian, Oksuzyan, Anna, and Grigoriev, Pavel. “Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt; 49.2 (2020): 486-496.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;van Raalte, A. A., Klüsener, S., Oksuzyan, A., &amp;amp; Grigoriev, P. (2020). Declining regional disparities in mortality in the context of persisting large inequalities in economic conditions: the case of Germany. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Epidemiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(2), 486-496. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyz265" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyz265&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2960096</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2021-12-16T19:27:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-28T10:21:56Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>