<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2960696</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:000</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eleonore</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lumer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">279196939</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hendrik</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buschmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">9618254</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-9613-5713</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10019</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction</namePart>
</name>






<abstract lang="eng">The use and interpretation of social linguistic strategies such as politeness is influenced by multiple factors, e.g., the speaker-hearer relation. Such relations influence an interlocutor's expectations regarding the interaction and thus also its perception. This makes speaker-hearer relations constituting a partner model highly relevant for the user experience in human-robot interaction as well. This paper presents a questionnaire-based study on the perception of human-robot relations in comparison to human-human relations across different roles (e.g., colleague, assistant) and spaces of interaction (home, work, public). It was found that participants perceive robots differently based on space, as they do for human-human relations in corresponding roles. Overall, humans were evaluated to have more power over and more distance to a robot interaction partner compared to another human. Our results provide insights into an intuitive interaction-initial partner model based on roles.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="LumerBuschmeier-2022-HRI.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2960696/2961610/LumerBuschmeier-2022-HRI.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>IEEE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Sapporo, Hokkaido, Japan</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29606969</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.5555/3523760.3523900</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">895–899</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<relatedItem type="Supplementary material">
  <location>
  
     <url>http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/4KJX2</url>
  
  </location>
</relatedItem>

<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Lumer, E., &amp;amp; Buschmeier, H. (2022). Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Human-Robot Interaction, 895–899. IEEE. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5555/3523760.3523900" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5555/3523760.3523900&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<harvard1>Lumer, E., &amp;amp; Buschmeier, H., 2022. Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Human-Robot Interaction.  IEEE, pp. 895–899.</harvard1>
<ieee> E. Lumer and H. Buschmeier, “Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Human-Robot Interaction, IEEE, 2022,  pp.895–899.</ieee>
<default>Lumer E, Buschmeier H (2022)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. Human-Robot Interaction.  IEEE:  895–899.</default>
<wels>Lumer, E.; Buschmeier, H. (2022): Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. In: Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. IEEE. (Human-Robot Interaction, ).  S. 895–899.</wels>
<frontiers>Lumer, E., and Buschmeier, H. (2022). “Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt; Human-Robot Interaction (IEEE), 895–899.</frontiers>
<mla>Lumer, Eleonore, and Buschmeier, Hendrik. “Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE, 2022. Human-Robot Interaction. 895–899.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lumer, E., &amp;amp; Buschmeier, H. (2022). Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Human-Robot Interaction, 895–899. IEEE. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5555/3523760.3523900" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.5555/3523760.3523900&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs> Lumer, E., Buschmeier, H.: Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. Human-Robot Interaction. p. 895–899. IEEE (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lumer, Eleonore, and Buschmeier, Hendrik. 2022. “Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, 895–899. Human-Robot Interaction. IEEE.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Lumer E, Buschmeier H. Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;. Human-Robot Interaction. IEEE;  2022: 895–899.</ama>
<angewandte-chemie>E.  Lumer, and H.  Buschmeier, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt;, Ieee, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 895–899.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Lumer E, Buschmeier H (2022) &lt;br /&gt;Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction.  Human-Robot Interaction,  IEEE:  895–899.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Lumer, E. &amp;amp; Buschmeier, H. (2022). Perception of power and distance in human-human and human-robot role-based relations (Human-Robot Interaction). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 895–899). Gehalten auf der 2022 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction, IEEE. doi:10.5555/3523760.3523900.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2960696</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-01-21T14:17:36Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-16T09:59:33Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>