<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961845</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:300</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Elvis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagan Jr.</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">60449953</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Quansah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Francis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Akomah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Egmond Kwesi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Agormedah</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Medina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Srem-Sai</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">James Boadu</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frimpong</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">167615</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">28977957</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Cognitive-behavioral coping among teachers is an important issue of investigation due to the reported high prevalence of anxiety associated with the COVID-19 pandemic. Whereas several studies have assessed COVID-19 awareness of individuals as a predictor of anxiety, the moderating role of awareness in anxiety and coping mechanisms remains unclear. The study primarily examined the nexus between awareness of COVID-19 and (a) anxiety and (b) coping strategies, including the interaction effect of COVID-19-related awareness in the link between anxiety and coping strategies among senior high school teachers. A descriptive cross-sectional survey design was adopted to conveniently select 184 teachers from senior high schools in the Cape Coast Metropolis. Questionnaires were administered to the participants and data were analyzed with means, standard deviation, Pearson correlation, and linear regression statistical procedures. Summarily, the results revealed a negative relationship between COVID-19 awareness and anxiety levels of teachers. COVID-19-related anxiety significantly predicted coping mechanisms of teachers. Further, COVID-19 awareness significantly moderated the relationship between anxiety and coping strategies adopted. These findings imply that the public health education and mass awareness campaign programs on COVID-19 could act as buffers against the spread of COVID-19, its associated comorbidities, and help improve the mental health of teachers. Promoting adaptation to COVID-19 through the use of functional management strategies such as active coping and emotional support should be encouraged in the Cape Coast Metropolis among teachers. </abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="socsci-11-00137.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961845/2961868/socsci-11-00137.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>active coping</topic><topic>anxiety</topic><topic>behavior disengagement</topic><topic>emotional support</topic><topic>religious coping</topic><topic>senior high school</topic><topic>teachers</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Social Sciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2076-0760 </identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29618452</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/socsci11030137 </identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., J.E., Quansah, F., Akomah, F., Agormedah, E.K., Srem-Sai, M., Frimpong, J.B. &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2022). Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3): 137. MDPI. doi:10.3390/socsci11030137 .&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<angewandte-chemie>J. E.  Hagan Jr., F.  Quansah, F.  Akomah, E. K.  Agormedah, M.  Srem-Sai, J. B.  Frimpong, and T.  Schack, “Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana”, &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, : 137.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hagan Jr. JE, Quansah F, Akomah F, Agormedah EK, Srem-Sai M, Frimpong JB, Schack T (2022) &lt;br /&gt;Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana.&lt;br /&gt;Social Sciences 11(3): 137.</bio1>
<ama>Hagan Jr. JE, Quansah F, Akomah F, et al. Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 2022;11(3): 137.</ama>
<lncs> Hagan Jr., J.E., Quansah, F., Akomah, F., Agormedah, E.K., Srem-Sai, M., Frimpong, J.B., Schack, T.: Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. Social Sciences. 11, : 137 (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Quansah, Frank, Akomah, Francis, Agormedah, Egmond Kwesi, Srem-Sai, Medina, Frimpong, James Boadu, and Schack, Thomas. 2022. “Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana”. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 11 (3): 137.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Hagan Jr., J. E.; Quansah, F.; Akomah, F.; Agormedah, E. K.; Srem-Sai, M.; Frimpong, J. B.; Schack, T. (2022): Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,11:(3):137</wels>
<mla>Hagan Jr., John Elvis, Quansah, Frank, Akomah, Francis, Agormedah, Egmond Kwesi, Srem-Sai, Medina, Frimpong, James Boadu, and Schack, Thomas. “Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana”. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 11.3 (2022): 137.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Hagan Jr., J. E., Quansah, F., Akomah, F., Agormedah, E. K., Srem-Sai, M., Frimpong, J. B., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2022). Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3), 137. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci11030137 " target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci11030137 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Hagan Jr., J. E., Quansah, F., Akomah, F., Agormedah, E. K., Srem-Sai, M., Frimpong, J. B., and Schack, T. (2022). Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 11:137.</frontiers>
<default>Hagan Jr. JE, Quansah F, Akomah F, Agormedah EK, Srem-Sai M, Frimpong JB, Schack T (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 11(3): 137.</default>
<harvard1>Hagan Jr., J.E., et al., 2022. Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 11(3): 137.</harvard1>
<ieee> J.E. Hagan Jr., et al., “Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana”, &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 11, 2022, : 137.</ieee>
<apa>Hagan Jr., J. E., Quansah, F., Akomah, F., Agormedah, E. K., Srem-Sai, M., Frimpong, J. B., &amp;amp; Schack, T. (2022). Linking COVID-19-Related Awareness and Anxiety as Determinants of Coping Strategies’ Utilization among Senior High School Teachers in Cape Coast Metropolis, Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(3), 137. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci11030137 " target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci11030137 &lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961845</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-18T07:11:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-21T06:12:53Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>