<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961697</id><setSpec>conference</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:conferenceObject</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:430</setSpec><setSpec>conferenceFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">accepted</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J. Berenike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Herrmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">262987169</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-5256-0566</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Byszuk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giulia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grisot</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">287681546</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-3038-6202</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">4964810</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Spatial distant reading uses computational means to investigate fictional representations of
space as a central category of sense-making (Lefebre, 1974), both in fictional world building
(e.g., Bologna, 2020) and in societal contexts (e.g., Wilkens, 2021).
Our spatial distant reading project investigates the affective topologies of German-Swiss
literature to examine different types of spatial representation in fictional Swiss-German prose
between 1854 and 1930, assessing iconic differences such as culture/nature, urban/rural
(Rehm, 2014), as well as the (alpine) mountains’ role in Swiss literary national framing
(Zimmer, 1998). A key resource is a list of spatial terms (N=187,421 entities), including
spatial named entities, other urban and rural toponyms, as well as natural terms (Grisot &amp;
Herrmann, in prep.). In the current paper, we take a methodological focus on this resource,
exploring word embeddings for validation (Task A) and extension (Task B) of our spatial
entity lists.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Herrmann_2022_Using_Word_Embeddings_for_Validation_and_Enhancement_of_Spatial_Entity_Lists-1.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961697/2961698/Herrmann_2022_Using_Word_Embeddings_for_Validation_and_Enhancement_of_Spatial_Entity_Lists-1.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued><place><placeTerm type="text">Tokyo</placeTerm></place>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>word embeddigs</topic><topic>spatial distant reading</topic><topic>swiss literature</topic><topic>interior space</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29616971</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> J.B. Herrmann, J. Byszuk, and G. Grisot, “Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists”, &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;, Accepted.</ieee>
<harvard1>Herrmann, J.B., Byszuk, J., &amp;amp; Grisot, G., Accepted. Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. In &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;.</harvard1>
<apa>Herrmann, J. B., Byszuk, J., &amp;amp; Grisot, G. (Accepted). Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;</apa>
<mla>Herrmann, J. Berenike, Byszuk, Joanna, and Grisot, Giulia. “Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists”. &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;. Accepted.</mla>
<frontiers>Herrmann, J. B., Byszuk, J., and Grisot, G. (Accepted). “Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists” in &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herrmann, J. B., Byszuk, J., &amp;amp; Grisot, G. (Accepted). Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Herrmann, J. B.; Byszuk, J.; Grisot, G. (Accepted): Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. In: International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan.</wels>
<default>Herrmann JB, Byszuk J, Grisot G (Accepted)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan.</default>
<ama>Herrmann JB, Byszuk J, Grisot G. Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. In:  &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;. Accepted.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herrmann, J. Berenike, Byszuk, Joanna, and Grisot, Giulia. Accepted. “Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists”. In &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Herrmann, J.B., Byszuk, J., Grisot, G.: Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan.  (Accepted).</lncs>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Herrmann, J.B., Byszuk, J. &amp;amp; Grisot, G. (Accepted). Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Herrmann JB, Byszuk J, Grisot G (Accepted) &lt;br /&gt;Using Word Embeddings for Validation and Enhancement of Spatial Entity Lists. &lt;br /&gt;In:  International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan. .</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>J. B.  Herrmann, J.  Byszuk, and G.  Grisot, in &lt;em&gt;International Conference Digital Humanities 2022. Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Accepted&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961697</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-10T20:34:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-10T20:34:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>