<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961317</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:150</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Usama</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">El-Awad</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">223960305</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Atefeh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Fathi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Arnold</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lohaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">174992</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Petermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tilman</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reinelt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">33696</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Religiosity can foster mental health after traumatic experiences. Yet, religiosity among Muslim immigrants has also been linked to separation-oriented acculturation, which is linked to reduced mental health. Therefore, the function of religiosity for resilience in Middle Eastern refugee and immigrant adolescents might differ as their migration contexts differ in terms of traumatic experiences and the nature of cultural interactions. Aims: This study examined whether religiosity is associated with better mental health after traumatic experiences, particularly among young refugees. In addition, it was explored whether religiosity is associated with better mental health among refugees through less marginalization and whether religious immigrant peers show worse mental health through stronger separation. Method: 135 adolescents (M-Age = 18.25 years, SD = 1.73; n(refugees) = 75, n(immigrants) = 60) completed self-reports on religiosity, mental health, trauma, and acculturation orientations. Regression analyses were calculated examining group-specific differences in potential moderating effects of religiosity on the relationship between trauma exposures and internalizing symptoms. Furthermore, potential indirect effects of religiosity on internalizing symptoms via acculturation orientations were investigated. Results: Stronger religiosity was associated with better mental health following trauma exposure. No group-specific differences were observed. While religious refugee adolescents reported less marginalization associated with fewer internalizing symptoms, religious immigrant peers reported more separation and internalizing symptoms. Limitations: Results are limited to male Muslim adolescents in Germany. The cross-sectional nature prohibits any implications for causal dynamics in the associations. Conclusion: Religiosity is generally protective against post-traumatic consequences, but associations with acculturation differ across migration contexts.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2512-8442_a000100.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961317/2961651/2512-8442_a000100.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Hogrefe &amp; Huber</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>refugee adolescents</topic><topic>migrant adolescents</topic><topic>religion</topic><topic>mental health</topic><topic>acculturation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>European Journal of Health Psychology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">2512-8442</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">2512-8450</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000749175200004</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29613178</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1027/2512-8442/a000100</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>29</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">26-37</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;El-Awad, Usama, Fathi, Atefeh, Lohaus, Arnold, Petermann, Franz, and Reinelt, Tilman. 2022. “Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 29 (1): 26-37.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> El-Awad, U., Fathi, A., Lohaus, A., Petermann, F., Reinelt, T.: Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. European Journal of Health Psychology. 29, 26-37 (2022).</lncs>
<default>El-Awad U, Fathi A, Lohaus A, Petermann F, Reinelt T (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 29(1): 26-37.</default>
<mla>El-Awad, Usama, Fathi, Atefeh, Lohaus, Arnold, Petermann, Franz, and Reinelt, Tilman. “Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents”. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 29.1 (2022): 26-37.</mla>
<wels>El-Awad, U.; Fathi, A.; Lohaus, A.; Petermann, F.; Reinelt, T. (2022): Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,29:(1): 26-37.</wels>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  El-Awad, A.  Fathi, A.  Lohaus, F.  Petermann, and T.  Reinelt, “Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;, 26-37.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>El-Awad U, Fathi A, Lohaus A, Petermann F, Reinelt T (2022) &lt;br /&gt;Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents.&lt;br /&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology 29(1): 26-37.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;El-Awad, U., Fathi, A., Lohaus, A., Petermann, F., &amp;amp; Reinelt, T. (2022). Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1), 26-37. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1027/2512-8442/a000100" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1027/2512-8442/a000100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>El-Awad, U., et al., 2022. Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 29(1), p 26-37.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;El-Awad, U., Fathi, A., Lohaus, A., Petermann, F. &amp;amp; Reinelt, T. (2022). Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1), 26-37. Hogrefe &amp;amp; Huber. doi:10.1027/2512-8442/a000100.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>El-Awad, U., Fathi, A., Lohaus, A., Petermann, F., and Reinelt, T. (2022). Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 29, 26-37.</frontiers>
<ama>El-Awad U, Fathi A, Lohaus A, Petermann F, Reinelt T. Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. 2022;29(1):26-37.</ama>
<ieee> U. El-Awad, et al., “Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents”, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 29, 2022,  pp. 26-37.</ieee>
<apa>El-Awad, U., Fathi, A., Lohaus, A., Petermann, F., &amp;amp; Reinelt, T. (2022). Different Relations of Religion and Mental Health Comparing Middle Eastern Muslim Refugee and Immigrant Adolescents. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(1), 26-37. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1027/2512-8442/a000100" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1027/2512-8442/a000100&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961317</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-21T11:56:16Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-07T14:46:49Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>