<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961488</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Felix</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dammann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">247091398</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Giorgio</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ferrari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">32701753</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10053</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We study an optimal liquidation problem with multiplicative price impact in which the
trend of the asset’s price is an unobservable Bernoulli random variable. The investor aims at selling
over an infinite time-horizon a fixed amount of assets in order to maximize a net expected profit
functional, and lump-sum as well as singularly continuous actions are allowed. Our mathematical
modelling leads to a singular stochastic control problem featuring a finite-fuel constraint and partial
observation. We provide the complete analysis of an equivalent three-dimensional degenerate problem
under full information, whose state process is composed of the asset’s price dynamics, the amount of
available assets in the portfolio, and the investor’s belief about the true value of the asset’s trend.
The optimal execution rule and the problem’s value function are expressed in terms of the solution to
a truly two-dimensional optimal stopping problem, whose associated belief-dependent free boundary
b triggers the investor’s optimal selling rule. The curve b is uniquely determined through a nonlinear
integral equation, for which we derive a numerical solution allowing to understand the sensitivity of
the problem’s solution with respect to the relevant model’s parameters.
</abstract>
<abstract lang="eng">MSC2020 subject classification: 93E20, 93C41, 49L20, 91G80
</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="IMW_working_paper_663.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961488/2961489/IMW_working_paper_663.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Center for Mathematical Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>optimal execution problem</topic><topic>multiplicative price impact</topic><topic>singular stochastic control</topic><topic>partial observation</topic><topic>optimal stopping</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">0931-6558</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29614880</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>663</number></detail><extent unit="pages">38</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Dammann F, Ferrari G. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Vol 663. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics; 2022.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dammann, F. &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Dammann, F., and Ferrari, G. (2022). Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return. &lt;em&gt;Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers&lt;/em&gt;, 663, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</frontiers>
<apa>Dammann, F., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 663). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</apa>
<ieee> F. Dammann and G. Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, vol. 663,  Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2022.</ieee>
<wels>Dammann, F.; Ferrari, G. (2022): Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dammann, F., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt; (Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 663). Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<bio1>Dammann F, Ferrari G (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 663.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</bio1>
<harvard1>Dammann, F., &amp;amp; Ferrari, G., 2022. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, no.663, Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Dammann, and G.  Ferrari, &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;, Center For Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<lncs> Dammann, F., Ferrari, G.: Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers, 663. Center for Mathematical Economics, Bielefeld (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Dammann, Felix, and Ferrari, Giorgio. 2022. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 663. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Dammann, Felix, and Ferrari, Giorgio. &lt;em&gt;Optimal Execution with Multiplicative Price Impact and Incomplete Information on the Return&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics, 2022. Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers. 663.</mla>
<default>Dammann F, Ferrari G (2022)  Center for Mathematical Economics Working Papers; 663.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Center for Mathematical Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961488</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-01T13:28:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-01T13:32:16Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>