<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961298</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:320</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction</title></titleInfo>




<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alejandro</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Esguerra</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">137006290</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Frank</namePart><namePart type="family">Gadinger</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">5656050</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Esguerra_22docx.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961298/2961299/Esguerra_22docx.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29612983</identifier>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Esguerra, A. (2022). An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In F. Gadinger (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Esguerra A (2022) &lt;br /&gt;An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today. Gadinger F (Ed); Oxford: Oxford University Press.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Esguerra, in &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: F. Gadinger), Oxford University Press, Oxford, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Esguerra A. An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In: Gadinger F, ed. &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford: Oxford University Press;  2022.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Esguerra, Alejandro. 2022. “An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction”. In &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Frank Gadinger. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Esguerra, A.: An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In: Gadinger, F. (ed.) Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today.  Oxford University Press, Oxford (2022).</lncs>
<mla>Esguerra, Alejandro. “An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction”. &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Frank Gadinger. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2022.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Esguerra, A. (2022). An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In F.  Gadinger (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt; Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Esguerra, A. (2022). “An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction” in &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;, Gadinger, F. ed. (Oxford: Oxford University Press).</frontiers>
<wels>Esguerra, A. (2022): An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In: Frank Gadinger (Hrsg.):  Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</wels>
<default>Esguerra A (2022)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today. Gadinger F (Ed);  Oxford: Oxford University Press.</default>
<ieee> A. Esguerra, “An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction”, &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;, F. Gadinger, ed.,  Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2022.</ieee>
<harvard1>Esguerra, A., 2022. An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In F.  Gadinger, ed. &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt;.  Oxford: Oxford University Press.</harvard1>
<apa>Esguerra, A. (2022). An Actor-Network Perspective on Polycentric Governing. The Politics of Socio-Material Knowledge Construction. In F.  Gadinger (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Polycentrism: How Governing Works Today&lt;/em&gt; Oxford: Oxford University Press.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961298</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-20T17:04:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-28T14:25:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>