<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961432</id><setSpec>journal_article</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:article</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:570</setSpec><setSpec>journal_articleFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Laureen P.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Helweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Beatrice Ariane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Windmöller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">304595513</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Leonie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Burghardt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">304940351</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jonathan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Storm</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Förster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nils</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wethkamp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ludwig</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wilkens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaltschmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">7702352</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Constanze</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Banz-Jansen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaltschmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">4430077</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">2685621</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Cancer stem cells (CSCs) are a small subpopulation of tumor cells harboring properties that include self-renewal, multi-lineage differentiation, tumor reconstitution, drug resistance and invasiveness, making them key players in tumor relapse. In the present paper, we develop new CSC models and analyze the molecular pathways involved in survival to identify targets for the establishment of novel therapies. Endometrial carcinoma-derived stem-like cells (ECSCs) were isolated from carcinogenic gynecological tissue and analyzed regarding their expression of prominent CSC markers. Further, they were treated with the MYC-signaling inhibitor KJ-Pyr-9, chemotherapeutic agent carboplatin and type II diabetes medication metformin. ECSC populations express common CSC markers, such as Prominin-1 and CD44 antigen as well as epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition markers, Twist, Snail and Slug, and exhibit the ability to form free-floating spheres. The inhibition of MYC signaling and treatment with carboplatin as well as metformin significantly reduced the cell survival of ECSC-like cells. Further, treatment with metformin significantly decreased the mitochondrial membrane potential of ECSC-like cells, while the extracellular lactate concentration was increased. The established ECSC-like populations represent promising in vitro models to further study the contribution of ECSCs to endometrial carcinogenesis. Targeting MYC signaling as well as mitochondrial bioenergetics has shown promising results in the diminishment of ECSCs, although molecular signaling pathways need further investigations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="ijms-23-02426-v2.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961432/2961433/ijms-23-02426-v2.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>MDPI AG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>cancer stem cells</topic><topic>endometrial cancer</topic><topic>primary endometrial cancer stem cells</topic><topic>MYC</topic><topic>metformin</topic><topic>mitochondria</topic><topic>EMT</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>International Journal of Molecular Sciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1422-0067</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">35269569</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29614321</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.3390/ijms23052426</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>23</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Helweg, L. P., Windmöller, B. A., Burghardt, L., Storm, J., Förster, C., Wethkamp, N., Wilkens, L., et al. (2022). The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;23&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2426. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23052426" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23052426&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> L.P. Helweg, et al., “The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 23, 2022, : 2426.</ieee>
<harvard1>Helweg, L.P., et al., 2022. The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 23(5): 2426.</harvard1>
<default>Helweg LP, Windmöller BA, Burghardt L, Storm J, Förster C, Wethkamp N, Wilkens L, Kaltschmidt B, Banz-Jansen C, Kaltschmidt C (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 23(5): 2426.</default>
<wels>Helweg, L. P.; Windmöller, B. A.; Burghardt, L.; Storm, J.; Förster, C.; Wethkamp, N.; Wilkens, L.; Kaltschmidt, B.; Banz-Jansen, C.; Kaltschmidt, C. (2022): The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;,23:(5):2426</wels>
<mla>Helweg, Laureen P., Windmöller, Beatrice Ariane, Burghardt, Leonie, Storm, Jonathan, Förster, Christine, Wethkamp, Nils, Wilkens, Ludwig, Kaltschmidt, Barbara, Banz-Jansen, Constanze, and Kaltschmidt, Christian. “The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 23.5 (2022): 2426.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Helweg, L. P., Windmöller, B. A., Burghardt, L., Storm, J., Förster, C., Wethkamp, N., Wilkens, L., et al. (2022). The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;23&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2426. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23052426" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23052426&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Helweg, L. P., Windmöller, B. A., Burghardt, L., Storm, J., Förster, C., Wethkamp, N., Wilkens, L., Kaltschmidt, B., Banz-Jansen, C., and Kaltschmidt, C. (2022). The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 23:2426.</frontiers>
<lncs> Helweg, L.P., Windmöller, B.A., Burghardt, L., Storm, J., Förster, C., Wethkamp, N., Wilkens, L., Kaltschmidt, B., Banz-Jansen, C., Kaltschmidt, C.: The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 23, : 2426 (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Helweg, Laureen P., Windmöller, Beatrice Ariane, Burghardt, Leonie, Storm, Jonathan, Förster, Christine, Wethkamp, Nils, Wilkens, Ludwig, Kaltschmidt, Barbara, Banz-Jansen, Constanze, and Kaltschmidt, Christian. 2022. “The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC”. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 23 (5): 2426.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Helweg LP, Windmöller BA, Burghardt L, et al. The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 2022;23(5): 2426.</ama>
<bio1>Helweg LP, Windmöller BA, Burghardt L, Storm J, Förster C, Wethkamp N, Wilkens L, Kaltschmidt B, Banz-Jansen C, Kaltschmidt C (2022) &lt;br /&gt;The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC.&lt;br /&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences 23(5): 2426.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>L. P.  Helweg, B. A.  Windmöller, L.  Burghardt, J.  Storm, C.  Förster, N.  Wethkamp, L.  Wilkens, B.  Kaltschmidt, C.  Banz-Jansen, and C.  Kaltschmidt, “The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC”, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;23&lt;/em&gt;, : 2426.</angewandte-chemie>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Helweg, L.P., Windmöller, B.A., Burghardt, L., Storm, J., Förster, C., Wethkamp, N., Wilkens, L., Kaltschmidt, B., Banz-Jansen, C. &amp;amp; Kaltschmidt, C. (2022). The Diminishment of Novel Endometrial Carcinoma-Derived Stem-like Cells by Targeting Mitochondrial Bioenergetics and MYC. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Molecular Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;23&lt;/em&gt;(5): 2426. MDPI AG. doi:10.3390/ijms23052426.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961432</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-28T06:24:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-14T09:08:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>