<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961672</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:510</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Greiner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">41164</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Benjamin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Owusu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this paper we empirically analyze the effect of the vaccinations against the
SARS-CoV-2 virus on the Covid-19 pandemic for European countries from February
2021 to February 2022 with weekly data. We perform panel fixed effects estimations,
GMM estimations and nonlinear penalized spline estimations. We find
a statistically significant and positive relation between the share of infections with
the SARS-CoV-2 virus and the share of vaccinated people. That holds for both
fully vaccinated persons and for people having received a booster injection as well.
As regards hospitalizations we find weak empirical evidence for a negative relation
between vaccinations and the rate of hospitalizations.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_03_2022.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961672/2961673/wpaper_03_2022.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Covid-19</topic><topic>vaccination</topic><topic>pandemic</topic><topic>externalities</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29616726</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2961672</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>03-2022</number></detail><extent unit="pages">22</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Greiner, A.; Owusu, B. (2022): Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<bio1>Greiner A, Owusu B (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2022.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2022). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961672" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961672&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B., 2022. &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.03-2022, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Greiner, and B.  Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Greiner A, Owusu B. &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 03-2022. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2022.</ama>
<frontiers>Greiner, A., and Owusu, B. (2022). Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic? &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 03-2022, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, A. &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2961672.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<apa>Greiner, A., &amp;amp; Owusu, B. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2022). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961672" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961672&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<ieee> A. Greiner and B. Owusu, &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 03-2022,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2022.</ieee>
<lncs> Greiner, A., Owusu, B.: Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic? Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 03-2022. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Greiner, Alfred, and Owusu, Benjamin. 2022. &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 03-2022. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Greiner, Alfred, and Owusu, Benjamin. &lt;em&gt;Can the vaccinations end the Covid-19 pandemic?&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2022. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 03-2022.</mla>
<default>Greiner A, Owusu B (2022)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 03-2022.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961672</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-08T13:52:24Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-08T13:55:13Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>