<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961709</id><setSpec>book_chapter</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:bookPart</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:340</setSpec><setSpec>book_chapterFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrike</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Davy</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">156184</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ulrike</namePart><namePart type="family">Davy</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Antje</namePart><namePart type="family">Flüchter</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10029</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">89044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">93309060</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="2022_UDavy_Minority Protection under the League of Nations.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961709/2961712/2022_UDavy_Minority Protection under the League of Nations.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29617090</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">131–165</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Davy, U. (2022). Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In U. Davy &amp;amp; A. Flüchter (Hrsg.), &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt; (S. 131–165). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Davy U (2022) &lt;br /&gt;Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law. Davy U, Flüchter A (Eds); Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press:  131–165.</bio1>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Davy, in &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: U. Davy, A. Flüchter), Bielefeld University Press, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 131–165.</angewandte-chemie>
<ama>Davy U. Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In: Davy U, Flüchter A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press;  2022: 131–165.</ama>
<lncs> Davy, U.: Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In: Davy, U. and Flüchter, A. (eds.) Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law. p. 131–165. Bielefeld University Press, Bielefeld (2022).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Davy, Ulrike. 2022. “Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality”. In &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ulrike Davy and Antje Flüchter, 131–165. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<wels>Davy, U. (2022): Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In: Ulrike Davy; Antje Flüchter (Hrsg.):  Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press.  S. 131–165.</wels>
<frontiers>Davy, U. (2022). “Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality” in &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;, Davy, U., and Flüchter, A. eds. (Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press), 131–165.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Davy, U. (2022). Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In U.  Davy &amp;amp; A.  Flüchter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt; (p. 131–165). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Davy, Ulrike. “Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality”. &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ulrike Davy and Antje Flüchter. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press, 2022. 131–165.</mla>
<default>Davy U (2022)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law. Davy U, Flüchter A (Eds);  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press:  131–165.</default>
<ieee> U. Davy, “Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality”, &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;, U. Davy and A. Flüchter, eds.,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press, 2022,  pp.131–165.</ieee>
<harvard1>Davy, U., 2022. Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In U.  Davy &amp;amp; A.  Flüchter, eds. &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt;.  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press, pp. 131–165.</harvard1>
<apa>Davy, U. (2022). Minority Protection under the League of Nations: Universal and Particular Equality. In U.  Davy &amp;amp; A.  Flüchter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Imagining Unequals, Imagining Equals. Concepts of Equality in History and Law&lt;/em&gt; (p. 131–165). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University Press.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961709</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-11T14:40:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-03-17T08:22:17Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>