<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd"><id>2961170</id><setSpec>working_paper</setSpec><setSpec>doc-type:workingPaper</setSpec><setSpec>ddc:330</setSpec><setSpec>working_paperFtxt</setSpec><setSpec>open_access</setSpec>

<genre>working Paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bettina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bökemeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="local">5537351</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Marcin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart/>
  <identifier type="local">10031</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">This paper empirically analyses fiscal policy behavior in the European Union
(EU) Member States and assesses how it has changed during the recent pandemic
crisis compared to previous crisis situations. Based on panel estimations
the outcomes reveal that this time is different, both concerning the policy direction
as well as its magnitude. We confirm that fiscal policy has turned from
formally pro-cyclical/a-cyclical design prior to COVID-19 period to countercyclical
in the pandemic years. Moreover, this changeover is independent from
the status of the EU membership, as it affects both Old Member States (OMS)
and New Member States (NMS) likewise.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="wpaper_01_2022.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/2961170/2961171/wpaper_01_2022.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription>
  <accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2022</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>COVID-19 pandemic</topic><topic>Discretionary Fiscal Policy</topic><topic>New Member States</topic><topic>Counter-Cyclical Policies</topic><topic>Fiscal Rules</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">2196-2723</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-29611702</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.4119/unibi/2961170</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>01-2022</number></detail><extent unit="pages">15</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Bökemeier B, Wolski M (2022)  Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2022.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</default>
<mla>Bökemeier, Bettina, and Wolski, Marcin. &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2022. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. 01-2022.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bökemeier, Bettina, and Wolski, Marcin. 2022. &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 01-2022. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Bökemeier, B., Wolski, M.: This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2022. Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, Bielefeld (2022).</lncs>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Bökemeier, and M.  Wolski, &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;, Bielefeld University, Department Of Business Administration And Economics, Bielefeld, &lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Bökemeier B, Wolski M (2022) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management; 01-2022.&lt;br /&gt;Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</bio1>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2022). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961170" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961170&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<harvard1>Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M., 2022. &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, no.01-2022, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</harvard1>
<wels>Bökemeier, B.; Wolski, M. (2022): This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</wels>
<ieee> B. Bökemeier and M. Wolski, &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, vol. 01-2022,  Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics, 2022.</ieee>
<apa>Bökemeier, B., &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2022).  &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management, 01-2022). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961170" target="_blank"&gt;https://doi.org/10.4119/unibi/2961170&lt;/a&gt;</apa>
<dgps>&lt;div style="text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;"&gt;Bökemeier, B. &amp;amp; Wolski, M. (2022). &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt; (Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management). Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics. doi:10.4119/unibi/2961170.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Bökemeier, B., and Wolski, M. (2022). This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries. &lt;em&gt;Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management&lt;/em&gt;, 01-2022, Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics.</frontiers>
<ama>Bökemeier B, Wolski M. &lt;em&gt;This time is different: Fiscal response to the COVID-19 pandemic among EU countries&lt;/em&gt;. Universität Bielefeld Working Papers in Economics and Management. Vol 01-2022. Bielefeld: Bielefeld University, Department of Business Administration and Economics; 2022.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>2961170</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-10T12:43:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2022-02-10T12:43:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>